Theater advertisements flew over mountains and valleys.
Wedding!
Look!
Advertisements also flew into the water.
Paralyzed what?
There is some writing on the slip.
It's a manual program.
The Moomin Theater presents a play written by Moominpapa.
Moomin papa?
The missing children. Starring Moominpappa, Moominamma, Nipsu with Emma as a guest star.
Yes, Emma. She is my dear aunt.
And the entrance fee is anything edible.
They are putting on a play.
You in the theater?
The last time I went to the theater was as a little boy.
That play was about a princess who slept in a rose bush.
I have to get to the theater.
But who guards these lawbreakers at that time?
I have a good suggestion for you to consider.
Take us to the theater.
Great idea.
I promise and swear that we won't try to run away.
No.
You won't get out of jail until you write that 5,000 times it's forbidden.
It's punishment for your bad behavior in the park.
That means you can't see the play.
I don't give a damn about it, even though it's about a princess.
No, I'm going.
With us?
No, you stay here.
In that case, you stay too.
I'm going to the theater.
Doesn't sound good. This scene needs to be rewritten.
Moominpapa, I want to play more than a lion's rear end.
After all, you also have another role.
I played a barking baby.
You didn't want any dialogue.
Emma, please sweep up later.
Is the play not finished?
Gotta start practicing or next night will go under the bench.
The play is about to be finished, Pika.
I'm halfway there.
There's no way I'll finish it in time.
It's the same for me. The curtain opens anyway.
Write as many turns as possible for Emma.
He hugs to get on stage.
All right.
Mamma, could you leave me alone now?
I am approaching the climax of the play.
I have my own doubts about the play.
I'll replace them when the show is over.
The play describes how a couple of children get lost from their parents.
Does it necessarily require the rear end of a lion?
Mamma, I'll keep Nipsu out of my sight.
Pinch. Let's go practice our roles.
The play will be good if papa leaves out the rear end of the lion.
There's more to it than the rear end.
The lion's head half is also included.
The lion is absolutely necessary in the play written by grandma papa.
A whole lion!
Here is Sell's key.
Keep an eye on the prisoners until I return. Did you understand?
Yeah. Do they swirl?
That's fine. If you let them escape.
Police uncle, who is he?
My cousin. He does exactly what I tell him to do.
Well, I'm going to the theater now.
Obey my cousin.
Hey listen, you knit beautifully.
Thanks.
First time someone compliments my knitting.
What are you knitting?
I don't know what will come of this yet.
It's funny, of course, but it's a little fun for me.
It's a little fun for me.
It's funny, of course, but it makes me feel safe to listen to the life of the sticks.
The only difficulty is that I just knit and knit.
And before I've decided what to knit, I'm already terribly far along.
And you can't knit slippers, for example?
Slippers?
Yes, when that color is so cute for slippers.
A surprising suggestion.
If I knit you all slippers,
do you put your feet up?
Of course.
I want slippers. It's so cold here that I'm dying.
Is it so cold now?
There is. I can barely speak through this chest.
Oh my god, what am I going to do now.
Maybe the tea collects the wine jelly better than slippers.
Before it's too late.
My cousin probably won't like this, but...
But what?
I would love to invite you to warm my home.
Fits!
Also little picture, don't cry little one.
wall
Mamma, mamma, more feeling.
Close the popsicle stick again.
This baby weighs an awful lot.
How do I act?
Excellent. I have absolutely nothing to fix.
I could have played a more talkative role.
It's funny that they did well this time.
Now you can taste my best cookies.
The earlier ones also tasted good.
My stomach is completely.
So does mine.
You are a flour thumb.
Would you like more tea? I have a lot of grape juice.
No thanks. We have pink bellies. Can't fit anything anymore.
Unfortunately.
I miss you. Are we leaving?
Of course.
It saddens me that I have to put you in prison again.
I'm sad to report, but we're not going back to jail.
Oh, why don't you?
We are going to the theater to see Moominmamma and Moominpapa.
And I absolutely must meet my old aunt.
Oh, my Cousin is guaranteed to have a blast.
We haven't done anything illegal.
Don't you?
We really don't. Why would we have put up prohibition signs in the park?
We just burned the wreckage brought by the water in the midsummer fire.
But when we told your Cousin about it, he arrested us.
Why didn't you say that earlier?
You don't have to go to jail if you haven't broken the law.
Can we go to the theater now?
Without further ado, leave now. My cousin was disappointed, but it can't be helped.
Hey, wait. I'll come along and tell my Cousin,
that you have not committed any violations.
All right. Come on, Moominpapa. Stop! About.
Next scene. Mom, what have you found?
Cradle. I would like to put it into a play. OK, papa?
Moominpapa! Moominpapa! I just read the script.
Who will play these roles when Moomin and Niiskunnet are missing?
I don't know. We don't have any more children, and the baby is not suitable.
You are nuts! The show is only a few hours away.
You don't get anyone to play children. How can a family be reunited?
It can't be helped. We are so short staffed.
I hope all the critics have fallen.
Hold on. Now let's go.
Moon now. You can make noise for a while, but you have to be quiet in the theater.
Whisper shut up.
Are you ready? Let's get started!
Ladies and gentlemen, thank you for giving up your valuable time and coming to see our show.
Tonight's play is called Lost Children.
The play has not been performed anywhere before.
What the hell is that?
Cradle, it's for you.
No! We hope you enjoy our show until the end.
Let's start already!
Cheers, cheers!
Thanks!
Huys, huys, little picture.
You can't take a walk.
Hush, hush.
Moomin, Goblin, Nisku, Miss, my dear children.
It's been a long time since you disappeared like tin hair.
He has forgotten me!
My heart has sunk to the bottom of the dark ocean.
From what I hear, don't let sadness take over your mind.
Children, come back home.
Save my heart from the fields of sorrow.
Can you hear how this sweet little one misses you?
Is he barking?
With a better voice.
I feel bad.
What's wrong with you?
Don't freak out, I'm going to throw up.
Have you become seasick?
From what I hear, let's go find the children.
What about our baby?
We can ask someone to babysit.
We won't be long.
Approximately how long?
A month, a year.
Until fortune once again agrees to smile on us.
You can cut it.
You'll be fine.
Yeah, but...
The second show begins.
Help, I'm stuck in the cradle.
When will the princess appear?
Do we still have a long way to go?
There is. Hurry Moomin, Goblin.
I'll try.
It is forbidden.
What do you write?
My cousin is an acorn.
I'll write five times just in case.
It's forbidden, it's forbidden, it's forbidden.
What do you write?
My cousin is an acorn.
I'll write five times just in case.
It's forbidden, it's forbidden, it's forbidden.
We left home already two weeks ago.
Frighteningly cold.
How are the children's leftovers doing in this weather.
Oh my darling, what happened to you?
Sprained ankle.
Oh Koske.
We're in trouble.
Wolves howl in the mountains.
I'll argue.
It won't work.
How did this happen to you?
Pumimama hugged me to help me.
Please help, I'm just trying a child parka.
A lion cannot step onto the stage without its tail.
It's already late in the evening.
I suggest we stay here for the night.
Do we dare? I feel in my bones that something terrible is going to happen tomorrow.
I smell our innocent blood lurking in the hideous beasts.
I hear hungry beasts howling somewhere.
I hear the howling of hungry beasts.
I hear the lion roar.
Hey.
Oh shit.
Papa, where are you going?
Oh you. I have to go.
I have to go tell that goddamn lion to take the stage.
Don't worry. I'll be right back.
Did he say the right words?
Hey, are you going to spoil my play?
I did take care of my share.
Mamma is climbing on stage.
A roaring lion.
The lion roared again. Where does my husband stay?
Both on stage suddenly.
I can't. I'm going to throw up.
Muunipappa, what are you going to do?
Go to the lava on the cradle.
Not usually laughing. Don't make me laugh.
Nobody knows you.
Help the lion. Are you going to eat me?
Don't be silly, laugh.
Muunipappa.
Oh, the whole lion eat muunipammas.
Help, what should I do? What does it have in mind?
Run away. Run across the stage.
Our he wore a shirt together.
The situation has changed. I will save you at the right time.
Help.
Help, help.
I'm not quiet, I'm going fast. I'm going to die.
Help, help me.
Daddy, hurry up.
I'll come to the rescue.
Help.
Oops, a snap.
Glad you're alive.
Were you worried about me?
Of course I was. I could have forgotten you before.
Mom, hello mom.
It is.
Me here, Moomin.
And me, scumbag.
Father, mother.
Moomin and the snotty lady.
Come closer so I can see your face.
We came back.
I've missed you.
Glad you found us.
Oh, Viljaana.
Oh, Aunt Emma.
Oh, you look grown.
Oh, it was a shame that I didn't manage to see the show here at all.
It was indeed a fine play.
Snuff, I've missed you.
Me too you.
Young criminals have escaped from prison.
Catch them.
No, no, I let the prisoners out of the cell because they are innocent.
They did not tear down the prohibition boards.
That's right, I'll tear down all the prohibition signs from the park.
And I was involved.
In that case, I'll keep you.
No, no, no, no.
Those kids are crazy.
Talk, please.
It is forbidden, it is forbidden.
Five thousand times is forbidden.
Surely there are five thousand times in it?
I swear by the rock and the stake.
One, two, three, four.
Now that the whole family is together again, I miss Moomin Valley.
Well, dare to smile, what are we going to do to these children?
Yeah, I'd like to hear opinions for once.
I can take care of them.
Is that you?
Now that I have stage experience, I could train new Actors for the theater.
Good idea, am I too old?
Character for roles maybe.
Everything is fine.
Well, are we heading home late?
I'm coming home too, don't forget me!
Keep your mouth shut!
My math got messed up.
Dad, we have to thank the viewers.
They are still sitting there.
Sure enough.
Ladies and gentlemen, this is the end of the play written by Moominpapa
Thank you for staying with us until the end.
It all started with the eruption of an underwater volcano.
After all, the eruption is already over.
Listen mom, what would you say if I wrote more plays?
Just write. You also have gifts as a playwright.
Really.
Start a new play as soon as we get to the rest of the valley.
The house looks the same, but I guess it's quite a mess inside.
I have to do a big cleaning.
You are right.
You guys are helping me.
Joo.
For the rest of the week, everyone was trying to remember where each rug or piece of furniture had been.