The inhabitants of Muunilaakso are quite stable in nature, but sometimes they too come up with new hobbies.
It's not that, and neither is that.
Oh!
Hemuli has started watching birds. What will he come up with next?
I see! There it is!
No, isn't Hemuli over there?
On.
What the hell is he doing?
Let's find out.
Hemuli, what are you researching?
Just a few bets, and I'm ready.
Oh!
That's it!
Oh, now you've cheered on the birds!
Don't you disparage. I am doing a very important survey. It takes me a week to draw one bird.
Only plants interested you before.
I've already studied the river Moomin Valley plant. And neither the greenhouse nor the cross-breeding takes up all my time.
I don't have guests. That's why it's not cleaned.
Oh brothers!
How beautiful.
Hemuli, have you drawn all these?
I am. I am.
And it takes a week to draw one of them.
Damn you!
There must be many birds that I have never seen.
Necessarily. The south has said to watch. Those vixen chirpers do not give up easily to observe vixen.
But this drawing is still in progress.
You see that bird very rarely. My last observation is from the previous year.
It has a black mask.
But it's still beautiful.
Go out into nature and watch the birds. You will be amazed at how much you can see if you borrow this book.
Humdinger!
You will meet many interesting species in the forest.
An unknown flower.
You can see that a lot when you're not always running.
Time out.
Oh, come and see.
Very strange.
Just like little cups.
Here it is. They are mushrooms.
Mushrooms?
There are also those like that.
Never mind, let's go see what we can find deeper in the forest.
Yay!
As a steep wall.
Hello! What is there?
I can't figure it out.
I think I know what it is. Shall we climb higher?
No climbing. What if you slope it down?
You become a hack.
You're not afraid.
Of course not. Difficult to climb.
Oh, gross.
I'll stay here and catch you if you happen to fall.
Now I see it.
It's a bird's nest.
Oh, are they scared?
They don't. The mother approaches the nest.
It's that black-faced emulli bastard.
What are they doing there?
Hi, friends. That it will come down soon?
They might even tell you what's there.
Oh, now what?
Hey, hawk.
Outrage.
Hawk, so many chicks.
Drive the hawk away.
Let me scream.
A pinch.
Pinch, bird.
I'll catch it.
I'll catch that bird.
Oh yeah.
Damn it.
The hawk is here again.
It scoops the chicks out of the nest.
Wait you too that robber. Go away.
Don't come any closer.
Oh, took it hard.
The hawk can.
The falcon can return.
We are allowed to take the chicks home.
Ai.
Let's take both the chicks and the mother to the Moomin house.
Oh yeah. Did Nipsu get it?
Nipsu, how was mother?
I caught it.
But it's chickenpox.
Now that's fine.
What's wrong?
Oh well. The left wing is broken.
Otherwise, it's healthy.
Nice to hear.
What about the chicks?
They look miserable.
They are hungry.
I guess so.
Oh, food for them.
I'll come along.
And me?
Me too.
Moomin, Do you know what is suitable food?
I know. I saw the mother giving the chicks berries.
Pick lots of berries.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Joo.
Blueberries are rotting blue.
The chicks ate them.
Mmm, maheita.
Nipsu, wake up and live and eat.
Isn't that enough?
Let's go feed the chicks.
Eat the bird golds.
Wake up.
Strange.
They're not hungry.
It sure is.
Ota.
Hello, snuffbox.
Hey, where exactly are you guys going?
To see Hemulia.
Ai juu
Listen, tell us how to feed reluctant chicks.
Huh? Is that a riddle?
No.
We saved the baby birds with hawks.
Hey.
And when he
axis
Hey.
Good attention.
Thanks.
They move cold.
Hey.
Hemuli!
Not at home.
He could be drawing.
That's where Hemuli comes from!
What's wrong now?
We have a problem.
Glad you came back.
What do you want from me?
The book, there was no need to return it yet.
What? No, no, no, we have other business.
We came to ask you about the baby birds.
Well, what do you want to know?
However, here are the books.
It's interesting. Thanks.
Can't take it, can't take it.
What about chicks?
We found a bird you haven't seen in a year.
That black-faced...
It can't be true.
Where did you find it?
But it's not in the same place anymore.
On the contrary, yes it is.
What exactly do you mean?
Well, we have that bird now.
In the mummy house.
Yes?
Where are they?
Why don't they come back already?
Worrying doesn't help.
Crazy. The mother eats berries full of carbon monoxide, but the boy is not good for it.
What is it because of?
I don't know.
That's crazy.
They ate when...
I have it.
What do you understand?
It's totally normal.
Oh is it?
When the chicks are born, they identify with the first creature they see, i.e. the mother.
The mother feeds them, and the chicks don't worry about food from the mother.
Yes.
What if the Mother can't feed the chicks, so what?
The chicks die quickly of starvation.
What are we doing?
I could come up with a solution.
Exploring nature is beneficial.
It's more than just Latin names.
So you think we can do something to keep the chicks from dying, Hemuli?
I think.
Huh? It's impossible.
Nothing is impossible if you try.
I'm so much bigger.
Yes, I can see that, but chicks have the brains of a bird.
Hypsu, you're just right for that job.
You're just saying I'd agree.
Don't be, Höpsu, let's get started, we have a tough job ahead of us.
How can this be achieved?
The sound comes from the porch.
Dad, what are you doing?
Finally? Good day, Hemuli.
What will it become?
Oh, it will. Well, you'll see.
Oh shit.
Fortunately, the mother survived, even though the falconry attacked it.
Well what do you think?
Doesn't it fly for a couple of weeks?
Now.
Ready!
So what?
Now.
Why don't the chicks eat, even though we give them suitable berries?
I will explain to you.
Must see to resort to logic.
Maybe the chicks agree to eat, even though the chicks won't.
To logic.
Maybe the chicks only agree to eat when the mother feeds them.
Tell me what to do then, huh?
Then the one who is witty will figure out a way to look like a mother, right?
No crazier.
Not so. That's why I've prepared the bird's equipment and agreed that Nipsu will nest in them.
Nipsu, come here.
Don't be shy, Nipsu. Tight, tight.
A special revelation.
The chicks don't notice anything.
Well, Nipsu.
Usually the chicks start chirping when the mother comes near.
Nipsu has the brain of a bird.
Dude, try chirping.
What?
I said chirp.
That, that, Nipsulintu.
Chirping and flapping wing movement.
Chirp, chirp, Nipsu.
Great.
Dude, start feeding the chicks.
No, no, use the cam.
They eat.
Succeeded.
Boys.
Oh, lovely.
Once the chicks had accepted the strange bird as their mother, it didn't matter who dressed as the bird.
The chicks ate and ate.
The chicks started to grow.
And then of course they ate even more.
Good morning, Snuska-muikkunen.
Shall I berry again?
Gotta go.
Do you have something to say?
You know, my friend, you know that birds abandon Moomin Valley and fly far away.
What?
The mother will soon be able to fly and it will also be time for the chicks to leave the nest.
Besides, that rare bird only came to nest in Moomin Valley.
This is Moominvalley being Moominvalley.
I know that.
Yes, I knew that.
But somehow I didn't want to think about it.
We just saved the birds from the hawk's claws.
How could time fly by so fast?
I'm sure the chicks can't fly yet.
Listen, Do you know why I travel so much?
I've been wandering here and there for as long as I can remember.
And I'm not even going to travel.
Because that really is my ultimate nature.
Is there?
It is, it is never good if you have to act against your own nature.
The nature of baby birds is never good.
The nature of baby birds pulls them south.
Moomin, so don't be too sad when they go and leave you.
They have to go.
Yeh, I know.
But I'll still be an ape, I'm afraid.
And the moving day came.
Today you will take off.
Is it ready?
I want to feed them some more.
The chicks could have been seen flying away days ago.
They have already grown decent wingspans.
Come on birds, move your wings.
Spread your wings, yes you can.
There you go.
Please.
How skillfully can they fly?
Come see us.
I will gather berries for you.
Next time you can give the hawks a ride.
Goodbye.
Take care of yourselves.
Moomin felt a little sad.
Caring for the birds had been so much fun,
that the bird suit was put in storage just in case.