From the last one
It's a beautiful day! Good morning, birds!
Have you had a goddamn breakfast?
Do you happen to know what day it is today?
I'll tell.
Today is, listen, my birthday!
Holy look!
Goodbye!
What kind of party is there something for me to organize?
I have to admit that I miss you.
Juli will definitely have a lot of guests and I will get a big pile of gifts.
Favorite food is served there, such as lemonade and cookies
and of course birthday cake!
I can't wait!
Good morning!
I can help!
Listen, little girl, do you know what day it is today?
No, but it says so in the newspaper.
Well, my big grin might help you remember!
Well, that's covered before breakfast.
Covered before breakfast.
Nipsu, Do you know what day it is today?
Don't you know?
I know.
I guessed it, dear Nipsu!
Well, tell me, what day is it?
It is yesterday's tomorrow, in other words, now is today.
Wiseacre!
Nipsu, shall we go fishing?
That would be nice, but wouldn't you rather go to the lonely mountains?
Good idea, it's been a while since the last time.
Hey, you don't have time to go so far that you bigots don't remember that today is...
Mom, Little My is terribly hungry, is breakfast ready yet?
It's ready, sorry for making you wait.
Little Myy, you know you can't talk in your mouth.
Then everyone to eat.
Grandma, I have something important to do.
Goodness.
What now?
The pot was left on the stove.
Strange behavior, what's the matter?
Now listen, I have something to do.
No need to shout like that.
Even more important.
Now shut up, today is my...
Help, mouse!
Where, where, where is the mouse, what did it go to?
Oh, it was just a dust rag.
You know you need glasses.
Yes, I was just about to say that...
Small breads are better.
Yes, donuts are better.
Mamma's donut pretzels are delicious.
I also think the donuts are better.
What do you say, Little Myy?
What are you talking about?
Which ones do we ask mom?
It doesn't matter at all.
Well, donuts then.
Donut rings.
And after breakfast, you weed the flower bed.
Joo.
I'll come to help.
Let's hurry then.
Why is everyone so weird today?
All right.
I'm disappearing.
Pikku Myi had a terrible time.
Now it makes me angry.
No one remembered that it was my birthday.
Hemp!
I want to hear someone say that
hi, today is Little My's birthday.
So that the plastic troll and everyone can hear.
Hemuli gets permission to handle the matter.
Good morning, Hemuli.
Oh hey, Little Myy, you're up early this morning.
What are you doing squatting here?
I was looking for a new type of grass that I heard about.
Oh, but do you remember what day it is today?
Well, I don't remember, but I'm sure somewhere in the world today is also a holiday.
I'm looking at me, so you remember?
Really, really.
You remembered?
I have to return one of the police chief's books.
I didn't mean it, today is mine.
Here it is now.
Listen to me.
Now it was found.
At last and finally kraminulosis spike formis to think.
No doubt, this is a new species.
It's my birthday, you hear?
Today I discovered a brand new species of grass.
Today is my lucky day.
I wouldn't have been able to understand that they were screaming so loud.
Yes?
Nuuska Muikkonen, of course.
He is Granny's best friend, so he gets to tell everyone that today is my birthday.
I'm pretty sure that Nuuska Muikkonen won't beat me at shouting.
At least I've never heard him scream.
Good morning, Nuuska Muikkonen.
Good morning, Little Myy.
Today is my birthday.
I just wanted to make sure everyone remembered it and that the party was organized and the cake was baked and the presents were bought.
I'm afraid that everyone has forgotten it, so could you go and tell everyone in Moomintala that, oh yes, it's Pikkum's birthday today, that a cake has been baked and si...
Yes?
Muikkonen's banana!
Or is breakfast more important to you than me?
Pretty rude too, fool!
Ah, there's Viljonkka.
Good morning, Viljonkka.
Little Myy, are you out for a morning walk?
Do you even know what day it is today?
Today? I don't know, but I know what day yesterday was.
Well, what day was yesterday?
Yesterday was my birthday.
To think! And today is my birthday.
Other people's birthdays are boring. Goodbye!
Yes?
This will be remembered even by you, my dear, Irppanokka!
How has everyone forgotten my birthday?
If I had a real family, they would definitely throw me a party.
How did I forget?
I have a family! Mymmeli will organize the party for sure!
Good morning, Mymmeli!
Good morning, Little Myy. It's good that you came.
I have a little problem because everyone else has gone out.
Mymmeli needs a housekeeper because she is going on errands.
I have to go. I guess I'm already a little late.
I thought so.
You take care of the house. And please. Then don't mess up the places here.
Now. I'll see you later.
What the hell Mymmelik Petty me.
My birthday only comes once a year.
Maybe no one will even want to congratulate me despite that.
It's good then. I organize my own parties.
I cook a festive meal, bake a cake and sing a congratulatory song to myself.
I'll clean up the tracks before Mymmeli comes back.
Oops. You can find anything here.
Jahs. I think it's wisest to bake the cake first.
Chicken eggs. Sugar.
Win. Flour.
Night.
If there is will, there is also skill.
This is going to be a mouthful.
Then the onions are difficult.
Shredding only pays for crying.
Just there. About. And salt.
No! No! I did something.
After all, this was pepper.
No!
It was supposed to hurt.
Hedelmäpoli is my favorite drink.
First the syrup.
Oranges. Apples.
Grapes.
And you don't skimp on sugar anyway.
Then we mix.
Let's taste it.
Too sweet.
With the intestine, it is corrected.
Now that should be appropriate.
Let's taste.
Terribly bad.
It's only bad if I throw everything possible into the mix.
Bring a little and drink this.
The most important thing is inspiration and fresh ingredients.
It is also an advantage to know how to enjoy good food.
It's a moment worth feasting on.
Of ore.
It doesn't look very tasty.
The food is cooked by me, so it can't be that bad.
It smells burnt.
I forgot the cake is in the oven.
Oh, oh, oh.
Now this is starting to resemble a festive meal.
Too bad there are only two candles.
That's it, done.
Then I can start.
I think this is how I raise a toast to the hero at first.
Little My, happy birthday.
Oh, thank you.
And that's how Pikku Myy is one step closer to adulthood.
I'm not, I was kidding.
The table has been set in Korean for you, Little Myy.
Just taste.
Shall I start?
Doesn't it taste good?
Yeah, it's good.
Mention something you like.
Taste this too.
Yeah, this is really good too.
It's a delicious smell.
You look beautiful today.
Thank you, beautifully said.
This is what I look like.
I'll take a piece of this cake.
Yes, please.
Terrible food.
That's enough now.
I can't talk to myself.
Feeling twice as miserable.
Stinker, come in there.
Hey, Stinkbug, are you in a hurry?
Me? Well, it isn't.
Slippery.
Then come celebrate my birthday.
What? Birthday party?
Why don't you?
Well, Ansa, you must be trying to block me,
or do something else annoying.
I'm nice and kind.
Why would I do that? I invite you to be my guest.
As a guest? Me? Yes, you.
Really? Really.
Are you absolutely sure?
Of course I'm sure. Well, are you coming or not?
I'll come. Of course.
Let's go to the end.
Am I the only guest? You are, come to the table.
Yes, it looks delicious.
Really? That's all, if you want.
Can you eat all of these?
Ha ha ha, oh guys, thanks.
Wait a minute.
Don't you have anything to say to me?
What? Ah, yes, of course.
Happy birthday. Thanks.
That's what I've been waiting for. Then we'll eat.
It's good.
What is this?
Oh, mention the idea of coming here.
Jaa.
Never before had such a wonderfully returned second.
Yes, it's rare that it got a little rough.
I like everything burnt.
Is it good? You are a forward cook.
Apparently I'm going to have to change my mind game about you little one.
Just thank you.
I wish someone else had said those words.
I hope the little girl has behaved herself.
I've heard talk of the Stinking statue being a caboose,
but I didn't dare it to be true.
Did you say something? I'm talking in the middle of nowhere.
I'm sure you'll eat it all then. I eat, I eat.
Mymmeli. The party ends.
Sting the last turtu applies.
I still have two left. I can't wait.
What are you going to do?
Mouth open for bigger.
I can't even taste it now.
When you're done eating, you jump out of that window.
I'm here for dessert.
Go already. Bye. Now I'm in a game of tees.
Pymmeli is a mess.
We are at home.
Did you take good care of the house?
Or are you taking a nap?
I'd love a cup now.
Oh.
I'm playing tees.
Pymmeli is a mess.
We are at home.
Did you take good care of the house?
Uhhhhhh!
Little one. What has happened here?
Sell! Wake up!
Pymmeli. Greetings. Did you come back already?
Little one. What the hell has happened here?
What? What are you talking about?
Erranjestas is very clean.
Admit it was you.
Me? How so?
Well, who else could it have been.
I think the rats might have messed up the kitchen.
I could hear rustling from the kitchen through my sleep.
Or rats? Or that way?
Then you have nothing to worry about.
I was already scared that you had eaten this.
What was in that jar?
Hair growth cream.
Hair growth?
It makes hair grow.
I accidentally left it in the kitchen.
What would happen if you could drink it, for example?
I don't know. I miss it, it could get really hairy.
As hairy as a skunk.
Is that what you mean?
But you don't have to think about it if the rats drank it.
They are already furry.
Now I have to clean up.
I'm leaving.
What are you suddenly in a hurry to do?
Goodbye then. Thank you for being a caretaker.
There is no hair growth cream.
Nymmeli is just trying to scare me.
On the other hand, how do you know that?
It can't be true.
My stomach twists strangely.
Oh, anyway. Are you sure you haven't eaten anything inappropriate?
In.
Well good. Grandma's medicine will surely help soon.
Thank you, Moomin.
A little nap would definitely help.
What do I do now?
If it was hair growth cream I drank,
I'm sure he'll be fine if I sleep for a while?
Ha ha ha ha ha! You have a weird hairstyle.
You really didn't drink hair growth cream.
Kikkuli is a real gem.
Teach me! Did you hear?
Did you hear?
Oh, it was just a dream.
It was a weighty one. I feel better now.
Is there someone there?
Who there? Don't be intimidated. Did you hear?
Is there anyone there?
who are you
It can't be.
Not even though these are my hands. Then he.
Oh no! That can't be my face.
Am I a furry monster?
Terrible! What the hell do I do now? Help me.
Good luck, Little Myy.
What?
Just like in that dream. No, you can't watch.
That suits you.
That's fine.
Teasing!
Come on, that's enough.
What? What the hell is this?
We dressed you in a fancy dress while you were asleep.
We thought it would be a good punishment.
Why the hell did you have to punish me?
You mess up Mymmel's kitchen in an absolutely impossible condition.
Oh, you knew about that. You can tell when you're lying.
Selling a Parka, or celebrating birthdays with Haisuli?
The skunk was happy.
The reason is yours. You forgot my birthday.
Little Myy, don't be funny.
How on earth could we forget your birthday?
You were mean to me this morning.
We just wanted to keep it a secret that we were planning a big party for you.
God bless you. You must have felt terribly lonely.
Cheers, cheers. Mind you, he destroyed my entire kitchen.
Sorry I lied.
You will be forgiven. Here is your birthday present.
Oh, thank you.
I left home because I had to buy a light red bow.
Yes, it is beautiful.
Well, now that everything is settled, let's start the festivities. Let's sing.
Good luck, good luck.
Good luck, Little Myy, good luck.
Happy birthday, Little Myy.
Here's the perfect gift for you.
Here's my gift.
Please, Little Myy.
I did this myself and it took an awful lot of time.
The new type of grass I told you about has been used for this.
I hope you like this gift.
The table has all your favorite foods and treats.
And you don't have to worry about getting hairy.
Good luck.