A pinch
Due to Voinen's excitement, Nipsu decided to stay and sleep in the Moomin house.
Luuskamuikkunen, as usual, retreated to the tent.
Do you remember what had happened?
A terrible rain followed the heavy rain and wind, and everything around the rain froze.
The horrors of the night were not over for Moomin.
Help! The rascal is splitting me up!
Don't come! Leave me alone!
Huh? Why is laju on the floor?
Ah, a pinch!
Good morning, mom!
Good morning! Has Nipsu woke up?
Not on your life. Where are they?
It's still in the room. Those polos!
Does dad still drag the gallows?
No. Dad is in the yard.
Dad, what are you doing?
The roses are dead.
So what too?
These are the old man's actions from yesterday.
The ground froze around the tree, but I didn't think the flowers would freeze.
Oh, if only we could have gotten a skunk in the ice cellar.
I have a dream that a skunk was chasing me.
Don't you mourn. I think the mörkö is looking for a breeze and a breeze.
At least they don't run away with the law?
Even that could be more favorable than them.
Don't the wind and the wind come down?
They would like breakfast in the room.
What did they tell? Why is the evil bastard chasing them?
They didn't tell. They just looked terrified.
We need to find out.
Moominma brings them breakfast and their secret is revealed.
Who for it?
Just me. I brought you breakfast.
You can come.
Well, what did they tell you?
Mörkö seems to be chasing the suitcase and not them.
What are those lilliputians hiding in their suitcases?
They have been great.
What is it?
And the suitcase again seems to have belonged to the grunt before.
Have they stolen it?
It didn't become clear. They were very changeable.
This is going too far.
For example, if we were to trap dangerous criminals in our homes.
Let's ask the grump!
I won't even hear it.
We don't want to mess around back here. Or what?
We ask that the police ask the scumbag.
Don't get the police involved in this.
What should we do?
Don't you Shout at it!
Wait for their tongues to heat up.
If you pretend to be unlikable, they will reveal their secret in no time.
They didn't tell the father anything, the mother a little.
We need a woman, but I prefer a tighter and fancier age group.
Yes, of course.
Waste away!
Where is the trip?
Moomin house.
I'll come with you to the village.
I think you are there.
Not anymore. My sister came home yesterday.
Well, what about him?
He commands and snores.
Hey.
Where are you going?
To meet you.
And I will come to see you.
And me?
I would otherwise be a gift.
Oh, a gift?
Yes, and it is very beautiful.
What is it?
You can't break it and you can't lose it.
Of course not.
Please.
Thanks.
Open it.
Oh, how beautiful I look.
I broke into them on the beach because of you.
Look, you can mirror it.
True.
Oh, thank you.
I give my heart to you.
I cherish it.
My eyes always remind me of you.
Oh my, Peikka.
I'll let you see.
Thanks.
Oh my, Peikka.
I always give my baby a kiss before I go to rest.
It's going to be expensive.
Besides me.
So I should go for a walk with the tweezer and the fan.
Yeah, and don't bother them at all.
They get to cry on my shoulder.
They should be made to talk.
I feel important and nervous.
This is where you get tea.
Thanks.
Sell, you are not needed.
I forced out their secrets, even if by force.
We're not undercover cops.
We only talk to them.
And you're hiding secrets.
I'll keep quiet.
Have you ever tried to be quiet?
Maybe not.
Should try sometime.
I'll come with Niiskunneid.
A gentle and understanding woman is needed here.
It's me.
A nut in the shell.
Are you ready?
I don't.
There's a Moomin here.
I have a matter.
Hey.
Here is the swamp lady.
A gentle and understanding girl.
Hello.
Nice to meet you and your friends.
Niiskuneiti wants to talk to you.
Will you let him in?
Well, if he necessarily wants to.
Come on then.
Exactly heart shaped and so beautiful.
I've never seen anything like this.
Do you want the same?
In.
There is only one such pair of shoes.
Keep it in your handbag.
Ah.
I'm snuffling.
Niiskunneiti will surely succeed.
So.
They kind of seemed to like the marshmallows.
I'll feel the chills in my bones tonight.
You are right.
If only we could find out why the morko is chasing them.
If that monster comes every night, mom will lose all her flowers.
Look.
Uh.
They go out.
Good.
Myy!
We have to stop Myy before he ruins everything.
I'll never forgive you if it got in the way.
Don't get involved in this.
Let Niiskunneid handle this matter.
I'm just covering for them.
Niiskunnemi would take them for a walk.
Where are they now?
I can't hear a word of their speech.
Me neither.
We need to get closer.
Then they notice us.
I'm the only one small enough to get close enough.
Don't go.
You're making Niiskunneidi nervous.
You make him nervous.
Shhh.
Now.
Can I ask one more question?
Moment.
Is that suitcase yours or someone else's?
That's it.
Is it?
Well, I'll try again.
Whose suitcase is that?
It's ours.
But for the last time, you said that the suitcase is grubby.
On, on.
Can I ask the same thing again?
That's all.
More about that suitcase.
How is it?
Do you own a suitcase?
Emme.
We own.
Don't give them anything else, that's what Pekka said.
What happened to you?
Excuse me now, but may I ask one more time?
As many times as you want.
Oh thank you.
I'll ask for the last time.
Please answer honestly.
That suitcase?
So.
Which one do you have?
Is it yours?
On.
So it's not a moron?
No, it's not curmudgeonly.
Ehdankin.
Thanks and praise, please.
Niiskunneiti had a hard time.
I would have said shit and he would have spilled his secret.
I'm sure of that.
Niiskunnetti is nice.
All other Mitalo residents are nice.
Do you think they would want to keep us forever?
Of course, if we can get through the mess.
Yes, if we can get through it.
I won their trust and now we are good friends.
Who wouldn't be your friend.
Thank you, even though it wasn't easy.
They mess things up.
I feel like I'm the only one who doesn't mess up.
I didn't find out much.
I should have been put on the case.
Niiskunnie, what did you find out then?
Well, first of all, the suitcase seems to belong to them.
So how are you?
Don't jump!
The contents of the suitcase, on the other hand, belong to mörö.
Well, it's a good time, it's a complicated thing.
Hi, what's in the suitcase?
That's what they say.
Only that it is the most beautiful in the world.
Under the sun?
Oh the most beautiful?
Ah, this is very confusing.
They don't look like thieves after all.
Yes, however, we have to drive away the mud.
I don't understand how a moron can own the most beautiful thing in the world.
Tiuhti and viuhti told me that Mörkö just happens to own it.
Mörkö himself could have stolen the contents of the suitcase.
Good unusual.
Tiuhti and fanuhith are terribly afraid of the revenge of the grunt.
But they are still not going to give up the contents of the suitcase.
Pretty cool.
There will be a storm tonight for sure.
What are we doing?
Same as last night.
If the contents of the suitcase belong to a moron, we can't just drive it away.
It's unlikely that a moron will agree to leave so easily.
If it stays, we may have an eternal winter.
I cover the petunias just in case.
Are you leaving here?
I'm going downhill.
I'm going home.
But Muikkunen's snuff remains.
Now don't look so gloomy.
I have a plan.
What kind?
Just one. Then you'll see.
Good.
It's going to be bad. It's already close.
Maybe something else will clear it up.
It's your turn to sell.
I know, I know. If you don't have a cross ace.
Now the rain is coming.
Just when you were winning.
Go under the table. This can get dangerous.
Crazy. How can you hit with a rolling pin from under the table?
Is Mörko here?
Yeah. In the same place as yesterday.
I went flat on the ground on its toes.
I'll go first. The rest of you stay behind me.
Moomin mom.
Yes, my darling.
You said you had a plan.
Isn't it about time?
Listen, Morkö. We want to talk to you.
We know you have come to claim your property,
whose dense breezes have been usurped from you.
Isn't that the case?
Did you sell the property to them?
Or would you give it for free?
I have beautiful things in my handbag.
Shall we trade?
How about this pendant?
Oh.
Oh, Don't you like it?
How about this?
Or this?
Nothing works for you?
You can get anything from my handbag, except aspirins.
Is this what you mean?
Or this?
Well, for once, it's not really for me.
Moomin, can I give you a shoe?
Ai!
You can't really.
Mom, it didn't hurt.
No, my hand just suddenly froze.
Now that you've got this shoe approved, you'll never go back.
Dare, Lapas to come back!
Oh, you missed it.
Moominma had sense.
Thanks, mom.
Anna, sorry Moomin.
I didn't remember that your shoe was from my handbag too.
Uh, never mind, mom.
What does Niiskuneti think?
You promised to give this shoe a kiss every night, or something else friendly.
Mom did the right thing.
Besides, I'm not going to tell niiskuned.
That's where the truth always comes out.
From now on I will always tell the truth.
Moomin, look, I found one!
Very similar but mine was much bigger.
Oh, was it much bigger?
Moomin had to find a shoe that was exactly like the one Niiskunnet gave him.
Here it is, here it is, I found it!
Look, this is pretty much the same.
It was a miracle, but miracles do happen in Moomin Valley.