It will be a beautiful day again.
Hat mats. They are busy.
Moomin troll. Moomin troll.
What mom?
This is already ripe.
Not yet. Wait for the color to turn golden brown.
I want everything to happen quickly.
Oh.
Don't push it when it's almost possible to break the egg.
Don't strain.
Succeeded.
So.
What are you doing?
Moomin troll.
Don't ask stupid questions. Do you have eyes in your head?
Little sells, cooking.
Oh, pancake night. Oh, do you also sell them fried?
Are they even edible?
Pointless, doubt it.
I was thinking of learning how to cook because I've reached marriageable age.
Are you that old already?
The pancakes are ready.
A pinch, no. Do not touch.
I can taste your blood.
Tapping.
It's not my fault.
Fear of salt.
Water.
I accidentally replaced sugar with salt.
So when mom is a jerk.
Mom, what business did you have with me?
Share, always.
Would you be so kind as to fetch some blueberry jam from the basement?
I have to stay in the kitchen now.
It's okay, mom. A pinch of fire.
I thought I was going to die.
How did Moomin mama let the mouse into the kitchen?
That you are, incorruptible?
Blueberry, blueberry.
I'd bet that I get worse.
A pinch.
I was joking.
Some paper roll.
It looks pretty old.
Keen drawing.
As if a child had scratched.
In my opinion, it could be some kind of map.
Some map.
I guess there is a path there.
And those are the lonely mountains.
Really.
But what example is this?
Hi, I'll bring you some tea.
Here's the blueberry jam.
Oh, thanks to the running boys.
What paper is there?
Some map probably.
It was found behind the jam jars.
Do you know who did it?
Yeah, I don't think so.
But Moominpappa could know.
True.
Nipsu, let's go ask dad.
Joo.
Don't disturb dad's writing?
No, no.
Dad, Do you know anything about this map?
It looks like a treasure map.
Phooey.
Is that a treasure map?
And we found it.
Gold and precious stones.
Dad, do you think we can find the hidden treasure?
Couldn't you take a closer look at the map?
The map must be old.
Tell me, where is the treasure hidden?
Moomin, I've been inspired for a while.
Couldn't you shut up?
Father please.
The treasure is hidden here.
Great, Nipsu.
It is.
Today's program has been decided.
Let's go.
Well, let's go.
Do you have everything?
There's a rope, a shovel, a flashlight, a cauldron and...
The heads are in the backpack.
It is.
Please renew.
Luckily we made it.
Eat a little before you go.
Maybe when we come.
Hey hey.
Don't go yet.
And we baked pancakes for them in a sweat hat.
That they dare.
About the abuser.
What makes you laugh?
They can't escape the pancakes.
I packed a few pancakes for them in the backpack.
Don't you.
I packed.
The search for Haarte is exciting.
Romantic for adventurers.
Aptly said.
What are you going to do with your share of the girdle, Moomin?
Have you had time to think?
I would like to buy a big sailboat and sail it around the world.
I keep my treasure under the bed.
It's hard to eat.
A good time, not with such a big fire.
This won't work.
Stop breaking the eggs and go get water from the well instead.
Clear.
How did this happen?
What?
What's going on here?
Hello, friends.
Good morning, Nuuska Muikkunen.
Good morning.
Where are you going when you have so much stuff?
To find the treasure.
Aaretta, above.
Really.
We found this map in the jam cellar.
Is this where your treasure is?
Yep, it's hidden in the place indicated by the sign.
Aha, at the foot of a lonely pine tree.
Do you know that place?
That pine tree grows on the highest place in Moomin Valley.
And since it's the tallest tree there, lightning often strikes it.
Hattivats gather there during thunderstorms.
Hat mats.
What does this mean?
Not even a hint.
This, this is war.
What war?
What do we do now?
We have been besieged by the Hattivats.
They were going to conquer the Moomin house.
Oh no, don't, I guess not.
Look at the eyes of the hatties.
They usually don't have such a wild look.
Not about you?
I don't notice anything unusual.
Seems to me they have a point.
Aha, well now I know.
Don't go boom mom!
Don't rush.
Let me pass through.
Curious thing!
Hat rugs are giving way.
Oh, that's why the shoe squeezes.
You want water, don't you?
Wait a minute.
Oh heaven!
A small hole.
Aha, one Hattivatti had apparently fallen into the trap.
Or so?
I thought it would never go wrong with a hat.
Papa, would you pour some water to praise?
Without a doubt, mom.
So, Eiti, bring the blanket and sell the doctor's book.
No Moomin, Pekko, let's rest sometimes.
Oh again, that would be the third time.
Yeah, but now I'm suddenly hungry.
Let's bark sometimes.
Hopefully.
Bitch!
Win
Hopeless.
Is there a long way to Aar-Tee at mp.m WH?
I would guess that we will come to the big Männy very soon.
Zzaaa, Aar-Tee? Now it requires a lot.
Otherwise, there wouldn't be any fun in it.
I guess it won't start raining.
Is it better now? Can you walk?
Hello Hattimatti! Why don't you say anything?
Take care of yourself.
Good, he seems fine.
Who said that the Hattivats came to take over the Moomin House.
Well, it doesn't matter anymore, Moominpapa.
So what?
Where are Hattivats on their way?
Probably in the lonely mountains that big pine tree that Lightning often strikes.
Phooey!
You see, Hattivats charge themselves with electricity in the Ukkose.
One of the Hattvates apparently slipped into the well from the electric power.
Pretty interesting stuff. Where are Moomin and Nipsu?
Oh terrible! Now they are in trouble!
Jaa.
That must be the lonely one on the pine map.
Yes, but where is the Aare?
If there is also a small tick drawn on the ground.
Alright, let's start looking.
Joo.
Did Moomin go with Nipsu to the lonely mountains?
Lahti. He went to find a hand.
It's a lonely turn.
Lahti. He went in search of the hidden Aaretta.
Or Aaretta? What the hell Aaretta?
Oh dear, you yourself told the children that that old piece of paper is the Aare map.
Aare map.
Well, exactly.
What happened now?
Oh, that's bad.
What's the bad thing?
To be honest, there is no such thing as Aaretta.
What?
I hear what you mean?
Can't find anything here.
At least I can't see Aaretta.
Moomin, do we have to dig up the whole hill?
It would be such a terrible job that I can't handle it at least.
Eh?
Hats, and we don't even have umbrellas with us.
What do we do now?
At least let's get out of the rain.
Oh this misery.
Yes, I did.
Dad, you're just not going to go out in this weather.
Aion.
Even wait for the rain to stop.
It may be late.
What do you mean?
Moomipeikko and Nipsu went to the big pine tree that really attracts lightning in the air of a thunderstorm.
If they've gone under a pine tree to catch the rain, anything can happen.
Oh no.
I'll come too.
Me too.
No.
We'll stay here and wait.
Moomi papa can go out into the rain alone.
Come on, I'm leaving now.
Don't worry.
Be careful.
Moomi Pappa said, you are not aarita.
What exactly did it mean?
I hate this air.
I hate, I hate.
I don't even mention it.
I don't hate, I don't hate, I don't hate.
Nipsu straightens up.
The thunder is already going further.
Is it going?
Miserable.
No treasure.
It's raining in buckets and Thunder is rolling.
Lightning strikes the eye.
The thunder is already going further.
Is it going?
Miserable.
No treasure.
It's raining in buckets and Thunder is rolling.
Lightning strikes the eye blind.
Painu arrested, Ukkonilmaa.
Help!
Mummy, Dress!
Hi, hi.
I'm lost in this rain.
Hey!
Ai.
Which children would be wise to stay away from the big pine tree?
Tule!
Oh man, they'd be saved.
Well, sure enough, they'll be saved.
Moomipapa went to help.
So yeah.
You still doubt.
But Nipsu must be terribly hungry.
So.
I'm hungry.
I forbade you to eat all the snacks right away.
But when I got hungry.
I don't have anything either.
I don't remember putting this package in my backpack.
Pancakes!
Niiskunneiti has packed them along.
The famous barking.
Time for salt.
That's it.
It is.
2p wins.
Nothing.
Hat mats. What are they doing?
Healthy I know.
You look over there.
They're coming at us.
I'm afraid.
How are we doing?
Help!
Take it easy.
The pine tree grows at the highest point in Moomin Valley.
Since it is the tallest tree there, Lightning often strikes it.
Hattivats gather there during thunderstorms.
Oh no.
What did you remember now?
A pinch under the legs. Lightning strikes this tree.
That's the pine tree. Oh no.
Oh.
Oh wonder.
Moomin troll.
Father. Father.
Father.
Moomin troll.
I am so relieved.
I was very worried.
Father.
Moomin troll.
I am so worried.
Father.
Hattivats absorbed all the electricity from Salama.
It saved us.
So that the Hattivats now in turn helped us.
I don't understand. What do you mean?
Every family seems to have a boy who gets into trouble.
How beautiful.
So. The glow of Hattivatie is the same as before.
Oh, have you seen it before?
In.
When I first came to Moomin Valley, I drew an accurate map of this area so that I would know how to come back.
If I could remember seeing that glow again.
Or so.
So that the Aare on this map is...
That wondrous glow, that's right.
Muus-Pekko! Muus-Pekko!
Moomin Pekko! The food is ready.
I will come.
Don't be sarcastic, Nipsu.
I'm serious. This is you!
Sell! Ouch! Do not!
It's you, it's the dining table. You don't argue with children.
Ouch! Sell, you didn't pull Nipsu by the tail, but at me.
Sorry. This is a real tail. Ouch! That's my tail.
Myy! Who!
Don't be sarcastic, Nipsu.
I'm serious. This is you!
Sell! Ouch! Do not!
It's you, it's the dining table. You don't argue with children.
Sorry!