Winter was coming, Moomin began to get restless.
Snuff Muikkunen!
At this time of the year, Nuuska Muikkunen always went to wander south.
Good morning dad.
Are you on your feet?
Joo.
We are buried in leaves from last night's wind.
So. Winter is approaching, but the campfire warms you.
So warm.
I guess we're going to hibernate again, aren't we?
Yeah, of course.
As per usual.
If Nuuska Muikkunen takes me south, can I watch over the winter?
Can I have a father?
I think Nuuska Muikkunen doesn't want a company.
But if I make him want to?
No, don't. Nuuska Muikku should not be pressured.
Why?
He is a hermit character. Only in winter does he have the opportunity to enjoy solitude.
I know, but...
Nuuska Muikkunen likes you very much.
And that's why he stays in Moomin Valley for the rest of the year.
Deep down, however, he is a vagabond and needs his winter solitude to recover from us.
I can understand how you feel, but if you keep going along, he'll feel bothered.
I'll leave Nuuska Muikkunen alone.
Don't grow up.
Well, why doesn't the fish eat? I haven't caught a decent catch in days.
The air has cooled.
So.
when are you leaving
Yes?
You're leaving again.
Joo.
Can I ask for something?
What?
Let me know when you leave.
But...
I will always be sad when you leave, even though I know you will return.
So. I'm sad too, that's why I thought I'd sneak out this year.
But I will be even sadder if I hear that you have left.
I want to say goodbye to you properly and wish you a good trip.
Please notify us of your departure.
Oh, it's about time, if I don't go hiking until after you're already hibernating.
Yeah. That's a good idea. In that case, we wouldn't divorce at all.
Hmm. Not really. I'll be back before you wake up.
Yeah! Let's do it boldly!
Hi! Moomin!
Hi Nipsu!
Moomin! Come on! I'm talking about the stuck-on hoody!
What is it?
I don't know. Niskunet and moles found. It's so high we can't get it down.
Well, I can come.
Carefully!
I found it!
Well, it's a kite.
What?
A kite to fly.
It is wingless.
The kite is tied to the end of the string and released into the wind.
Watch out, Moomin!
Dream, dream!
Good!
Be careful here!
Let it come!
Is this a kite?
That's a total bummer!
It can certainly be fixed.
The string has broken from the kite when someone was flying it. Then the wind has brought it here.
Let's start the repair work!
Let's have a good time, shall we?
It just looks like junk to me!
We will have fun.
Is that a kite?
Can it be fixed?
I fancy.
What a strange looking kite. It must have traveled from somewhere far away.
Well, is it going to be a dick?
Of course.
Then to work! We help you!
I can fix a kite without your help, if only you can find me a really long and strong, but thin thread.
I think I have a suitable thread.
Good. Then I'll get to work right away.
Good.
Then I'll get to work right away.
Good. Then I'll get to work right away.
Good.
Then I'll get to work right away.
How exciting, I haven't flown a kite in ages.
You are a child again.
Nisku, okay?
Yeah, who flies first?
Me of course.
All right. Moomin-Pekko, hold the kite.
Did I see that? Like that. I'm ready in a pinch.
All right, don't leave until I say so.
Now, Moomin-Pekko.
You have to put in runs.
When the wind catches the kite, you start to let go of the string.
All right. Moomin-Pekko, hold the kite again.
Alright please. I'll let go.
Now I'm leaving. Let's let go.
Will a kite rise?
Didn't rise.
Stop it, you're breaking the kite.
Hey listen, the kite is really bad.
And it isn't, but the wind is too weak.
I guess you're right, too bad.
The wind was so strong yesterday.
Is that okay?
Maybe it will be windy enough soon.
Higher!
It feels heavy, shall we let go?
Let's get there little by little.
Clear.
Nipsu, let me set the record straight, you can't.
You don't know better than that.
You are too light to hold a kite.
I am!
I believe in Moomin, a kite will lift you into the air.
A pinch.
So what?
Could I fly sometimes?
Dad would enjoy it.
Don't run away.
I did this before Nipsu was even born.
Hupsista.
Moominpappa boil, coil, boil.
Well, I'm boiling.
Look.
Oh.
It certainly wasn't my fault.
Of course not, but the wind is so open up there that we have to move the center of gravity a little lower.
Dad, the kite is fine.
A kite could fly me.
Now.
Well, now you can't run around anymore.
Not so.
What now?
No more jumping on a kite.
Hell no.
The flight characteristics of the kite are then defined.
If I hold onto the kite firmly, it will lift me to the heights.
Maybe, but it's dangerous. After all, with what a rush the kite came down.
Like I just said the kite doesn't fall.
Still.
I do what I want, but others must not notice, or they try to prevent right.
Sell, don't bother.
Sell, it would be better if you didn't go.
Next time when...
What are you doing?
Nothing, just told Nipsu that the kite won't fly down anymore.
No, like when Niisku grazed it.
There are no guarantees.
Nipsu, do you support a kite?
Light.
Moomin, do you still want to fly?
I want to. This time I'm letting go of everything.
Nipsu, do you support the kite?
You carry the bread.
Nipsu, I trust you.
You can me.
Can you survive this?
Sure, dude.
I'm not so sure.
Close your eyes to whom you cannot look.
Nipsu, let go when I say hep.
Clear.
Well, hep.
Hi, I ran out of thread already.
Hovering high.
It's windy higher up.
Handsome.
bathing
Iha sucks
Sullatt?
Exercise
E.g.
Does S have
It's Heidi
You can't help it
Driver
Freight
It's not that bird.
Probably some rag.
I guess so.
Nipsu, you can't see the back of the kite?
I can't even see, my eyes are closed.
It's not a rag.
But sell.
Maybe it's because you don't see him here.
Why would it sell?
I don't know anything, I didn't see.
Nipsu, you too.
Sell, I was itching to get on the kite.
Moomin, pull the kite down slowly.
Be quiet Moomin, be careful not to break the thread with a gust of wind.
It's grandma's best yarn.
I'm worried about the knot.
From which node?
From the knot of the new thread and the old tail.
The string lasts, but what about the knot?
So what?
A knot is, you see, always a knot.
Don't let go, sell.
Windy as hell, watch out.
If puto is from here, then I'll be a convert.
Sell, stay in your fields.
I have no problem.
We are almost on the ground.
The knot was opened.
Come on. A pinch!
Nisku, get your act together.
Yeah yeah
A pinch, fire.
A pinch!
Myy drifts in the direction of the lonely mountains.
Okay, open the door, mom.
I really hope that Myy is invincible.
Five to five, I'm on my way!
Oh, it's going to be a long journey home to the lonely mountains.
My! My!
Now he was being driven towards the woods.
If he falls into a tree, he is saved.
I don't see Sell anywhere.
In my opinion, this is the direction he flew.
What now?
I'm starting to feel that Myy has already hit the ground running.
Oops, it's not. He floats in that sky.
What is it?
I probably saw something.
Do I sell?
I don't. Just as if a magician had attached a panther on his back.
Ai.
Did you see?
Would you like to sell?
Not just a magician.
I saw it too.
Forget the magician. We are looking for a sale.
Why can't this rebellion land?
My bun!
Where is Myy now?
Nothing will come of this. We poke around in vain.
My bun!
The print will come. We poke around in vain.
Hey, sit down.
Selling?
There it is.
The head can even be wet.
Yes, but...
Myinkappa will surely find little Myin.
Myy?
Here I am!
I knew that Onni follows Mya.
Myy will not disappear from this world.
But maybe Myyle was right that his hair got a ride.
I didn't see Sell.
Moomin, be careful!
Use your hands!
Help! Dad helps!
Moomin was finally rescued.
But pretty sure he had taken worse bumps than Myyn.