Good morning, skunk, good morning!
Who are you?
What are you doing here?
Look!
What have you done to grandma papa?
Are you the best?
Me me?
Am I a thief?
There's no point trying to fool us!
Oops!
What is your name?
It is...
Mikku Matta, I know what you're going to do!
Pinch movement in the joints!
Oh granny troll here!
Granny troll here!
The best burglar has knocked out grandma!
Granny Goblin!
What's the fuss here so early?
Come down!
Grandma Papa needs help urgently!
The best burglar came in and knocked out granny.
Knocked out?
Oh, I don't!
Granny troll, don't chase!
Run now to get the police master!
Tell me there's a criminal lurking here!
But he is...
Granny, don't take it too hard.
Maybe papa isn't feeling bad now.
Hello granny troll!
Granny Goblin!
Granny, what's the matter?
Sell the mug!
Don't try to block me!
This scoundrel hit on grandma's skills!
Oh, mummipapa!
What has happened here?
Tell Sell!
No?
Mummipapa!
Didn't grandma papa get knocked out?
From whom?
From Murtoparka, from there!
No?
What?
Isn't it the best?
It isn't!
So who is it?
Dad's old friend. His name is Hömölö.
Just like that.
He came unexpectedly to see me last night.
Ahem, a bit embarrassing!
Why didn't anyone tell me?
Hey hey, nice to meet you!
I think it's a lot of fun too.
My name is Hömölö.
Hey.
Now this was funny.
You thought Hömölö was a burglar.
I was not given a chance to explain.
Do I look like a burglar?
We apologize.
You are so hasty.
I thought papa was knocked out when I saw him lying on his knees in the ditch.
Good thief's face, gets permission to bear the consequences.
Brave girl!
We haven't met in ages and we talked until the morning.
We slept downstairs.
And I thought a burglar had crept in at night.
That decorative plate on the edge of the fireplace is beautiful.
I was looking into it.
Crazy thing.
A false alarm of Kuosisauda!
Always sell conclusions.
Gag!
We laugh here.
Anna cakes!
Goof, you can stay with us as long as you want.
It's been an incredibly long time since we last saw you.
Thank you very much.
I think it would be fun to know how long Moominpappa and Hömölö have been friends.
We have known each other since we were growing up.
We were schoolmates.
Oh, Juku!
I changed majors at a fast pace during my school years.
As I recall, we met in the last grade.
Was it that stupid?
Up.
Moominpapa and I got on well.
It's fun that you were able to see each other again.
Oh, I forgot.
I have a little gift for you all.
Number?
Oh for us.
Oh.
What's in it?
Oh, I always like gifts.
Open it up.
All right, I can open.
That's a nice man.
I thought as soon as I saw the goof.
No.
Shall I open?
Open, open.
What was it?
It was a gift.
And poh, I say.
They gave me goosebumps.
You haven't changed a bit.
Don't give a shit about me.
Someone was known to be sick.
Could have had a heart attack.
Oh, I was already taken by heart.
None of you look old and sick.
It's a beast for us to make jokes.
The teachers were always in his line of fire.
Oh, what the hell was he doing?
Well, he hung a water jug above the classroom door.
Or put frogs on the cathedral.
Frogs?
You were as chubby as I was.
Dad, did you make koltos too?
Papa, I guess not.
Me? Of course not.
Hömelön was joking.
haven't you told
how did you hide the Rotten Egg in the teacher's room
and it was never found?
Did I include one?
I never thought fathers were like that.
Fathers wear a hat and look dignified.
Hats don't always make you look more dignified.
What do you mean?
It's just that hats might not be your style.
Shut up! I know what you were trying to say.
You can wear a hat on yourself because of the stupid ears.
I don't, don't bother.
Those were good times in those teenage years.
We had a great time.
Listen Hömölö, would you like to go back to the past?
Well, that's where I'm heading right now.
Father...
All right, right now.
Let's go.
Our course.
I will never learn to understand adults.
Why do you guys have such a big jump?
Gotta make sure while the iron is hot.
Properly.
Take care of yourselves.
Yes, please.
Bye.
Bye, Dad.
Reminiscing about their school days makes them complete jerks.
Are moving.
Oh well.
I know the place.
It is very difficult for me to imagine my father as a small child.
He must have been rasaville.
Hey, I made it up.
Oh what?
It's going to be a tough one.
Istemukaa.
Let's go after them and convince them.
Why?
I am curious to know what they did as children.
Sounds fun.
Let's go.
I hardly recognize the father.
They think they are little boys.
Are moving.
They have no idea that we are following them.
Yes.
Behind that pimple is the school...
Yeah, that's where the old thesis can be seen.
Well, we have to take a look there.
Oh.
The building has not changed at all since our school years.
Is there still the same principal there?
It would be fun to meet.
Our former school.
Same rusty gate.
Everything is unchanged.
And it's three minutes behind the clock.
Nice to be here again.
Hey looker.
We still have our secret passage.
Nope.
That's it.
Oh, unusual.
From here we got out and sneaked back.
And the headmaster roared at us with a red face when he had found us.
Do I sneak in like the good old days?
Inspiration. Go ahead of you.
So what's that?
Hey, could you have a little smoke?
Clear.
I got stuck in my stomach.
It doesn't work as easily as before.
I feel that the corridor has become more cramped.
Or maybe. The corridor is unchanged and we have become thicker.
Probably.
Oh, you looked at that.
Oops, our tree brand.
Yeah, we carved them into that frame.
When we got out of school.
And as we carved, we forged an eternal friendship.
It's a wonder they survived.
I remember that we climbed a tree and got a good kick out of it.
There they are. What can you do?
Flashing wood.
And now they are climbing it.
I used to climb a tree while playing.
They're total brats.
And way too old to do tree climbing.
Someone will come.
How to survive? A joke.
Hazel hen!
We got up.
The view is the same as then.
Just like in the old days.
This is something.
While we were happy here, the principal used to be cruel.
Hey, are you rascals from school again?
Do you remember?
I remember. I can still hear his voice in my ears.
Hey, are you rascals from school again?
I can hear it too.
Doesn't the word work?
Right off the tree.
Come on, Headmaster, we just...
When we had to do that...
I don't listen to any explanations.
As punishment, you get to clean the whole school.
I will personally check the final result.
But, Headmaster, it's good if we don't...
No complaints.
Start cleaning immediately.
Yes, but...
Let's give it a try.
Bad luck.
I see. The principal believes that we are still his students.
Can't hear the word or doesn't it work?
While you're cleaning, pamper yourself.
Do not climb the tree.
Come on, roll up your sleeves.
Excuse me now, Headmaster, but when we really don't...
Well, now what?
Well, since we haven't been students at this school for years.
We just came here to compare old school memories.
Absolutely.
I guess you'll notice his mustache too.
Well, a mustache.
Funny looking mustache.
They probably belong in tonight's fancy dress.
Fancy dress? Oh, the annual star party.
And it is now today.
You have successful masquerades, but it is not related to cleaning.
Every corner clean.
The father and the fool are in a real bind.
It's just right for them.
What is the star party like?
There are sure to be goodies on offer.
Hey kids, why don't you come help us?
How did you find us?
We were careless.
Did you know we shadowed you?
I don't know you.
Sorry Headmaster, of course you don't. May I introduce?
I do know. You're his little brother, aren't you?
Kid brother?
And you are clearly his sister.
I'm not.
You are a cousin and this thumb pot is a little cousin.
And I won't be barked at as a thumbs-up.
Welcome to school. I will show you the classes and introduce you to the students.
Like real.
Can we participate in the star party?
Of course.
Hiihaa.
Lovely.
Principal, listen.
The two of you will clean up first.
Follow me.
Hey then dad.
See you soon.
Be diligent.
Just celebrate, just celebrate.
Oh, anyway.
The headmaster still only sees us as little schoolboys.
So it seems.
Maybe we'll let him stick to that belief.
Masquerade costumes are stored here. You are free to choose the outfit.
Let's see what we can find.
I want to be a star princess.
A bow gun.
I chose something to wear.
I already took mine.
Hi, I saw a dress.
Can't find anything suitable here.
A pinch, look.
No.
Well, how does it look?
Sell, don't scare me.
You look like a wizard.
Am I becoming a witch?
Hi, are you new?
I haven't seen you here before.
Hey, we're new.
who are you
I am Vertti.
All yellow beaks must always show themselves to me first.
Oh yeah, you run the school.
Did you guess right?
Itiks have no right to speak here.
Don't joke, I can shout you out of here.
You don't.
I can.
Vert.
Good day principal.
It rained perfectly.
I will introduce them to others later.
They are new.
Stay in tune.
Let's try.
You don't.
I have to start preparing my suit too.
Ha, does the headmaster participate in the masquerade too?
Of course.
I appear every year in the costume of the star bearer.
Unusual.
At least from Kullunkuri.
Vertti, take good care of them.
Yes, Headmaster.
What now?
This is the principal's office.
Let's explore places every chance we get.
We have to follow the traditions.
Right.
Exactly.
You are quiet and focused.
Give you some cream from behind.
Good work.
Hello, Saki manager.
Nice job.
Who are you?
The students of this school, of course.
Up, up.
The students don't have mustaches or top hats.
As an older student, I gave enough advice that that joke is outdated.
True.
Don't imagine that the headmaster will fail.
What the hell is this talking about?
This is a cat, isn't it?
We used to do the same thing.
And once the headmaster really lost his mind.
Who are you?
Saki leaders.
Same as you.
Hey, let's make the headmaster the biggest prank of all time tonight.
That's an impossibly great idea.
I don't know how good you were back then.
But I can assure you that nowadays no one comes up with tricks as clever as me.
Wow, you seem very confident.
All right.
Let's see who comes up with a better trick.
Are we competing?
Yay, I'm getting excited.
It's not easy to fool the principal.
We have our pride, we must win.
Must win.
Could you find a better suit?
There could be something fun here.
Aha, interesting header.
Would that fit?
At least it feels warm.
We must hurry now.
A bunch of beautiful hats suits you.
So do I.
It looks more like a cleaning mop.
I think the principal is coming.
Fire scares Kat and Piansseo in a panic.
Did you wear a funny outfit?
Hey, wrong hat.
Well, it's time once again to start our annual star party.
Oh what!
I have a lovely outfit, thank you.
I feel a piece of cart.
It's a cat, what the hell.
Nipsu, what's wrong with you?
Oh, oh, oh, I don't know.
How's that roof over there?
Whoah whoah, I finally went.
I don't see anything.
Help, help.
Hi unusual.
Pinch, did you get hurt?
You are so stupid.
Now we start the main event of our star party and light the campfire.
It's now a menu.
On.
The time was up.
Oops, what's next? Has the ring gotten wet?
We succeeded.
Right timing too.
Fireworks.
How beautiful.
We did it.
Reserve better in the old one.
We are unbeatable.
Dad went crazy.
Oh, now what?
The principal passed out.
Hi-hi.
Although the headmaster badly.
The headmaster does not regain consciousness.
What's the trouble?
Too big a guess, I think.
Principal, please open your eyes.
Oh, how terrible.
The reason for the corpse papa and hemelo.
Dad, what are we going to do?
The principal is now taking it easy.
I forgot that he has become old.
Had my heart failed me?
Headmaster.
I have gone.
Could you do me one last favor?
Headmaster Kulta.
What do you wish for?
We'll do anything.
I have a special drawing on a shelf in my office.
Oh, the drawing.
I would like to see it one more time before I die.
Principal, don't die yet.
So the drawing is on the shelf.
That's how it was.
I'll go get it.
Try to hurry.
Where is it?
Is it this?
I found.
I found it, this is it.
Because the other one too.
What a terrible scratch.
This reminds me of something.
Now I remember.
We drew these pictures of the principal.
Do you like these?
Headmaster.
I guess I got string products.
How so?
And you weren't on the grain the whole time?
Right from the beginning.
Hard to believe.
I don't see.
You can be a principal, as long as you don't separate children from adults.
Skillful trick principal.
I finally got my revenge.
All doing villain hooks.
I had fun.
Thank you for coming.
Thanks.
Oh principal.
Don't sell, you can't.
I run faster.
I think our contest was left unsettled.
I'm wrong.
Don't brag, son.
I never would have believed that grandma papa was such a badass.
Me neither.
I have to tell mom about this.
Tell me!
Wait and see.
Thanks.