The moon shone over Moomin Valley.
There will be moonlight.
The moon looks big.
Yes, but it gets smaller as you go up.
It just looks smaller.
You never know about the moon.
What now? The witch is flying again.
A witch? Where?
There, at the edge of the moon.
Oh, now I see him.
I feel sorry for Niisku.
Yes, sometimes you get your aircraft ready.
Yeah, but he's wasting an awful lot of time.
Niiskuneiti said that Niisku has apparently designed a new ship.
Didn't give a damn.
Oh, why not dad?
Well, when Niiskua wakes up so heartily with his ship.
But look at those.
He jumps clear of the old broom, grabs something and sweeps his way.
Just like that, unfair.
Niisku, I'm going to sleep now.
Aha.
Doesn't keep watch every night.
Succeeded!
What worked?
Fortifying agent.
It does a lot.
Succeeded!
Fortifying agent.
It makes paper and cloth indestructible.
Have you figured it out for your aviation?
Of course.
You will be the first to hear about my invention.
Don't tell anyone.
And, and.
Hi Is this your new ship?
So.
Now it doesn't look like a ship anymore.
Well, no.
The previous flying machine was far too heavy and consumed too much fuel.
But this new version is very light.
Made of fabric and not wood.
And I dip the fabric in my cookie solution so that it becomes strong.
Yes, Isko, you are a remarkable scientist.
There is a puzzle.
Nope.
My new ship floats beautifully.
Of course I planned it.
But I don't know how to make it go where I want.
What are you researching?
Water.
What about water?
The dome.
Kuplin?
Well, a bubble.
Bubbles pop to the surface.
It was really big recently.
Well, five bubbles.
But who makes them?
Something is rotting at the bottom.
I think so.
I thought that if someone has special bubbles.
Something is rotting at the bottom.
Mother.
So?
Can you give me some soap?
What do you need it for?
Roll soap bubbles.
All the nicest.
I don't know how much soap to add to the water.
Now.
I have to wait for the soap to dissolve.
Well then.
The dome.
I have to wait for the soap to dissolve.
I think bigger bubbles.
But there will be more small ones.
Moomin veikko, we guarantee big ones.
Don't blow so hard.
The soap is out of date.
Should it flow more?
Oh, wonderful.
Could I blow too?
Of course.
Yes?
Weird.
Is this just soap and water?
Is there anything else needed?
Oh yes.
Otherwise, bubble.
The dome.
Shall we then go to the left-hand view?
Do you know?
I'm clear!
It was achieved.
Take our own cup, to our people.
I've started giving and seeing each other.
Let's go!
Jouni fainted,î.
Al it is!
No more cutting!
House spщё!
Jone's sexual drink!
Oh!
Stay!
Huot platforms!
You talk!
Let's try.
We'll see how it goes.
Just like Hemuli said.
Give me my side.
Wonderful.
Yeah, but I want even bigger ones.
Oh yeah.
What now?
I think I know how to get huge bubbles.
My sister told me that the witch has been flying her broom around here again.
On, on.
Do you, Pakerrat, still have your aircraft?
Of course.
I fly on a scientific basis.
I wouldn't mind knowing how to fly on an old broom stick.
Well, of course.
Moomin papa, anyone can fly with a broom.
And it's so terribly unscientific.
That's how it is.
But even those have to practice flying.
Is there something wrong with the broom?
No, but I wish it had something like an armchair as a seat.
Get wet.
You continue your work and show the witch that you can fly without spells.
That's what I'll do, Moomin papa.
Pane, we hope for you, Miss Niisku.
It's probably a bit of dampness.
We don't need much.
Miss Niisku, Do you believe that Niisku's aircraft will ever fly?
Of course. Niisku's triggers always work.
Niisku, may I come?
Niisku should lock the door.
Anyone can come in and grab his miracle liquid.
He's an invention and not a shopkeeper.
Here it is.
Is there?
On.
Doesn't look like much. Could it have any effect?
I'll show you.
We'd rather wait for Niisku to come.
Don't get angry.
We only take a few drops.
But...
I'll tell Niisku when he comes.
It's timely enough.
I can't wait to blow big bubbles.
This is a scientific experiment.
Niisku is only satisfied when he finds out if his substance also works for soap bubbles.
Now I'm fiddling.
As long as you don't overdo it.
Orhita a lot.
Maybe too much.
Better too much than too little.
Be careful, Myy.
Stay away. It could explode.
Oh boys, how big.
No, Niisku's invention is a fascinating sport.
The bubble gets bigger and bigger.
The bubble looks really tough.
Now it left.
No good.
And it still hasn't crashed.
Let's go outside and blow even bigger bubbles.
Pretty funny.
Take it easy, little shop.
Yes.
Sell, be careful.
Don't disturb the giant bubble on my side.
Myy.
Sell, hi, are you okay?
Hi, very funny.
In what bubble?
You should be able to claim those much bigger bubbles for yourself.
How does the bubble get there?
You like me.
Cook, cook, cook, cook, cook, cook, cook, cook.
No dice.
Not when you push harder.
Good, it worked.
Very funny.
The bubble takes me lightly.
The bubble does not compress.
The bubble is not thick.
Hihi, let's go somewhere.
Good idea.
Let's join Moomin Valley to show ourselves.
Yes, we get confused there.
I'm going higher.
Go ahead, Mars.
The smell is good.
Bend bubbles and straws.
Let's try.
The bubbles went the wrong way.
A bowl.
Look here.
Look up.
Wet girl.
Niisku, look at the giant soap bubbles.
Beyond belief.
These are real soap bubbles, Niisku.
We borrowed some of your magic liquid.
Or just a little bit, hey?
That what?
Niisku, your invention is a great success.
The bubbles don't break at all.
Come down now, Miss Niisku, so I can look at your soap bubble.
Later, Niisku, honey doesn't dry out.
And why not?
We have absolutely no idea how we're going to get down from here.
We learn against.
Take care of yourself bubble.
It's much easier than building an airplane.
Believe it or not!
Typical answer from a layman.
Listen, where are you going?
Oh, snot-nosed!
Moomin Mom!
Moomin Papa!
The Moomin troll is flying in the sky in a soap bubble.
In a bubble?
Nuska-muikkunen!
Moomin-pikku, möök is there too.
And my sister.
What has happened to you?
There are good views from up here.
That's nice, but you'd better come down.
They don't seem to be able to.
How do we give them dinner?
What if the bubbles burst?
They won't break.
How do you know?
After all, the bubbles are reinforced with my sperm.
Niisku-neiti and Myy, try to grab the ladder.
Clear!
I still want to fly!
You can't! You won't start to slow down in time anyway.
Come on now!
Sell, hurry!
Remember, niisku-mistress!
You'll get a Moomin goblin!
Sell, it went great!
It scares me.
The bubbles drag the ladder along with them.
The wind is rising!
Niisku-neiti, don't give up!
How do you two hit it off?
Hang on, I'll come with you!
Wait!
They can fly thousands of kilometers away from Moomin Valley.
Snuff-mum, isn't there any way to get the kids down?
The only option is to call for help.
Could he agree?
As sure as fate.
From Markiil!
Bubble bubble!
We are smashing into a mountain wall.
Let's try to catch the wind!
Maybe we can get over the mountain after all.
I want to see what's on the other side of the mountain!
Hey!
Meri!
And you never know when your grandma is coming back, do you?
No, it wasn't until dark yesterday.
Why do witches dance in the sky all day long?
I really don't know where grandma goes.
I guess he has some witch jobs?
We have to find the witch before the kids wander too far.
We are drifting into the open sea.
This isn't funny at all anymore.
Mikku mie is sleeping.
Moomin and Pekko as well.
Hey, don't sleep!
Moomin, Pekko and Myy, you need to wake up.
What should I do?
We will be separated from each other.
Terrible!
You can't leave me!
Someone's coming this way.
Someone flying.
Witch!
Just head on like that.
Who's the fine lady?
Don't fly this.
I will save me, Moomin, Pekko and Myy.
Huh, where are they?
There.
Share, that's how it looks.
And it apparently flies in different directions.
Yes, please help us, please help.
I can help.
If you tell me what that ball you're floating in is.
I'll tell you, I'll tell you, but I'll save us first, promise.
Well, let's start with the past.
Come help their help.
Maybe it smelled.
Moomin, papa, I can't get down.
Same problem as children.
Watch out for the skunk's foam at the mouth.
Fear not, this is not expensive.
I'm not afraid of water.
Little Myy is fast asleep.
Let him sleep, and he will be less trouble.
Phew, flying witch.
Mother.
Low.
Low-no-go.
A thousand thanks.
I can't help anymore.
Don't wait for me to get them out of the bubble.
Oh, you could even try.
I'd help if I could, but my witchcraft doesn't feel like it's working, it's bubbling.
I can probably help with that.
Oh, you're the little cookie.
And you the famous witch.
A scientist who can't even get his own bubbles down from the sky.
A witch who can't conjure soap bubbles burst.
Niisku, don't make a joke about it.
Excuse me, could I have a candle, scissors and matches?
Phew, you don't need a scientist when you use fire and scissors.
But a scientist finds a way to use them.
Hey, hey!
Hey, help!
Oops, more bubbles!
You paps!
I'm a bonehead.
There's a witch down there, look.
There is no joy in seeing her.
Shut up, don't make more bubbles.
Oh my, please help them down too.
A scientist can certainly act as the situation demands.
You know I can't fly, that's your hay.
Help them down.
Come on, I guess I have to.
Thank you, Nisku.
Tell me one thing, how did you get inside the bubble?
Well, it was quite easy when the bubbles were fresh.
I didn't even know my invention had that feature.
Milestone blisters. Maybe it should be left to heaven.
You can't be that bad.
Mouth soup, don't you hear the word?
Mom, what are they talking about?
Don't worry, the witch is fun to annoy a bit.
Noita feels very important now.
Ouch! What the hell am I doing here?
Oops, now they're coming down.
The soap bubble scene was brought to a happy conclusion by the cooperation of science and magic.
But Nisku and the witch did not become best friends.