One day a vampire escaped from the zoo.
It wasn't the terrible dragon rafts from Transylvania, but still scary.
Everyone was very worried because it is disgusting to be in the teeth of a bloodsucker.
There isn't. Crazy, not a single picture of a vampire.
Did you look properly?
I looked.
It doesn't have all the animals!
Although the name of the book is World Animals.
Then maybe a vampire isn't an animal after all. Is it a plant?
And ran away!
Maybe Hemuli knows what a vampire looks like.
There are carnivorous plants.
A vampire is not a plant!
It is, if it is not mentioned in the animal book.
If it's even an object!
Really?
You're a fool. If it's escaped from the zoo, then it's obviously an animal.
It probably is, but it would help if you knew what it looks like.
I would mainly like to brush up on my old knowledge with the help of a book. A vampire is a type of bat.
Bat?
Everyone who hears tries to cover themselves to prevent the vampire from biting.
A harness would be the only safe outfit.
Pidua gets goosebumps when he imagines you in the harness!
I will not participate in the tournament.
Someone is at the door.
Have you come running on foot?
I am truly a disaster.
Well, what's so crazy?
Everything is crazy.
You must have heard about the vampire who escaped from the zoo?
With pleasure. What has happened to it?
According to the latest information, it may have gone towards Moominvalley.
The vampire is coming.
It's entirely possible that it's already here.
Terrible. It's a disaster. What the hell are we doing now?
We try to protect ourselves from its bite.
Do we need to get protective gear?
That would be wise. Thanks for the juice.
Does the harness work?
Fine. I didn't know you had one.
Remember to keep the doors and windows tightly closed.
That is important.
Are you going to catch that vampire?
Oh it is. Professionals will come to the rescue.
It's quite clear.
What if I find it?
You run away.
The weather had to be caught.
Yeh, yeh. But it can bite you.
I bite it first and it doesn't do anything.
I have to move on now.
Keep your eyes open and stay inside.
Goodbye and goodbye.
Thank you for visiting.
I'm careful you too.
Chief of Police, I'm coming along.
I see. Stay with me.
Moominpapa said that a vampire looks like a bat.
I hope we never have to see that.
From that night on, the residents of Moomin Valley lived in constant fear of vampires.
S IT WAS WRONG
Well, no face here?
Let's tie that too.
Kumal index
No, I don't see anything
The eyes must also be protected.
No
Now be wise.
What on earth? Is it masquerade?
So
Vampyyri won't be able to bite Nipsu now.
But how can Nipsu eat?
Nipsu says that the vampire has taken away his appetite anyway.
Nipsu says that the windows must be closed.
Ah, the windows are closed.
Oh the horror, the chimneys also have to be blocked.
Hmm.
Nipsu, you're safe inside. Use the bandage only outside.
Shall I untie you?
Oh, they dress you!
Do you dare to go out in bandages?
Of course, this is the most secure after the body harness.
I'm not scared, I caught this vampire.
Not without me!
Tel!
Help! The vampire is here!
I bite a vampire!
It's biting me!
Stop it!
Talk to me by pretending to be a jerk!
Good day, Hemuli.
How many days!
Can you see through that net? Seems awkward.
This is inconvenient, but better than getting bitten by a vampire.
I wouldn't have believed you.
A vampire bite is dangerous.
I'm not arguing, but I thought you knew that vampires hate garlic.
Is that true?
Let's hope.
Know him. You seem to trust the power of garlic.
Yes.
Well, you can't afford to capsize the boat.
Garlic has been used for centuries to ward off vampires.
If only I could get some garlic pearls.
Snuff, Muikkunen.
Good day, Hemuli.
Oh, you have garlic around your neck too.
Did you catch the vampire?
Well, not yet.
I don't think there are any vampires.
On, on.
The zoo was here yesterday looking for people.
Everyone here seems to be afraid of vampires. All except the Moomin.
You don't seem scared either?
Maybe not, but the exterior can be deceiving.
Let's stop the fuss and rush after the monster.
Did you hear that, Moomin?
It's fine.
How do the locals react?
Who anyway.
Mom is not at all, but dad doesn't stick his nose out at all.
Good day.
Good day, Mrs. Viljonka.
Come in quickly. Moominpa gets alarmed if I keep the door open.
Oh yeah, for heaven's sake.
Hey papa, what if the vampire has taken Mrs. Viljonka's hamo?
No, no. He couldn't have come past the garlic.
Oh, right.
The date for the vendors has now been decided.
Aha, right?
I hope you are in a generous mood.
I'll be back soon to collect the donations.
We have a lot of useless junk.
Couldn't the sellers wait until the vampire horror is over?
When would that be?
No, no. In times like these, civilian courage is needed and oh Heroa valuables.
So yes.
I'm moving on.
You are brave. Use caution.
Hmm.
Oh.
You're not a vampire are you?
Share, you are afraid of garlic.
Papa, papa, would you come here?
What matter?
What the hell?
The vampire is here.
what did you say
Vaampyri.
Dad, what now?
Mamma, run away.
Here we come.
Vaampyri.
Dad, what now?
Mamma, run away.
Here we come.
Mm.
What is this?
Wow, the vampire is here.
Oh.
Mamma.
Is everything okay?
Were you attacked by a vampire?
Oh.
Hmm...
An unusually affectionate vampire.
It tastes like pancakes.
The vampire must be sent away.
Cute little faces.
Mom, are you sure the vampire didn't have time to bite you?
Of course not. How would it bite me?
It is out of character to say that a vampire is affectionate.
It's hearty?
I have heard that the victim of a vampire's bite turns into a vampire himself and protects his prey.
Goblin gold.
Do I look like a vampire to you?
What are you going to do with a vampire?
Yay, can't it stay in the kitchen?
A vampire?
Yes, it's always warm in the kitchen.
Let's keep it in a jar.
Not all the time.
I don't live in a house with a vampire running around on the loose.
You can go outside when the mamma muvi is released from the vampire's glass jar.
A vampire is dangerous.
Dad, could it be possible that there are more than one type of vampire?
Ai!
You know, even if this species doesn't bite.
The vampire hasn't bitten any of us yet.
And maybe I won't bite.
That's true, but what...
I won't give up my little vampire. I won't give up.
Thanks for everything, but I think I'm going home.
Police Chief! Police Chief!
Daytime someone.
Did you catch the vampire?
Who? Me?
The vampire must be caught before the charity sale.
Really.
Look under every single stone.
You can trust me.
Oh God! Oh God!
I have to go for a tour.
There is nowhere to stay.
A cute little vampire.
Are you hungry?
Well, let's go see if there's anything in the kitchen.
Mamma!
So what?
Hemul came.
Please invite him in.
Keep him company while I give the vampire some jam.
Hemuli hardly cares to come in.
Neither do I, by the way.
Oh, you're stupid.
You can immediately see from the vampire that it didn't bite anyone.
I think we'd rather stay on the porch.
That's good, there's some tea for you.
Thanks mom.
Mother!
Tule!
The lady wants to see a vampire.
Yes, of course.
Oops, where has it gone?
Back to the kitchen I guess.
Oh, how are you doing, little vampire.
So you want to keep the fact that there is a vampire in the Moomin house a secret.
Well, that's clear.
They would immediately come to the zoo to get the vampire away.
Wouldn't that be better?
No, we do take care of our guests.
Too bad, everyone in Moomin Valley believes that the vampire is on the loose and that's why they're afraid.
It seems we are at an impasse.
This is a puzzle.
Police Chief!
What's wrong with papa now?
Throw the garlic beads off your neck.
We have found the vampire and buried it.
That's just news.
Verily.
You can tell everyone that there is no need to be afraid anymore.
Hurrah!
Great stuff, Moominvappa.
You are the hero of Moominvalley.
I will arrange for you to be granted a stable.
I don't know that at all.
I export to spread the good news.
There's someone at the door.
Honey, would you hide the vampire?
Of course.
Come on, Trakula, you don't chew socks.
Hello, Viljolka, come in.
Do you have the goods for sale ready?
Children can carry them away right away.
I just put the things together on the table.
Go further.
Great day, I'm going for a walk.
Even if it's a mess, you can't break anything.
No!
Vampire, vampire, where are you?
Dad, what now?
I can't find a vampire.
Father hid it when Viljolka came.
Where did father slip it?
Well, you'll have to ask dad.
But when I can't find my father either.
I'll help. Dad never finds good hiding places.
Not found.
Looks like we'll have to ask dad after all.
Father!
There you are.
Tell me, where have you hidden the vampire?
I put it where those things from this table have been taken.
Viljolka picked them up at charity sellers.
Also the pot with a lid.
So. Oh, there was a vampire.
Did you have to be Hanna?
Come along, Nuuska Muikkunen.
Alone.
One can only hope that the cover is still in place.
All the stuff from you is here.
Oh, there they are.
True madam, Viljolka.
I put that pot among the others by mistake.
We want it back.
Share, what's up?
Kastus, it's stored here.
Let's peek inside.
Is there something there?
It's a kitten.
Dad.
Rude.
Nope.
Viljolka, has anyone gone to lift the lid of the pot?
No, not me at least. Children possibly.
It may still be here.
I'll have to look. Does that fit, Viljolka?
Of course.
Let's disperse then.
Dad, it's not here.
Not visible!
I guess it has faded.
I will help you.
The lady doesn't need it.
I will help you in your search.
This is who my house is.
There is no doubt.
If you're looking for a kitten, then why are you all up in arms?
I guess it's best to tell the truth.
We're not looking for a kitten, we're looking for a vampire.
And it was already in the pot from you in the summer. Is there a vampire in my house?
We will try to find it.
Today you announced the grave before the vampire.
And even deeper. How do you do anyone?
I'm so sorry.
There it is. Over there, the back of the couch, which...
Where?
Vili whose.
No sweat.
This is not a vampire.
It's just a bat.
Bat?
A regular bat.
Oh.
Are you sure?
Absolutely sure.
I've never seen a vampire, but often bats.
This is a bat.
Joo.
Good day, hold Vili by. Good day.
Are you at home?
Who cares, hoi.
Not at home.
Vili whose.
It was a pity. Come back later.
Good day.
Police Chief.
What are you guys doing here?
We are going to organize a big party with Vili kunnu in honor of the fact that the Moomins wished the vampire away.
Or really a party?
Just join in, Chief Constable.
Feel good.
Actually, I had something for others.
Being nothing, you just say the information that the vampire has been caught.
It was supposed to be dead and buried.
It's true.
Moominpapu clearly said he buried a vampire.
Then there must be two vampires.
No, there's only one missing from the zodiac.
Let's leave the Moomin house right away and ask for an explanation.
Good idea.
Come already.
Let's go right now.
Let's do that.
The Moomins were annoyed about it, and didn't want to start making up explanations about another vampire.
They went ashore and took a long sailing trip.
Maybe another topic of conversation would appear in mummy valley in time.