There is nothing bad to say about the books, but sometimes they seem unnecessarily strong.
Just like before.
Just like that.
Good morning, as usual.
As usual, good morning.
Did you say something?
I wished you good morning.
Is it morning already?
Just don't say you've been up all night reading that book.
A mother's love is so sweet.
Did your mother's love keep you awake?
Oh to have children and drown them in love.
As far as I know, you have to get married first.
Oh, I'd dress my titties in frills and they'd worship me like the boys do, even if they don't have frills now.
How many children do you dream of having?
I'm all about mother's love.
Two dozen would be a good number.
In that case, you can leave me off the bills.
What are you up to so early?
Myy.
Please know that I must not be woken up yet.
Like there's something strange going on.
It is. Why don't you sleep?
I look just like my mother. Do you agree?
Some are simply born to be mothers.
Maybe so.
Moomin! Moomin!
What, mom?
I'm a mother.
What, mom? What matter?
Oh, there you are.
Two clueless children are lying on the porch.
Don't now.
Pretty small.
Oh wonder.
Say something else. Would you help carry them in?
Two small children.
What the hell is wrong with them?
If only you knew.
What now, swamp lady?
Fate has taken over.
Oh well.
Oh, the horror.
Hey, listen.
What's wrong with you?
He's really warm.
And he doesn't seem to have hurt himself.
Oh, you little roaches.
They must have wandered all night when they got here.
What kind of parents do they have when they have let their little children go astray?
Very hungry.
There is food for this.
They would wake up.
You heard what they said.
Chop all the food.
Wait two years.
Warm water, thermometer, aspirin, bandages just in case.
Eat as much as you can handle tight socks.
Who exactly are you?
Nips.
Where are you from? Where are mom and dad?
The horror, what happened?
Father and stepmother left us in the forest while we were asleep.
To the wolf's mouth!
What the hell.
Our own mother is dead. We have a mean stepmother and she hates us for being so pretty.
He persuades father to leave us to be eaten by bets.
That reminds me of something.
Little children, don't be sad. I will be your new mother.
Don't go to the bowl?
Are you sure?
My food said yes.
Keep those good kisses alive.
Note that they have not been loved.
They are not used to being shown affection, but they get love from me.
Oh, they get love from me.
We are in no rush. There is enough time in the world by any measure.
Oh I'll wrap you in love and it's soft like cotton candy.
Miss, are you all right?
Are you sure she wants kids?
I want to. I mature at night and I know my part.
Sounds.
What's wrong, you're a good mother.
There are carts here.
I know the carts too.
Grandma, the kids need strollers more than you do.
Be teary-eyed and hop on board.
Mom pushes you.
I'm done!
Disrepair.
Let's push mom sometimes.
Mom, come along for the ride.
Oh my little darlings, you are so perceptive.
Shut up. It bothers me.
Mother.
I don't call.
Mothers don't call.
Mother.
A new day.
I have to get up before the cultists.
Wait, you don't remember, you don't hug mom yet.
Don't you muse?
How is it going, is taking care of the little monsters getting annoying?
Don't you call my golden knobs monsters.
It's no fun when he never gets mad at us.
I want to stay away.
Mother.
Help.
That was it.
I'll catch you guys.
Mom helps.
Stand up. Moomi papa, it's not right to think about my children.
You should be a little tougher on them.
Neither do I.
You'd even get mad at them. Those tricks just weren't funny at all.
It's an irrelevant question, but ask yourself why they pulled that stunt.
What do you mean?
Children's playgrounds have apparently never had their own swing.
Do you not realize that they have been subdued and depressed?
Ova's lack of a hammock lulled them into powerlessness.
You mean I should make them a hammock?
Oh Moomin papa, I knew you would understand.
Well, there's a hammock for you.
We'll see how long the swing can withstand that wear and tear.
Ugh, this is so boring.
Let's figure something else out.
What are mom's little darlings up to?
I won't tell.
Oh, you don't tell mom.
It's a secret.
Well, we all have our little secrets.
At least mom is happy when you're not doing bad things.
Ah, that's what the mother of the neck is.
You look pleased.
Are the monsters if you don't do it?
After all, I'm a mother, I miss nothing more than seeing my little ones immersed in their games.
The tricks show intelligence.
What are they currently doing?
Mud bottom.
Mud balls.
It's their soma secret.
Good target.
Shall we start?
Soma secret.
Soak the hammock with mud balls.
Carry on or play, darlings.
Mom wash as a hangover.
No.
Tomorrow boy.
Did it hurt you?
Enkai.
Oh moms, I'm dying for crumbs.
Stop it, kids.
This will be taught.
Thank you sell.
This is not what the vints can survive.
Now the mud war begins.
Wait a minute.
There is something strange here.
They are right there.
Give me more.
Joo.
Stop now.
Wake up.
Stop it.
Mom, you've got the cones.
You can hurt yourself.
Myy.
I'll come to the rescue.
Good thing.
Rapataan is not a rondit.
You're a moron too.
Hoomipeika and sell.
Stop it.
Can't hear the words?
Tomorrow you will even stop.
As if you chose a bad place.
Move out of the line of fire.
Ahead of faith.
I'm a mother.
A mother's love is overflowing.
But I'm also a very tired mother.
Now you're teasing me.
What I'm doing now.
I do mother for love.
I don't understand where the children are.
Do to death.
Finally the mud war ended.
It was actually quite refreshing.
It must have been fun here.
Terribly fun.
Hello, Hoomipeikko. What are we playing now?
It's a joke that you are prisoners.
And we keep you in the torture chamber.
Next you go to trim the porch.
It's covered in mud.
So you don't know where the children ended up after they got lost in the woods.
I don't fear the worst. This is horrible.
Don't be sad. I interview the residents of the surrounding area.
Well, nips and nips. Isn't it time for a real discussion?
Who is there?
The Moomins. You don't usually wash the outside of the house.
Drugs seem to have a lot of children.
No. There are two guests.
Mother!
Oh, my child has been kidnapped.
Harjelko, hardly at all.
Are you their mother?
The children just came to drag like slaves.
Good lady. This is a police matter.
Glad you found mom.
I'm not looking for motherhood, but her children.
Joo.
This lady's children have been missing all week.
Can you explain why they are cleaning at your place?
No ha...
This could be a serious thing in values, Moomin papa.
Kidnapping is a felony.
No, not the policeman.
Hey, we're not Moomin, kidnappers.
Ai.
But then what are you here for?
Nips and nips. I want to hear the answer right away.
Well, when the kids came up with one new game for us.
And what kind of game is that?
We played that we had been left in the forest to be eaten by wolves and then we came to the Moomins.
We had a lot of fun.
You guys are killing me.
Try to calm down, dear lady.
Mother!
Don't get upset over a small thing again. It's so terribly embarrassing.
I'll show you what's embarrassing about it.
Help!
Wait till I catch you guys. Wait!
Hey there, the game is over for today, but we'll be back.
Don't be stingy.
They have apparently run away before.
And hung out at home.
Dear children, don't let yourself be caught up in them.
Just run and come visit sometime.
The home feels quiet now that the little...
The golds are gone.
Yes, I just hope that Niiskunnemi didn't regret it.
Oi and, and.
A mother's love is better enjoyed only in moderate doses.
You will still be a wise mother.
Thanks mom.
Where is the sale? I haven't seen him all day.
He is reading upstairs.
That's unusual.
I guess he's not reading the same book about mother's happiness.
I don't think so, but he is completely under the spell of the book.
He doesn't even answer when you talk to him.
He finds out the facts of life.
Don't disturb him.
Mother
When I grow up, I'll be a sea rosso.
I am interested in selling the joys of motherhood.
And he seems to have already figured out the facts of life.