The morning looked beautiful. Miss Niisku was in a good mood.
Wet girl!
So!
Humid! What is it?
Where in the heck is that basket?
What basket?
Bread basket. I went to work and I want a basket for my lunch, but it's nowhere to be found.
Did you look at the skateboard?
Of course.
Weird. Where did I see that last?
You put things in their proper places. You always lose them.
And I won't waste! Hear the breeze, you have to come up with a basket that will never go to waste.
Me? A basket that won't go to waste even for my naïves, so it's...
Solve the problem before you go to work. Bye.
Niisku-neiti, you pissed me off.
I'm going to the Moomin troll now. Bye.
Congratulations! I need to get a basket!
Hey hey hey.
Assu-come
Looks like our basket.
It's our basket!
Hey dude!
Hey wet girl!
Isn't that our basket?
It might be. It was lying in the corner of the niisku shed.
Well, you should have guessed it from the trail.
Congratulations! Need it in the basket!
Give it back!
Later! The basket fits perfectly into the bill.
What's bothering you?
Häijyläinen.
Adapted from niisku-girl.
It was a sell.
Moomin, stop selling!
What? Slip!
Moomin!
Help me up!
Take this direction!
Later, we will!
Wet girl!
Give the basket back!
Paragraph! I'm on a good run now!
Cory-oops!
Later, come back!
Come on!
Oh, that's where the hell went!
Admit it!
Congratulations! Sell!
I can't! Today I have restless legs!
So yes.
The little mole was like being stung by a wasp.
Sell! where are you
Little sell, answer!
Moomin!
Excuse me, has the sale been seen?
It isn't!
Well, oh, thank you!
What has happened to the sale?
Are there families in hiding?
Never work!
what are you doing
Sell, I found you!
Dirty laundry!
Myy!
Stop young man!
Look, you're not going anywhere until you've washed the sheets!
Me?
Just you!
Yeah, the hell sells.
You shouldn't have started doing laundry.
I don't understand what has happened to Pikku.
And where has he gone.
Myy!
No one can catch me today!
I blow like a storm wind!
I can!
You can't escape!
Wait a minute!
Moomin!
What is yours?
My paw!
Did you mix it up?
Look what you did to Moomin!
Apologize immediately!
I'm not pushing Moomin now!
He fell in his own time!
I scared Moomin, what if the leg is broken!
Yes pah!
From a big crash!
Hey sell!
I could have been hurt too.
Did you get up?
We have to carry him home.
Oh Moomin!
We can't do this alone.
We need to get help.
Hello! What's up with mymmels?
Help!
We need help!
Police case!
Hey!
Papa, would you like to taste this broth?
So what!
Really good, suitably seasoned.
I wanted to try one new recipe.
You always cook tasty food.
Thanks papa.
Moomin papa!
Moomin went bad!
what is
Moomin!
Carefully!
Hi parka!
Paw swelling.
I can leave.
Anyway, thanks for the help.
And I didn't even offer tea.
Thank you, once again.
Get well soon, Moomin.
Thanks, I'll try.
I would meet.
Thanks again.
I'll have a small talk where I'll see him.
Moomin huts Uncle
Let it hurt.
Well, the wrap is almost in place.
Moomin rukka, are you leaving the poo and Kielmäszämo?
The little one has started to crow.
I'll take the guesswork out of him.
So you can't do anything to me.
What are you looking at there?
Are you sure you don't want to stay in the Moomin House?
Myy?
Mii!
Mymmeli, Did you see the sale?
I did, but he was in a big hurry.
He is always forced to.
Has my sister done bad things?
Well, sort of.
Please.
Oh great, pumpkin soup made me feel like it.
Be careful, it's hot.
Can I get nothing but soup?
Oh, oh, oh, oh, I'm being silly.
You and the scumbags are healthy.
Why only get soup for dinner if you've sprained your ankle?
Good appetite.
Thanks as well.
Looks delicious.
Good.
Thanks for the food.
See you tomorrow Grandma Pekka.
Just bye.
Beautiful dreams.
Didn't come sell tonight.
Well, Mymmeli, he would hint in that direction a bit.
I have no desire to see it sold.
He is still ours.
Boy, you've gotten heavy.
Or old of you.
Don't be silly.
I hope I don't have to carry you for others.
You have to, I won't be walking tomorrow.
Oh, sometimes you sound just like your father.
A compression bandage and grandma's liniment will heal your ankle mountain for sure.
Grandma Peikko, don't bother to hold a grudge against me.
He must be miserable.
I have no comments.
Myyy, where are you?
Little Myyy.
Hey Mymmeli.
Ylta, have you seen the sale?
No, I haven't seen anyone from the Moomin house in a while.
If you see a sale, have you seen the Moomin house people?
If you see sales words, the food is ready.
Joo.
Mymmeli, right away you can come and tell the seller your business.
From heaven.
Myyy, Little Myyy.
Hey, hum.
Cherish me.
Mimmel.
Let's wait.
Don't miss a minute.
Grandma Goblin, listen, I'll put his foot in there.
Me.
Goblin, listen, I'm going to hurt my leg because of you there.
You come home right away and in the morning we go to apologize to Grandma Peiko.
Me.
I don't want to.
Pit me now.
It wasn't my fault. And it wasn't, and it wasn't.
Mimmel.
Let the sale stay. He can stay here for the night.
But?
I'm sure he'll want to go home tomorrow.
What? It's a hill.
Are you going? If nothing is too much trouble.
No.
Let's go tomorrow Mummi and have a look.
You're a nice snuffling muikkonken.
Good night.
Let's eat.
Yesterday's fart is fine for you.
About.
Well, doesn't it taste good?
Don't rush. There's no rush.
Speak up.
Dad was right. It doesn't hurt at all.
Are you awake?
I am.
So when Eiti came, can you go for a walk down?
I guess if you help.
Does it still affect the leg?
Yeah, it's timid.
Oh dear.
Mmm.
what are you doing
Today I'm cooking, since I was allowed to stay here for the night.
You don't have to.
I already cooked.
Eat. There shouldn't be anything wrong with that.
I'm going for a walk.
Don't you eat?
I don't. I'm not hungry now.
I'll just do the laundry first.
I stand up.
Thank you, Niis kun Eiti.
Is it too tense?
Not at all. All well and good.
Except it hurts terribly.
I will tell Pikku Myi what's going on and who's giving orders when I see him.
Is Myy back?
And I don't care if I don't come back.
And unless he apologizes, I'll stay.
Really cheap to taste.
I came to apologise, but now it would be my turn to go and start.
Well then, don't apologize.
I took the knife.
It's good if you have the same voice.
I feel sorry for you.
That's the point here.
Oh Myy, wait.
Don't disappear again.
Don't disappear.
Don't face.
Don't disappear again.
The Moomin troll is going crazy!
Listen.
What the hell?
Muomi-peikka
What?
Doesn't it live there anymore?
I can't sleep after I've been motionless all day.
It's not fun to play alone. Snuff may still be around.
He is awake.
Myy, why don't you go back to the Moomins already?
Yes, but yes, I'll leave Nuuskamuikkunen right away if I'm a problem for you.
I don't care, but the Moomins are worried about you.
The cat containers are worried about the Moomins, not me.
Moomin's leg is still sore.
You need to apologize.
We will never forgive me.
Mummy Moomin!
Hm?
Good morning!
Has Moomin woke up?
On.
Oh, isn't it with you.
He ran early in the morning with a happy mind.
He continues.
Haha!
I go out early in the morning with a happy mind.
Ai!
I ordered them when making crutches.
Geecha!
Whoah
Who from there?
Yep! That's what I got!
Sirä!
Me too, I guess you weren't scared.
How about? Foot?
Ha, it's been healthy for a long time.
What?
I've only pretended. I wanted to scare you.
Father and mother are worried about you, and so am I a little.
Really?
And nick lady and nip.
You tricked me! I avenged you!
My costar is going to be creepy!
Hop, hop, snap!
Hopoti, snap!
After all, the little girl didn't have to apologize.
But he was a little sorry.