T vessel
Oh, sorry Moomin mom.
We were clumsy.
Eh, that's okay.
Oh, this fell.
Thanks.
Are you going out?
Yeah, now that the mark is gone.
Have fun.
Tiuhtia viuhti really seem to have settled into the Moomin house.
They are very small and the only ones that can be searched
pencils dropped between the floor wires.
Hey, this looks like a particularly secret place.
Yeah, no one can find here.
Let's go get the suitcase here.
Let's get it here.
Are you sure we could keep it in our own room?
What if someone enters the room while we are gone?
So what?
Moomins don't go there to hang out.
They are nice.
Yes, but strangers.
After all, Moomins let anyone in.
Anyone.
Do not go to press!
You lied to me.
How so?
Moomin still has it.
Even the shoe I gave you.
Out!
Moominma gave it to the grunt.
I saw.
I saw the shoe in Moomin.
But was it the same shoe?
Of course.
I guess I know that.
Oh yours!
Momma Moomin did give it to the grunt.
I'm going to see Moomin immediately.
are you coming
I'm coming, I'm coming.
The truth must be dug out.
Let's dig.
The story seems strange at the time.
True.
Mymmeli and I went to the beach yesterday.
So what?
We found an exciting object.
Remember that wreckage we found after the storm?
Of course.
It's only been a few weeks.
And remember that wooden sculpture,
whose snuff Muikkunen found.
I remember.
Moomin fell in love with it.
Don't remind me about it.
It's here now.
And it isn't.
Remember, I'm talking today.
Alone, my own truth.
It was nothing but a stone now.
It is as beautiful as before.
Are you sure it's the same?
It is, of course.
Beautify Rilma's legs and rear.
True.
Only the legs are a wooden doll.
Beautiful girl with big eyes.
The Moomin licks at it.
Is it still on the beach?
I fancy.
Unless no one has found it.
Sell, do you believe that
the waves shout it away?
I don't know.
The waves just hit the beach.
If Moomin spots the statue,
he saves it.
And not placing it in the room.
Can't fit through the door.
He faked it with some kind of construction.
Yes, I know that.
Oh well.
I can't predict that.
He is sitting and supporting some statue, a silly expression on his face.
Sweet!
Disku, Miss, Weren't you on your way to the Moomin House?
I was, but I just remembered one important thing.
The way is clear.
Bye!
You're not going to leave either.
No, we just...
Then why do you have a suitcase?
Will you help us in carrying?
With pleasure.
Thank you, Moomin troll.
Think nothing of it. This is a small favor.
We will continue this secret place.
The bag is not heavy.
Oh, sorry.
The secret place isn't very secret if I've seen it.
I'm leaving.
Don't snitch on anyone.
Of course not.
What are you doing up there?
What does it look like? I'm coming down.
You can't. You're too small.
I pretend I'm not.
Moomin goblin, I would like to ask you one thing.
Ask away.
Didn't Moomin-mama give you a hand too?
Anto, above.
Then you can't have it because morkö took it.
I still have it.
But I don't have any.
I still have.
But that's not possible.
We gave Mörö a boot as well.
He pretends he didn't.
Well, no, but because of Ed, I say that it was a different shoe.
Ruttika, tell me the truth.
It's a secret.
I want to know.
If you tell, I'll tell you my own secret.
What is it?
The secret of how to sell.
Yes, but what is it?
You tell me first.
No, you tell me first.
Let's start telling at once.
Alright, let's do that.
Y, K, K.
Yesterday I went to the swimming pool with Myppeli and we found that female-shaped bow image again and...
What? That wooden woman.
The mouth of the cave.
Hey, you haven't shared your secret yet.
Later.
This shit. Tell me first.
Your meat!
What's Moomin doing there?
Are you looking for shoes again?
Maybe he doesn't see shoes, but he's still looking for something.
I think he's important, he's gone.
How far do we have to go?
As long as you row.
The beach is already far away.
This granny will be taken so far that she will never come back.
Yes, this is far enough.
There are ocean currents here.
It's further away.
He looks sad.
Let's make him happy.
How? There's only one way.
You are right.
Tight and tight.
You look so terribly sad that we thought we'd cheer you up with something either...
That's fine.
It's fine, but you don't have to.
Well, we'll show you what's actually in the suitcase.
Do you want to see? It is very beautiful.
Of course I will. Whew!
Hmm.
Do you need help?
No, yes we dye.
Thanks for the help.
Now we open the bag.
We're opening up to the first one.
Oh, through me.
How do you like it?
That I like?
You're not sad anymore, are you?
In.
It's fun.
Very funny.
What a ruby, how it changes color.
From warm red to Sapphire blue, then light red.
Just like a flame that flares up and then suddenly it takes on the tinge of a black tulip.
Hmm. Maybe it's the king ruby.
Well, it sure is.
The one the Magician is looking for on the Panther's back.
Hi, hi.
He may now be somewhere far, far away looking for a ruby, but he will return to Moomin Valley one day.
First the morkö and now Taikuri, the little polo.
Not even a week had passed when a terrible accident befell Moominvalley as if from a clear sky.
Hmm.
Not even in the bedroom.
Weird. Where did you see it last?
Somewhere here.
Maybe it's in the garden.
I haven't been out all day.
So yes. Moomin mamma's handbag was missing.
The bag contained dry socks, iron wire and aspirin, and a pocket knife for slicing the scumbags.
What is it?
My handbag is missing and I feel so helpless.
Can I get a falcon if I find it?
You can. I will organize a big party for everyone with cakes for everything.
And no one has to wash up in the evening or go to bed early.
I'll find the bags!
Not me.
At least your handbag isn't in the basement.
Great, Niiskukulta.
However, I haven't been to the basement in days.
Word spread and eventually everyone in Moomin Valley was looking for the handbag.
Is it crowded?
What exactly are they looking for?
My handbag.
The one where you have your little pockets?
Exactly that.
You guys just go play.
It's so nice to sleep in Moomin's handbag.
Mamma seems sad.
Maybe we don't have this.
Maybe we need to give it back.
Ai.
You found it.
The bag was found.
Tiuhti and faniuhti found Moominmamma's handbag.
Oh, thank you very much.
Where did you find it?
From that little guy. From the big birch.
Moomin's handbag is pretty.
In honor of finding the bag, we're having a big party tonight.
As you know, this party is organized because Moomin's handbag was found.
A big thank you to everyone who participated.
Let's raise a toast to our heroes for tiud and viuhith.
Without a handbag, Moomin Valley would be missing something.
Chip!
Moomin has something to say to you.
We are happy that mom's handbag was found and thank you.
To thank everyone for a great party,
Tiuhti and viuhti have decided to show what is in their mysterious suitcase.
We have a unique opportunity.
Come on, Tiuhti and viuhti, are you ready?
At the ready!
At the ready! Y-ka-ko!
How wonderful!
How could Mörkö exchange a jewel for a shoe?
It must be a royal ruby.
King ruby.
Magician!
The ruby I've sworn to find.
Storm off! The ruby is ours!
Go away evil, Magician!
Magician!
The ruby is my property.
And it's not!
Mörkö changed it with Tiuhti ja viuhit for a heart-shaped shoe.
Or even a heart-shaped shoe?
That's right!
Mörkö gave the ruby to these two and I saw it with my own eyes.
I have been searching for this ruby for 300 years.
Sad, but it's not yours.
Couldn't you exchange the ruby for, say, two large diamonds?
No way!
I can't take the ruby by force.
This is getting on my nerves.
Magician!
Would the Magician like a mug of punch?
Thanks, I haven't had a punch in 85 years.
Quince.
It's you too.
Could there be more?
Thanks, that's enough.
Magicians are not potions.
Great, Christmas, right, punch.
Or it's up to you now.
I'll show you some magic.
You can hope three times.
Do you have anything?
I'll show you some magic.
You can hope three times.
Please and hope.
Three of you in line to wish.
What now, are you afraid?
You look so old, you're not afraid.
I'm not afraid.
Oh yes, broke the Spade I had borrowed from Moomipapa.
I hope Spade.
No such wishes.
I would like a new Shovel.
Keep what you get.
Oh, thank you very much.
Thanks for the loan.
Next.
Sorry, but...
What can I do for you, young lady?
It can be a bit difficult.
For me?
Is that what you want?
So.
Come your eyes.
Your wish has come true, little lady.
Oh my goodness.
Low no go.
I wished for similar eyes when I am with that legless woman who is so beautiful to you.
You changed completely.
Please give me a mirror.
Quite beautiful actually.
Kamala!
Would I get my old eyes back?
I only complain about one wishful thinking.
Mr. Magician, may I have hope now?
Please, golden carriage, crystal goblet, whatever.
At least I would like a sack full of gold coins.
Moomin wishes.
You hear, keep two sacks, and I'll get another one. What do you say about that?
I've already made my decision.
Ai.
Please, restore the eyes of the little girl.
He can see well in those too.
Goodbye gold coins.
The wish has been heard and fulfilled.
Well look, you would have thought before you wished.
My Moomin.
Magician.
What?
If you can do magic like that, why not do it for yourself?
It doesn't work like magic only on others.
So is it okay for us to wish something for you together?
Yes, I guess.
Give us hope.
In for a penny in for a pound.
We wish you a similar ruby.
Keep what you get.
It's for you.
Thank you, thank you.
Thanks.
That's how the magician's 300-year search ended.
And Moomin Valley has never celebrated so joyfully.
Everyone was happy.
Except maybe a nitwit who would have liked a bag of gold coins.
Thank you, thank you.