Are you sure you can get along now?
Don't worry, honey.
Be careful with fire.
Mommy, you already said that.
The jam is on the shelf in a familiar place.
You already said that.
Oh, did I say.
And then wash the sheets and clean the dump every day and...
Not every day now and remember...
Now we have to try to try to try to try to try to try.
Now we have to hurry so we won't be late for the wedding ceremony.
We have to pass over lonely mountains.
Oh yes, so true.
Take care of yourselves.
We will be back as soon as possible.
After all, I can count on you with a nod and a snot.
Celebrate in peace.
Try to take good care of yourself.
Remember the coming-of-age party!
Don't forget me!
You get nothing!
On what basis?
Fear not, I have something for everyone.
Well, here we go.
Have a nice trip!
Keep the sharks in the sharks!
Thank you, thank you.
Hey hey!
Bye!
I can eat these.
When you eat what's on the table.
That's where we start with the house spekky kids!
Let's think that we are the hosts of the house.
Yes, oh I want to sleep outside among the cooks.
Hi, may I make a suggestion?
Let's go to the river to swim logs.
Right now, right?
Let's go!
I'll come along!
Hey hey!
I can when I can't swim.
Nipsu, don't always marise!
It's hard for me to keep my balance!
Nipsu, don't spin the log!
Hey, it's dangerous to stand!
Go sit down!
Nipsu, stay tuned for that!
Nothing will come of this!
Their back paws are like macaroni!
Nipsu, you must not rotate!
Hey!
Hooray! Where did you all go!
Moomin!
Miss Niisko!
Jahuku! Jahuku!
Please help!
Nipsu, don't mess it up! It's low here!
True! The ice reaches the bottom!
Hey kids! What are you doing?
Sorry we!
Get out of the water right away!
The river is too dangerous a playground!
You're still drowning!
He looks like a hemule!
I don't know!
May I ask who the aunt is?
It's none of your business!
Get out of the water now and mess up kids!
Yeah, yeah, yeah!
South!
Who the heck is that old coot?
You guys scared me!
Remember, that was the last time you make judgments!
The river, there are dangers, it is very shallow!
All rivers are dangerous!
Think what would have happened if I hadn't missed it!
We would play in peace!
That's right!
Mom would agree with me,
if he were here!
We lean on our backs to support the land,
and we've never had anything happen to us!
You have been lucky!
Don't I'm a snotty young man!
Even if you haven't been in an accident yet,
it didn't seem to be included!
Now you can welcome me to your home.
Is it clear?
That's where your home is.
Talk to mom.
Mom and Dad aren't at home!
I mean...
Is innate?
Saatio, what do you have to do at the disco?
Hey ole biisi relationsiÿ Deadpool.
We are not at home.
Oh, when are they coming back?
Not for a long time yet.
Or so.
Mom and dad went to our relative's wedding on the other side of those mountains.
Oh, good unusual.
And you'll be on your own until they come back.
Hello ma'am. We know how to take care of ourselves.
Well, he sure can.
Your parents are thoughtless, downright irresponsible.
You mustn't talk bad about mom and dad.
Not so! And who is the lady?
Ugh. And I'm not a lady to you.
Call me Hemulitäri.
Hemuli who lives here is my brother.
Oh, my goodness, what a mess.
This if mika proves, you can't survive alone.
Moominmamma and Moominpapa won't be back for a long time.
Absolutely. I'll take care of you.
Wake up.
Now comes another one for the sound clock.
Let's start cleaning. Here are rags.
Too much.
Not ma'am, but Aunt Hemulitä. what is your name
I am Moomin, Moomin Goblin.
Didn't the aunt mean to go to Hemul?
Yeah, yeah. Hemuli is already waiting for aunt.
Oh, no problem.
My brother doesn't know I'm coming.
And I wouldn't be able to bless it with peace because I would think only of you.
I could be so irresponsible that I would leave the little helpless children at home for days.
Aunty is talking ugly again.
That's what he says.
Did you say something? I don't.
I'm starving.
The food will be ready soon. So when Eiti helps her aunt.
I bet the food is bad.
Wake up.
What's on your ankle?
Ah, the anklet.
It's not appropriate.
Little girls don't wear anklets.
As an adult, you are free to make yourself a laughing stock.
Yes, but...
I think the anklet is beautiful.
Oh, you must be a snob.
Your clothes need to be mended.
Somehow they have never been ironed.
I thought we might have been apart.
Now we are climbing.
Moominmamma and Moominpapali are much nicer.
I'm sorry, but I'm leaving now.
Oh, don't leave just yet, you snob.
Don't be upset.
I can't stand that hideous hemuli aunt.
Well, the soup is ready.
Looks tasty.
Is the table set, Moomin?
There is. A snotty nose.
Nus cam Ichinomiya year.
Nuskamuikkunen left because he saw what kind of mess was coming.
Come on, sit down at the table and taste the soup.
Joo.
One is gone.
Nuskamuikkunen ran away.
Myy.
Listen, Myy, it's not appropriate for little girls like that to talk with their hands in a gust.
Where does the snowman live?
In a tent by the river.
In a tent? Well then I have to get him some soup.
Uh, that, but...
Eat now before it gets cold.
Moominma's soup looks tastier.
Guess it tastes awful.
Myy.
I know I'm a good cook.
Have a taste, now please.
Thank you, beautiful.
Better than the new ones.
It tastes just as delicious as Moominmamma's soup.
I didn't guess, wasn't it good?
You can get a pinch more if you want.
Do you like it, Myy?
Probably a treat for someone who lacks a sense of taste.
That's right...
Ouch! Why you pipe me?
The giant should go away.
Well, this is no match for mother's soup.
Just like that.
But I think this is really good.
Do you think so?
I am.
It's funny to hear that there isn't anything really good for breakfast tomorrow either.
I want more.
It fits.
Nipsu is a real piggy bank.
Now this road ends at a corner.
Terribly hungry.
Sell, don't fight.
Do not eat food.
Nipsu must not poke around when it is in the spoon's mouth.
Moomintroll can't make a sound.
Sell, top ends off the table.
Ma'am, can I have more?
Don't call me ma'am, you're welcome.
The stars twinkled.
Muaska muikünen.
They create their light.
There you are.
Aunt Hemuli.
I brought you some soup.
Aunt is kind.
You really live in a tent.
That's how I live.
Isn't living in a tent unhealthy in the long run?
Muaska muikünen.
Hey.
Did you come over for the night?
If it works.
The soup was good, but I can't stand my aunt's nagging.
In the north I saw that huge whale.
Moi.
So what?
Then I went to the deer mountains and there I met the magician.
Nope.
They're still watching.
Tell me what you did then.
Well then...
I spent the night in an old dilapidated castle.
And how are you in the middle of the night?
How late did you stay up?
You should have been asleep a while ago.
We immediately go to sleep.
Moomin.
I close my eyes too.
Good.
Like that.
I want to hear the end of that story.
If we speak in whispers, my aunt probably won't hear downstairs.
Now. What did you see there in the castle?
I listened.
The heavy door opened with a creak and the old king came out wearing a crown.
But he was just a skeleton.
Do not.
Niskuneiti, you have to press a lot harder to get the dirt off.
Ai.
Little sister, you're just brushing the floor with a brush.
Oh, right?
Broom here. Use the brush like this.
Aaah, let it go well tonight.
Are you learning?
Auntie can clean when she can do it so well.
Make fun of the smaller mouth, young woman.
Yes, aunty.
Don't land on the grass.
The grass swarms with disgusting insects and worms.
Yes you are difficult.
What's wrong now?
Wash yourselves well before you enter.
When will mummy and daddy come home?
At least they don't have time for this trouble.
Are you saying that we have to continue with the old model?
I don't understand aunt.
We have to drive Auntie away!
But by what means?
I hope that the sea will come here and scare the aunt on its way.
Aunty would scare the crap out of me, and that would be it.
I guess so.
Would a poison ivy help?
Mmm, what a lovely scent.
Aunty, I have something to do.
Miss Niiskunne, you came just in time.
Taste these cookies.
Uh, yeah.
Ooh, good.
Unko, I'm happy.
Well how can I help?
Well, only when...
Bogey.
Aah! Hi muli aunty.
Did aunt scare the crap out of you?
Ms. Niiskun, please start mentioning the name of that object.
It won't be a bad thing, I'm afraid.
Really? That's great.
Jehu, now found a way. Soon we will be free.
The Needle stung me again.
How can you do it?
Now.
Bogey!
Dude, help! Help!
We succeeded! Aunt was scared.
Auntie is really afraid of the dark.
What a thud came from inside.
I will never forget this incident.
Tomorrow aunt will already be gone.
You know, even if he goes to the foot hill already tonight.
Did you notice the look on my face?
Oh, that's what it was all about.
I guess you don't like me.
I'm going to shoot tomorrow as soon as I wake up at my brother's.
I didn't stay here long, but I must say I enjoyed it.
Thanks.
I'm hungry.
It's your own fault that you didn't eat the soup I cooked.
Oh, that Aunt Himulitadi's soup was delicious.
Sopp and sopp, who cares about sopp?
Now we can do what we want.
And I can keep my hands busy for the rest of my life.
It's not very feminine to hold your hands in a gust.
I can keep my hands in a gust.
For mouth soup, you're making soup yourself.
Nuska muikkun, Are you going to leave?
Eat fish well today.
I'll come along. It has rained so much now that we will probably catch a lot of fish.
Come on then.
Yeah, I'll come too.
Please wait for me.
Hey, now they leave me here alone.
Even if that same me goes fishing with him.
Sell, why not luck?
Well, I would think that the three master fishermen catch so much catch that it's enough for me too.
Come see me again.
Same words, you come and see me.
Yeah, take good care of yourself.
So do you. Thank you for everything.
Aunt Hemuli didn't say anything.
In the name of truth, we were quite unfriendly to him.
Oh, this is where you all are in trouble.
Hey Hemuli.
My sister came to greet me. We haven't met for a long time.
Oh yes, he boasted that you are extremely reliable children.
Ai.
You're welcome, powerless law.
Hey.
My sister was worried about me.
I'm still alone.
Oh, aunt's umbrella.
Six.
Channels.
Let's save aunt.
Help. Help.
Aunt Hemuli, how long will it take. Help is near.
Aunty, please release me.
Just don't decide to let go.
Let's hit.
The rescue was successful.
Give it to me.
Are you OK?
Aunt Hemuli has nothing to worry about. Nope.
Thanks for asking, Granny. I'm fine, I'm fine.
Hey, I was aiming for the umbrella.
A pinch.
Nipsu has become a gentleman.
Many thanks to everyone.
There was luck on the way.
Thank you all. Thank you, thank you.
I sneeze.
Come on, let's start cleaning.
Go briskly from one corner to the other, Grandma and Grandpa are coming tomorrow.
I'll be in command here until then.
Myy.
Yeah, I know, but you shouldn't have asked for the quilt back.
That woman is still our bone.
And not a badass suit either. You're not into him anymore, that's for sure.
Sell, what are you muttering there?
I'm fine, I'm not muttering anything.
Hey kids, here we come.
The Moomin house has been kept in such great condition that we can leave the children alone at any time.
Indeed.
And not.
Preferably not for as long as now.
I'm glad you've missed it.
I am pleasantly surprised, I thought we were in for chaos.
So am I.
Yes, chaos awaits you next time, if we can just be ourselves.
I had a really nice time. Thank you kids.
Thanks to you guys.