Captain Hurme had been sailing the seas with his pirate crew for who knows how long, but he had never been caught in a storm like this before.
The ship was tossing and turning in the sea so violently that the captain was afraid it would sink at any moment.
It's too late to count now, Lifeboat Captain Hurme thought to himself as he slammed against the helm.
I know no better way to die, he cried, than to sink into the waves of the sea of my beloved enemy.
I don't care about myself, but I wish I could save the princess I kidnapped from the royal train.
I don't care about chests full of duploons, jewels and the finest silk in the world.
Either princess would survive this terrible storm.
Is that a good book?
Terribly good.
The storm doesn't seem to be abating at all.
It wouldn't be nice to be alone in this weather. You feel safe in the Moomin house.
Oh, what was that?
Just as if a branch had broken.
Moomin, would you read the story out loud?
Can I pick up where I left off?
Then tell us in your own words what has happened so far that we are missing something important.
Just say the most important things.
A brave pirate.
Oh, how wonderful it is when someone reads out loud.
Just keep going.
Captain Hurmerros and his crew have robbed the royal galley.
They took with them gold and jewels and also the ever-living princess.
It's an exciting story.
It is.
The storm at night grew so fierce that the sinking of the ship seemed almost inevitable at first.
Pretty well made.
The captain noticed that the princess had passed out.
He was alone and scared below deck, with only a roper for company.
The howl of the storm was unbearable.
The ship launched at the start.
All the captain could think about was the princess's…
Mamma, would you make some tea?
Would you like me to bring a cup to the study?
I quit today.
Children will surely like it too.
Reading makes you thirsty.
You read very fluently.
An exciting book.
Could I have a glass of raspberry juice?
When is Niisku coming home?
He didn't say, but I think he will soon.
It's good that Miss Niisku came to us while she's traveling.
Or what, father?
Necessarily.
It wouldn't be nice to be alone on a Stormy night like this.
Not so.
It seems to be sinking.
It won't last much longer.
The crew must be secured.
We can't get the boat out in this weather.
Are there any survivors?
No one has been seen yet.
Have you raked the beach?
Can you see anyone there?
Well, at least we haven't heard that.
Please keep me posted.
Listen, Niisku.
what did you say
The mast of the ship seems to be flying the main flag.
I'm pretty sure I also heard the bang of the hammer.
Are you kidding me?
I'm not kidding.
I can't see anything.
You can't see any headshots from this far.
You look at this.
Or, are you far away?
I can't see anything.
You can't see any headshots from this far.
You look at this.
Oh, do you have a telescope?
You should have said earlier.
Hey, look.
Now it seems to sink.
Do you see anyone?
Do you see anything?
What's going on?
It's not true.
It sank there.
Pirate ships seem to be quite rare these days.
Even the few ones are certainly terribly old.
Now, if it was a pirate ship, at least that's what it looked like.
But nothing happened to Rana.
Nothing at all.
It's funny that I read that pirate book just yesterday.
Books and reality must be far from each other.
In Perja, the life of pirates seemed pretty bleak.
Really?
It would be cool to be a pirate.
Are you serious?
Yes I am.
I would sail all seas and search for treasures.
But the treasures have been stolen from others.
Well, that seems to be the case.
But I wouldn't steal.
Then you'd be just a sailor.
And you're not a pirate?
Do you know where Moomin might be?
Probably a daring week in its tent.
Really?
Miss Niisku, here is a letter for you.
It seems to be from Niisku.
Please.
Thanks.
I want to read the letter right away.
I can do that.
What is it?
Niisku writes that he will come home already today.
That's nice.
But Moomin mom, we don't have a crumb of food.
Don't worry.
I'll put up a diary and Niisku can tell about his journey.
Papa would definitely like to hear about it.
Thanks mom.
There is a lot of food for humidity.
I guess he got the parts faster than he thought.
Ha, good news.
So the aircraft will surely be ready soon.
So, I guess.
Niisku should build a pirate ship.
I could become the tailgate and then we would fly.
We would be unreachable.
It doesn't show.
Where the hell have they gone?
There's no one here either.
Moomin-Pekko is definitely looking for an adventure.
They must be exploring the shore.
Everything seems fine.
Let's go to the beach of the cottage. You can find treasures there.
What now?
I heard some sounds.
Whence?
From the inside.
Weird.
It doesn't have to be, Niisku.
Oh yes, Niisku. Of course.
Hey Niisku.
Niisku, are you here?
Wet girl!
You don't want to...
Was it really a pirate ship?
Oh yes. And we caught the pirates when they swam ashore.
Did you catch every bandit?
We don't know how many of them there really were in the beginning.
It would certainly be wiser to lock yourself in the Moomin house just to be safe.
Oh dear. And I should also look after the greenhouse.
We're hoisting the sails here too, little fool!
You'll let Miss Niisku go or you'll regret that hairy bully!
No way!
I need a hostage to get out of here!
Well, then you're just yourself!
What?
Do you think so? Stay put, stay ahead of me, bite!
Don't come here!
You can't hurt him!
He's a hostage, you know!
With his help, I can get out of these corners with my skin intact!
You better take me prisoner! It's easier to carry me!
You could be fed a fish and no one would care!
I'd be interested in its kitty litter mouth!
Well, that's how it starts!
But stop that babbling! what is your name
Little Sell!
I am captain Hudikka!
Go and fetch the officials of this village villain!
And don't test my patience!
I'll go if you promise that Miss Niisku is safe!
Well of course it is!
If you hurt him even a little, my revenge will be terrible!
Well, it's gone!
Wet girl
Captain Hudikka! You have been tuned!
I will release Miss Niisku immediately!
can you hear
That I would let him in there with you? I will never.
I guess I'll keep him to myself. If I get a new ship, you get her.
What do you think about it, mackerel?
Listen for a moment. Your entire crew is behind bars.
All men?
You are the last one. I'm getting into the swamp.
Thanks. I was afraid my crew was gone.
What are you thanking? They are behind bars.
Some people think they belong there, but I don't think so.
Set him free and get me a ship.
It must have two masts and fifty cannons.
No tricks or my prisoner must suffer.
You can't get enough.
There was no talk of this at the police academy. What do we do now?
You must free the swamp lady.
He must be terribly scared.
I'm doing my best, but this is so weird.
I've never seen anything like it.
It's not Niiskunneid's fault that the pirate ship sank.
We know, we know. Oh good time.
Why did I become a police officer?
Hey, you hunsvot there.
Free the crew and get the two masts.
Listen now, Captain, times have changed.
There are no more cannons on sailing ships.
Cape echoes, how do you sink ships?
Are you trying to trick me?
Grandmama seems to have an old assault rifle.
I'm sure you'll get it, but I'm not sure if it'll work.
I warn you, its horns too.
This is my last warning, so be careful.
You have two hours to get the ship.
Set my crew free or you'll regret it.
Don't be afraid, I'm not going to hurt you.
I just have to threaten those over there.
Otherwise I'll feed my hostage, Haile!
Ugh!
I won't do you back.
Sure, right?
Get the two-masted one if there are 50 cannons.
He's not feeling well.
The choice is in your hands.
Bring it to the table.
He seems serious.
Oh, we have two hours then.
My goodness.
What are you talking about?
Hi, hi, hi, hi, hi, hi!
Hi, hi, hi, hi!
I have a suggestion.
Let's climb on the roof, drill a hole.
Let's drop something on the captain.
I've always thought you don't care.
Now it has been proven.
Sorry, Chief.
What if there is a squirming hall, then they have to get out of there.
Quietly! And you can't do better.
Doesn't help. I have to calm down now. Well, take it easy.
Captain Hodikka! Can you hear me?
Did you miss the ship so quickly?
There is no other first sailing ship in Milaakso.
A smaller yacht might do,
but I don't know if I can borrow it for this emergency.
I need a boat to live on the coast of Spain.
Calm down good man, calm down and listen.
You haven't done anything criminal here,
so if you miss that ship, we'll let you all go.
You can go wherever you want. Although on foot, but still.
Fresh air, sun, no sailing and no storms. Think about it.
We are sea scum and not vagabonds.
The Tramp's life is not funnier at all.
Behind the lonely mountains there are certainly many wealthy travelers.
There you can find gold, precious stones and...
I want a basket of the best rum, too, you fools.
Vai tollot?
Yes, planks, pines. I'm Captain Hudikka.
Now I'm getting angry.
If you were on my ship, you'd be on the hook for the money. Did you hear?
The boss loses his cool. Let's go calm down.
To whom, too. In my prison, you don't need to wait for butter on your bread.
Calm down, chief, good. Now is the best time to flaunt.
Take it easy now.
The only side dish on the bread would be mold.
The dead hour has already passed.
I warn you that you only have an hour until you can say goodbye to this child.
It's okay, little lady. I can spend.
It's okay, little lady. Hold on just a moment. We will save you.
Water, water!
What are you mumbling?
Can I have some water? Terribly thirsty.
Hello macaroni! My hostage needs a drink!
All right, bitch. I'll bring you a drink.
I can go.
Too dangerous. We take care of everything.
Just a moment. I have one suggestion that might work.
Snuffbox.
However, you should be able to handle it all on your own. Think you dare?
Of course.
What's taking so long there? You will have to wait too.
No problem. I don't mind the wait.
It's true, I'm thirsty too. Throat dries up when yelling at the police.
But don't worry, they will come soon.
Now bring that drink and fast!
Here it is, Captain.
Then don't try any tricks!
I'm not trying. I came all alone.
Are you for me too?
Yes, Captain.
Stop, and put the tray on the floor.
The bigger Mug is for the captain and the smaller one for the Niiskunneids.
Go further.
Hold on, wait there.
It's red.
Well, it's strawberry juice. It's really good.
He gets to drink from the bigger mug and I drink the other one.
There is not enough drink in the smaller mug for you.
There's no strawberry juice for a fancy drink, so I'll take that other one.
I'll take this.
No, no, swamp lady. Don't drink it.
Why not? I guess it hasn't been poisoned.
Or poisoned? Crazy idea. No, no.
Or maybe a sleeping pill.
I thought so. I even tried two different drinks.
Run it! No, good sir. I'm not thirsty at all.
What is it? You say the drink isn't poisoned.
Juas he! I-peikk!
Or do you have a romance brewing?
A fool's errand if you ask me. One of you will drink this and drink it cool.
I drink, I drink. Give the Mug here.
Don't moan, Goblin. What if you get poisoned from it?
There's nothing dangerous about it. Don't worry at all.
They se!
Let go. Hooray, hooray!
To the last drop.
Fortunately, there was no poison in it.
Fortunately, no.
And no sleeping pills either.
Not in my case, not even that.
Moomin Goblin! Moomin Goblin!
Calm down now. Your fearful friend sleeps for a while and then wakes up.
Thought he was tricking me. Captain Hutikka, all that.
I'm very thirsty.
Good.
I'm sorry, can we get you another mug.
Let's ask without sleeping pills this time. They will surely be surprised when I don't sleep.
Awake and eyes wide open.
Let's surprise them.
Moomin Goblin!
No problem. Everything is fine.
No, not here.
There is nothing dangerous about this drink.
Oh Moomin, you...
I was pretending. Was I convincing?
Oh you!
Captain Hutikka won't wake up all day now, and not the next.
And when he woke up his head ached excruciatingly. And that's fine.
The police chief let the pirates free before long.
You can't pirates in Moominvalley, especially without a ship.