Muu-mi-pappa, you're looking here!
Ugh, my breath has turned completely white.
Haa!
Hey, little myi, you didn't even go out to play with the others.
I don't! I find it boring to play in the sand every day.
Leave like that and great!
Do not follow, great great great great great great great great great great great great great great great great great great great!
I'm fine with that!
I play in the sand every day.
So would you go for a walk with me?
I could do some physical fitness.
Huh! Or for a walk?
Excited! Excited!
Come on, body papa!
Do we collect berries and colorful leaves?
It fits.
I know a place where you can find a lot of them!
Hello! The Terho collection competition will be held.
And if I happen to win...
So what then?
You carry me on your backpack.
Excellent! And if I win, you get to carry me on your backpack.
You know it's impossible!
It seems so!
Hello! Hello! Hello!
Work hard!
Joo!
Come on!
The trick is always so impossible!
Luckily you're not!
Have a good day, Mrs. Viljonka!
Good day!
Artists!
Artists indeed!
Huh!
Does it grow wood?
Beautiful!
Although it doesn't look like wood.
Fence a lot!
Sell good!
It's just a draft.
Some sort of outline.
Mrs. Viljonkka paints the final speech on the canvas.
I feel like that wastes a lot of work!
Am I wasted?
You can see the trees anyway!
Little Neid doesn't seem to have even the most rudimentary sense of art.
Hey are you?
Why do you need art trees when there are real ones growing around?
Art is...
It elevates the culture and elevates it spiritually.
Let's talk!
My spirit is not exalted!
A glance is not enough even for you.
Excuse.
Sell, let's go collect berries.
You don't want to bother the bully lady.
He has worries anyway.
And poof!
Viljonkka knows nothing about art!
Calm down Sell.
Roll up your sleeves, kids!
Don't be lazy here.
Fresh-from-the-oven cookies.
Thanks, mom.
Mom, we built a great sandcastle out of sand today.
Oh, what fun.
I'd love to come see it.
Late.
Your turn has already called it out.
Oh yeah, that's a bummer.
Hey, listen!
Let's all start molding sand sculptures.
And then there will be an art exhibition.
An art exhibition at the swimming pool?
Absolutely.
The topic can be chosen freely when he is modeling with sand.
We will have fun if we all participate.
Kiwi, kiwi, kiwi!
What topic did I come up with?
I will make an ice sculpture.
I mold flowers.
Moominpapa!
So?
Oh, are you asking Viljonka to come to the exhibition?
Of course.
Yes, and the children of Viljonka too.
Yeah, a sand sculpture exhibition.
And it's open to all Moomins.
Then we can build a sandcastle on the beach.
Fun!
It is.
Mom, let's go.
I have to think.
We will discuss it with the children.
See you now.
Goodbye!
See you soon and everyone come to the exhibition.
Why not?
Now we can give those rossocks some sort of foretaste of real art.
We need to enlighten the less gifted mummies.
Children, tomorrow you can show others what art is.
I'm so excited that my stomach is churning.
I have invited you to the beach to make sand sculptures.
As a topic, you can choose anything that is Moomin.
What would I shape?
You can choose the method freely.
You can mold with your hands or use a shovel or some other tool.
Have fun. It's time until sunset.
Good! The lack of time should not surprise you.
Ladies and gentlemen, shall we begin?
Joo!
I look forward to seeing what happens.
Moomin papa!
Sell, what's wrong? Why aren't you busy with work already?
Well, I don't know what to mold.
And you yourself haven't started?
Yes, I still had time.
Dad, that's where the corn is coming from.
And childish, of course.
I want to understand.
Greetings, Mrs. Viljonkka.
Good day!
We are honored that the whole family is participating in the project.
Oh oh, the joy is all ours.
And besides, I thought...
Would it be appropriate for you to show us what real art is?
Myy.
It's a hilarious and terrible street.
Great, well, let's get started, please.
Everyone else has already started work.
Alright, we'll just dress appropriately first.
Children, put on your work jackets, now let's start.
Well, we are ready.
You look like professionals.
When you do something, you always have to try to do it seriously, that's how it is.
Oh, oh, oh.
Now listen carefully.
You have to mold your own original and unique sand sculpture.
Mom, what does a unique sand sculpture mean?
It means the same as unique.
What does a unique sand sculpture look like?
I have completely understood.
Don't ask stupid questions.
The point is that you are better than others.
Joo!
Do you understand?
I want to visit the castle.
So do I.
That will make a great plastic kappa.
Completely unfinished.
Part of the job.
I have understood.
Completely unfinished.
Can you tell what this is going to be?
Of course I can.
It's like scrambled egg pudding.
Wake up, Hemuli.
It's not an egg pudding, but look now.
Don't you see?
Sorry.
It's a chocolate cake.
Or what?
Not just a tiger cake.
And it doesn't look like a flying saucer either.
Let it be.
I was stupid for even asking.
No, not at all.
I'm stupid when I can't look.
Could it be a radio button?
Or a can with heather?
What will it become?
Well, Nipsu, tell me what you think my work looks like.
Now I know. It's a chocolate cake.
Doesn't it look like a top hat to you?
From a cylinder?
Nope.
Goodbye.
Say what you say. It's a top hat.
It's a handbag.
It is. What are you making, little girl?
It's still a secret.
Well then, let's wait.
Does this look like a flower?
A pinch!
You still haven't chosen a topic.
The problem is that nothing pops into my head.
What is that?
This is it, the heart of winter.
Do not.
This is going to be amazing.
When I look at other people's creations, I am sure that the children's work will be the best.
But they are my children.
What is it?
You would know that if you knew anything about art.
It's wet, of course.
Bogey? My child doesn't want a statue of that scoundrel.
I hope the morko didn't hear. It can be heard for miles.
Do you hear?
The bastard can come here.
King!
Your mother has no sense of humor.
Now you can do exactly what you want.
Yes, but our mother will get angry if we leave the statue unfinished.
Agrees.
Omaapa on asianne.
Uh, full thongs.
Now I know what sculpture I will make.
It's true.
Admit it.
Hey, look what you did.
Hi everyone, Would you like a cup of tea?
It tastes good.
I taste these. Help for the heat.
What Moomin mom?
What has happened to the sale?
For sale?
True.
There it is.
The size is already right.
So.
You've come up with a topic.
Quite an artificial topic.
Looks like there will be a big sculpture.
You guessed it, moron.
Did you say dirty?
Is that what you mean?
Why wet?
That you don't understand art?
I'm in a grumpy mood and you're not grumpy.
Get out of the way of my artistic inspiration.
Yes, but...
Begging now.
Even more.
Say, the thing is visible, hasta you too.
Mörkö scares me like a statue.
If it turns out to be as bad as it is in real life.
It's bad, Messy makes a mess.
The sale seems to be having fun.
Fun.
Tsvarom!
Suomess People Are
hurry to finish.
You have to get younger.
We have fun, but remember that you are real artists.
Art is not fun, art is pain.
Great art always requires great suffering.
Moomin Pekka.
What matter?
Do you want to see my sculpture?
what you
No.
It looks amazing.
It's great that you say that. I was afraid they don't really look like flowers.
Are they flowers?
So.
Yes, yes.
I have shown them my sculptures only to you.
Just like that.
I think the flowers are beautiful, what is in the Moomin laksa.
Yeah, probably.
Uh, again.
Alright, done.
Like such a big wet one that other people's eyes are reddened.
I'm not wet.
Oh, and the weather was so beautiful all day.
I think it will rain.
What do we do now, Moomin-Daddy?
Share, yes. Everyone seems to have their work ready.
Let's not stop here, shall we?
Then you have to choose the best work of art right away.
Ai.
Sure enough. After all, we don't know who is the best sand sculpture.
No, that's not exactly how I thought about it.
It's best to choose so that other people's Eros don't go to waste.
The purpose was to organize an exhibition and not a competition.
We just wanted to spend some leisurely time together.
Even then, the size and highly artistic contribution that my children have made has been completely unnecessary.
A screwdriver that we've all done what we can.
And I think the result is good, imagination has been used.
Don't now. My children's artistic tendencies have not gone unnoticed.
Let's clap for this.
Oh good unusual.
Tunnel, tunnel, tunnel.
Listen, kids.
Kids, stop now.
Your clothes will get wet and dirty, as will your hair.
Right here on the spot.
Yeah, we're going home now.
Goodbye.
Like that.
Oh poor. Of course, the rain has crumbled all the sculptures.
What about that? The tide would have broken them at the latest. We knew that.
If I had known that, I would have made my sculpture further from the shore, like the whale.
A pinch.
Better this way.
Oh.
I would have known that, I would have made my sculpture further away from the beach, like the sea.
A pinch.
Better this way.
Who would want to constantly look at sculptures on the beach?
They live in memories.
Moomin, tell me whose sand sculpture you thought was the best.
I don't know.
Sorry for being late.
Missing sales again?
Myy hurriedly went outside when he heard us saying that the rain would spoil the sand sculptures.
Yeah, myy took my tent.
Or like that?
Myy hurriedly went outside when he heard us saying that the rain would spoil the sand sculptures.
Yeah, myy took my tent.
Or like that?
If we had to choose the best sculpture, the little girl's creation might very well win.
Will I sell it or not?
I agree with Moominpapa. Myunkörkö felt very real, at least to me.
No kidding. And the poison looked as orphaned and unhappy as usual.
Sound!
Rare frequent lightning.
I'm a little scared.
What the hell was that?
What?
What's going on here?
Is everything okay with Myi?
Kummakajo.
Moomin, what are you up to?
Oh, oh, forest fire!
Snuffbox's tent is on fire!
No matter what!
I can't escape!
Is the poison out?
Poison!
Poison! It is!
are you ok
Has it happened to you?
Phooey.
Lightning struck and there was a hole in the tent.
Oh, how funny that it didn't happen to you.
Mummy Moomin!
Excellent!
I would have gone to hell, but the poison saved me!
What on earth? Poison?
Phooey. It's your sand sculpture.
No, but real poison! The right one!
So yes.
You were in fornication mode. How would poison have saved you?
I'm telling the truth, the truth, the truth, the truth!
It was real poison! It was! There was a problem!
You must have been dreaming.
It was real poison! It wasn't!
Damn whores! Moomin!
Aren't they just crazy? No way, now that was poison!
Don't sell wait!
Hey sell!
That's a Moomin! It wasn't poison!
It was poison! It was, it was, it was, it was!