Coming, coming! There's a Moomin house over there.
It had started raining that day in the early afternoon.
Everyone was sitting inside when Tuutikki came to the village.
Good evening, Moomin.
Hey, come in.
Mother, Tuutikki came.
Ninni, please come in.
Aren't you alone?
No, I have Ninni with me.
Nini?
Come in.
There's no one there.
Oh, he's there even if you can't see him.
Is there?
There is. Ninni is just very, very shy.
I leave the door open. Come in when you want.
Oh my, he's soaking wet.
Maybe it doesn't matter if it's invisible.
Get wet, fun.
What is everyone staring at?
You know that if someone is startled very often,
secondly, he can become completely invisible.
Isn't that right?
Yes, an Aunt has taken care of Ninni out of sheer duty.
Auntie doesn't like Ninni at all and is therefore absolutely terrible at this point.
Auntie doesn't Scream and doesn't get angry. You would understand that.
He's just chillingly ironic. It's terrible, absolutely terrible.
What does ironic mean?
Well, suppose you trip and land in the middle of the tea table.
What would your mother do?
He would ask, were you hurt?
And many would be upset, but this, Auntie would say,
you may think that's dancing, but don't dance in food anyway.
That's irony.
Ugh, disgusting.
Auntie was terribly ironic about the day
and so my Ninni polo began to gradually fade and fade,
until last Friday he suddenly disappeared completely from sight.
Terrible.
Aunt gave me Ninni,
because he can't take care of invisible relatives.
Well, what did you do to aunt? Did you muzzle him properly?
That kind of thing doesn't work at all on ironic people.
I took Ninni to me and now I brought her here so that you would make her visible again.
Very flattering, but...
Moomin mom if anyone can do it. And Moomin can play with him.
Tuutikki, is Ninni talking?
No, unfortunately, he doesn't speak.
Goodness.
So what could we play?
Of course, Ninni wins if we play hide and seek.
Auntie hung a tie around her neck. Do you hear where he moves?
Oops, the door opened.
It must be Ninni.
Get out of the rain already, Ninni.
The Moomin house is now your new home.
The Moomins are very benevolent.
This here is Moomin papa and this is Moomin mamma and this is...
Just like mom, sister, Nipsu and Moomin the Goblin.
We're just at the tea table. Will you have tea if you can drink now?
I'll bring you some juice.
I would like to see how the juice flows inside him. This way, Ninni.
That's all there is to it. Until then, unfortunately, I can't tell you about Ninni.
You'll make it somehow.
There will be no difficulties here.
Is this here, Ninni?
Well, I think I'll leave here too. There is one thing and another at home.
I'll try to drop in here from time to time to see how you guys are doing.
Let's do it like that.
What now?
It occurred to me that you had some extra residents here.
It was. It was dense and windy. They moved out last week.
Right, good.
Oops, you finished drinking. Will you take more?
I hope you like it.
Ninni, will you come up with me?
Tight is nice.
Here is your room.
I leave the juice on the bedside table so you can drink it whenever you want.
Oh, do you want to go to bed?
Just get under a warm blanket.
Ninni, if you get a strange feeling at night or loneliness starts to bother you.
You can come wake me up.
Come on, just ring my tight ear.
Beautiful dreams.
Is he sleeping?
Sleeping.
Could you find a cure for Ninni in your grandmother's notebook with foolproof home remedies?
Is there a cure for invisibility?
I don't remember directly, but we'll see.
I believe in the power of medicine.
I know that, honey.
Let's go to the invisibility medicine.
I don't remember directly, but we'll see.
I believe in the power of medicine.
Honey, I'll go find out.
I want to see Ninn.
That's it.
Evil eye, heavy mind, hanging tail.
Ha, that's it.
The recipe was written on the back of the envelope in shaky handwriting.
But yes it was right because it said so.
A cure if someone starts to get foggy and hard to see.
I hope the medicine worked.
Grandma's recipes are always delicious.
I tell you what. Is Ninni still sleeping?
Look, Ninn's shoes are visible.
Cotton daddy.
Sell tomorrow.
Has he gotten up yet?
No on, on.
Where is it? I guess he hasn't eaten yet.
I would assume he is in the dining room.
Oh my goodness.
Where is it?
Be quieter.
Ninni takes medicine.
Single sip Moomin for troll delight.
Like that.
The medicine should take effect in a couple of hours.
Ninn's shoes float in the air.
Yes, the shoes have appeared.
They look funny.
Those are beautiful legs.
It's unlikely that mummy's medicines will work quickly either.
You must look terrible when you prefer to go invisible.
Don't mind the small sale.
He always talks in that style.
You still can't see any food crawling inside him.
What are we going to do?
Flour.
Shall we go to the mushroom?
Boring, I can find a single one.
I will find.
Ninni, shall we go?
Settled.
Who collects the most mushrooms?
You must tell me which mushrooms are edible.
Let's tell.
Father, father.
Look, Ninn's shoes are already visible.
Moomin mamma's medicines are known for their effectiveness.
It can't be caused by the medicine.
I guess the medicine worked faster because of the absence of the body.
Or because aunt is far away.
Aunt is far away.
booked
Musi
I have to
Aunt is far away.
deb
Libra?
Ai!
Awesome! You have collected hard!
An awful lot of mushrooms!
I only have half that much.
How much do you have, Moomin?
Four times more than I have!
You've never collected so much.
There's something rotten here.
Oh, they were Ninn's mushrooms!
Eh, I guess so.
That terrible aunt never let Ninny go to the mushroom, so now she really has a cold!
Ninn probably had a permit at her aunt's place to only harvest.
Oh how awful, oh how awful!
Stink, what does he want?
Do I bite him?
Long time no see.
It would still be in between. Last time you dipped my swimming trunks in glue.
Hehehe, that was fun!
What is that basket swinging over there?
I don't mean to be rude, but I won't tell.
Jukra, what could you do while invisible.
Ninni, I'll take care of you. Let's go.
Come now, Ninni!
Hey, hey, hey! Is Ninni the real name?
Or a species name?
Stinker, stop now! You startle Ninn.
Is she a girl? Was it Ninni?
It's a fitting nickname.
Varo, Haisuli.
Well, from what, that's the question.
Don't tease Ninni or I'll get really mad.
Without shoes, he would make a great bank robber.
Don't imagine! The nipple becomes completely visible.
Yesterday, his legs started to show.
And at this very moment they disappear.
Thus!
Stink, it was your fault.
Tell Mummy Moomin and Papa Moomin that Ninni will make a great bank robber.
Ninni doesn't agree to that, and besides, we're going to make her visible throughout the pool.
He has also taken mom's magic potion.
Whose basket is this?
Mine and mine.
Oh unusual, really beautiful.
Our catch was small because Ninni collected all the mushrooms.
It's okay if there are few mushrooms, but when you can't eat these mushrooms.
This is a poison ivy, and this is a toadstool.
Watch out for these two mushrooms.
I guess this is Moomin the troll and Mipsu's mushrooms.
We didn't collect toadstools.
You guys have a little less, but this is panther toadstool, and what about this one?
Both have fly agaric.
Oops, but I don't see a single toadstool in Ninn's basket.
How has he collected so much on his own?
Ninni hoi, come out, where are you?
Moomin mama, it's called Ninni.
Ninni, I would call this a beautiful mushroom basket.
Hey, I saw Ninni's legs.
Great Ninni, you know, he gets to see your face too.
It only takes one joke, don't worry about the smelly mouth, he's just threatening.
Don't think about bad things, that's my life instruction.
And mine is to bite him that teases you.
If someone is such a good mushroom picker, I think they deserve to be fully featured, right?
Look, her skirt is visible.
Ninni, you're making progress.
Good luck, I can't wait to see you in full.
It will happen soon, but I don't think mouse gray is your color.
Tomorrow, sleep as long as you are sleepy.
Good night, Ninni.
Hey, mom's gone.
What the hell are you doing? Do you know what time it is?
How do you like this?
It's really pretty.
Nice to have someone in the house who wears clothes. How does it look on Ninn?
What is this?
Hair band.
Good morning, Papa Moomin.
Morning, you are early.
Where is Ninni?
Still sleeping.
You are up early.
How much tail is visible?
I am.
It is.
As containers.
I am.
I hope she noticed the Dress I had put up.
The dress looks just right.
Now you know where to talk.
So.
Yes.
can you take
Dress!
Don't live!
Don't start.
Dress!
That's what it looks like to me.
Yes, yes.
Thank you all for everything.
He can talk!
Although Ninn's face was not yet visible, it was a great relief to hear her speak.
It feels stupid to talk to someone who doesn't answer, and then it's easy to say something stupid.
Thanks for watching the video!