From the Mona attackers
During his long winter Moomin had a dream.
Oddly enough, he dreamed that he was sleeping.
Moomin! Moomin!
Alisa!
Alisa, you have learned to fly on a broomstick!
Yep, I'm a fully flying witch now!
Hey, take me for a ride!
No way!
Don't be boring!
I already have a passenger!
I!
Myy!
Alisa, can't we go higher?
Joo!
Come back! I want to fly too!
Can I fly now?
Hop in!
Hey!
Just like a dream.
Still true.
Ugh! Alice! No, no bouncing!
What are you talking about? The road is flat!
Sell, is that you? No wonder the broom shakes.
I'm pretty clever, aren't I?
Hey, where did you get the broom?
Well, I borrowed the witches.
Did you borrow?
Well, I borrowed the witches!
And don't ask for permission now!
No, there's a witch over there.
So it seems.
We better fade away.
True.
Stand two. Give me back my bone.
No luck!
Yeah, I did.
You have another broom. What can you fly with?
This is just a parabone.
This is my real bone.
This broom is now mine!
Or a broom? Phew! It's not a bone.
Take a closer look.
Isn't this a bone?
Snake!
Myy!
Moomin!
Sell, are you safe?
Myy is not here.
Right?
I dreamed.
You scream out loud.
Oh, sorry. Did I wake you up?
Can you see anything?
Just snow.
It's so bright.
To kill you.
Creepy light.
It is.
Spring hasn't come yet.
No.
Then everyone sleeps.
At least most of them.
Is my brother still watching?
Of course.
He said he would have the blue copies ready by spring.
But is it possible to succeed?
Shall we go see?
Let's jump out and get in the middle.
Well, not anyway.
It's warm and wonderful at Peitana.
Oh, let's sleep until spring like all decent people.
Spring is still far away.
Oh yeah
Well, let's sleep then.
Niiskunnuni, Did you say something?
Oh, I'm really hungry.
Moominmamma, vaapukka juice tastes good.
So.
Everyone praised it last winter.
Moomin troll.
What?
I have a feeling that someone is watching us.
Are there people here besides Moominpa and Moominamma?
Of course it is.
What?
Cry?
Where?
Tuutikki lives in the bathroom and does not hibernate.
I heard from him last winter that there are many little creatures that are too shy to show themselves.
Are there any here?
I guess, even though we can't see them.
Behind the counter, for example, and in the clock, in the oven, and in the dark corners of the room, I sensed it.
Have you messed with the oven?
I don't. They would have been nervous. You shouldn't even know.
What do they look like?
Tuutikki said that some of them look a bit like us, like our ancestors.
Like us?
Well, I haven't seen them.
Are they as pretty as us?
I Tainan will watch and wait for the dawn.
I do the same.
Moomin Peiki
Now you have to be as quiet as a mouse so that Moomin's ancestor doesn't get scared.
Has it dawned yet? Are you ready?
Well I am.
The sky is cloudy, but the owl is hidden.
Maybe it doesn't come up at all this time of year.
Moomin, I miss this.
What do you need a broom for?
I'll borrow it, I won't stay long.
What are you whining about? You already know how to fly with a broom, don't you?
I'm leaving now, you can't do anything.
Put the broom here and be tidy.
How many times do I have to say you can't go to Moomin Valley?
It's boring here, I want company.
Fly broom, fly.
I'm taking me to Moomin Valley.
Hop, hop, hop.
Fly obey me fly now.
Hard-eared girl.
I'm flying.
Oh, brothers, how wonderful.
Must not.
What do you say now? Are you still complaining that it's boring?
And for a change like this.
How do you feel?
No, Grandma, stop the broom.
Come on, you wanted to fly on a broom.
First solo flight.
Grandma, please, don't stop the broom.
If you want to learn how to fly a broom,
forget about ketaled and focus on studying.
It's hard work you know.
What, are you mocking me too?
I can climb down.
You can stand, and even if you fall, there is soft snow below.
Don't move your ladder, grandma, I'm scaring you.
So, to the elevators, and don't blink down.
Was it worth going out now?
Now we could not have continued our sleep.
It went great.
Snow is like cold fine sugar.
So I'm standing on top of the stairwell?
You stand, everything is under the snow.
Why is the liter door open?
What now?
The trees have dwindled.
Someone else is burning our trees.
But who and why?
I sensed that we were not alone in the forest.
There are winter animals here.
It's something else.
Bogey!
It grows huge in winter.
Granny, I'm scared.
Don't worry.
Goofy, stop it.
Don't come any closer.
You're too cool for us.
You can chill us to icicles.
Oh my goodness, you don't feel lonely at all.
I don't think we can help you.
At least without fur and earflaps.
Come on, little lady.
Who has brought this big firewood, look?
It knows something bad.
There has been more than one.
Hoop!
Pure whiteness for the naked eye.
Peeking into the bathroom?
Tuttik!
There's nobody here.
Right?
Ah, see for yourself.
Shouldn't there be some invisible heads here?
It's hard to know about things you can't see.
What is it?
Like something was holding my back.
So, of course. It's one of the heads.
Mummy, peikk, yes!
Where has it gone?
Hi, unusual. I've never seen anything like it.
Bye bye, Moomin, Goblin.
Did you guess where Tuutikki is?
Hello, Tuttiki!
Hello, Tuutikki!
This winter, Niiskunneitiki is behind.
I woke him up by accident.
You know that spring is still far away.
Yeh, the sun doesn't even want to rise.
But tomorrow the sun will come back.
Will you come?
Niiskuneitti was worried when the sun remained hidden.
However, the sun sets almost immediately.
Tuutikki, Moomin there must have been bandits in the valley.
Don't now.
A large pile of firewood has appeared on the rock.
Share, that's right. I do know.
Among them are our trees.
Yes, unfortunately nothing can be done about it.
The critters of winter are pretty indifferent when it comes to ownership.
They need a lot of fuel for the midwinter bonfire.
Midwinter bonfire?
Now your trees can also participate in this celebration.
Bonfires are lit to attract the sun back.
Well, isn't the sun coming back anyway?
You don't know that. The bonfire is always lit on the same day.
At night you will see winter animals.
If you live in the bathroom, would you let?
If you sit still and I don't scare them away.
Good, you come along.
Well, of course I will.
Wait, you can't.
Did someone scream?
Who is that?
Don't come any closer, I didn't do it on purpose.
Get us out or grandma will turn you into a toad.
I already apologized to you, don't stay angry for too long.
I'm cold, please go away.
Stupid, stop, you can't.
Dude, leave Alisa alone.
Grandma, troll.
Alisa.
Goofy, Alisa is my friend, be nice to her.
It just stood there drooling while I skied down the hill.
I managed to dodge so that I didn't even touch it.
It's okay, Alisa.
Listen now, Mörkö.
Isn't Alisa a pretty girl?
Well, Morkö.
I must have used a slur, but I apologized nicely.
What's wrong with that?
Then I asked if it had seen you and it got the hepuli.
It's mysterious.
Dude, what the hell is wrong with you?
A grunt.
Oh yes, I freaked out.
It's nice that you came to visit.
I had a hunch somehow that the old man was still awake.
And so I came.
Well, what did your grandma say?
Nothing, because I didn't say I was coming here.
Granny Goblin was brave when she chased away the bully.
The bully usually doesn't attack anyone.
Maybe Mörkö doesn't like Alisa.
Just like Eiti.
What did Mörö have to do with being here anyway?
Mörkö wanted to see granny troll.
And why?
Because it's in love with granny troll.
May I be protected.
Hey, what now?
If Mörkö is really in love with grandma.
Don't bother.
This is going too far.
I just that it's not like that.
It's true.
What's that drumming?
The invisible heads are calling.
When will the animals come?
They are already here, all around us.
Oh, are they? Where, where?
Oh yeah, you can't see them.
I don't see any critters either, but I feel they are here.
Oh, are they? Where, where?
Oh yeah, you can't see them.
I don't see any critters either, but I feel they are here.
Yeah, but you Alisa are a witch.
Yes, you and the goblin will soon find out.
Wake up!
Oops! Now I see one of them over there.
Now I see too. Are there a lot of them?
Did you find out where the little heads stay?
You never see them.
So how do you know that they are the ones that are making the drums?
Kasku, they sometimes get dirty in the bathroom too.
How great, Juhla?
I would have missed this.
What happened now?
Bogey.
What is Mörkö doing here?
It has come to see Granny again.
No, it wants to warm itself in the blaze of flames.
Hi hey!
Mörkö ruined the party.
Oh my, our Mörkö parka.
No matter where it lands its icy backside, there remains a stupid smudge.
Well, Mörkö, saved our firewood a bit.
Oh!
So I didn't use your hands.
I really want to sleep.
I thought I'd stay awake until the next sunrise, but I guess I can't stay awake until then.
See you again next spring.
Bye bye, and take care.
Yay yay, the moon lights up my journey home.
The blocking of Kuuvie and Alisa must be stopped.
I have to take real action.
Let's get real!
What did the witch mean?
It sounded very threatening.
Let's hope that the witch will let the Moomins sleep until spring.