Heavy storm.
I can't sleep.
Hats.
Tomorrow we should go sailing.
But there is a high wave in the sea now.
We can hardly leave.
The day is shining.
I don't believe it.
You wouldn't believe that it stormed violently yesterday.
Not so.
Good morning.
After all, you woke up from such a nightmare.
I barely slept last night because of the fierce wind.
But look at the weather now.
The storm brought us clear skies.
The seed begins to refresh the sea air.
They always say that a storm cleans the air.
Good morning.
Hey listen, why don't you go to the beach already?
Has the sea calmed down?
Can we sail?
Certainly, now look at the calm and the beautiful.
There may not be enough fire.
And you can probably find fun things on the beach.
Yes, I saw beautiful shoes, for example.
Granny, let's go already.
Well, yeah, that's fine.
Coconut.
Show.
The nut is mine because I found it.
You know how to be childish.
When will you grow up?
There is sweet milk inside the coconut.
It's just salt water.
Lovely sweet milk that takes the tongue out of the mouth.
There was Rappu in the coconut.
Good day, Rappu Nanen.
I hear a whisper that comes from the far ocean.
Oh gosh, someone cried.
True, it is crying.
Johan is a freak.
There must be something inside the shell.
Whenever I look.
Let's investigate.
Ah, I see nothing at all.
It's really strange.
I can't see anything at all.
That's where the crying is.
Let me have a look.
It's not in Simpuka.
Hi, selling.
what are you crying
Hey, get out of the water already.
why are you crying
Hey, it's a mermaid.
We have to catch him.
I guess you can't do that.
Come on, now.
Momipeko is waiting.
Don't leave me.
Hey, slow down.
Don't cry.
We know how to help you.
I haven't seen you here before.
I had to get rid of the others when we hurried to the southern sea.
Now I'm all alone.
Have you hurt yourself?
The storm surprised me when I was looking for companions.
The wave brought me here.
That night storm.
Go applies.
It sure hurts.
We have to do something.
You agree.
Moomin mamma's liniment helps us when we have a pee.
But I'm not sure it works on mermaids.
Yes, it should be waterproof.
The only medicine that heals our wounds is tears.
Do you have tears?
Oh tears? Just ordinary?
No, no. I'm a salmon snake.
Oh what did you say?
Something about salmon roe, I guess?
So.
what did you say
Something about salmon roe, I guess?
A salmon snake's tear?
I don't think Moomin lives in the valleys with salmon snakes.
All right. We do what we can.
Stay here and wait.
Oh Moomin-Pekka, you are always so kind.
Now you stick to it like a stick. And don't go swimming.
The tears of the salmon snake are probably oil spillage.
But we will do our best.
Yeah, that's right.
I love the storm.
But why does it always break something?
Healthy muuta.
Joo.
Mom and Dad, we need help.
Good time, now what?
There is a wounded mermaid on the beach.
We have to go help.
Well, it's a miracle.
The sea is a beast. Only swim when the sea is in a good mood.
You sound like a bitch.
And ugh, be careful what you say.
Imagine, a mermaid can only be cured by the tears of a salmon snake.
Do dragons live around here?
Or do you need a salmon snake tear?
Do you know where we can find a salmon snake?
Joo.
I've seen one in a museum.
Probably in some bone collection.
At least it doesn't bring tears.
You are right.
Let me think.
Salmon finger.
Oh yeah, you're not sure.
Do you know a salmon snake?
Great.
I'm not sure he qualifies as a salmon snake.
What is he?
Well, I guess he's some kind of Lizard.
We became friends many years ago.
I too have heard stories about Edvard the salmon snake.
Dad listen, Do you think Edvard can save the mermaid?
And heal his wounds.
If he counts as a salmon snake?
Listen to me, I think you should at least try.
I agree, we have to try our best.
But I have no idea where it is.
It's been a long time, but someone said they saw Edvard at the lake at the foot of the lonely mountains.
It's in those landscapes.
I guess he's not there anymore.
Hey, let's go!
Joo!
I hope Edvard hasn't gone anywhere.
I hope so too.
I haven't seen him in a long time.
Hey!
That's the lake now.
Beautiful, wonderful scenery.
Hey, it's not a pleasure trip.
Let's find Edvard as quickly as possible.
Myy is right.
Let's disperse.
Nipsu and Myy search the lake.
Moomin and the squishy lady are going with me.
All right. Myy and Nipsu will see each other later.
Be careful that Edvard doesn't deposit.
Very quiet.
Edvard hides in the lake bed.
We have to call him out.
Get it done.
No, where exactly are you pushing me?
Stop it!
It hurts me!
Sell! What exactly are you trying to do?
Don't be afraid!
Now!
Help!
Help me!
You are the bait.
I bark out Edvard.
Let me go.
Right away! Help!
There's something there.
I don't want to be eaten.
Oops. Yes, it's quick power.
Ah!
It was just a catfish.
How come?
It almost swallowed me.
There is pressure in the grass.
I guess not that.
It looks like a footprint.
Hi sell and nip!
Has Edvard been found?
Help! Don't leave me!
A huge footprint.
What? Where?
Is there a footprint here?
That's how it seems.
It's a big salmon snake.
The tracks lead there.
Dad, let's go follow the tracks.
Maybe we'll find Edvard.
Clear!
This is where the footprints disappear.
It means...
The waterfall is so big that Edvard can take a shower under it.
Look, there's a cave over there.
Let's go there.
The cave looks deep.
Doesn't seem like fun.
Help!
What was your roar?
The sound must have come from the cave.
So it happened. Let's push in.
I am ghosts in my senses.
I'm afraid.
Let's turn.
Don't slip!
It was just a tiny drop of water.
Just like that, go ahead.
Try to hold on.
Moomin comes soon and brings the salmon snake to the tear.
Can't help but hope they find Edvard.
They will surely find it when papa is with you.
Where could Edvard be?
Let's try.
Edward, Hitaka.
Edvard, hi.
There's a Moominpapa here.
Do you still remember me?
Edvard!
Huh, it's tiring.
I'll wait here.
I'm looking for happiness at work.
Dullard. You do what you want.
So do I.
I'm hungry.
What sound is that?
You're going to have to.
As if the sound was coming from here.
Help!
It stares.
It eats up minutes.
No, I don't taste good at all.
Wow!
Dude, what happened?
Oh, Edvard.
We were right.
Oh, that's it, Edvard.
Oh, and nothing small.
Hey, look. Tear, tear.
Ack, ack sound as it falls.
Falling.
Did, did, did, did, did, did.
I got it.
Also, try to help me somehow now.
You swallow a tear.
Tolo, what did you do?
How can you be so stupid?
Give back the tear.
Edvard, hello, do you remember me?
It must have been years since we met.
Dad seems to remember you.
Oh, Kind Salmon Finger.
We need one tear from you.
Sorry to trouble you.
We ask for your help.
Cry one tear into this stable.
And if you don't cry, I will.
Don't scare him.
When we explain why tears are needed,
he does understand.
Really?
Well then try to explain.
We need a tear from you,
that we can heal the wounded mermaid.
He can't swim at all
and suffered terrible pains.
Of course we want to save him.
Do you know a mermaid?
Please think of something sad.
What are you going to do?
What's wrong with you?
Hijalappas, I'm unkind!
Dad, what does he mean?
I think he's saying
jump on the horses.
Oh yeah, it's good!
I'll come too.
And me?
Nepsu, please, I'm not coming.
I'm walking home.
No, he won't eat me!
Father Edward understood us.
He clearly wants to save the mermaid.
Yes, he is very kind.
Yes, you will get well.
Help is already near.
Try to last.
Hebs is falling!
Edward is here!
We found him!
Moomin came!
Oh, where exactly are you?
Here in the upper air!
Here, here!
Hello, you're Edward.
Please save your mermaid tears.
He's getting weak already, hurry up.
Edward, honey, please.
A tear from Pira.
Teardrop!
Not trying to hurry now.
Don't be rude to him.
It is not easy to cry on command.
Could he help with the onion?
I have my own ways.
I'll try the frying pan.
Oh mermaid.
I can take a little longer.
You will get better.
Don't give up.
Fight for your life.
Don't give up!
You are saved!
Try to get fit!
Look at Edward.
Edward cries.
The tears don't seem to help.
Edward is not a real salmon snake then.
Edward succeeded.
The sailors became healthy.
Humdinger.
Edward did a good job.
You were kind.
We thank you.
We are all very grateful to you.
Thank you, Edward.
Thank you all
Thanks again. Goodbye.
Now you can swim in the southern sea.
Take care of yourself.
I am so happy.
A big octopus!
Mermaid! Keep your money!
Good!
Help! Help!
Thank you, Edward. Cars already for the second time.
Good luck to both of you.
Edward has become very caring.
He is a gallant cavalier.
It is, it is. Absolutely.
Like they probably were.
Edward, take the mermaid home safely.
Goodbye, mermaid.
Good!
Thanks.