One summer day Moominpa got a bad cold.
Papa, I brought you hot milk. how are you now
Poorly.
At least the fever is gone.
If the onion milk is as long as it is hot.
I'll try.
Listen mom, I've been thinking about it all pretty much.
I see. What have you been thinking about?
If I wasn't alive, you and Moomin wouldn't know a damn thing about the wild adventures of my youth.
Oh, I thought you were just talking about them in your memoirs.
No, no, they only start from the moment I met you. I alone know about the earlier stages.
Why didn't you start with the first steps of your life, the way memoirs are usually started?
Although it's nice to start with me.
I had my weaknesses, my youth was apparently stormy.
Ipsu will open, I have news.
Hello to me.
Huumi pappa is dead in his tracks.
If you come right away, you'll get a fairy-tale wide from him. In a hurry.
Alright please.
Muaska muikkent.
Hello my, how is Moomin papa?
Just fine.
Nice to hear.
Yeah, but he's mad at you for not coming to see him.
Do not.
You must come right now.
The little salesman said that you will give me a fairy-tale gift.
And that you're mad at me.
Sell, I just told you to ask them here.
I made sure they came too.
You know Papa Moomin, when he gets sick, he takes it so seriously.
Well, now he wants to tell you about his youth.
Cool stuff, I've always been interested in that.
As a child, I looked just like Moomin the troll.
And strangely enough, I had friends who resembled snuff and snuff.
Did you meet anyone who looks like me?
I met
A beauty without bangs.
One stormy and disconsolate August night.
A package made of an old paper bag was left on the steps of the Löytö children's home.
We even dare to throw trash on our steps.
The cart was noticed by the director of the children's home, who looked a lot like Vili jonkka.
Oh, abandoned child.
It was me, you.
Were you rejected?
Oh, oh, this is going to be difficult for a child.
I don't want to be number 13.
There are 12 finders before you. I don't like number 13 myself.
Hey, you've wet your bed.
I dreamed that I was sitting on a potty.
You are twice as hard as others.
I think it's unfair that exactly that dream was completely true when I left.
Life is unfair.
Well, when you greet me, you hold him here at a 45 degree angle.
Did you understand?
That's a 90 degree angle.
Doesn't Tadd think it should be?
Must not. For the reason that I have decided that the angle should be 45 degrees.
The head of the foundlings' home didn't tolerate being bullied against him.
After a few years, you won't get a degree angle.
Heaven, that's me.
Unbelievable. I have seeds, canes, ears.
I'm nice and round.
I have other things with me.
I have everything with me.
Nice upright ears.
I'm nice and round. No disgusting corners or lumps at all.
I look really cute in every way.
Only my slightly short legs break the perfection.
But they grow if I walk and run a lot.
Oh!
So I was lashed to my first skirmish and to the maple of death.
I was saved.
And that's when I made my decision.
I'm not going to live a safe, stagnant life. I create my own happiness.
The best, Auntie. Big tasks await me.
Life is short. I'm leaving. Don't mourn.
Postscript. I took a can of pumpkin jam with me. Munipeikko.
Maybe I should have left during the day.
If I close my eyes, I have nothing to fear.
I should have left for the day.
Hey!
Ouch!
Amu!
Who made that watermill? It's beautiful.
I have done it.
Ai!
Hey!
Big tasks.
I have done.
Hey!
I'm taking an important exam.
Oh, try?
So, I studied how the new ship's propeller spins.
Oh, the propeller! Do you have just the right ship?
Yes, I just finished it. It is being painted now and next it will be ceremonially launched.
Oh, that sounds amazing.
Well, do you want to see the ship?
Sure, I'd love to, where is it?
This way.
Oh yeah, I'm Fredrickson, what about you?
Moomi.
That's the name I was called before Moomin came into the world.
That's it.
Tremendous. It sure is fun to build your own ship.
It is, it is. You have to stay and watch the landing.
Oh, with joy. Stay as long as you want.
That's what I like.
So has Hosuli faded away?
I asked him to paint the ship.
Was it to make him lazy?
Hi Hosuli!
I'm here, Fredrickson.
I was looking for red paint.
My new friend Moomipeikko participates in the descent into the water.
Please paint faster.
This here is Hosuli.
How do you do.
Hey, same words. Don't worry, I'll paint as fast as I can.
Hosuli didn't look exactly like Nipsu, but otherwise resembled him.
This is the command bridge. The ship is steered from here.
There's someone there.
Ahaa, himself on Juxu.
And you didn't notice that the door said no entry?
I don't believe in bans.
He was just like you, Nuuska Muikkunen. Quite obvious.
What is the name of the ship?
Meren huiske.
So does it wheeze when it sails?
Of course not. The name tries to be poetic.
I first thought of Siiri or Helena, but this seemed better.
How the hell did you manage to get the ship moved to the river?
The monstrosity, we haven't thought of that. What do we do?
I'll just paint now, I'll know soon enough.
Did you come up with a solution, Fredrickson?
I'm asking Drontti Edward for help.
Drontti is apparently taking a nap further down the river.
It's so big you can't help but notice it.
Is Drontti dangerous?
Not at all, but I'm careful not to accidentally step on you.
Fredrickson are you serious?
I am, I am. Drontti always pays the funeral expenses.
Hey, Edward, can you hear me? Fredrickson is here. are you there
Aha, there it is.
I would like to ask a favor, okay?
Couldn't you bathe in the river today, just for a change?
The water in the river is sweetly warm and the bottom is fine fine sand.
Now it stood up.
Let's start the waterlily ceremonies.
Let's hurry to the ship!
Anchors up, close hatches.
The water is rising, everyone in their places, watch out for the waves.
Start the machines!
Succeeded! The water bill was successful!
Drontti is staring at us, Fredrickson.
How do we get past the drone?
We were sailing on a collision course.
There's no way around this.
What can be seen behind the drone?
Real sea, ocean and exciting adventures, who knew.
Yeah, adventures.
It would be incredibly kind of you to let us sail past.
It doesn't cost you anything.
Wouldn't you like to move your little stern?
It's too late now.
Moomin, I think this could be classified as an adventure.
Hi! Hi! Hi!
Back! God!
That sounded like a hosul's voice.
What's on his mind now?
Hi! Stay in our jar, we'll get you.
Ilkimys, you launched, even though I was still painting.
Yeah, yeah!
Sorry, I'll throw the rope.
Wake up!
Hurrah! We got past the ront!
Hurrah!
Long live, sea spray!
Hooray!
Long live, sea spray! Hooray! Hooray!
No, who is it?
Bogey.
Who is that moron?
It will alarm someone.
What will it do if it catches on?
It's not doing anything, it's just lonely.
But if it manages to touch you, you will be left in a mess.
It's too late to go help now.
Hi! Moomin! What are you trying?
Don't ask fools, I'm going to save the drowning.
Don't get stuck now if you go too close to the swamp.
I can't watch edited.
Besides, this is an adventure.
Go away, don't come any closer.
When it's freezing, it's freezing.
I turn to ice. Help!
Hi, saving Moomin here.
Oh, I'm freezing. Help, help!
Hey, jump into the canning jar.
Wake up!
It was my third adventure.
And at the same time, the first time I saved someone's life.
It was wonderful! I want to become an adventurer too.
Who was that woman you saved?
And how did he do?
Well, that's another story.
I really like those other stories.
Who was that woman?
Director of the children's home.
Was it?
Yeah, he was obviously looking for me.
Yes, number 13.
Pass the horror. If I had known, I wouldn't have meant...
Well, what's done is done. You acted bravely.
No one asked for an opinion there.
Tell me, Moomin, who are these forest people?
They are my friends.
I take care of them and teach them a thing or two.
I just remembered I have work to do downstairs.
Me too.
Hey, stop! Don't go anywhere. Did you hear?
Discipline is everything.
Place yourself in order of the length of the queue right away.
I understand why papa skipped that episode too...
Too bad you didn't know aunt before you rushed to help.
Yes, but I would have saved him anyway in accordance with my heroic nature.
How was your childhood?
Of course not. Don't be sad, mom, or the orphanage phase was dark.
But the next period of my youth was exciting.
But I'll tell you about that and the headmistress of the children's home later.
Like all good story tellers, Moominpappa knew how to end his story at the right place.