Ugh, what a beauty to see through a magnifying glass.
What wonders of nature.
Oh, and so many kinds.
Hundreds of thousands of species.
Sorry, good morning.
Oh, morning!
This is a small road to a lonely mountain.
Take it straight ahead, so you can't get lost.
Thank you. May I ask what you researched so closely?
Flower.
A flower?
A glorious flower.
A flower? Oh my god, flower.
Moomin!
Wet girl!
Sorry, you won't have to wait for Moomin.
What a man. Have you ever seen flowers before?
At least he hasn't looked at them. I guess I was looking for something completely different.
What?
Jaa.
Hello to me who has found a new place for the garden.
Well, not yet.
A new garden?
Haven't I told you.
I'm not, but it looks like you are to mamma.
Yeah, my garden is way too small for the current mess.
Thank you, Mummy Moomin.
My wife and I have been thinking for the last few days.
Where could you find an area large enough for a new flower garden?
Well, there is no matter how much land is in the neighborhood.
But it should be near my house on the south slope by the water.
I see. Share, then it's more difficult.
What the hell is that man doing?
Hi there, Looking for something?
I investigated.
What?
Rock, find out how old it is, i.e. from what period it comes from.
Well how old is it?
Remain the adult of the season.
Really?
Not very much.
Sounds old to me.
Well, such a young man, you won't mind.
I would like to continue research now.
Of course, sorry.
No, I have another question.
Is there anywhere you can get your decent night here, Jan?
Sure, just come back tonight.
I still have another question.
Is there anywhere you can get your decent night here, Jan?
Sure, sure, just go back to Moominvalley.
Oh, how did you know I came through Moomin Valley?
We met before.
You were amazed when we looked at the flowers.
Right, you look familiar.
Or did I surprise myself?
Oh, and you laughed.
So watch as I search for gold for my work.
Honey, have you searched here?
Not yet, but all the stones must be looked at and the formation of the rock must be studied.
That's the only way to find a vein of gold.
You were very surprised when we were looking at the flowers.
Well, I imagined you also studying the rock, because it interests me.
Yes, of course.
Have you ever found gold in the world?
Yeh, of course.
Oh, I'd like to be a gold digger too.
Oh, I guess you like gold.
Yes.
I like shiny things too.
The best part of this game is when you find gold.
I don't care about flowers.
Jaha, or do you think that there is gold in Moominvalley too?
Not from Moominvalley.
Aha, is that absolutely certain?
Yes it is.
Munni said that you are interested in the Moomin Valley rocks.
It's true, I wanted to get it in shape.
Where are you going next?
There may be some gold that has migrated from elsewhere in the lonely mountains here, but not a gold vein.
Just don't ask me to reveal where I'm looking for gold.
Of course not, I don't want urki.
Behind the lonely mountains.
Peace out Moomin, it would be heavenly to have a decent dinner again.
Well, I guess you're not home often.
Well no, real gold diggers are looking all the time.
And I don't have anyone at home with a bucket.
No you you.
You are a nice family.
What do you say, mom, if we keep the gold digger with us as long as he's comfortable?
What's up, it's fun when you have guests.
I suggest I can't stay any longer.
I'll have to see you to continue looking for gold again first thing tomorrow morning.
However, the gold prospector fell ill that same evening with a high fever.
I think it's trouble.
There is nothing wrong with you, I hope you get better.
Mom, how is the patient?
Time in high fever.
Then he will have to stay here.
Certainly. He hasn't eaten in three days.
In poor condition, he can't search.
I have to see if I can find a book about stones or gold.
I would give it to him to read.
I have to stop by the Moomin house to find the gold there.
How to find gold?
It's not so easy to learn.
I'm not a snuffer.
Well, probably not. I'm only good at inu.
Hello Moomin-Pekko!
What?
That man said there is no gold in the Moomins.
That's what he told his father.
But it doesn't have to be true.
What do you mean?
If I found gold in the Moomin, do you think I would tell the others?
Yes, you have to be able to trust people.
Hey, the seller is right.
Remember how stealthily Ukkeli sneaked here.
He seemed tense.
By guarantee, he had found something.
Where were you then and what did the gold prospector say to you?
Hey, you're not serious about flipping and selling something.
I want to make sure there is no gold in the Moomins.
It would be horrible if people rushed here to dig for gold.
I think that would be wonderful.
Oh Mr. Gold Digger.
What is your winner?
Know him.
Oh, you look much better already.
Would you like a drink?
No thanks.
Yes, you must eat or drink something.
My head is buzzing and anyway I have a bit of a uterus.
Tell me how long I've been lying here.
It's starting to be the days of the week.
It's a week, Moompa.
So what?
Maybe I should get a drink.
I'll give you some juice.
After that first glass of juice, the gold prospector's condition started to improve.
A week later, he was able to go for a leisurely walk in Moomin Valley.
By then, a rumor had spread everywhere that a famous gold digger was looking for gold in Moomin Valley.
You have liked me so well that I ought to have a drink.
I should have a drink.
You've taken such good care of me that I can't thank you enough.
The first gold ore I found, Kimpale.
And you have kept it as a memory ever since.
It has brought good luck over the years, but now I think I'll find gold without good luck.
Hold on, Kimpale.
I'll put Moominpapa's manuscript on top of the bundle as a paper weight.
That's what it's for.
No, don't.
Then there's this.
It looks like a map.
Right. It is said to be the treasure map of a famous pirate.
Treasure map?
No, but that's probably just a false assumption.
Oh my goodness, just like Moominvalley.
You are right. That's it.
Familiar, crack. I know that rock.
As I said, the map is almost certainly faked.
I typed paper, the typefaces are too new.
Maybe the map is just a joke.
But since it's from Moominvalley, I thought you'd want to keep it.
Excellent. I suggest we all go treasure hunting.
Do it, but don't dig yourself into exhaustion.
Mr. Goo-seekers!
What, little sell?
Have you searched for this treasure yourself?
You climbed over the cliff to Moomin Valley.
Yeah, true.
I'm sure there's a big crack in the rock.
If so, at least I didn't notice it.
Well maybe, I believe you.
But on the map this cracked rock is drawn much closer to the sea.
Isn't that right, Moomin?
Yeah, I guess. That's right.
Oh, oh right?
Well, there you have it.
I'm not interested in treasures.
The map is a joke.
See you soon!
Good luck!
So Koolanetsija said goodbye to the people of the Moomin house.
Now we go looking.
Yes, treasure.
Mom, will you come?
I'm coming. Sometimes you have to do nice things.
Mom, this is not cool.
Not at all. There are treasures after all.
That's true. Even the koola finder has definitely been looking for treasure.
We're going to look for it.
I don't think we've been seen.
Good.
Why do we have to hide?
Digging for treasures is secret.
Snuff, smiley!
Hide!
Come forward. I know you are there.
Let me look sometimes.
Aha, right?
Here. This is where the crack is.
There's a crack in that too.
I think it's too small.
This is definitely the one.
Where are we going here?
East. We take 39 steps to the east.
Are you sure it's not 39 meters?
It's always about the steps.
Listen dad, we have pretty short legs.
And it isn't. Our body is longer than usual.
One, two, three, four, five, six, one, two, three, one, one, one, one, one, one, one, one, one, one, one, one.
Unit, unit, unit, unit, unit, unit, unit, unit, unit, unit, unit, unit, unit, unit, unit, unit, unit, unit, unit, unit, unit, unit, unit, unit, unit, unit, unit, unit, unit, unit, unit, unit, unit, unit, unit, unit, unit, unit, unit, unit, unit, unit, unit, unit, y
unit, unit, unit, unit, unit unit, unit, unit, unit, unit, unit, unit, unit, unit, unit, more
To this point.
And you can't just see the treasure.
Did you believe in the treasure?
Well, of course I believed. And I believe.
Yes, but if that map is a mistake or just a joke.
And it isn't.
Someone else can continue.
I'll continue.
Heavy work.
Yes, it will suffer if you can find the treasure.
Dad, shall we dig a little further? If it was 39 meters.
It's possible too.
My faith would be like that if they dug a trench.
I hope papa Maltaa watches his back.
The Aare map is a suspected falsification.
We have to dig from an ever wider radius.
Are you digging tomorrow too?
We dig.
I'll come again to see how you grind.
Rather! Jihuu!
I see! Now comes the enthusiastic companion.
Elegance! Why did you leave me alone?
Sorry Nipsu. It wasn't meant to be.
I want a gold mine too.
We don't dig for gold.
Don't try to string. Everyone says that the gold prospector has told you where the gold mine is.
Who all?
Well, everyone.
You are mistaken.
I can't.
We don't dig for gold.
Look Nipsu.
Moomin, what's wrong?
Moomin, are you done?
Interesting.
You found this nugget.
No, the gold digger gave it to us.
He has been digging there.
And now you are going to.
Nothing of the kind.
Everyone in Moomin Valley knows that you dig for gold.
Listen now, Hemuli.
Hi, hi, hi.
Moomin!
It's a surprise that you can find gold right in the corner of your house.
Oh, Hemuli.
Morning, morning, morning.
Hello, Moomin.
Good morning, Nipsu.
I dig until dark.
Oh, Nipsu.
Are you sure you understood everything I told you yesterday?
Oh yes, you're not looking for gold in a vein, but in a treasure chest.
Much better that way.
Yeah, yeah, but we're not sure there's any treasure.
Or so.
Then I dig plain gold.
I'm about to get a headache.
There's Mrs. Vilionka.
Listen dad.
Let's dig the cage so no one else finds our treasure.
You are right.
Moominpapa.
Did you say I'm digging for gold in the right place?
This is actually a kind of new hobby.
A clumsy excuse. Nice good neighbors. I'll keep digging.
Dig in kids. We will defeat them.
Oh, oh. What will happen in Moomin Valley if we find the treasure?
What now? I hit something hard.
Dig carefully. Manually. Beware of immensely valuable treasure.
No.
The search for the treasure took a week. And nothing was found.
Moi.
No gold ore was found in Moomin Falls either, but real gold sand was found in the river.
The mines were abandoned and everyone rushed to the river to wash the gold. Everyone except the Moomins.
Yes, the gold chips are impossibly small.
And wanted.
We have gold.
Yes, the gold chips are impossibly small.
And wanted.
Are you sad that you didn't find the treasure?
I don't really get exercise. The landscape does look quite untidy.
Poor thing, the potholes have to be filled.
Hi, I can help. And me.
Now invented. What did you come up with?
Hemuli, wouldn't this area be well suited for a new flower garden?
For a flower garden?
So. The country is so excited that half of the foundation work has been done.
I think this would be a perfect place.
You're right.
My house is close like this, by the river, and there is no shade.
Let's call it Gold Fever Park.
Great. Let's get down to business.
Clear.
The garden will be bigger, won't it just Hemuli?
Yeah. Well of course.