Hey, hey, hey!
News! Big news!
Big news, come check it out!
Say, what's the matter?
A prophet has appeared in Grandma's lakso!
A prophet?
He is so wonderful, so wonderful!
Who's here?
I want to see.
Who is this prophet?
What the hell is a prophet doing here?
Come and see, and you'll see!
I'm very hungry.
I'm in a hurry, it's going to be a big party!
Party!
Or big dinners?
Dear friends, it's time for a change.
I have come here to help you change your life.
Dear friends, go back to nature and live a free life.
Back to nature!
And be true to yourself!
Where are the eateries?
Shut up and listen!
Only freedom leads to happiness!
Isn't it great?
Splendid?
A prophet.
Where do we eat?
He makes everyone happy.
I get happy just looking at him.
I have come to bring you happiness!
You are prisoners of your habits and narrow views.
Shake off your old clothes and put on something new.
Put on your freedom.
I guess he's a tailor.
He is a prophet and that's cool.
Good people, be happy!
Shake your worries off your shoulders and be free.
Aren't we free?
I have always imagined in my mind that we are free.
Maybe I'm wrong.
Whatever you do, be happy.
That must be right.
The most important thing is to be happy.
The prophet is right.
Let's throw our shackles away.
Back to freedom!
I hear you go go!
I want a new life too.
I didn't know before that I'm not free.
Freedom and happy!
Dad, what are you building?
I'm moving to live in this tree.
Don't you live with us anymore?
I really don't.
I return to nature and I am free.
I don't even feel bad about myself.
Sun and wind.
Bark and leaf crunch.
Then!
Dude, what are you doing?
I do the work.
What work do you do?
Fresh juice only.
Only? Oh fresh juice only?
This is real freedom juice.
The juice has a very refreshing effect, when you drink it you feel free.
If the juice sells well, I would make a lot of money and be happy.
I simply call this lucky juice.
To me it looks like regular fruit juice.
But it isn't.
When you're thirsty and you drink it, you instantly become much much happier.
Mahdankohan?
I'll prove it to you.
I drink this miracle juice myself.
I'm thirsty.
The scent of nature and freedom.
Oh my guts probably went to waste.
Did the juice really taste that awful?
The rowan berries became bitter, but when the taste passes, Aromio's blissful.
I didn't become happy.
Moomin-Pekko, it's your turn to taste.
I don't want to.
I'll taste now and say what ingredients I need to add.
Please.
I try to find happiness in another way.
Hey, just a quickie.
Poison. Pepper.
Listen mom.
So what?
Father has moved to live in a tree and Nipsu prepares happiness juice to become rich.
Is it freedom?
Oh well.
Is it lucky juice?
Maybe freedom is that everyone gets to do exactly what they want.
In my opinion, I have always done what I want.
The drug mom is right.
So that it is also freedom when you eat and sleep when you want.
I guess so.
But it's difficult for a watch.
Is dad happy in his nest in the tree?
Well, maybe you're not always happy even when you're free.
Freedom can be surprisingly complicated.
Moominpappa probably notices how difficult it is to work in wood
and before he gets a cup of coffee in there, it has time to freeze.
The freedom fighters are pissed off.
Hey nipskuneites.
Hello Moomin.
Where are you going?
Look what I'm wearing.
What do you think of the new freedom dress, will it suit me?
It's unusual.
So what do I look like?
How so?
Oh you guys, can't you see that I have a new hairstyle?
I'm leaving here now to look for a new life of freedom.
So do I.
I fall in love with a nice man and live a new life with him.
What the hell new life?
Oh Moomin, you should look for a new life too.
Bye.
So trinket lady!
Well what are your feelings?
So, towards Nipskunei.
I don't give a damn about him.
Hey, wait, pretty girl!
I am the most beautiful creature I have ever seen.
The time of freedom has now come, and I cannot live without you.
If you become my own, then I will love only you.
For sure.
I worship the ground you tread on.
I'll follow your heels like a shadow.
That sounded pretty good.
Will you even go through the fire for me?
Of course, if it doesn't burn.
I will carry you in my arms through the storms of life.
I'm not as light as I look.
Freedom of life.
You cook for me and then we are happy.
Now I know, I'll rob you.
Are you robbing?
We plunge across the sea and look for a new home.
Sounds wonderful.
Malta can hardly wait to see what comes next.
Hei Boomipeikko.
Do you want to know one thing?
I don't believe in skunks.
I want to know one thing.
That matter concerns the marshmallow lady.
What do you know about wetlands?
Would I tell you that.
What is that thing? Say it already.
Niiskunnei has a fiancé and they intend to elope.
I'm going to miss Niskunnei.
I won't miss you.
Right? A young couple sails on the sea.
When you sail, now we live in a time of freedom.
Come on.
If they do what they want, you do what you want anyway.
You're a man, aren't you?
What do you mean by that?
If something is stolen from you, you take it back.
Hit that man, it's cute, right?
You could be right.
I am free and can do what I want.
A real man's speech.
I can be freer than anyone else in the whole world.
Of course you can be a Moomin, Goblin.
A good fight is invigorating.
Well, are we going to leave soon?
I don't want to just look at the ocean.
I do need some time to think.
Crooked, seducer of innocence.
I'm a black hand.
Lady, I will investigate for you.
Can you trust that man?
Mustakaus and our underling are just talking.
Take your sword and fight for your woman.
Take your sword hand, you coward too.
What's wrong with you?
And you have not gone to fight for me?
Well, when I'm scared.
Let's get started then.
I just forgot that I have an appointment soon.
If only tomorrow.
How crazy.
Would a domineering man run away from you?
The lucky lady, the black hand is glad that you can help.
Makomak's pirate.
Maybe you think you're funny?
I didn't believe that man, even though he spoke nice things to me.
I showed that boy, didn't I?
I wouldn't have wanted that.
That's right miss.
I'm dying of laughter.
It looks like it's going to rain heavily.
Honey, would you like an umbrella?
Would you like an umbrella?
Oh, thanks.
Wait, no thanks.
If it rains I get wet, that's perfectly natural.
Honey, do you really find it fun to live in a tree?
Certain. Here I can feel completely free.
To be free and happy like a bird in the sky.
I can see that you are enjoying yourself.
That he just catches a cold.
Moominpa Ressu.
He is too stubborn and proud to give in.
But daddy will come back.
Papa doesn't enjoy himself for too long on one thing.
I believe papa will soon tire of freedom.
I should probably go weed the garden.
It's been a long time since the last time.
Firewood would have to be chopped and the pipe snuffed.
And the porch floor would be pretty dirty.
Everyone is so busy living a free life.
What if I tried freedom too?
It can be fun.
I'm very hungry.
Father!
What now, Moomin?
Father, I want to speak with you among men.
I have tried to live a free life.
Nothing really comes of it.
I want to be free and happy just like you.
Well, listen, Moomin.
See, the thing is...
Dad, are you okay?
Can you bring me another blanket?
It's fine.
Oh, oh, it takes a lot of everything to live a free life.
Should have asked to bring food too.
Father! Father!
Now we're in trouble, you're reading this!
Well, what's the matter, my son?
Dear family, dinner is ready.
Warm it up in the oven when you get home.
You can find raspberry jam on the top left shelf and in the aspirin spoon drawer.
Best regards, Moomin.
But mother can't start living a free life, right?
This becomes a problem.
He didn't hurt you.
Oh my, I'm getting too old for this.
He immediately went to look for his mother.
Clear!
Mother!
Mamma!
Sweetheart!
It's not even in the vegetable garden.
Mother!
What's wrong now?
Oh, aitee!
What are you doing here in the middle of the night?
Have you seen mother?
We are not, we come this late from the prophet.
Did you go see him yet?
We went to ask what free life is like at its best, but he had already left.
It is because of that new prophet that mother has left home.
I don't think it helps, it's terrible!
Mother!
Mummy Moomin!
Mamma!
Where are you, Moominma?
Which one is he in?
Where has he gone?
Mother!
Mummy Moomin!
Why did Moominma leave us?
How can Moomin imagine that we will survive without her?
If we don't make it, that's fine with us.
What do you mean by that?
We tried freedom on your initiative.
My? Isn't that idiot prophet behind it all?
Moomin is probably right.
I feel like Moomin got tired of us and our new free life.
That's why he left home.
Oh you! My corner window!
Why are you coming so late?
I have news about Moomin.
Right from home!
Mother!
Do not! I don't want to wake up my mother.
Moominma wanted to borrow my tent, so she could have some time in peace.
Shouldn't you be at home in peace?
Apparently, Moominma wants to sleep in a tent again sometimes.
Well, at least he scared us once.
Hey, aren't we all going home to sleep under the covers?
We'll come again in the morning to pick up Moomin.
Okay, I'm getting tired.
My corner cabin, you can stay with us for the night.
Oh, thanks Moominpapa.
Thanks.