Moomin Valley is bathed in sunlight.
Such a day makes you sing and dance.
So.
So struck.
What makes you sing today?
I'm so good to be.
Nice day.
I have a feeling something really funny is going to happen.
And exciting. Maybe there will be a whirlwind.
Moomin troll.
I didn't even notice it. Hello.
Where are you going?
As long as I go.
Whereabouts?
Come on, come on over to dad.
Mom and Dad have something to tell you.
Ai.
Exciting.
No you you.
Moomin already had time to leave.
Maybe he came to meet you.
Joo.
But he didn't say where he was going.
Just like that.
Moomin troll.
Moomin difference.
We haven't had a fancy dress party in ages. They are kept on a leash in the manor.
Aaah, the one that's like a haunted house!
Pikkumyu, better people live in that house, more precisely the nobility of our kingdom.
The host is very kind to invite us.
I can reveal to you that I was told to be invited to a costume party.
Every Moomin is a resident, isn't there a bigger one?
There will be a puff.
So food and drink?
You want to come too.
Necessarily! And then we danced the night away!
Isn't that so obvious?
Ball...
Dear Niiskun Eiti, I would like to introduce you to a young man.
For a teenager?
Even for a noble. He is what was right for you?
A million!
What do you sell?
Hoomipeikka is better suited to niiskunnei, and you can't woo me to that young man.
It's about time I got my own swing.
Children, remember to be neat at the party.
Don't judge someone's food.
Mom, we're always neat at parties.
Aren't you?
No, mom.
In Vittikomero, kommumimama!
So. Here probably.
It's been a long time.
Let's see what's here!
I think it is completely unnecessary for us to dress up in fancy dress.
We fit in quite well like this.
You and I very well, but niiskunneid and mey need at least a wig.
A wig?
Ugh, stupid!
Moomin, this one?
It doesn't fit a bit!
Just that. Let's think it's still in stock.
The wig is a bit out of shape, but luckily we have a whole week.
May I try it on?
Just try it.
Oh, that looks really nice, mister.
Really? Did you wear this wig when you were young?
We wore wigs at the party, didn't we?
No, I remember.
Moomin mama, at least this is a man's wig!
Well, is that about...
Dad used it.
Do you have to keep all the junk? They only collect moths.
Hypsis, this will make a good wig for sale.
Will you come?
I'll make it a little smaller so it fits like a glove.
Thank you, Moomin Mama! Put the wig on, I'll read all the masks from the board.
So sure. All the young men are going out of their way to pick you up for the dance.
What happened to you?
I'm excited!
How can I wait a week?
Hi, what are you eating? Nuts?
Nuts taste awful.
Hey, come play.
Hey, don't run away!
No hello, Hemuli!
I'm bored.
It's no fun playing hooky alone.
And I'm not kidding.
Need a playmate?
Then jump to Moomin to play. And don't be in my shoes.
Moomin is never home and everyone else is getting ready for a costume party.
I know. You don't even hear talk about anything else these days.
If only I knew how great it is to dress up for some silly prom.
Absolutely blown away. I'd rather watch a tumor than dance in its pus.
In a mess?
No.
Hello, Snuska-muikkunen!
Hey!
Aha, I'm starting to understand why you haven't been seen.
Canoe or not?
It's a lot of hard work when you're trying to tinker alone.
I know, but I want to survive without the help of others.
You wanted to build a canoe in secret and then surprise everyone.
Well, that's what I thought, but now you saw what I was doing.
Oh, sorry. I hereby happily forget that I saw what you were doing.
Can you forget?
Of course. I forget what I want.
I'm thinking about something else and I'm like, I've forgotten.
Let's hold launching ceremonies when the canoe is ready.
You are the guest of honor!
I came.
Well welcome.
Are you amazed?
Moomin Pekka, what's wrong with you?
Are you a wet girl?
No, but the duchess, who resembles the lady of the meadow.
We are in a big hurry to get everything done by face.
Next next next next next next next next.
We are in a big hurry to get everything ready for the masquerade.
Oh yeah, to that costume parade.
It's prom!
Moomin-Pekka, how do you dress?
Me?
Come up with something, the party is for four days.
Four days?
Moomin-Pekka has to dress up as a prince, right?
No, when for a swineherd who secretly loves me, a meadow lady can take that nobleman.
No, Moomin is a prince, and he is my cavalier.
I'm hungry.
You will get food right away, we have already eaten.
Moomin-Pekka can be the servant of both of our prince stories.
No way, she appears as a black woman. That's right.
Servant or black knight, it doesn't matter, but do I have time to prepare?
Of course, we will help you.
Moomin-Pekka can just as well be in Tartsa's, Leopard's stables.
Well thought, powerful Tartsan will carry us on the dance floor in his arms.
Tartsan must have a crocodile. Nipsu would play a role in that, all his own.
That's right, let's start making a mask for the trinket right away.
Moomin-Pekka is on the trail early.
How far can the spur be?
Oh yeah, I can't watch. I mumbled to him.
Good morning!
Good morning.
Ha, hypocrite!
Aisuli will definitely notice Moomin-Peko's carrier.
Finally, the day of the masquerade dawned. The police chief is looking for a lady.
Who is there?
I? I came to get you.
Oh, your suit is so familiar.
Wearing a police helmet on purpose, I look just like your assistant.
Wait a minute, Rova-Viljonkka. I'm not coming to the masquerade.
You are my cavalier.
I don't have time. I'm going to collect plants.
Guaranteed not. You go to a costume party.
Yes, but Mrs. Vilijonkka...
If not, then no. It drains all the time.
Bulge your abs.
I can be Tartsan if Moomin-Pekko doesn't want to.
I have a Tartsan top for Moomin-Peko.
He has used it before.
I'd rather be the Black Knight.
Moomin, please, it's too late.
Let's get that upper part. Where is it, Mummy Moomin?
Isn't it in Moomin Peko's own room?
Soon then! It's definitely time.
Moomin-Pekko! Moomin-Pekko! Moomin-Pekko!
Hey.
Just don't say you're coming to the party too.
Of course not.
I happened to pass by your construction site, and when you weren't there I stopped by here.
Did you see my secret?
I don't. Of course I closed my eyes.
Good. Nothing will come from work today, but the canoe is almost ready.
Great. Not many days left, eh?
Couple three.
Well then, you could launch it right away.
I guess so. But it still has one thing and another to finish.
And what do you think? Could someone be pushing it into the water secretly from you?
I believe so. What do you mean?
I saw Haisuli sneaking over there.
Did I smell?
And you haven't noticed anything?
I'm not.
What if Haisuli has fallen into a hole?
Aha! Found!
Moomin, look at this.
Ugh! Where did you go?
Rushed somewhere with the muikku.
Moomin!
So what now?
You look just like Tarzan.
Come on.
O Stink!
Stop that, you rascal!
It won't stay on the surface. I wouldn't have believed it.
It's not ready yet. Come back.
This is fine for me. Edition you just dress up to celebrate.
I made the canoe myself.
Listen Moomin, you have a really stylish loincloth.
Moomin, don't come any closer than back.
Watch out Stinker, the king of the Tartus jungle is coming and will tear your fur into swords.
Good Moomin!
All the guests must have already arrived.
Shouldn't have waited for the Moomin.
I think that Moomin is kicking his heifers.
You would have made me a tartan.
You cannot carry two princesses in your arms.
What exactly are you talking about?
Quietly!
I'm a Moomin.
Horse gallop!
Nobody here in Moomin Valley has a horse.
Look!
Odd one out.
I'll drive him on his way.
What a scoop!
Look, crocodiles don't bark.
An unusual dog.
He is the other, the other, the other, the other, the other, the other, the other, the other, the other, the other, the other, the other, the other, the other, the other, the other, the other, the other, the other.
Is it yours?
Yes, but he's a crocodile.
And we haven't met before.
Emme.
Mrs. Vilijonkka sent me an invitation to the dress prom.
But apparently I'm lost.
We are going to the same place.
Maybe we can go the same way.
It's fine, how about me?
Noble sir!
It would be fine for us to go on your sled.
Just something.
It was lucky that we bumped into each other.
Niiskunei is a nerve.
Boldly.
The dance may have already begun.
Apparently.
Niiskunneiti finds herself in an embarrassing position without a cavalier.
Perhaps.
He gets mad as hell.
Certainly.
Oh, how lucky we were to actually get to ride.
At least I feel like a princess.
With your kind permission.
I acted as a companion for both of you at the dance.
Permits will come!
Maybe you'll also let me have a merry-go-round with you on the dance floor.
Oh sure.
The Moomin doesn't even have to come.
We don't need tartans.
Even less crocodiles.
Moomin troll.
Old man.
Who do you
Hawks are eight.
Act Alexia.
Kuk points.
Adjective to the extent of æ¯c.
Keyword Bay part check.
keyword Bay part check.
The job was missing.
However.
No Brad punelee.
Wait for me!
This menu will take forever before we get to the party.
Now don't think about it. You push, push, push!
Moomin bump into you.
Look at those two of the best Moomins I've ever seen, you must say.
Everything else. They have come into their own.
Cypress Magnifier!
Oh, I'm hungry.
To the dance floor! Let's dance hard to catch the others!
I want food first.
I'm going home.
We just got here!
I have lost a wig and a couple of days and a fan.
I don't care anymore.
You can borrow my wig!
Let's go dancing!
Let's rest a little first. I walked here.
My wig didn't get the perfect shade.
Oh, Rova-Viljonkko!
Oh, dear Marquis!
You have already seen the small shop.
I came to introduce you to another fine lady.
Did I even hear the right way?
Yes, Beauty.
Dare, little one!
I've been here waiting for the lady to come back.
Oh, are you really?
Of course it's true. A private lotti awaits.
Follow me.
Moomin Goblin!
Oh, how Soma carried!
Did you do it yourself?
I am. Glad you like it.
Can I enter the old age?
Of course! Please, beautiful princess.
Thank you, Prince Soma.
Beautiful moon!
So.
In this regard, sail to the moon in this beauty.
Likewise.
And there we danced our heads off.
Joo.
And to the moon they flew.
Or at least they thought so.