I hear, what are you going to do today?
Hardly anything special.
Good thing you don't have any other plans.
Think you could fix a sewing machine?
Oh, a sewing machine?
Just like Alalanka pulls annoyingly.
Dad listen, will you fix my watch too?
Is it not working properly?
No, it always stops.
I am very handy in all home appliance and appliance repair work.
Like that.
Jaa.
Dad, here's the clock.
Where do I put it?
Carefully put it aside on that newspaper.
Does that take long?
You can go.
Let's go.
In the meantime, you could try to examine the watch yourself.
I've always wanted to peek inside a watch.
Moomin, what are you doing?
Do you fix your watch?
Will anything come of it?
I would believe so my dear.
Yes, I can fix this.
Interesting, let me correct.
I want too.
All right, but be careful.
I don't want the watch to go to waste.
Hundreds of small strollers.
I'll rip every one of them off.
Sell, don't just break.
Of course, I'll fix it.
This would make a beautiful pendant.
Won't come, don't.
It was fun fixing the clock.
Really.
You wouldn't have had to remove all the parts.
When I do something, I do it properly.
Dad, look at this.
I can't get the gear out.
Wait and see.
Isn't this about...
Let's move the parts of the watch separately from the parts of the sewing machine.
Joo.
Now.
What do we do now?
No sweat.
I have a perfect memory of what the insides of a watch and a sewing machine look like.
Really?
I'll fix the sewing machine first.
The remaining parts belong to the watch.
Muuvipapa always finds a way.
Can it be successful?
Kill the worry.
May I come to your aid?
And me?
Me too.
This fits here.
I guess the spring belongs somewhere in here.
The strap comes here.
Let's see.
Fits perfectly.
This part looks great here.
I turn the lamp here.
That's it now.
It doesn't look the same as before.
Well, you could be right about that.
A strange sewing machine!
Dad, there were no parts left in the watch.
I guess you're right.
What do we do now?
It may not be Tismale's former sewing machine, but what is it?
Mamma, can you answer that?
No, I can't.
A sewing clock with a shadow!
One part is left over.
Where would it be put?
Moomin, please go and get the magnetic tool box.
Joo.
Thanks.
Oh!
What was it? Time block huh?
I suspect the magnetic field.
Moomin, don't we have an old radio somewhere in the corner?
Yes, but it doesn't work.
Bring it here, though, now.
Clear.
If my calculations match, there should be a strong magnetic field, maybe also an electric field.
What is it?
So.
Moomin, are you doing something to the machine?
There, I twisted this wheel a bit.
Who are you?
How so? We are you.
Why do you look like me?
I look like you because you are me.
Are we related?
Good miracle, but I'm you.
who are you
What do you mean?
I am you.
Welcome, I'm making tea.
Good unusual.
They disappeared.
Who were those twin beings?
Where did they go from here?
Yay, I think we've put together a pretty remarkable machine.
Let me now put back the part that fell from me.
Well, here it is.
The gear should fit in this slot.
Dad, now the machine starts again.
Share, share, let's see.
Dad, what's going on now?
No gray warping.
Let's see, the hands of the clock are turning backwards.
What?
True.
Good to scare.
Aaah, what's going on now?
Father.
That must be it.
Namely, a time machine.
I have read about it, but that they really exist.
Time machine.
It takes you to the past or the future wherever you want.
It's the same thing.
Now I understand.
We see ourselves as we were a few minutes ago.
Just like that.
Who are you? How so?
We are you.
Why do you look like me?
I look like you because you are me.
Maybe we're related, but you're me.
who are you
What do you mean?
I am you.
I am me.
We all go back to the past again.
I want to go now.
It's not a problem when you've built a great machine yourself and also know how to use it.
So let's go back in time.
Tel!
Where have we come?
What era have we entered?
I don't know.
Father look, just like lonely mountains.
We are lonely mountains.
Where is the Moomin house?
All I see are huge trees!
I would guess that the place we are in is an ancient Moomin valley.
It looks different today.
It seems so.
Calm down, I know how to treat natives.
We are under siege!
It scares me.
What do we do?
You must not fall into the grip of fear of flight.
Hey there you pale-faced friends of ours, we're up to no harm.
Father!
Cereal!
Who are they?
They look like blue Moomin to me.
Are they our ancestors?
Isn't it just my boy.
I hope they were vegetarians.
Good day!
Hey start stop!
They'll probably start checking if we're fit to eat.
That's how it seems.
How are they going?
How big is the welcome bonfire?
I don't think there is a welcome bonfire.
Well, not for sure!
They roast us over a campfire.
This is no longer a joke.
I've always said I don't like relatives.
Best to leave.
Mielumi right away.
Vuh! Vuh! Vuh! Vuh! Vuh! Vuh! Vuh! Vuh!
Father, what will be done to these three?
I can't evict them.
We have no choice.
Looks like they have to be included.
Speed up!
Nice to get home!
Yes, we are back in the time we left.
What a relief.
Traveling is overrated. Luckily I was there.
Dad is watching.
Please come and have afternoon tea.
Oh mom, we were just on a big adventure.
That was cool.
Did my sewing machine have something to do with it?
Mamma honey, it's not a sewing machine anymore.
Right?
Oh, and tell me, who are these three weird-looking hairballs?
They are our ancestors.
Or really ancestors?
What does that mean?
From the Stone Age Moomins with a time machine.
And it was fun!
We were almost roasted alive over a campfire.
Well, it all hurts.
However, you survived unscathed.
Would the ancestors like tea and cookies?
No you, you.
It seems to me that the ancestors enjoy us.
Let's hope so.
Aivas papa, what are we doing?
We mustn't pay too much attention to him.
Not then, I guess.
What did you do with that, ancestor?
I guess you can't change your ancestors.
Probably not.
Ancestor, where are you going?
Oh, those were my favorite dishes.
Pappa is our ancestor.
What happens now?
What was it?
Au!
What on earth?
What was that?
Me too.
I can't do that kind of destruction.
Father, the ancestors invented a trap door to the basement.
So it seems.
Oh no, now they're eating our food supply.
It must be prevented.
No, no, no.
Oh, oh, oh.
They have a lot of food.
Oh, Dad.
Oh, mom.
Let's come.
Möö and Niskunneit, come help.
The ancestors do not know what these cans and jars are.
What's wrong with you?
What are you squealing?
Don't aim that gun at me.
Teach, ancestor.
Father they have taken your hunting colors.
So it appears.
I got it in the back of the chamber.
How could they find it?
Isn't the rifle dangerous?
No, it has not been loaded.
Help.
A pinch of extract.
Hanissaa.
The Moomin troll will help.
I have to go.
The Moomin troll helps.
A pinch.
Welcome to the slowdowns when I felt the door.
What are they going to do to me?
Ai-ai-ai, ai-ai.
Help.
Good morning!
I'm afraid that the ancestors think the nip is in good taste.
That's where they come in handy!
We cannot leave a pinch to the mercy of the ancestors.
Try to bring Nipsu back to us.
Yes, but how?
Tell him to run this way.
OK, I'll click.
Guess I've been the one to do that too! You shouldn't eat me!
It sounded like a hoot.
What was he in such a hurry to do?
Oh, what a species! This is a great find!
Help! We will be killed!
Nipsu, come here!
Remind?
Here!
No more!
Ancestors!
I'm sure of the species definition.
This is a miracle, a real stroke of luck.
The greatest discovery of the century in the field of biology.
Nipsu, you are my witness. You saw them too.
Are those hair tufts a great find?
Remarkable. I saw the ancestors in Hemul's garden.
Look at this book, Nipsu.
I have studied these things for a long time.
Here are the ancient Moomins who lived in Moominvalley long ago.
They were just such fluffy heads that ran at my heels.
Right. Ancestral or ancient Moomins lived here thousands of years ago.
Well, then how is it possible that they are against me in the present time of the world?
Tell me, their family is supposed to have died a long time ago.
And now they're here to chase you around Moomin Valley.
Can you imagine anything more exciting?
Such a revolutionary discovery is already quite valuable.
Without a doubt. Perhaps worthy of a university position.
Let's agree that I'll take the money and you get the position, Joako.
Oh horrible.
What? Hemu?
Yes, he invited the press and research team to Moominvalley.
Honey, what are we doing?
I suspect there will be some problems.
I am sure that the ancestors will be tried to be caught.
I do think that is much easier said than done.
I hope so.
But where are the ancestors, Pekko?
Oh, I forgot.
Remember what you had to do.
I'll go back.
Keep your fingers crossed.
If Hemuli can't find the ancestors, we're in trouble.
Don't worry, Daddy.
I have an inch.
Do not! Tell me that.
Soon you will see.
The hit of the day, will you come to help?
Of course me.
It's so exciting that your stomach churns.
In a pinch!
Don't drag it out.
Get in the cage for it already.
Are you sure I'm safe?
You are you are. No danger.
Being baited by ancestors scares me.
But getting rich is tempting.
Shut your mouth now and into the cage.
Remember, Hemuli, that I have only promised for a moment.
I hope the ancestors are okay and haven't been caught.
Come on, hey!
I guess you're safe there?
Now they come.
Good.
Ouch! They are here.
They go to help.
Help!
Hemuli, they're killing me.
Now if they poke me in the cheek, a ghost will appear for you.
Help!
What now?
Ancestors.
What is it about?
The ancestors came back when they smelled mother's roasts.
I finely chop the vegetables.
I, for my part, tasted it.
True. Myy and Niiskuneiti helped me.
Look, the ancestors fell asleep.
Stomach full.
Now is the right time.
Be careful, papa.
While they sleep, we send them back to their own time.
Now I start.
Ancestors were lost.
It's all over now.
I guess this is what it feels like after a hurricane.
I think that Hemuli will be very disappointed.
Yes, but has our Hemuli got a new interesting hobby?
Mother, what do you mean?
Yeah, yeah. He gets to search for ancient mummies for the rest of his life.
Is that what you mean, Moomin?
That, even if you feel sorry for him.