Hey, would you like to take me on your back when you take off?
Hello! Why don't you answer?
Hit miss, where are you going?
Let's see mommy.
Well that's not new! It's stupid to run after!
No! Something has happened!
Hey!
Oh you!
Well, what is it now?
Isku is finally trying out the aircraft.
Right away?
Yes, it's great to see, even if you walk a little slower.
Why is everyone running?
They went to help Isku. The tent still needs to be dismantled around the aircraft and the ball is inflated with gas.
Come on now!
Isku's aircraft is finally completed.
Does it look weird? Well, it hasn't been gassed yet.
Now the ball is filled with gas, which is much lighter than air.
And when the ship is in the air, it is steered by this propeller. So you don't have to fly just with the wind.
Iskuneiti sector is filling up!
Clear!
Mummy, mamma and black, how are they going to be stoned?
Oh, we're getting ready here.
Thank you for coming, dear friends. Soon my ship will rise into the air like a swan and know that it will fly even in the wind.
Thanks. Thank you, thank you.
Thank you, thank you, thank you.
Look!
What is there?
Another aircraft!
Not exactly a flying basket!
Well Johan now, someone has stolen it so I can figure it out.
Oh my, this is not true.
Good day gentlemen, Do you remember me? I came to visit again.
Yes, we remember Mr. Brisk, who could forget.
The last time he skied!
Yes, and ate all the jam from us.
We had so much fun last winter that you must have missed me. Do you still have jam? I'll be there as soon as I land.
And I was sure that I was the first.
Oh, the horror!
The ball was too full.
I'm getting ready!
It's hard right now.
Don't worry, dashing Hemul's ship is just a basket as a girl.
Not when the ship is much bigger.
Kompas, you've really rocked.
I would like to see how this ship flies first.
Let's go look at that other trick.
I'll go along.
I am also interested in the intentions of the guest.
We need to conduct an inspection of the ship.
Hello, baby!
Good to watch flying, your basket!
How fast does it fly?
How so?
So will it win?
Of course it wins.
So when the aircraft has an engine.
I think it will win the race.
Really? How fast does it fly?
Hard to say when it hasn't flown yet.
Gas leaked out.
Ha, movie troll!
Hemme who expected uncle this early.
Winter hasn't come yet.
Has it stopped skiing?
No, but I can get to the slopes faster by flying.
The dashing Hemul's Laundry basket is lost on my plane.
Without a doubt, Niisku.
And he's gone with the wind.
You can turn in any direction and even fly into the wind.
That's right.
Sure enough.
Palla's ship quickly fixed.
But I still think it's unfair that that crazy stranger
just arriving on my first day of flying.
This jam is great.
That's actually why I came.
There was still some left in the cellar.
Even I can't take it anymore.
That's good, Moomin.
Thank you for your courtesy.
Would you like some jam?
I was waiting for those words.
As much as you need.
Jam into the jam with pancakes.
Now what?
I saw someone flying past the window.
Ugh, weird.
Oh, would Niisku have already fixed his aircraft?
No, the pilot must have been a witch.
That's it!
He always knocks on the door with a bone.
Moomoo, why don't you tap your knuckles?
Because I'm a witch.
Hello, this is a surprise.
One day I saw a strange flying device, which must have landed on a patch of land.
That's right, the pilot is sitting here.
Oops, a real witch.
Dad right and when I fly, I fly with the right broom.
I've been feeling good since the old days.
You have to go with development, and development is flying with tools that you can build.
I make a broom myself in five minutes.
It must be uncomfortable to sit on a broomstick.
Someone seems to have built a real aircraft here.
It hasn't flown yet.
But my ship is.
You may also say that my hot air balloon flies better than an old broom.
And not fly.
Yes, it flies. Besides, only witches can fly on broomsticks.
Well, shall we compete?
How?
I fly on my own broom and you fly in your flying laundry basket.
Okay, I accept the challenge.
How do we proceed?
We choose our quantity, take something from there and return.
Well, where are we going?
Moompa, do you have any suggestions?
Mmm, that... What do you think, Nuuska Muikkunen?
Would you visit the top of the lonely mountains?
Wow, that's an excellent destination.
Hemuli listen, Do you know anything that only grows there?
A star-shaped white flower grows at the top, and there is no lower one.
Whoever brings first, who wins?
And the winner is me.
I'm going to win the air race.
You win, I always win.
Do not release the ropes until I give permission.
No, no, trust us.
And then this. Hemuli, don't let go.
Grandma, are you sure you'll win?
I'm the witch. I'll win, you fool.
You don't know that. The dashing Hemuli seems so sure of victory.
It could be embarrassing for you if that happens...
The dasher here gets embarrassed, and no one else.
That's it, I'm ready. Fuck that witch.
I'm ready, Toope.
Then don't get mad if you lose.
Remember, participation is important, not winning.
I'll show you the losses.
All right. Facing lonely mountains. Loose.
I kept crying.
Oh, not selling. Right down from there.
Start! Ate kapju go.
Don't stop, it's going to sell.
The laundry gets fixed like in lice tar.
Is it your best?
Absolutely.
An unequal race.
Too early to say.
Mr. Reippailija's ball also increases speed.
I could have flown there too.
Mr. Reippailija is guaranteed not to win the air race.
Niisku's flying horse would be from another country.
Has it been fixed?
They would have waited for Niisku long enough to have a more interesting competition.
Let's go to Niiskulu.
I'm sure that Niisku's miracle glue has already started to dry.
Yes, competition will develop from this.
Moomin, can I come along?
Of course you can.
But shouldn't you stay and see if your grandma wins?
Maybe, but get so nervous that I have to get something else to think about.
Let's go then.
I have to admit that I have seen even more exciting competitions.
Or what mom?
I like calm races, during which you can take a nap.
So do I.
The grass smells so good.
A trick from the water.
It doesn't leak anymore.
I don't think so.
Soon in the sky like a bird.
Hopefully. It really pisses me off that I'm not the first.
Reippailijan's Laundry basket is nothing compared to your dishes. Kinda beautiful.
There's gas in the ball again!
Moomin Pekka!
I'm getting wet!
Glad you came. You just came to see my test flight.
That's cuter than Reippailija's basket.
It sure is. Shall we begin?
Oh Niisku, wait a little longer.
Mom and dad watch the race between Noida and Reippailija.
These have not yet returned from the lonely mountains.
I'd like mom and dad to see your first flight.
Good, do I have to wait long?
Look! Grandma will be back soon.
I'm glad the Rogue lost to the witch.
Grandma!
This is what grows at the top.
Thanks for the gift. I'm going to plant a rare seedling right away.
Where does Mr. Reippailija stay, you say?
Judging by his pace, he may still be on his way to the lonely mountains.
His laundry basket seemed rudimentary, in a technical sense.
No broom, Neraten. Where are you Alisa?
Went to see the beginning of Niisku.
That's where Alisa comes from. Niisku is also included.
Did you fix your ship?
I got it. Then Niisku gets to take the test flight.
Listen Noita, you should also fly a race with Niisku.
It's an organization, but it's the same if Niisku wants and he can get his ship into the air.
The witch has already returned. He was going at such a good pace.
Now that I got up here, I could pick anyone up.
But when I failed to plan, how do you return to a headwind without your engine?
There's still a bit of jam left, if only I could keep going.
It's been a memorable day, hasn't it?
Yes, papa.
Imagine, we had a brisk hemuli, but we still had jam left.
We had a flight competition, but there is still a test flight coming up.
Let's hope it goes well.
Oh, of course it's going well Niisku.
Just thank you. For the first time in my life, I feel insecure.
Niisku miss, turn off the gas tap.
Mmm, mmm, mmm.
The trick seems faster than a laundry basket.
If it can get up in the air at all.
So you think you can't?
The tractor weighs at least a ton because it has a house and everything.
Well, the field is empty in front of the ship.
Takeoff requires a runway.
Move a little further.
Oh, where is Myy?
Ha, Sell!
Niisku, Myy may be hidden in your ship.
Ah, you you.
Sell, have you locked the door?
Open!
Calm down Niisku!
Sell, open now!
Stop it, I can't focus on these levers.
Focus? What?
To focus on the levers. Hey Myy, you're not just trying to start the engine, are you?
I'm curious to see what the mic lever can do.
Hey, hurry up and hold on to the ship, Myy has shoved himself into the cockpit and is trying to board.
Would Myy be able to get the ship into the air?
Of course not, it's impossible.
But if he somehow succeeded then, I wouldn't be the first to fly on my own ship, and I wouldn't be able to handle it with Takuu.
Oh, you're afraid I'll start the trick.
Sell, stop this madness and get out.
Sell, please.
A little magic could be in order.
Oops, the door is open.
Let me come along!
You can come, but today, because it's a test flight.
It's dangerous.
You think something might happen?
Not going to happen, the ship is well designed.
Well, in that case, I can come along.
Anything can happen with you.
What did that mean?
Sell, stop.
Calm down, little one, I promise you'll get on the first flight I take passengers on.
What if there is a gas leak or the ship goes awry?
Then I'll ever get on board.
Little boy, why do you say that?
My brother's ship won't go astray.
Well, now I'm sniffing the air.
Be careful.
Land happily.
Thanks.
Don't be restless.
Nisku knows what he's doing.
The ship moves forward.
The ship can't rise.
It just slides along the grass.
Why didn't I get to the helm?
Wax!
I want to.
It was close.
The laundry basket may be slower, but at least it takes off.
Even a low salary.
There is still hope, dear Miss Nisku.
The ship is coming straight at us.
Best to run away.
Ai!
I want to.
Oh grandma!
Oh, oh, I had to.
A witch is embarrassed to fly on her nose.
The bone also fell.
Grandma, watch out!
Nisku, don't come away!
Grandma hurry up!
Run away from below!
Get up, now get up, up!
Alisha!
Fly, oh fly!
Nisku, don't go.
Nisku did it, he flies.
I want to.
I made it, I made it.
I'm finally flying.
Disgusting means of transportation.
It's better than your broom.
Not as convenient.
How so?
Test method of nozzles on an aircraft.
Be careful not to get caught by a leotard like me!
Thanks for watching the video!