A beautiful day has dawned in Moominlaakso.
Oh, good, clear sky!
Good morning, mom.
Good morning, my Troll.
The sun is finally shining.
It's funny, papa is looking for pieces of glass to look at the sun through.
I'm going out.
Good morning, dad.
Good morning.
It's an old windowpane.
Yeah, you shouldn't throw anything away.
What did you say?
Well, when I have to break the glass into six smaller parts.
Knock it against something sharp.
No, no, it only produces nasty shards that you can get in your leg.
I guess so.
Amjainen is busy.
The glass should be divided into six parts. How can you avoid chips flying?
Grandma used to always put wet paper on either side of the glass before hitting it with a hammer.
Genius.
Awkward shards of glass stick to wet paper. Yes, grandma knew.
I guess you don't need the glasses to be small right away.
No, let's do it after breakfast.
Joo.
Hmm, it's getting cloudy.
The solar eclipse cannot be seen if the sky is cloudy.
Well, not like that.
Clouds, go away, go away!
I'm so nervous that I can't eat more. I'll get some candles.
Take it easy. The solar eclipse is visible only in the afternoon and it comes very precisely.
Yeah, but I can't be in my fields.
It doesn't take more than five minutes to fix the pieces of glass.
But... oh! Clouds!
Alas, at the time of the previous solar eclipse, I was still a child.
So do I.
Better, perhaps, to have clouds now, rather than later.
Sweeten this air.
But you're going to leave anyway.
Of course. Witchcraft intensifies during a solar eclipse.
Yes, but doesn't it hurt somehow if the sun is hidden behind the clouds?
It will become clear.
I just mean that during a solar eclipse the sun is hidden.
So does it matter?
How can you ask such stupid questions if you want to become a witch?
Do you know what solar eclipse causes it?
Great!
Grandma, what remarkable thing are you going to do there at the end of the year?
Helper of the black sun of the demon. It strengthens my magic power.
There's no need for that. You're a good enough witch anyway.
Of course, but there's always room for more.
But first I nourish myself with toadstool soup.
Pour water.
That's enough.
Light.
Oh.
Great dad.
Let's drag the little pieces onto this paper.
Shall we light a candle?
Where is it?
What do you mean?
Solar eclipse.
Sell, it's not until the afternoon.
Oh, just then.
It's broken glass for us.
Oh me too?
Of course.
Thanks.
What do you get out of this?
If you look at the sun without glasses, your eyes will be damaged.
A solar eclipse is dangerous.
I can't see the sun.
Don't whine.
I can't see anything at all.
Of course not, the sun is covered by clouds.
I guess so.
Which one would be clear in the afternoon.
Otherwise we will not see that the sun is not visible.
Crazy.
More clouds.
You would stay home.
Don't talk to the restless.
That's how a strong gust of wind drives the clouds apart many times.
Hey.
Lovely.
Now I can go see Moomin.
Primitive people believed that the sun went dark because someone spoiled the animal.
But the sun grew back every time.
Right, but they were primitive.
They beat the drums so that the animal had to throw up the sun back.
Make fun of it.
Are the clouds echoing?
It doesn't look like it.
I would have wanted you to see the eclipse.
Let's hope that the sky will be cloudless at the time of the next solar eclipse.
Then you're an old man.
I'm so disappointed.
There's still time for the blackout!
Which wind would disperse the clouds?
The wind is blowing!
Drive the clouds away from the sun!
Hey!
Thank you, Alice.
Hello Snuff-muikkunen!
Are you dying to see Moomin?
I came!
Oh brothers, what a wind!
The air is clearing!
Who knows if we will see a solar eclipse after all?
Oh!
Someone is gnawing on the sun.
I wouldn't have believed it.
What the hell are you on about?
Solar eclipse through stained glass.
An eclipse?
Yes, the moon eclipses the sun.
And you can see it through the glass, right?
Joo.
Give me too.
There is no extra.
What do you have in your hand?
It's for Snuff.
Just like that.
Muikkune just went fishing on a boat.
Hardly, just in this mood.
A real fisherman doesn't give a damn about the weather.
The fish don't eat in this weather.
Au, au, au!
Let me take a look.
But give it back when Snuff-muikkunen comes.
No up, up!
Oh, oh, how wonderful!
Will the sack get dark?
Evening probably like Hämärä.
Hämärä is a good burglar.
Ha ha ha!
Alisa is in it.
Snuff-mikkunen!
ha Isu Li...
He i is still beautiful!
I can borrow it and get it back after the solar eclipse.
Red kettle.
Hello everyone!
Nice to see!
Did grandma give you permission to come?
He is not at home.
Alisa, you look through this glass as the sun shrinks.
The skunk just said that you had gone fishing.
With the roof.
He's a tough talker.
Moominpapa, the weather seems to be clearing up.
I would say something else.
The clouds disappeared as if by magic.
Ocean rushes to do and the power is pushed.
It flickered when the permission locations were searched.
Ehschaftalaisilla pohjoisuvassa, North recommendations and explanation will be updated as soon as they arrive.
Oh, pull up theuttering cable!
Haha.
Oh dear god!
Oh god direction, one, two, three.
A little further and Sequakes!
zostaa lhy Mansion!
Aaaah!
O like this!
Oh damn!
Wake up!
The wind blew my hat too.
Let's go inside and have a look. It's too windy.
What about papa?
Papa will come when he's got his hat on.
Oh! The other side of the sun is splitting.
Lovely. I don't really like the dark. It's terrifying.
Wake up!
Tehuusikohan.
I feel that the charms have been short-lived.
Oops! I'm super cool.
Oh!
The solar eclipse is important to grandma.
He gets more power from it.
Grandma was terribly angry when the clouds didn't seem to disappear at all.
Now grandma's spells have become really cool. Right, Alisa?
Well, at least he seems to think.
I don't think that a darkened sun can have an effect.
I don't dare, little one.
Joo.
Wake up!
Alisa! Alisa!
where are you from
Come on broom, don't worry about the wind rushing to the Moomin house to save, Alisa!
Toward the wind, obey the broom!
You're the curitor, you can't!
Wake up!
Now I'll catch you.
I will now show that you are a real witch's broom.
This is how it is flown.
Have you been to my room before?
Joo.
A couple of times I went in through the window.
Time-honored crush!
What are you doing here?
You were downstairs playing cards with Nikikenen and Nipsu.
One plays badly and the other cheats!
Come and see, you can see the bridge from here.
What?
Stink! It really is a skunk!
No!
Hi! I'm going to blow a broom!
Hi! Stink! Where did you get the broom?
I found in the forest.
Where from there?
Hope it helps later.
What can I do?
I don't know, I'll try to figure something out from here.
Doesn't the broom obey?
No, I can steer it a bit, but I don't know how to get down.
Oh well, sleep.
I can't hang around here anymore.
ha I Su Li!
Tell me about it below!
Stink, you said you could direct a little.
Joo!
Then direct here.
Yeah, what?
Aim above the bed.
Good idea, I'll do that.
Ai!
Oh heaven!
I stank, no wonder.
Hey, let go of the broom.
It didn't happen to you.
No.
You flew on Aliisa's grandmother's broom.
So I flew.
Well, where are those?
Kicks his feet in the air in fists.
The wind knocked him off the broom.
Terrible, where is grandma?
Come and show me.
Have fun with free movement!
Up, up.
Over there!
Grandma!
Can I leave?
Out of breath huh?
No, just unconscious.
I'll carry him to us.
Now I'm disappearing.
Oh grandma dear.
Don't worry, mommy has a cure for that too.
Nobody cares about me.
Moominma, is grandma going to get better for sure?
Of course, I will cook him a tasty broth.
Grandma!
Is the witch still unconscious?
On.
I wouldn't have thought that a witch would slip on a broomstick.
Solar eclipses were of no use.
How is Aliisa?
Is this out of concern?
That's how a blow could prepare a parachute for the witch.
Oh grandma!
Where am I?
In the Moomin house!
Moomin...
You've hurt your back, stay in bed!
What has happened to me?
Guess where it is? This is my bone.
It won't come down because your spell is affecting it.
Hilppati, happati, silmati, sossistu, broom alaset.
Now we're going home.
Can you get up?
Well, of course.
You have to stay long.
Witches don't lie down.
Tolerable.
To end up in a Moomin house of all places in the world.
Moominpapa carried you the whole way.
Don't add to my pain, this is already humiliating enough.
I don't always eat their wacky crap.
Are you sure your grandma doesn't want to eat anything?
Yes, even though Liemi looked so nice.
He is too depressed.
Maybe he needs a spider's web as a seasoning.
You said I don't want to eat.
I don't want food or drink.
Grandma, grandma wants.
I want to eat.
You said I don't want to eat.
I don't want food or drink.
Grandma, Grandma wants the best for you.
Wait a minute.
Would it be possible to taste vaapukka juice after all?
Let me be.
Grandma!
Now I'm going home.
Lying down will be enough.
Are you healthy yet?
Scratch the frog, maiti will heal me.
What about me?
You go to sleep.
Grandma!
I want to eat.
I have to thank the Moomins for taking care of me Teese.
Oh, and have fun with them.
Grandma!
Moomins are for witches.
For the first time, Alisa could play with the children of the Moomin house without feeling bad about herself.