I have a big load of laundry waiting.
A day to talk about for a long time.
Really. Moominma was humming even more than usual.
Moominma was humming even more than usual.
Oh.
Hemuli investigated whether the rain had brought out new plants.
This plant shouldn't bloom anymore.
Last year, quite a bit. Wait a minute.
Right. Blooms a month later than last year.
Hi Hemuli. Good morning.
What did you do?
He has found a plant again.
Hemuli.
Oh, you're there.
Glad the rain finally stopped.
We go to collect mushrooms.
Good idea. There are impossible mushrooms in the forest over there.
I didn't expect to see that plant here.
It needs to be studied carefully.
I'm kind of interested in a plant.
And not all of them are even pretty.
And no edibles.
What luck. Another one too.
I don't see even a glimpse of a mushroom in you.
Me neither.
Let's go deeper into the forest.
Let's see who collects the most.
I win.
The one who collects the least gets to take the buckets home.
I am a friend.
I caught the biggest mushroom catch.
I guess it's the quality and not the quantity.
My mushrooms are edible.
Mother promised to make mushroom stew.
Let's all go eat.
Hurrah!
I love mushroom stew.
Oh the spring of life! I brutally saw mushrooms.
We have to save some or we get to eat mushrooms for the whole week.
What is yours?
Nose itches. Come to think of it, I haven't had a hay fever in years.
Oh, what's causing that glow.
I have never seen this mushroom before.
Well, neither do I.
The mushroom didn't glow with Takuu when it was put in the cocoon.
How does it taste?
You should never eat unknown mushrooms.
I'm going to lay them all out here.
I got the mushroom book.
It's not quite that. That mushroom is not in the book.
Images may be inaccurate. Browse again.
You won't find that in the book. If it's a new species.
Joo.
It has been found!
Wouldn't it be best to ask Hemul?
I brought him here.
I'll come along.
A new species of mushroom.
Moominpa said you should come and see those mushrooms.
And right there!
All right. I will come.
Please wait for the reference works.
This and this.
Sorry to keep you waiting.
Let's get rid of the twigs and pine cones.
Well, how about mushrooms?
They are a new species at Takuu.
Our name will appear in the newspaper.
And the name of the mushroom will be ehkuvat myiha pero.
Isn't there a hit name?
And it isn't. The mushroom is called Nipsu rousku.
I can't find a mushroom in the library either.
May indeed be a new species.
We get fame.
I want a statue of me put in the Academy of the road.
I need to get a bigger statue.
The statue must be beautiful and collectable.
Don't get excited prematurely.
Many things still need to be checked.
Moominma's mushroom soup is the best in the world.
I love this recipe.
Impossibly good.
Thanks to the hardworking mushroom pickers.
Hemuli, Would you still like it?
No thanks.
Moominpapa, can I borrow the study?
You can. I can't work on a full stomach.
Thanks. So I'm leaving.
How about a cup of coffee?
No, no, no.
Not for me either. There was no empty stomach left.
Will Hemuli stay with us for the night?
Very possible.
How come those mushrooms haven't hurt before?
How come those mushrooms haven't hurt my eyes before?
Although I have been there often.
They may have come from space.
The spores have been floating in the universe for millions of years.
Just hardly.
I'm going to take a guest year.
Do it. This hay fever, or whatever it is, is taking all my strength.
You better go to bed papa.
Good suggestion.
Oh, oh.
You take this to Hemul.
Hemuli, Hemuli.
He has fallen asleep.
Of course it takes power.
Hemuli doesn't die. Can't hear.
I guess I checked for a moment.
Look. As if the mushrooms had changed.
What? Oh.
Amazing.
Oh, oh. The cap has changed shape and the color has intensified.
A strange phenomenon. Oops.
The sponge shakes.
Oh.
Mushrooms smoke.
Fungal spores, probably.
I don't tend to spread them anymore.
And there are a lot of spores.
You see. Now the caps have become star-shaped.
Interesting.
Wait a minute. Now it looks more familiar.
A very interesting mushroom.
Listen, Hemul.
So?
Isn't that the one?
Oh right, Mar. That's what it looks like when it's older.
There is no picture of the young mushroom in the book.
We're not going to be famous.
Yeah, it's not a new species.
In the northern mountains, mushrooms grow abundantly in rainy summers.
I'm terribly tired.
The mushroom seems to explode and spread its spores over a wide area.
It makes me tired too.
If spores get out of your body, then...
So what happens?
No clue. Let's continue tomorrow.
Good. Tomorrow.
Now I don't like to listen.
I'll sleep like a baby for sure.
It's too much trouble to go to the weather.
The room should be tidied up, but...
Kaiserehti not tomorrow either.
Oh, it's raining again.
This year we have received more rain than necessary.
The upstairs windows must be closed.
That I wouldn't have been able to fly.
It started to get so weak.
Has the top spiral always been this far?
Let it be five through the window.
Let's sit down to rest first.
And then I close the windows.
Has the top spiral always been this far?
Oh oh.
Mom, mom, what's wrong.
Oh good morning papa.
Mom, what does this mean? Why are you sleeping here?
Your forehead feels a little hot.
You don't have a cold at all.
Ekohan.
Oh, what's yours?
So tired I couldn't open the door.
I was waiting for you to open.
And apparently I fell asleep while waiting.
You woke me up.
Special type.
It's true that you catch a cold when you sleep on a cool landing.
Mars immediately to bed.
I obey from papakuula.
Oh, just like that.
What happened to mom?
Wake up, Moomin.
The boy is up early.
Moomin, Do you sleep here?
And Hemuli too.
Good morning.
Good morning dad.
Have you stayed up all night studying mushrooms?
Are we?
No, before it.
Moomin, something is coming to see mothers' trouble.
Joo.
I don't think you're fine either?
I am.
Then come quickly, quickly!
Don't be so busy, Papa Moomin.
What?
Don't get excited.
Mamma is the same if she sleeps a little.
What's wrong with you?
Now try to wake up.
I think I'm awake.
But I'm not at all sure if it's comfortable for me.
Listen, Moomin papa.
I'm still taking doubles today.
I have to agree that you look tired.
Hey, look, the mushrooms have changed shape.
Oh yeah, I remember something like that.
Too troublesome to try to remember.
I'd much rather just go rogue.
Hey, that's the mushroom in this picture.
The mushroom is sometimes called the knockout mushroom.
Being protected from rain strengthens its properties.
When the spores enter the body, they cause restlessness.
That's the explanation. That's why everyone is so sleepy.
How nasty spores? What the hell am I doing to you?
The forest is still full of those mushrooms.
And there have been more since yesterday's rain.
If they dust their spores in Moominvalley, everyone will get sleeping sickness.
I find it enjoyable in the meadows.
And it's not!
Moomin goblin, where are those mushrooms located?
It's not that easy to explain.
Here is a pen and papers. Mark the locations of the mushrooms.
But then I should move my hand.
All right. You say, I'll move my hand. Does it fit?
Yeah, yeah.
First, let's go straight.
I see. Straight from the Moomin house.
So what?
Directly?
Night straight?
Directly or directly?
Directly and directly.
I ran out of paper already.
Let's forget the map. Just tell me.
It's terribly tedious to try to remember.
Johan is now. So what do I do?
Well, Moomin the goblin.
Remember to say when you have to turn.
Yeah, yeah.
It is said in Kerja that if you manage to collect all the mushrooms,
they won't grow back for maybe a hundred years.
So if everything goes away, we're safe.
And Moomin needs to be made normal.
Don't fall asleep, Moomin troll. Please, we need to find the mushrooms.
Dad, don't shake the cart.
We mustn't waste time. Are we still on the right track?
Yeah, I don't grow those mushrooms on them.
Oh, impossible.
Oh, there are too many.
This is what I was afraid of. Jump down and come collect.
It's a big job.
But it has to be done, Moomin troll. Pull yourself together.
Then you can rest as long as you want.
Oh, oh.
Oh, all the mushrooms picked.
Let's take the mushrooms home and burn them.
Moomin goblin, let's go home.
Oh, father, don't leave me here.
Just like a carousel.
I enjoy this much more.
Hen too.
Moomin troll.
Hey.
What do you have in mind?
Should we go to the beach? Starting to feel wet.
Wait, I'll save you.
Muhumi get ashore.
Don't learn.
One hundred and one thousand
Knockout and mushrooms.
Yeah, everyone else fell asleep except dad, who wears a nose mask because of the hay fever.
You need to be delivered home.
The mushrooms must be burned first.
It's not necessary. Mushrooms drift into the sea.
Take my support!
The Moomin troll will definitely come to help, get up.
The journey home took a long time.
A week had passed.
No, I want too.
It doesn't work, the balance is upset!
Hmph!
Au!
Look, now how did it go?
We like to pretend.
Understand it.
Mummy Moomin!
Just come here!
Go sit on it!
Oops, this could be fun.
Come on.
Ui!
Au!
Everyone had now recovered from the silence caused by the member.
But Moominpappa was so stressed that he dived under the covers.
That some people can handle it.
Nights!