I show with my neck.
Since you're going to hang it around your neck anyway, why did you even ask?
I still ask for my kindness, but I can't help but ask.
I'm showing off to the granny troll.
He always answers well as you wish.
I show with my neck.
Granny Goblin!
Where has he disappeared to?
Wake up!
What did Niisku see?
The boat sailed towards here.
Twinkling unknown boat.
Granny Goblin!
What did he like about water?
The boat sailed over him.
Look back there granny troll!
The goblin squealed and got out!
Don't wait!
Dive in now, it'll bite your brain too!
Wake up!
There is more to worry about granny troll
than all others combined.
Is everything okay?
All good.
Horribly naughty sailing.
Pursi heads to the Ipsu rock.
Hmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmm
Not a single sint.
If I return home in style
can imagine selling.
Ipsu idiots!
Of course, tie the hook to the line, right?
What? Oh, yes I set the hook. No, you can't pull, I can't swim.
Stop, no, you can't. Help, help. Oh, no, no, no, no, no, no.
Help, help, help, help, help, help, help, help, help.
Calm down, everything is fine. I was saved.
Well, family, new excursion spot. Go ashore.
We spent many hours at sea.
There don't seem to be any other hikers, but don't worry mom.
Yes, we'll make it. I don't think we have any friends other than each other.
A bit primitive.
Well, mom, let's roll. By the way, it's too quiet here.
Oh, you.
They use our beach.
Sly noisy. It annoys me.
The fun goblin went to drive them away.
Why? Why me?
You are the wisest.
They can be pirates.
I've never heard of pirates that dance.
All right. I'll go talk to them.
Good day.
Kas, have a good day.
What do you like about the beach?
Fine. Even without favors.
You can hardly even get a hamburger here.
But welcome to the club.
Aren't you just pirates?
Of course. How did you know?
We are, of course, our Meriroscope family.
I have to go.
Goodbye.
I was right. They are pirates.
What do we do now?
Oh, pirates.
I'm going to bite them so they leave.
And you won't go. Stay tuned, Simi.
They are pirates. What do we do now?
Oh, pirates.
I'm going to bite them so they leave.
And you won't go. Stay tuned, Simi.
They need to drive off our shores.
Beware of pirates.
Are you trying to say that we will let them take over our beach in peace?
I guess there's nothing else you can do here.
We have to drive them away so they don't realize we're behind it all.
And if that method doesn't work, I'm going to bite.
I have one inch.
Tell me.
Let's lie.
I'm going to bite.
Tell me.
They lie that the sea is teeming with sharks and other beasts.
I came to warn you.
Hello ma'am.
Oh from what?
There are sharks in these waters.
Great white killer sharks.
There they are again.
Ai, ai.
Sharks have caught many swimmers from the beach.
Fingers and noses wash up on the beach.
Hey, come out now.
Be careful, hey.
What?
Hi, hi.
A short walk to the beach.
Please wait for me.
No hurry.
Speed up, run for breath.
Speed up.
Hehe
We have a gun after all.
What are you driving?
I'll shoot it from the shark's breath.
Oh, no, no, no? Come on, that's not a good idea.
Don't stop me.
What if you have other vite cosa?
I mean your kids, no shooting.
Titten's shed for the present.
He's hooded.
What?
Oh, save, girl, save!
Yes, Voovi-Peikko will definitely save him.
Hold on to me.
That's what you saw.
Thank you, thank you, children.
You saved your daughter's life.
I don't even know how to reward you.
I can't thank you enough.
The girl would surely have either drowned or fallen into the teeth of a shark,
if you hadn't come to help.
They don't have much to give, but you take this.
No, no, I can't take anything. No kidding.
Who or... Please accept it as a token of our gratitude.
I'm so kind.
Thanks, Vaino.
Au!
Is something bothering you? No, no, no problem.
Oops, that was not a successful operation. What now?
So. They seem pretty nice to me.
Oh, you'd let them stay on the beach huh?
At least we could play together. The kids have a good ball.
Shut up. You only changed your mind because you got treats from them.
It's not true. Don't always misrepresent.
Hey, stop bickering. Sanaharkkai help us a bit.
I've lost my sister. I just don't know.
Where is your fighting spirit?
There's trash in that, too.
How naughty pirates throw trash around it?
Loudness can still be forgiven, but not littering the beach.
Littering the beach of Önäsity
Oh, you're probably the beach trash collector.
I can give you these scraps. I don't know where you put it.
Well, just thanks.
Voice, why is this tune getting so thick?
Thick?
That I'm fat?
You bitch!
Miss you, nothing...
Don't you collect roju collection?
What now? I'm going home.
You bitch!
What's wrong with you? We're coming home too.
Did I say something wrong?
I don't know.
Listen dad, how do we get the pirates off our shores?
Do they have to be evicted then?
It is because they litter the beach and appoint me as a beach cleaner.
And they don't even look like real pirates?
The beach is ours and we want it back.
Oh your beach.
I doubt you're right about that, my boy.
How so?
For example, it feels good to take a nap in the sun,
but you can't own the sun.
It stays in the sky to everyone's delight, doesn't it?
In the same way, the beach is intended for everyone's use.
Yes, but...
So are we doing wrong in trying to evict them?
We got sweets and apples from them.
What are you talking about, Nipsu? Don't care what happens to the beach?
Because you can't swim and you can't fish.
If you and mummy don't drive them away, we will.
Yeah, for sure.
Sniff, snuff, what do you say?
If someone tried to break my lip harp, I would defend it to the death.
I'm sure everyone has something important that they won't give up.
So we defend our own shore.
Mumipekko and Nipsu, quick.
Why do you need so many branches?
Don't ask me about it.
Wait, this time you're leaving.
What the hell is a little girl aiming for when she makes a campfire?
Ha, the sale is here.
Will it return? Burn.
But how does burning a campfire relate to chasing away pirates?
You'll find out soon, won't you?
What do you need so much seaweed for?
You'll see.
The algae is really wet.
Doubles, thick foul-smelling smoke.
And when the wind blows from the south, all the smoke goes into the pirates' mouths.
Aha, you're going to drive the pirates out of their way with smoke.
Yeah, dude, you're not the idiot.
That sudden note is all that burns.
Uuu, get up, get up, bucket, smoke.
You'll soon learn what it's like to be on the same beach with a little baby.
Hihihi.
Oops, the wind is changing direction.
Hey, come hang out.
I'm from there now.
Hey, let it go, let it go.
We have to give it a go.
We must.
Cool velli pants.
It doesn't matter where that smoke comes from.
Someone must be krill.
You are hot pants.
No one can suffer from smoke for that long.
Not so. It's true.
Yes, but the wind has changed direction again.
Re. I make a lot of smoke at work because of it.
I think the smoke is bad for me.
Nipsu, I guess you want to get the beach back?
Not right now.
Aite, the children are here.
Good day again.
Thanks for the goodies.
What are you doing there?
Since it's almost lunchtime, we thought we'd fry some fish.
Hoho, it happened at a good time.
I thought we would cook soon.
Can we come to the campfire together?
Of course. Just be nice.
Yes, that's fine.
Good. Hello, aite. To cook food.
Idiot, you ruined everything again.
Which one did I fit in?
Things on wheels. A real picnic.
The single stem looks ripe already.
Isn't it a treat? Poke your cheeks.
Yeah, yeah.
What's wrong with you kids?
Eat as much as you can.
You're not hungry at all.
If you have had too much sun.
Pity throws good food away.
Yeah, really.
Ipsu!
That...
We remembered that we have work to do.
Do I have to do it right away? It's sad.
Yeah, yeah. Excuse me now.
I have nothing to do.
Ipsu, aren't you letting us down?
It wasn't meant to be.
We have to go now and have some fun.
This is good. Eat this.
Do you offer?
We have a lot of grilled sausages.
Thanks. Ipsu, you want to come before I get mad.
Don't always dream of delicacies.
You know what we have to think about now?
Yeah, I know.
Maybe they're not the kind of people you can drive away.
We must hope for a gale or a whirlwind to help us.
A hurricane that after sucking is.
This is good.
A hurricane that will suck them into its throat.
Where is the hurricane?
Tell me, I'll order it here.
Ipsu, in your head it's coming.
I was just kidding.
Ipsu, do what you do, but don't try to count the fun.
Hey, that's what got me thinking.
Now a way was found.
Now.
Jaha, you guys gave up, you're not trying to evict pirates from the beach anymore.
Are you tired of some trick?
Well, no.
You can see from your face that you haven't given up after all.
We're not!
Look at what we're building.
This cow predicts the weather.
Or like that?
Here comes the benefits.
Well, I guess you know how to read the Weather Bulletin.
Trust me admit, be careful.
Do pirates believe the weather forecast I sell?
Will you come to my place?
You should have your ears and legs cut off first.
Isn't it you or something?
I trust you now!
Is everything okay?
Don't wave!
Don't bounce there!
Don't stop! You don't like the nativity scene straight!
Sell, now you can start!
Don't fool around!
Don't interrupt me, I'm trying out my voice!
Don't wave, pirates can hear most of what you say.
Plimplomplomplum!
Emergency notification! Emergency notification!
Hat notice for people on the beach!
Let's get out of here now! A typhoon wind that is being approached by a mummy boat!
What?
The 40 foot high waves swept away the sand as well as the hikers!
Go either north or south!
I must say that cleverly invented.
From what I hear, shouldn't we tell those human holes,
that everything is just a joke?
I don't want people on our beach either.
Oh papa.
Lord time.
Kids, hurry to the boat.
Photo hikers have five minutes to collect their backpacks and leave.
Good invention.
So. They are in such a hurry they trip over their own feet.
Come on, have fun!
Nipsu, from you!
I support it too.
Come on!
Sky! The typhoon is indeed here!
I have supernatural powers! I can kill the wind!
Moomin-Pekka is selling, nipsu, are you breathing?
Au!
Get off me.
Anna, excuse me.
You kids here again. What are you doing now?
We're just taking a walk.
On foot, yes.
Let me out!
Misery! This time we almost succeeded in driving them away.
To expel whom?
Well, who do you think you are?
Why?
Our! And we don't want you here.
Your beach?
So.
The rain finally came.
Is it possible for the boat to be properly closed?
Oh. Oh no.
Moomin-Pekko.
Mom and Dad, what are you doing there?
Don't ask. Come and help with securing the boat.
Oh! Oh!
Oh!
You were very helpful.
Just thank you.
You know how our life would have turned out if you weren't there.
Indeed. Many thanks to everyone.
If the truth be told, then...
It sounds like you guys really like the beach.
We should have asked permission to land.
Not when we should be apologizing.
We don't own the beach.
We could have played together.
You said it right.
Now can we have some hot tea?
Yes, please.
Thanks.
A hot cup is good after a typhoon.
You have a good weather service.
It's true.
You probably don't have a home because you're pirates.
What? I thought I was kidding then.
Or that way?
It seemed strange to us that pirates have children.
This is how we spend summer vacation.
Sailing around.
From here, we thought about reversals.
We have together.
A couple of us decided to head south.
So?
Take this reward at random.
It's probably worth it.
You could get a good price for that.
A pinch!
It is the left eye of the salmon roll.
I got it as spoils of war in the China Sea.
Just like that.
Moomin, boss. Beware that ye transgress it.
Can you imagine a real salmon snake eye?
Don't believe everything he says.
It's just a crystal ball.
It's not from the China Sea.
Hi everyone then!
Too many of them!
I told you a trick!
Let's meet!
Hey!