Moomin with his family and friends was going out on the water in a boat that had been found on the beach.
The destination of the trip had not been decided, because it is more fun to travel that way.
Honey we will be back.
Let's hope.
We don't need that much stuff.
You never know about the sea.
Well, no, but...
There we have to light a campfire.
We collect trees from the island.
Yes, but it's tiring if it's raining or if the island is bare.
It's not an adventure after all.
Excursion life can be nice too.
Hey, screw it up!
Hey!
Moomin!
Hey niskunäiti!
Could you have fallen?
Pops.
Be more careful or you will hurt yourself.
It was good practice.
Is your brother coming?
He is obsessed with his blue copies.
Oh, boys, let's hit the water in a real sailboat.
Is it ready?
This doesn't look like it!
Shall we take it all in?
I just came up with this.
Moomin, where exactly are we going?
We don't know that.
Emme.
Hemuli!
Did you find a rarity?
I don't. I'm afraid I already have this in my collection.
Jeez, are you guys moving?
We're going on a boat trip.
Oh yes! And no one objects.
No.
But why do you need so many struggles?
There are still many here.
To the sails!
Anchors up!
Go for it!
To the port!
Haven't the Moomins come yet?
They don't!
Isn't it a great day?
Where are we going?
It hasn't been decided yet.
I don't want to go anywhere far.
Why don't you?
I'm not a good swimmer.
If the ship gets into trouble at sea, I'd just be a burden.
Look at the weather.
There is not the slightest chance of a storm.
Thanks. All aboard.
Mummy Moomin.
Myy.
Nzkamuikkun.
Niskuneiti.
Hemuli.
Let's go.
Are you going too?
Moomin Mappa said that we will stop on an island.
I could collect rare plants.
Speed up the hairpin.
The boat is completely.
Yes, you can join too.
Go a day while waiting.
Maybe that trickle broke Kameli's back.
Fool. The boat could carry many more.
Do you see?
Yes, one can still fit. Isn't that right, dad?
Of course. The sea is almost calm.
Let's go.
Kerquom 2004
Hu approval.
Mecca
Worried about Niinus!
A pinch should have come along too.
The trick is the Janis pants!
Well, he's pretty bad at swimming now.
Besides, he eats too much.
This is life.
It is.
Oh, we've gotten into trouble.
There's nothing to do but start rowing.
Shouldn't.
No.
There's nothing to do but start rowing.
Shouldn't.
Muikkunen, take the oar.
Clear.
I row faster.
See Souda briskly.
Don't even bother with our work.
We're moving, albeit slowly.
There were galleys.
There must be a strong current at this point.
Strong current.
Oh my goodness, I didn't get a new plant this time.
Throw the fishing line into the water in the nose and start collecting seaweed.
Whistle the wind.
Many a sailor has drowned at the bottom.
Oh, look.
There's an island over there.
Too small to do anything there.
Not for me!
Aha, even if I don't row, we move forward.
The wind has picked up.
Look, beautiful island.
Sata Maki is pretty good.
I bet there are completely unknown plants here.
Watch out for wild beasts and cannibals.
I'm dying to get a cup of coffee.
Someone gets to go look for driftwood on the beach.
Dad, I'm jumping rope.
The goods were needed.
We live an excursion life, but comfortably.
Perhaps we are the first on this island.
Oh, thank you.
What else?
The island should be explored.
I'm going on a research trip.
Explore all locations.
Let's go on a research trip.
What?
Explore all locations.
Are you coming along?
I'll stay with grandma.
Here comes the wood for the bonfire of the shipwrecked.
Oh, how much.
I think the island is uninhabited.
I wouldn't be surprised at all. I haven't seen anyone.
I am.
Who?
Medium size, White.
What do you mean medium size?
Just like me.
What did it look like?
White to the pool, like I said.
A bit like a ghost.
You just haven't seen the visions, little one.
And you don't believe me?
I believe. You think you saw something.
Three wakes and seven sows.
An exciting find.
That must be it.
What a find.
This island is bursting with rarities.
What is that?
Mr. Dad, the barometer shows rain and a storm broke apparently.
Hey, what the hell are you guys?
This is your barometer, right?
Let's go your way.
Don't trample all the plants on them.
I think Myy has seen the hat.
Are Hattivats ghost-like?
Yes, they look a bit like ghosts, but they are harmless.
Someone was clearly yelling for help.
In the heme of c oli thalassemia.
Let's go away.
Help, help, ouch.
How many hattiwatts?
Hemuli of the park.
Help me go down.
What have you been doing when the Hattivats are so angry?
Nothing else when I knocked this lock.
It hardly angered Hattivati.
I also clicked on the barometer to see what kind of weather was coming.
Maybe the Hattivats thought you were going to steal the barometer.
Nuhuska muikkunken.
Tell them I don't want a barometer.
How do we expel them?
Hurry up.
I'll slide down.
We have to do something.
I'm thinking.
Hurry up.
Now I invented Hemuli.
Hattivats cannot see or hear well, but they have a very sensitive sense of touch.
Swing the lock even back.
Did I see that?
Harder.
Do you see? They feel the vibrations of the earth.
Keep rocking.
My hands get heavy when I write.
I'm falling.
Rocking seems to work well.
Hemuli!
Are you OK?
Disgusting creatures.
I'll take their crappy barometer.
It feels.
I'm next.
I'll take their crappy barometer.
That's hardly wise.
This doesn't even work.
How do you know that?
The weather is great now, but this barometer shows rain and thunderstorms.
Real pancakes instead of canned.
I know what is needed on a trip.
Moominpappa knows how to plan everything so well.
The barometer shows deep low pressure.
There's going to be a storm.
A terrible squall, if the barometer of the hats is intact.
Hemuli, yes the barometer may be intact.
Look at the horizon.
A heavy squall is coming up.
Hurry home before it hits.
There is no time, we are in trouble at sea.
What can we do now?
It would be a waste to go home right away.
We haven't even gotten to explore the other side of the island at all.
I want to study hat wadding.
I don't. Absolutely not.
I think we should go.
What do you say mom?
Honey, you're the captain.
Good, Annas, while I think about it.
We will stay.
Really?
So hurry up.
We have to do this.
Let's go.
So hurry up. We have to set up a tent.
A tent?
Of course. Mummy Moomin has also packed the tent.
Is there? Mom, you're an exaggeration.
First, the sail is trimmed and hauled to the boat's shore.
Prepare.
I don't think the waves reach that far.
Next, the tent.
Don't procrastinate.
Oh hey, maybe this is too much for me.
Not sitting there and resting.
However, I am.
I'm going straight to this tent.
You stay here.
But when you get up,
remember to put the rope on the tree.
Is that right?
You can trust me.
Well, let's get to work.
Oh hemuli parka.
I haven't come across this before.
This is certainly rare.
I'm snuffling.
What does it look like?
There is a gray curtain over the sea.
It will rain soon.
I'm up.
There is a gray curtain over the sea.
It will rain soon.
Let's go before we get wet.
No, no.
What now?
It's so exciting.
It's great to stand on the shore of the bubbling sea and watch the rising storm.
So?
And at the right moment.
So that you avoid getting wet.
Exactly.
What are the Hattivats up to?
They are waiting for a thunderstorm.
Why?
They become electric in a thunderstorm.
Really?
Oh, now it's dripping.
Don't be afraid.
I am your safety.
A storm.
A thunderbolt struck close by.
Certainly.
The storm is over.
from this day.
If you have been stranded on a desert island in a heavy storm,
can't help but wait for the storm to subside.
But if the waves and rising water suck the boat's hull,
does worse.