TSM channel
...
Ui...
The sick girl that Nipsu had found and taken to the Moomin House slept late the next morning.
Good morning!
Good morning, Moomin.
How is the girl?
The fever is on its way.
Oh, he's still sleeping.
Grandma's medicine took away the fever, but she is very tired. Rest is good for him.
What about the patient?
Better already. The color has returned to the cheeks and the fever has subsided. He'll recover from it soon.
Mmm...
These flowers, I have plucked the twigs for you, oh lovely maiden.
Hey, it's so exciting to be excited.
Good morning, Papa Moomin.
Morning, you're up early.
Is Moomin still sleeping?
Joo.
Not that I'm interested, but how is the girl?
Better, but he needs another year of rest. Don't worry.
Would I worry?
Fireworks rockets.
Yes, and handsome. Rumblings were heard many nights, but the cause of them was only discovered on the beach.
Myi noticed a wonderful light phenomenon from behind these trees.
Or with the roar of the firework rockets, it almost woke me up too.
They were loud.
They were handsome looking, but terribly noisy.
It was remarkable that no one saw fireworks from here in Moomin Valley.
They were shot into the sky from too far away.
Tongo, the beach is close and you have to watch the fireworks from a distance.
Sell, why weren't they visible here?
Idiot, that's what I'm wondering when I don't know.
Well, who's messing with us?
Does it hurt?
Yes, and could have supervised me.
It wobbles in a different cunning way.
I'm going with you tonight.
Ai, minne?
Well, to the beach to catch the wind.
That's what you're going to do.
And that, I haven't talked to Nuuska Muikkunen yet.
I'm talking to me.
Listen Nipsu, if someone wants to shoot firework rockets at night stealthily,
that someone wants to remain invisible for sure.
Well, it's obvious.
If he doesn't want to show himself, maybe we should leave him alone.
Petya, at least I'm leaving.
Alone on the beach in the middle of the night?
Not me alone. There will also be a retail sale.
It's the same for me.
If you don't dare, go alone.
Eh, that's not what I meant.
I guess you also want to know who is there?
Sorry to bother you, but would someone go and change the wet towel on the girl's forehead?
I have my hands full with work.
Er, I'm going!
are you going
What's wrong with you?
I saved the girl's life, maybe you can't trust anyone.
Oh!
Remember not to wring the towel too much in the water.
Yeah. What the hell has happened?
He's completely messed up.
Hi, and haa.
Oh.
About.
Sleeping Beauty.
Oh.
Oh!
No, you just stay in bed.
who are you
Don't you remember me?
I'm a jerk.
I saved lives, I brought you here.
Oh, right?
You don't remember me, even though I'm strutting around in a sweat hat.
Oh, I apologize.
You told me that you had come to see the hemul and then went to work.
Hemulia?
Woe to you, Don't you even remember the hemuli?
I don't. Oh, stop stoned.
Fear not, it may not be fatal. I'm calling mommy Moomin.
Is it your mother?
Not like Moomin. This is a Moomin house.
Moomin house. Moomin.
Tytte has already woken up.
Well, did he say something?
Nothing to mention. He doesn't remember me.
Really?
How is that possible? I held him above me and he looked at me.
Is it hard to remember my face?
I find them harder to forget.
Did you ask his name?
I forgot.
Is there anything new about the girl?
He has woken up.
It's fun.
Let's go take a look.
Just stay in your fields.
No stone unturned. I already feel good.
Oh great.
Is your aunt a Moomin?
I am. What do you already know?
That boy tells and I think aunty looks just like Moomin.
Oh shit. She has picked those flowers for you.
Oh dear.
Tell me what your name is.
My name is Nana.
Would you like the food?
You have slept for a long time.
I'm a little hungry.
I guessed. I'll bring you some soup.
Thanks.
And greetings to that nice boy.
Sorry if I was rude to him.
Nipsu thinks you've lost your memory.
Yours.
Everyone is curious to see you.
I invite them here.
Wake up.
Go further.
The girl is doing great.
Oh, what fun. We were so worried.
Thanks to all of you.
And especially for nips.
Sorry I was dumber when I woke up my lifesaver.
Or so?
What's the little thing?
So trip me up again.
Dude, don't be silly.
Now.
I'm Papa Moomin.
And here is our son Moomin the goblin, the little girl and the little mouse.
Really fun to get to know.
Hemuli also came here, but you were still sleeping.
Ai Hemuli.
I have to meet him. I have an important matter.
Yes, but Hemuli insists adamantly that he doesn't know you.
Yes.
Apparently, my fiance hasn't told Hemul about me.
Groom?
Well, since I'm already engaged.
Engaged?
My fiance has certainly visited Moomin Valley Hemuliluo many times.
Just like that.
Hemuli is a good friend of mine, but she has never talked about anything about Sulhans.
But my fiancé wrote that he is currently in Moomin Valley.
What exactly is the said young man up to?
Making a firework rocket launcher as my father's apprentice.
Phooey!
Would there be any lead varnish for you?
The children did see how someone shot fireworks at the sea yesterday.
It must have been my Fiance. I guessed he's here to make rockets.
Moomin!
Sniff, little one!
What exactly is going on here?
The calculation of the firework rockets has finally been solved.
Well, what's the explanation?
Come quickly! I'll tell you on the way.
I say where we are going.
For Hemul! Speed up!
Just like that.
Good!
Glad you like it. I have cooked sopa according to my grandfather's recipe.
You are so kind to me.
Will you take more?
Thanks, I can't.
I'm still trying to sleep for a while. The children go in search of your Bridegroom.
Thanks grandma.
Why does Nanan's Husband secretly make firework rockets?
He wants to surprise his bride's father.
This one thinks the Groom doesn't know how to make good firework rockets.
Oh, and the Groom has come to ask Hemul for help.
Nana's father has fallen ill. And now there is no one to make rockets for Midsummer.
That's why Nana came to get her Fiance.
Right. Nana had even tried making rockets herself.
Damn, lucky he tripped over me.
Aha.
My host, didn't I have to register today as well?
I guess not.
Are you sure?
On.
That it wouldn't be at the bottom?
Laadotonta.
You can tell in another letter.
If you didn't notice, may I look in the bag?
You watched it yesterday too, remember?
I remember.
Well, how did it go? Found something?
No. It wasn't found yesterday, but maybe it will be found today.
I can't take it anymore. Penko bag, that's all! Speed, speed!
Do not drop letters.
Well, was there something?
I have never taken Kost to the wrong address.
I know, but I'm waiting for a terribly important letter.
From a young woman, huh?
Hey Hemuli.
Here is the letter.
From the Botanical Society. Seed list probably.
Oh, why did you immediately say?
You doubted me yesterday. I'll pay you back now.
I was actually. Oh guys, I finally made it.
What has happened?
I have discovered a new species.
Oh so?
And the Botanical Society has recognized it.
Congratulations, let's begin.
Good day.
Where is the trip?
For Hemul. Is he at home?
It is, unless it has flown its way on a cloud.
Oh, what fun.
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey.
Hello everyone.
Did you come to congratulate?
What?
Well, thanks.
Do you know the young man who makes firework rockets?
Yeah, that, sort of.
The man's beautiful Bride has come here.
Where is the man? Tell me if you know.
Or the Bride? Could that girl from yesterday be his Bride?
On.
The girl finally woke up and told us everything.
Oh, what a relief.
The groom prepares firework rockets in the cave for Midsummer.
Is that true?
Yes, but he asked me to keep it a secret for now.
We go last night to a spectacular fireworks display.
Good. Then he has had time to prepare.
Let's go see the man and tell him his Bride is here.
Brag it. The young people will surely be happy when they see each other again.
Then travel every hoof.
No wait!
Tell him that I have now been officially recognized as the discoverer of a new species of kämmekka.
Oh, that's great! Good luck and success!
Congratulations!
Thank you!
You are something to be proud of. Well, go already!
Hey!
Is the groom here?
Let's shout!
Yay!
Hey there!
Hoi!
I don't think it's here.
Let's investigate!
This!
Are you scared?
I'm not interested in meeting anyone from the groom, nothing else.
Let's go!
Ahoy!
Nana's fiancé, I guess.
How do you know my bride?
Here.
Thanks.
In.
Oh you!
I'm on my way now.
What are you in a hurry to do?
If I find another new species.
Of course, I could still become an honorary member of the botanical society.
Hemuli!
We would like to arrange some cookies for you.
Friendly.
I've changed a lot since we last met.
Now I understand what your father was trying to explain to me.
I have learned how beautiful flowers are from my uncle Hemuli.
Fireworks can be just as beautiful.
Great beats and correct colors alone are not enough.
They must form a whole.
Oh, be so happy.
I finally got some cool rockets born and tried them out last night.
I am very satisfied.
Someone else saw the fireworks.
The engaged couple decided to go to their homes, but before that they were raped by fireworks.
And in honor of Hemul, the table was set in Korean.
Dear friends, we have been touched by a great honor to have Hemul with us this beautiful evening.
Our friend has discovered a new species of palm carp, which will soon be named Hemulensis or Hemuli Formis.
Our renowned botanist will tell you in more detail in a moment.
Hemuli, describe the new palm.
The palm I found has sixteen sows in a row and...
Oh good, unusual, that's exactly what the new palm is like.
Hemul was thoroughly celebrated well into the night.
Thanks for watching.