Have you heard of Moomin Valley?
In winter, it sleeps deep in cinemas.
You see, all rational beings fall into hibernation as soon as Moomin Valley is covered in a blanket of snow.
This is the Moomin House.
Do you notice? They are reasonable people.
Here is Moomin, the hero of our story.
This is Moominpapa.
And this Moominma.
Oh, and this vekkul is so small that it must be a small one.
You never know who you'll find sleeping in Moomin House.
But now it's time to start the story.
However, it can get boring if everyone is asleep.
Don't you want to jump straight into spring?
Spring. Spring has come.
Hi everyone! Hello, it's spring!
Moomin!
Oh, are you awake too?
Who can sleep when you wake up?
I shouted from Riemu.
Say one thing.
Well what?
Do you find it fun to wake others up?
Of course.
I just dreamed that I lived in a watermelon.
You have to get up, the sun is shining.
What's so amazing about that?
Winter is over, spring has come and life is wonderful.
Sleeping is wonderful too.
You told us to wake you up on the first day of spring.
Did I order?
Don't you remember?
Well, pretty casually.
You can go back to sleep if you want.
However, I can't sleep anymore.
There you see.
Mother!
Happy spring, Moomin troll.
Moomin mom, I'm hungry.
Do you have watermelon?
No, but much more.
Let's prepare a really sumptuous breakfast.
Nuuska Muikkunen is back.
You can get there faster along the highways.
It wouldn't be half as much fun.
Are you going to leave your house?
Oh yes, it was fun to spend the winter at your place.
Your sister hasn't come back yet.
I'm still going!
Sniff, little one!
Hello Moomin troll.
You came back early this year.
Could be.
Wasn't your trip fun?
That was it.
But I sensed that spring had already come.
Tell me about your trip.
Sometimes the Moomin of others.
Let's go wake up Nipsu and do something special.
Nipsu doesn't like to be woken up.
I hear snoring.
Let's whistle one more time.
The snoring stopped.
Dude, come out.
Nuuska Muikkunen is here.
I want to sleep.
We are going to do something special.
Oh special?
Maybe by this year.
I want to sleep.
Maybe climbing this mountain is special.
We can be the first to climb to the top.
I saw it on a cloudless day.
The whole Moomin valley should be visible from the top.
Good morning.
Good morning? Are parents following?
Mom was there when I left.
Yes.
A strange way to hibernate.
We enjoy it.
Why do you always have to do something special?
Beautiful.
Not a great view at all.
Smoke rises from the chimney of the Moomin house.
Mummy Moomin is cooking something delicious.
What?
Someone has been here before us.
Look.
Silencers.
Big and black.
Could it be anyone's?
Dad could use it on Sundays.
Page.
Pretty much bigger than me.
Do you see?
It's hard to see the point of this.
Even deeper.
My hat is better.
What is it?
The hat feels shrunk.
I'm not pulling it off.
Autan.
The voice is swollen.
What is it?
The hat got stuck on the father's head.
The old hat is indeed stylish.
This hat is not mine.
The kids found it.
It's beautiful.
What do we do about it?
I don't like the whole hat.
Throw away?
That would be a shame.
Do you know someone big enough?
In.
It's good for this.
Or into a trash can?
Well guessed Nuuska Muikkunen.
Let's have breakfast now.
Come to the table too, Nuuska Muikkunen.
Lovely smell.
See you out with Moomin.
Will you come along?
Or do you prefer to stay here?
What, are you going to spend?
You will present the future?
Moisture.
Now it's almost ready.
This year, my flight deck is finally finished.
No.
Needs finishing.
Is it even possible to build an airplane?
Well, of course it isn't.
Niisku has dreamed of building one.
You can always dream.
I settled for more modest dreams.
So do I.
Do you ever stop eating?
I guess you're not dreaming about anything.
Sure, I dream of an empty pantry.
Who here has eaten eggs?
It's good that there is finally a trash can.
What are the young people now?
They look like clouds.
Do not touch, they may be poisoned.
I'm floating.
Lovely.
I want too.
Are you comfortable with it?
We went.
What if you fall?
What if the clouds rise right up and someone falls?
Long cloud.
Wait, wait cloud.
I'm falling, I'm falling
Moominpappa is writing his memoirs.
An awful lot of everything has happened to him.
Memoirs become unusually extensive.
Yes?
Sky.
Moomin troll.
What the hell are you doing?
I'm flying, these clouds just came out of the house.
Come closer.
I will save you.
You don't have to.
Wait, stop.
Dad, hop on board.
On my dare.
Jump or fall.
Too late.
Mom, emergency.
Well, now what?
You know what kids do?
I know.
They sail on the clouds, see.
I told them to be careful not to fall out.
Pinch, are you ready?
I can.
Wait, cloud, come back.
I'll be nice now, don't move.
That's right.
Right in your fields, cloud.
What?
We play together again, cloud.
Come, come, come here.
What, a cloud?
My cloud is shrinking.
Blacksmithing was fun.
Yes, but I haven't finished yet.
Are Moomin and Ladybug there?
Hey hey.
Their clouds last longer.
But they are also dwindling.
They would come down already.
Hoi!
I'm starting to count.
One.
All.
Do you want something?
Good hiding place.
Are there any good hiding places here?
This is where you can find me.
Come, come here.
But!
Yes, Moomin must be in the house.
I saw Moomin crawling into the fireplace.
Did you find it?
In.
Looking from the basement?
Of course.
Did someone just laugh?
Cry?
I have to go home.
Is something wrong?
There is. I still haven't found it.
There is. I still haven't found a Moomin.
He is so thick that there is no good hiding place.
Hey, there's laughter over there.
Here I am.
Let's imagine I'm the only one who wasn't found.
who are you
You don't know me do you?
You tried hard.
And you didn't find.
Please introduce yourself.
Or so? Is this some new game?
I'm a swamp lady, what about you?
Well, I'm the king of Moominvalley.
You are too ugly to be king.
That was unkindly said.
Wasn't it the father?
Do you know where Moomin hides?
Here he is.
Where?
Well, here.
Now you get permission to tell who you really are.
Father?
I'm not your father.
You are. I'm a Moomin.
Moomin is kind and funny looking.
Not like you.
Have you looked in the mirror?
What does this mean?
My entire muzzle is gone.
No!
I'm hairy all over and...
My tail is now thick.
I had a dream.
This cannot be true.
This is too horrible.
What do you shout with?
What has happened?
Go!
What on earth?
He claims to be a Moomin.
Is this my moomin baby?
It's me.
I really am a Moomin.
Are you a believer?
are you
I guess I've changed somehow.
Calm down, calm down.
Yes, this will work out.
You have nothing to worry about,
if you really are a Moomin.
Say I'm a Moomin.
Healthy if.
Say you know me already.
I don't know what you think about this,
but i'm me
Mom say I'm your very own Moomin.
I'm a Moomin.
Say it, mom.
Don't I know my own child?
Mother.
You really are my own Moomin child.
Hi mom.
Kite.
Oh, Moomin.
Father.
Moomin stocking,
where did you hide?
To the hat.
Better get rid of the hat.
Because everyone wanted to keep the way they were,
it was decided to throw the hat away.
However, Moomin was not unreservedly satisfied.
You don't find a hat like that every day.