I think this is going too far.
I want to go back to Moomin Valley right away.
This looks suspiciously like avico again.
The time machine must have overheated in the sun.
We need to get into the shadows to freeze it.
You know I get tired easily.
We have noticed it before.
I suddenly became terribly thirsty.
Shit, you can't. We have no more water.
I'm most thirsty.
You still can't drink everything.
Hey, stop now.
I brought this field bottle.
I'll keep it from there.
I'll take the bottle.
It is...
Hey!
Water!
Oh!
What is it now?
Momi Peikko!
Come and go!
Is everything okay?
Look, over there!
Oh!
Ramidi!
Ya Sphinx!
Hey, I'm falling!
You are always the same!
Whip it!
The pyramids!
Help yourself with the riddles.
What exactly were the pyramids?
Kind of graves.
Building them was difficult.
Dad, Do you know what's inside the pyramids?
It is shrouded in Darkness, but now we have an opportunity
reveals the words of the pyramids and leaves our mark on the history of archaeology.
The pyramid is guaranteed to be full of treasures!
Oh, maybe real treasures!
Hey, wait!
Whip it!
You too!
Where is the entrance?
After all, there should have been a door!
I'm going to dig into this.
Are you sure it's safe?
Hmm, one pyramid was built by many sexes.
I could almost bet that one troublesome tunnel won't hurt.
How's it going mummy?
The first one gets the treasure!
Dig, dig!
Just the first one?
You can't afford to be second!
Moomin would wait a bit.
Let's leave quickly!
Yes. It took more time to build the pyramid than to destroy it.
So. I guess it wasn't planned terribly well.
Good miracle. How do we get through this?
Yes. I guess the pyramid needs to be rebuilt.
After all, it took many generations to build.
So.
Yes.
Ha! Let's escape!
A pinch! Be careful!
Anna, excuse me.
Are you making a fuss here? What have you done?
You have destroyed the tomb of the thousand-year-old king.
For that, we apologize a thousand times.
Sorry.
That's not enough!
Best to fade away!
A hopeless situation.
Moomin-Pekko told to dig.
That's what you said! I tried to stop, but Moomin-Pekko said...
That's not true! Why are you twisting things again?
Moomin-Pekko!
Why are you twisting things again?
Take off your disguises, even you wretched grave-robbers!
Remove the masks from your faces immediately.
Masks?
We are not wearing any disguise.
It's a lie!
Boy! Naomiot!
Start! You ripped my head off!
Must not!
Stop it!
A little courtesy, if you can ask for permission.
Don't, use those rough grips?
Idiotit!
Can't you see that this is my head and not a mask?
Oh yes!
Terribly rude people.
Do not tickle.
It's true.
What is it about?
Do not tickle.
Forgive me.
We didn't know you were from the Land of the Sun.
Others certainly wouldn't have been able to do this either
to destroy the Pyramid as easily and quickly as you.
Ihi, take it easy.
The Mooms and I have come to earth to perform
special things to do.
It should have been noticed immediately,
but how about finding something to drink or eat here?
Dude, don't get too excited.
Let's disappear before they change their minds.
Good idea.
You don't have to come and be escorted.
We're in a bit of a hurry.
Not this water.
Nipsu, you're coming.
We have to get away.
Speed, speed, speed.
This time we come to the ancient Moomilaakso.
This is no Moomin Valley.
Oh, what is that?
It plunges us into places.
Keep it interesting.
Oh, racing.
Oh, unusual.
How can you beat tough men?
Just different from the ones here.
Who do you mean by lots?
At least not me.
And you don't outdo me.
If the world were different, I too would be a brave soldier.
That's right, honey.
Even if you are somewhat overweight.
Now.
Now we don't divide.
Tell me where we are.
At least not in Moomilaakso.
It seems we are still in the land of the Pyramids.
The time machine traveled too short.
The radiant Cleopatra enters the arena to hand out the prizes for the races.
What? My Cleopatra?
Oh oh, the same beauty with a mighty fleet of Sails.
She is really beautiful in the picture.
Yes, such a handsome and long linear nose.
Oh, could I be just as beautiful and could I remain in history thanks to my beauty?
Before you can go down in history, you have to die first.
Cleopatra's beauty is just a joke.
She needs all the creams and dyes in the world to make her navel look great.
Oh, to know the secret of her beauty.
Miss Nisku, you're perfectly fine like that.
Muvi-feikko, you don't understand anything about the essence of women.
Neither do I.
Not really.
No matter how beautiful a woman is, she always wants to be a little more beautiful.
It sounds really funny, but that's just the way it is.
You too mom.
Me too a little.
Hey, Cleopatra is leaving.
Let's get after it.
Short.
You go run.
How so where? After Cleopatra, of course.
We want to know his secret recipe.
If we get it, this time travel thing was worth doing.
Whatever happens.
Let's keep climbing.
Mamma, wait, sell and I'll knock.
On what basis do you think Cleopatra tells you the recipe?
What are they waiting for?
Waiting for their turn to win Cleopatra's lovely hand.
Wow!
Jubilee tea is popular.
A real star.
How long can it be before we get to see Cleopatra?
Well, that's it.
The Queen is not in her sunniest mood.
It can take ten or even thirty days.
Huh! So long!
I believe that we women can wait even a month if necessary.
In a breeze.
No, you're gloating.
Honey, Will you hold a place for us in line while we do some research?
And you, Mi Pekka man?
I'll come along!
Mamma!
Mother!
Everything here is so amazingly big!
Oh my, what's wrong with you.
I've been away from the battlefield for three days.
Now I'm done.
Take the letter from Antony to Cleopatra.
We will deliver the letter for sure.
You can rest.
I'm borrowing this.
Does it fit?
Excellent.
It's too heavy.
Yuh, my neck is going to snap.
That's how we skip the queues.
It is said in this letter of Antonius.
We must deliver the letter to Cleopatra without delay.
Hi, that's it.
And the mother and the little girl.
Let's go after them.
Silvä.
Where are you going?
I guess you can see this.
A special express letter to Cleopatra.
Sorry.
Is it in the past?
Good day.
Mamma wait for us.
Niskuneiti.
What is the matter?
We... that...
Hey, what's up there?
Now.
From what I heard, I would think that it is not appropriate to play in the palace.
This is far from a joke.
The floor is like a skating rink.
Which of these rooms belongs to Cleopatra?
I don't know.
If I were to move to a palace, I would choose a room with the best view.
Your opinion has not been asked.
Niskuneiti's point of view makes sense.
The queen probably wants to keep an eye on her kingdom.
The matter is clear as day.
Don't be shy.
Upstairs!
O Antonius, my heart withers.
Be prepared to die of grief.
What a charming room.
Everything is so brilliant that it touches the eyes.
I would like to live this kind of life even once.
Cleaning such a big room is hard work.
Nipsu, leave some grapes for me too!
Who there?
Now let's take this book.
Please leave.
And you don't want a letter?
I bring a message from Antonius.
Oh, from my General, Antonius.
He is, he is so...
I picture beautiful.
Is he?
Mouthpieces!
Antonius.
How can you make fighting more important than me?
You don't promise to come back until those stupid things are over.
What's wrong with Cleopatra?
Oh Cleopatra rukka, sad.
Let's leave him alone for a moment.
Cleopatra is now not in a condition to hold a proper conversation.
Oh, what do you think?
Is there a key to the secret of beauty?
Oh beautiful perfume bun.
Hihi, a couple of sprays as a souvenir.
Something smells in here.
I started to feel dizzy.
Sell, may not use other people's goods without permission.
Good luck!
No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
Cleopatra, can we have these beauty products as souvenirs?
I have no reason to be beautiful anymore.
Take what you want.
One's sorrow, another's happiness made us happy. Thank you, thank you.
All Antonios.
What the hell is wrong with Cleopatra?
Without Antonius, my life is worthless.
Take me to the world of shadows.
Don't he now, you must not die.
Did he try to kill himself with a poisonous snake?
Kärmeen looks nice. It's unlikely to be toxic.
It doesn't have a poison tail.
Pinch, hey, let it bite you as a test.
Don't joke!
Are you okay?
Are you messengers from heaven?
Please take me out of here.
Yeah, but...
He has suffered a lot. Honey, we'll take him with us.
A world of shadows?
No, of course, but to Moominvalley.
Cleopatra overcomes her depression,
after he has rested his nerves for a while with us.
Great idea. Everyone will be excited.
I'm already excited.
And I got to know Cleopatra's beauty routine.
Well, let's get down to business.
I guess you can't wait to go already, Moominpapa?
Without a doubt, with Cleopatra's help, we will still decide
The Riddle of the Sphinxes and Pyramids.
I'm sure.
Suddenly, start the time machines!
Moominpapa, we will be found soon!
The time machines have to be adjusted to Moomin Valley and it is a precise job.
Cleopatra!
Cleopatra, I found you at last.
Jaha, who are you?
Cleopatra, I have returned to you, Cleopatra.
Just like Antonius.
Would have spoken.
Oi Antonius!
Cleopatra!
O Antonius, are you really there?
I am. Let's see it with your own eyes.
Ah, so he is Cleopatra's lover.
General Antonius himself.
Very handsome.
I've had enough of wars.
Even in the midst of the battle I could hear your sighs and complaints.
Then I felt great restlessness. From now on, it's just the two of us.
O dear Antonius.
Sorry. Go away.
Sorry, but...
Do not disturb.
Shouldn't I...
Gosh!
General Antonius, is that sword real? May I touch it?
Doing the same.
Oh, how wonderful it is!
I live. That venomous snake doesn't...
Of course you live, Sweet Cleopatra.
Can I fit the helmet?
As you wish.
Great!
What a shining sword!
I think this is a nice place.
What bliss.
But I will order its swindler to be punished.
Cleopatra, it is good to be with you.
Hi Anthony! The sword was forgotten!
Also the helmet!
I have the love of Cleopatra. That will do.
Let us be.
I don't need anything anymore.
Not these too?
They are ours!
Amazing.
Love is indeed greater.
But you can keep the sword and the helmet even if you love it.
Right. But you also once said that if I just love you, you don't need anything else.
Oh, did I really say that.
Too bad Cleopatra isn't coming with us. Or what do you say?
I wish I could turn into a reindeer in the flames of love.
Phew! When you come back!
Cloudy.
Police Chief Awakened!
Did the Moomins return?
Not yet.
Can they get back to Moominvalley first?
No.
Let's go.
At our house.
Can they get back to Moominvalley first?
So. That's what I thought too.
Yay, that's weird.
We're back!
Welcome. We have time to worry.
The ancient Moomin Valley looked like.
Share, something like that.
Cleopatra, gave me this box.
The secret of beauty was found here.
Lovely Cleopatra! I came back.
Ah, Antonius my General, is it really you?
If you just love me, I don't need anything else.
You can't hurt yourself.
Humi Troll, love is not for you.