Moomin Valley is once again a true haven of peace.
On a perfect day, police chief Mymmel and little Mymymiele go on a fun trip.
Police, why don't you ever arrest anyone?
That what?
You're just buzzing around your sister like a bee.
Oh, not that. Yesterday too I spent the whole day tending roses in my garden.
Oh, that was on Monday. The pleasure trip has continued for three days.
Time flies with your sister.
Roses and pleasure trips are not part of the official duties of the police.
What do you think the police would consider a video?
Well, to examine fingerprints and chase bandits, of course.
But when there are no criminals in Moomin Valley.
And I guess not if they are.
Who would break the law here?
No one is boring.
Maybe from some corner, but not too busy with work.
Well, no.
I can crack up to my heart's desire at any time.
The salary comes from nothing.
Hi Myy, I have a request for you.
Oh, what request?
You're disturbing. Grab some snacks and go somewhere else.
Lovely scent.
Soman Eito, I'm handing you a bouquet that pales in comparison to your beauty.
Joy belongs and corresponds to the truth of rare flowers.
Not familiar with white lilies?
They grow everywhere.
You again?
Are you rehearsing for a play?
We don't. Leave us alone.
Young lovers talk like this.
You're ruining the mood.
It's confusing.
I've come up with a brilliant spread.
What?
Let's start dating.
Oh!
I want you to be my sweetheart.
Spring is in the air without a doubt.
Moomin Valley Police.
Good day, Police Commander.
Was just on an inspection trip.
No, no, perfectly calm.
I am happy to report that the crimes have completely stopped.
It's quite loco in Moomin Valley.
Right?
What?
Yes, but when...
Oh, this came out of the blue.
Sad.
Or so?
Or it's already decided.
Yes, but what about me?
Hello, police.
Beautiful day today.
Hmm.
Hey kids, where are you going?
Hello, Moomin.
Well, day.
Is Moominpa at home?
Of course, have there been any crimes?
No, unfortunately not a single one.
Hmm.
Oh weird, that's horrible.
That's right, I'm desperate.
Moomin Valley won't be the same without you.
When does the police station close?
According to my information, very soon.
As deserving as you are.
That's it.
I have been very competent.
No more crimes are committed in Moomin Valley.
Hmm.
That's what it smelled like.
Stink alone is not enough.
You realize I'm getting fired from my police job, right?
Oh my god.
You also don't happen to have anything on your face that I could arrest you for.
I have gone to this man.
A police officer.
We need to help the police.
He is so nice.
We could write a petition on behalf of the police.
But the matter has already been decided by a higher authority.
So.
And there's no need for a police station here in Moomin Valley.
The chief of police needs to find another job.
But he is comfortable in his current position.
That will sell.
Uh, I'm pitching a tent.
Daredevil!
You must help my sister.
What has happened to him?
Nothing really, but he is hopelessly in love with uniforms.
So what then?
I shudder when I think about how things go when the police get fired.
Your sister is eccentric.
I am convinced that the police will be allowed to wear their old uniform.
Yeah, yeah, but it's not the same.
It would then be like a fancy dress.
Is there nothing you can do about this?
Did you come up with a solution?
If crimes were committed here, the police station could not be abolished.
But when we are so law-abiding here.
If someone falls into a crime.
Do we?
Let's make Moomin Valley a nest of crimes.
Remarkable.
Where did I put it?
Mom, mom!
What's the matter?
Have you seen my hat?
Well share, yes. I saw it in you yesterday.
I put the top hat on this morning too.
Jeez, when did you waste it?
I just woke up from a nap.
You left your hat somewhere.
I never leave it anywhere.
Hello, have you seen my handbag?
Me?
As I recall, I saw it on you yesterday.
Yes, but in the morning, as usual, I went downstairs with a bag in my arm.
Where did you see it last?
In the kitchen, pantry or dining room.
Oh holy sylph.
Mother, mother!
What, honey?
Have you seen my knife?
I'm not.
I'm sure I left it on the desk.
You haven't seen my handbag have you?
What's going on here?
I'm looking for my top hat, it should be around here somewhere.
Just don't say it's lost either.
That's it, but in the morning I still had the hat on.
Hand this.
What do you mean?
My hook is missing too.
In the morning I was fishing, but then the fishing rod suddenly got in the way.
Johan is a freak.
Top hat, handbag.
Stolen.
What?
There is a thief on the move in Moominvalley.
I realized that you are missing more things.
So missing.
Mammoth, mammoth!
Have you found your handbag?
I don't. What about your hats?
In.
And don't forget my knife, Dad.
Nuuska Muikkunen is right.
What did dad mean?
My luck is gone.
Now steal my hat.
And my handbag.
Devilish.
And a knife.
Healthy muuta.
Who might be interested in my Handbag?
There's nothing valuable inside.
Now comes the end.
What's wrong, Nipsu?
Someone has stolen a gold coin from me.
Oh, from you too.
What? Has anyone else lost their gold coins?
No coins, but a handbag and a hat.
I will stab Muikkunen's problem.
Oh all our treasures.
Who is to blame?
The thief must be caught.
It's not our job, it's the police's.
Properly. Let's go to the police station.
Absolutely.
Valuables have been stolen.
Everything is done to find the criminal.
The arrest will happen soon.
Thank you, thank you. Goodbye.
Well, well. What's wrong now?
Looks like we've been hacked.
It seems so.
And not just looks.
We have a cold-blooded, hardened criminal.
A coin was taken from me.
What has been stolen from the store?
A string of pearls is made from chocolate and mymmels.
Nope.
I gave it to him. It was an expensive gift.
I want chocolate with them.
I warn you that in these cases the chocolate is almost always lit before the rosmus is closed.
What is missing from Niskunen?
A wonderful treasure box.
All of them with their contents or?
Are they more visible, and the shoes are missing?
A thief is not good for anything.
But don't be sad.
I'll catch the thief, any way I can.
Are you sure?
Of course.
Sell, tell the insiders that I'll come to comfort him as soon as I recover from my haste.
So the police began to investigate their latest case.
Ah, yes.
On this table, are you putting these in your handbag for the last time?
Exactly.
Are you sure you left the knife on the desk?
Joo.
And you don't have any leads?