The time machine isn't broken. I'm just checking that it's OK to use.
Jaa.
Miss Isku, if you could go anywhere you wanted in a time machine, which era would you choose?
I think I would like to live in Rococo times.
Oh, for what?
I would live in a beautiful castle in the middle of flowers, and in the hall I would hold proms and handsome princely weddings.
And would say to you, beautiful lady, you must start a loan course.
It's getting late.
Hihihihi.
Hey, Moomipeikko.
what you now
A special outfit.
I want the good old wild west.
Jaa.
Where the Indians and cowboys fought each other.
And the setting sun lit the valleys aniline red.
Oh, you're already leaving. What would you do there?
I would like to find myself a man.
what you now
So is that man missing?
Whoops.
I want to see if there is anything for me.
It's about you, but you're still half-faced.
You don't understand at all.
Uh?
Moomin wants to be a victorious lone rider.
Men and women heading west in rocking carriages.
Alone against the Indian and the dangers.
It was life. We're going to the wild west.
Yep! Nuuska Muikkunen, Would you like to come too?
Yeah, not really.
Nuuska Muikkunen does not want to travel with all of us.
It's not like that.
Now we need more oil.
Mamma, where is the slot machine oil at?
Moomipappa is very excited.
It's good I want help.
No what!
The time machine is gone.
Good lord, the kids have gone on a trip alone.
And they left me here.
Although I just wanted to go to the wild west.
Wild West
This is the Wild West.
Worth seeing.
That's right! Nothing.
You can already feel the inviting smell of campfires.
Like that? It smells like shit.
You can see smoke over there. And people.
You know, Indians.
Are Indians dangerous?
No, mine is more dangerous.
What do you mean? Nothing.
Look at the cattle farm and how many cows.
I'm a cattle rancher.
Single calf.
Hello, my horse. Go for it. A hobo, a hobo.
A stupid pet too. Why don't you move?
Whoop, whoop, whoop, whoop, whoop, whoop, whoop, whoop, whoop.
Whoops. The head is gone. And the farm has a tail.
This was the end.
Too big for you.
No cow is too big for a real herdsman.
Yes, the cow is always caught.
Hey, let's wait.
Get off the end of the breakaway rope.
Oh, Peikka. And I can't, when finally...
Oh, Peikka.
I finally caught the cow...
I'll come to the rescue.
Uh, uh, uh...
No, no, no, no, you're asking for help!
Don't go here and there!
Uh, uh...
Au!
What was it? So what?
Even the whiny cattle thieves. Stop bullying my herd of cows.
You will soon be swinging on a tree branch.
Oh, let's rock.
Oh, Peikka, stop.
The trading game can be left for another time.
Hey, the herd is on the loose!
Paatan!
Oh, terrible.
I hate cows. So do I!
Let's push in!
Yay!
Help!
The men must have gone.
The herd became agitated.
It wasn't my fault?
We better get out of here right now.
Tel!
Sorry.
City.
I'm hungry and thirsty.
Let's bark something small.
Let's go already.
Hey, doesn't this look like a saloon?
At least it smells nice.
Bye, bye.
Hey, wait for me.
Oh!
Au!
Moi!
Waiter, that old familiar cowboy special pancake.
And milk to drink!
Same dose for me.
And to me.
Milk and pancake.
Good, we have more cows than people here, so there must be plenty of milk.
Have we ever met?
It's our first time here.
We just came.
Really?
Yes.
We want those portions.
They are coming.
It is...
Why is the service slowing down?
Do you have any problems?
No, it isn't.
Now I know why he looks so familiar.
He is the wanted cattle thief, looking very young.
Hey, what's up there? No service here at all?
Whoah, whoah, here we go.
They are going to surprise you. They demanded the cash register at gunpoint.
Hands up or something.
Don't count playing.
It was spent.
Peculiar. What are you really freaking out about?
Don't ask me.
Sheriff, come help the wanted man here.
What does that mean?
That the police are looking for him.
Let's go.
Moomin cake.
A bad picture of a Moomin doll.
Too bad.
The cow fight was not without consequences.
Oh terrible, what are we going to do?
Shall we be hanged immediately if we are caught?
I must not be hanged.
Something has to be done.
Moomin cake.
How do we get through this?
Without flinching!
No, no shooting.
At least I'm innocent.
Wretched cattle thieves, let's arrest you.
Don't shoot me with that gun.
I am not responsible for the consequences.
We are innocent.
That's what those cattle thieves always say.
They are terribly young.
Believe us, it was a joke.
We're just pretending to be herders.
It was a herdsman's game.
Sheriff, don't listen to them.
The thief still has the gun.
Oh gun, what do they mean?
Show it.
Clear.
This is a game.
Don't wait until I eat.
And, and, and, and, and, and.
A real muggle.
The bank has been robbed.
Se oli Billy the Kid.
Right, or Billy the Kid?
Handle, handle, handle, handle.
Right.
Ai kuka?
One day you will get caught.
You'll see.
Now or never.
Let's get out of here.
I will never come here.
Oh, what a fascinating man.
Miskuneti, what are you dreaming about?
We must escape.
Please wait.
I'm raging my sin...
Are we far enough?
I can't run.
We're probably safe by now.
Why am I always pale?
It's all Moomin's fault.
Why did he have to try to ride a cow?
Billy the Kid had him under his spell.
Try to understand myy.
Understanding is put to the test.
Forgive me.
Let's go already.
Let's try to get back to Moomilaakso as soon as possible.
Hey wait where did we leave the time machine.
Someone will come over there.
The sheriff is after us.
I don't want to go to the gallows.
That someone is not from the city.
A pawnbroker.
Tough robber.
Come on miss, you won't get too excited again.
Billy the Kid we saw.
What the hell does he want from us?
You all got out of town.
True, we have you to thank for that.
It won't last, colleague.
Why did you ride here?
I was interested to see how you got on.
How did you survive?
Or so.
What matter?
The sun is about to set.
You can't stay overnight in the desert.
Come to me.
Is this an invitation?
We don't agree to be swayed by gangsters.
Miss your hand.
Will you take me for a ride?
Miss Isku, we're going to Moomin Valley.
Well, get on your horses.
Deny yourself.
Maybe they won't come?
They will come if they want.
Hit miss, wait.
That hard face, where are you taking the blow girl.
Bring him back.
What is it about?
Bank robbery and rode his way with a hit girl.
It's terrible.
Back before it gets dark.
Joo.
Oh my, light-footed hepsankeikka.
Deny yourself.
Where did the bank robber take the hit girl?
Moomin, don't mourn.
We will find him.
What if we don't?
I know, but still...
What is that?
Pinch, what do you mean?
Wait, I'll be right back.
I can't believe my eyes.
I found the coin.
I thought you found the lead to find the blow girl.
If you guarantee coins, there will be more.
Is there? Where?
Behind your back.
Nope.
Oh, money.
About that many coins.
And they are all mine.
Wow, money, money.
Yeah, that's a lot of coins.
Pretty remarkable.
We sense something.
Maybe, Moomipeikko, notice.
Does it make you tired?
No, not at all.
I am under the spell of a wonderful sunset.
So.
The wilderness continues as far as the eye can see.
Sunsets don't even bother me sometimes.
It can't be worse.
Now we are there.
There's also a home there.
Oh, that must be charming.
We had a day.
I can buy anything with these coins.
Idiot, nothing to buy here.
Not so.
Go ahead, forget the money and go to sleep.
I'll be hungry too.
Oh.
What was it?
Coyote.
Like it's hungry. It scares me.
It won't eat you.
You are too ugly.
I am.
Don't be afraid. I was guarding.
What is the niiskunnie doing right now?
I hope he's okay.
A romantic howl.
It was Coyote.
Do you make the same noise when you're angry?
Don't be stupid.
I'm not a wolf.
I'm just playing now.
What do you say about this?
That good like this.
I have a 4S.
What is it possible?
Why did you get angry?
I can't stand this!
Oh, I won.
You said you don't know how to play cards.
But you still know, don't you?
Oh, did you say something?
Let's play one more round.
And not play.
I have enough money, even if I rob a bank every day.
Oh, well, I'm starting to wait.
You can sleep in the bed.
I'm going to the sofa in the room.
Doesn't this one have a guest bed?
Well, it really isn't.
Don't you have friends in the village?
Friends?
Who needs them?
Good night.
Here's another coin.
We're probably going in the right direction.
I don't care about coins now.
I want to sleep.
When you sleep for me,
coyotes will eat you.
No wait!
That's it.
Ha, Bill's hideout.
I want to sleep.
Did you find the neck lady?
Sshh, more.
Did you see my neck?
There's nobody there.
Let me have a look.
Sells to me. There is nothing to look at.
I want to see it with my own eyes.
Shhh!
Billy.
What is he talking about?
So.
What's the commotion?
Wow, my head is ringing!
Let's go get the nick girl.
It was cunning to follow us.
Come closer.
Hm.
We came to pick up Niskunneid.
Let him go.
The law is a braggart boasting over my dead body.
Only strength ends here,
only the strong survive here.
Feel free to shoot me anytime
but a true hero fights eye to eye and takes what he wants.
I move to the side before it crashes.
A pinch!
The law of Svillinänne is followed here.
Yes, but when that...
What are you waiting for?
When you take it and smash it, I shot Vill in the skull.
Don't be stupid. All I have is a water gun.
Billy dies laughing.
You would have had a great opportunity to show what you can do.
I'll show.
What are you talking about? I'm ready.
Poomenta, Billy.
You came right after me.
Look what's here.
I won in a card game.
Don't slack off.
Billy has challenged Moomin to a duel.
And Moomin will fight for your honor.
Will Moomin and Billy fight over me?
Lovely.
I tell you what. Play me cards.
Not good for quality.
I have no game luck because of you.
Let's think about it.
Shall we see who wins the rodeo?
Yes, the one who stays awake the longest wins.
What do you say to that?
All right. I agree.
Don't fall.
Moomin is a prude.
It's fine, but don't let him run too hard.
Viskuneiti, don't joke about giving advice.
Billy is clever.
Moomi, stay back.
Oh, calm down.
Moomin will fall off the ride at any moment.
What can we do?
Well, something, of course.
Hey sell, be careful.
A lazy cow too.
Billy, shut up a little.
Sell, be careful.
Bulls get angry when they see red.
Give up, Ipana.
Hey, you don't know who I am.
That, what?
Hey listen, tyler, don't tease the bull.
No, no, no, no.
No, no, no, no, no.
Can't come here.
Myy.
You can't, stop Sonni.
No, no, this is how it has to be now.
You can't, you can't come.
Myy.
Stop Sonni.
Ohion.
Moomin, hey.
Good, good.
I'm fine, but how did Billy get better?
Billy, did you get hurt?
Wake up already.
Miss Nisko, don't worry.
What are you going to do now?
Oh hello.
I admit that I lost.
Miss Nisko, you can be proud of those friends.
Yes, thank you Moomin for fighting for me.
Don't, everyone's watching.
Five of it, I love you.
It's so quiet when the kids are gone.
I miss them.
I miss them too.
Oh heaven.
Welcome home.
Glad you got back safely.
Here we are.
We had a little adventure.
Moomin was a hero.
A man's gotta do what a man's gotta do.
It's like you've changed somehow.
Our son has grown up.
Oh, it is.
The Moomins have become wildly manly.
But I can thank the little seller for that.
And sale has finally become feminine.
Well, yeah, maybe, I guess.
Thank you.