Moomin Valley seems to have returned to its former peaceful state.
There is no sign of worry anywhere.
Or for a while anyway.
Moomin wait!
Mother, mother! Are they ready?
What?
Pancakes!
Not yet, the magician's trees burn carefully.
You're just making the dough.
Pancakes don't take long to fry.
Are the pancakes ready?
This concern is overwhelming.
I'm such a muggle head, you fool!
And you're not stupid, you're wise.
Phew! I'm an unhappy tuner, rotten egg.
A wanderer, you would scurry decently on the ground.
Pah!
If you know how to make a sledgehammer that moves on the ground,
you can certainly build one that flies in the air.
I believe in talent.
I don't think there's much to anything about tohelo.
Last night I thought, now me.
I have finally managed to make a flying rake.
But then I looked again at my work, how I,
who am so sensible, I can be so low-witted.
I'm a complete moron.
Pancakes are ready. Go tell everyone.
I can go too.
Where are Moomin and Snow Maiden?
Niiskunneiti has been again.
Ai.
Don't take it so hard.
Biscuits fall into depression when their inventions fail.
Also Moomin Pappako.
Don't make up stories, will you?
Yeah, or memoirs.
Niiskunnetti, Would you like the pancake?
Yes, please enjoy.
Moomin go get daddy.
He's stuck on his writing stick again.
Joo.
Niiskunkunnie, what is this?
As morning came, the sun circled the eastern sky and gradually.
Everything began to cherish.
Even the smallest fool reads.
Oh, I have absolutely no literary talent.
I'm a miserable hobbyist with no writing skills.
Best to stop.
In.
What is it?
Mom told me to eat pancakes.
Oh, I'm struggling in the throes of creation, I'll be back later.
Aha.
Was there anything else?
It was, no.
I guess I heard wrong.
I heard wrong too.
Moomin, I'm waiting, I'll come.
Yes, it tasted good.
I'm going out.
I'm not going either.
No, I'm going on a dangerous research trip with the snuska-muikku.
Hi, snuffbox.
Hello to yourself, I thought you would come.
What is that?
A leaf boat, it sails all the way down the river.
It goes all the way to the sea and drifts to some unknown land.
Sometimes I take a boat trip somewhere.
Shall we go?
The little girl wanted to come along, but I said it was too dangerous.
You should have chosen your words better.
Look.
Hey, wait!
They too needed excitement in their lives.
Wait!
Are we really going to climb a mountain?
I don't think all of us can do it.
I'm not going up.
But I will go.
I prefer to keep me company.
Uh, can't you girls wait for us in the cave?
It's right next to the path.
Do you see that you can walk along the path?
It is difficult for the girl to understand this matter.
It's really hard to understand.
We want to climb.
Let's go already.
Will you come along, Jysu?
I guarded the background. I protect the cave from below.
Pelkuri.
Don't underestimate. Someone has to stay behind to watch the girls.
Shall we go to the cave?
I don't care.
Better stay here. You never know who lives in the cave.
That too, Fool. Nobody lives there.
That's why I don't care.
An uninhabited place is creepy.
I think we are right above the cave now.
I can't see the opening leading down.
Maybe it's a little towards that.
Wow, I've never seen a clam like this.
And what about that?
Mussels like that are probably valuable.
Little Myy, come here!
Where is Little Myy?
He pressed into the cave.
Terrible, he should come and collect seashells.
Sell, get out of there!
To the ground, Rabbit!
It's dangerous to go in without a fog!
Well, how the hell would you go in then?
Wait there! We will save you!
I guess you, Niiskun, and you won't come with me to the cave anyway?
Yes, I create.
Well, let's go then.
I'll take your hand in case you get scared.
where are you
You'll make Niiskuneidin afraid!
Oh, I thought I'd scare you!
Your voice is shaking!
My voice always sounds like this!
Shhh! Helja!
I hear something!
I can hear it too. Maybe the wind.
It didn't hear!
I can hear it too.
I can hear it too. Maybe the wind.
It doesn't sound like a jerk!
You can't scare me! Nobody lives here!
Moomin and Snoopy are just there.
They have come down to the cave and now they...
Why would Moomin and Snuska Muikkunen snore?
Yes, it must be someone else...
Oh sell! Let's stop!
I'm pulling a Moomin now!
Is it good now?
Which goes first?
I!
But remember to be careful!
Clear!
Who goes first!
Quietly. There's no rush.
Are you OK?
Of course.
Ai myy!
Help!
Moomin are you okay?
Moomin Hoo!
I believe so.
Except for the back panel.
Who shouted so cruelly?
Our friend Hemuli was here for a nap.
Oh heaven.
This is one of your games again.
We didn't know you had settled in comfortably here on Nokos.
I had not settled comfortably at Nokos at all.
So what are you doing here?
To tell you the truth. I haven't been myself lately.
Have you lost a rare stamp again?
Vice versa. I have them all.
An Aiki stamp, which a collector can have.
So what else is there?
My stamp collection is complete.
And no one has a better stamp collection than you.
Of course not. Mine is the best.
There isn't a single rarity or misprint that I don't have.
Then I don't understand.
I am young. And besides, there are no collectors.
Ai, you, you, you, you, you, you, you, you, you, you, you, you, you, you, you, you, you, you, you, you, you, you, you you, you, you, you, you, you, you, you, you, you, you, you, you, you, you, you, you, you, you, you, you, you, you, you, you, you, you, you, you, you, you, you, you, you, you, you, you, you, you, you, you, you, you, you, you, you, you, you, you, you, you, you, you, you, you, you, you, you, you, you, you, you, you, you, you, you, you, you, you, you, you, you, you, you
No, if we're being precise
Hemuli was in the cave taking a nap
Oh, Hemuli parka
Cah, the ghost's sobs were his snoring
I never snore
You're snoring
I'm here
Kattia kans
If you don't tell anyone, I'll show you something special
What is it?
Oh boy!
That's it
Ampa wonderful
Beautiful Russian
Someone owns it
I guess that could be fixed
Of course, and it wouldn't even be difficult
You don't know that, the bottom looks bad
I'm sure it's seaworthy
There are holes in the kurje
Oars are missing
You don't need them, we paddle with our hands
You melotte
Be careful, the boat is rocking ha
Russian
I've lost my confidence and it makes me feel weird
That happens to anyone
For you too
Yes, but not very often
Well, that's a relief
How do I get my confidence back?
I don't know
Mine usually comes back in its own time
I hardly ever make another plan
I, too, can leave my memoirs to be torn apart
What's wrong with you all?
You look so gloomy
I was too confident
So do I
Hi, Moominpapa, Moominpapa
What's wrong, Nipsu? We can hear even if we don't howl
Come to the shore quickly, we have found the boat
Oh, the wreck that washed ashore?
It's not a wreck, it has a sail
We fix the boat and then it's ours
I will come
I'm coming, Nipsu. Adventure is exactly what you need to cheer yourself up
As old
You might be interested if the boat has a sail
Yes, yes. A neat little ship
Good shape
Father, is it ours because it has been abandoned?
Maybe the boat has been left here on its own luck
Because it leaks
That would be understandable
But discoverers always become owners
It's not quite like that
I have to wait a bit first
So what do we do, Father?
We need to refit the boat so that we can anchor it in case of a storm
Necessarily
My guess is that if the owner comes forward, we wouldn't give up the boat
On the other hand, no one may know where the boat is
So what do we do after we've restored it?
Pity the boats left on the beach
Sending a sail to the seven seas?
No, no, no, no
I think I'll see the rest of the world too
I think I'll watch together
I guess I'll look around
And you don't have to fear
If we got into big waves, we sailed between them
And not so, Moomin papa?
Roughly
Well, my friend, let's get it done
Will you help with the planning, Nisku?
That's fine
Moomin papa, can I do something?
Would you really?
Well, if you don't mind
I'm not really a construction guy
First we have to pull the boat dry
Russian!
We need at least ten miner sleepers under the boat
I'm going by myself
Me too
And me!
And then you probably need a few more logs for the floor
And we need a lot of nails
That's right, we also need a ladle and a full head
I'll help choose the nails
And I'll guard the boat if the owner comes to pick it up
Ram the sails
What?
Are the children sleeping?
They sleep like logs
No wonder they worked so hard
I can't wait for us to sail somewhere
Yeah, I'll take you anywhere in the world you want
Anywhere
I don't miss far
Shall we go to sleep? We have to get up early
Oh, Meri, life is a hard seat for a worker
Yes, I just feel so bad about this
Ressu, Meri is good for him
Hi, hi
Perfectly patched, even if I do say so myself
And now the rest
Joo
Look, Moomin, I'll tar the boat
Yeah, yeah, I only tar where you can't reach
Nipsu, hepse, macra crab, you can get more tar
Ha, ha, myself! I let you tar because you wanted to
Picking up tar is not my thing
Start speeding up, get off your bums
Shall I cut from this, cut it off mom?
Cut, that's it
What's wrong, Hemuli?
The boat work seems to be progressing hastily
True, it will be ready soon
That's what I was afraid of
So what did I come up with?
Couldn't you come up with a new collectible?
Like what?
Anything, like collecting butterflies
It won't even be heard
Well, decorative items
Decorative items
He can collect them endlessly
Unscientific
I think you should start collecting something
Mother, mother
Hurry up, we're driving, we're getting on board
We ride we get on board
I'm coming, I'm coming
You conjured the sail really nicely, come on
Are you ready?
Push with all your might
Y...
K...
A...
And now for the test sailing
Joo
Great hemuli
Come on, mom
I think I'm going home
I just got a new idea for a flywheel
Now I can get it working
It's as clear as day
Let's go later
You untie the rope, start paddling
Mamma, we'll be back for dinner
You don't have to
I only make cold cuts
Ups, ups, ups