In Moomin Valley, almost everyone sleeps through the long winter.
However, now it had happened so strangely that a small number of Moomin goblins had woken up.
I'm good! Moomin jam is needed after winter.
Yes, mom is needlessly worried that you had overcooked the jam.
Alas, they are still sleeping.
Good thing there are two of us awake.
Moomin and you don't want to try?
My heavy carcass would break the tray.
Find another platform.
Aren't we supposed to go see the tuttik?
I'm pulling you.
You are afraid of going down a high hill.
And not afraid either.
And not afraid.
Tuutikki is not at home. Where could it be?
It can be seen coming from there.
I guess you're right.
The tuttik also slides in the snow.
Does it slide?
Well, at least that's how it seems to me.
He's coming this way.
where have you been
Catching the sun.
You have to go an incredibly long way before you see it.
Well, did you see the sun?
Just a glimpse, but then it sank back into the horizon.
Hi, what kind of fringe shoes are you wearing?
Ice skates. You can move well on the ice with these.
Could you show me how to use them?
Of course.
Great.
I'm going to make the skates myself.
I don't think you can.
About Whoops!
All you have to do is attach some knife-like ones to the soles of your shoes.
Tuutikki, I suddenly got the feeling that we are not alone here in the swimming room.
Oh, you know it.
Who? Where?
There's no need to hang around, you won't see them.
Or is there someone here that I don't see?
Behind the kitchen table, right?
No. These are invisible, just like Ninni was.
Oh oh! At the top, someone is doing the trick.
It's one of the heads. There are eight of them.
Hey, don't walk on my heels.
I'm sure there were no head lice here last summer when we went swimming.
It wasn't.
Of course not. There are many creatures that are not suitable for summer, spring or autumn.
But when winter comes and the days get shorter and the others have gone into hibernation, that's when they come out.
And some of them are so small that you can't even see them.
I don't understand winter at all. I don't.
Of course not. You Moomin house residents have always slept through it.
I can't wait to tell mom and dad.
Moomin-Pekko!
What?
I guess we get up in the morning?
Why are you asking me?
I don't want to continue sleeping until spring.
Well, we woke up today.
But we don't know about tomorrow.
Of course we don't. That's why it's incredibly interesting to see what happens.
But wake up from me in the morning, if it does.
Clear. Shall we sleep already?
Moomin-Pekko, what if it happens the other way around?
What if I wake up and you just sleep?
I don't mind if I sleep all winter.
Well, tomorrow you can sleep.
Moomin-Pekko?
Moomin!
where are you from
Hello. You have a perfect ski hill here.
What sneakers are you wearing?
Now don't be silly.
Don't know what these are?
I don't! That's why I asked.
These are skis. These are when I went down the hill.
Did I see that? Can skis also slide on ice?
On ice, skates are skis.
Stick! It is used to slide in the snow.
It's nice going, but isn't that on a silver platter?
It's a family expense.
Shall I teach you to ski?
Just fine. I'm learning to ski by watching you.
I'm a skier.
For me it is. You can be sure. I don't need teaching.
So you travel. To be always by the snow?
Right. Life must be a struggle. It's good jam.
And you can't ski then?
I'm a skier.
Must be a fight. It's good jam.
So you can't fight in summer or spring?
Too easy. Must be in the cold outside air.
A hardened person always stays warm.
Sounds interesting.
When you poke around in the open, you get unnecessary inches.
A little poem I made up.
Don't you swim in the middle of winter?
Hell, I swim.
Beri is deadlocked. You can't swim in it.
Is there a river here?
It is, it is, but the water looks very, very cold.
Excellent jam. Could you possibly have any more?
Not here, but down in the basement there is. Does the cranberry sauce taste good?
Well no, that's enough for now.
But it might taste good after a swim.
Hop!
I get chills even watching it.
Is everyone around you like that?
No, unfortunately. Come too.
No, thanks.
What are you watching?
Hey, we're looking at that crazy guy who's traveling in the river.
Swim in winter, there are strange people here in Moomin Valley.
Yeah, but he's not from here. where are you from
My name is Surku and I have come here to look for my brothers.
Or your brothers? Are your brothers hibernating?
No, my brothers don't hibernate.
In Moomin Valley, everyone else hibernates, except the little one, the little one, the invisible heads, me and that swim.
My brothers are in the lonely mountains.
Oh, up there?
Curious thing. I have thought that wolves live there, not dogs.
Wolves are brothers of dogs.
Thus. After sleep, the jam even tastes tastier.
I also really like strawberry jam.
A very young man.
Hauveli, Don't you eat your jam?
I don't. You just eat.
With pleasure. You seem to be worried about something.
I guess I am.
It won't do you any good. Don't think about unpleasant things.
What makes you think wolves are your brothers?
They are. Everyone knows that. And I feel a wolf in me.
You can feel it, but I assure you no one can see it.
I want to go to the wolves and howl at the moon.
I can see why he thinks he's a wolf, but we better keep him here.
You can't join wolves.
Yes, I want to.
You could go traveling with me, I like small dogs.
I don't know.
We will become good friends. I'm staying here in Moomin Valley for a while.
Will you stay with us?
I'll stay. The slopes are great and the jam is excellent. Oh, I have to build myself an igloo.
Oh, a snow hut like that?
So. Delicious. If it's okay with you, I'll take some of this jam with me.
Can I borrow your shovel for a moment?
You can, but what do you need it for?
I'm going to break the barrel.
Well, that's easy.
Is it okay?
I am.
Our Hemuli guest is an absolutely impossible jam mouth.
It is. And not the peace it blessed since he came.
Tuutikki, Can you ski?
Of course. Now I just haven't had time.
Hemuli is going to teach me to ski.
I can't move my legs when they are tied.
Of course, that's the joke, move the skis.
The skis fly away.
So, first you learn to fall.
If I learned to ski, I wouldn't fall.
The sale has also received skis.
The hood is made of barrel boards.
Your successes will be much better.
Bend your knees and let's continue.
This slope is too steep for me.
I want a smaller hill.
Next time then. Now let's go.
Trying to cause an avalanche?
This slope is even steeper than the previous one.
No don't, mourn. You already know how to fall perfectly.
You have to!
Speak up, you have to!
Now they are dancing!
Don't go, talk, go!
Don't go!
Please stop me. Just throw yourself on your ass.
It's going great. Smooth and original.
Hi, please.
Hey, please stop me.
Very nice mummy again.
Alas, why are you dancing in the window?
My brothers howl in the mountains.
They must be hungry for wolves.
They call me over.
I have decided to go and greet them.
A twitch?
Win?
We're in trouble. The jam is running out.
Because of the hemulin?
M-m, he's gobbling up jam.
Tell him to go away.
A quick one.
It's aggravating. Everything has its limits.
Ai!
Lumimyrsk.
It might mean that spring is not far away.
Good morning.
Good morning. The jam has already run out.
The bottom is shining.
It was a delicious jam.
It doesn't hurt at all, even if it ends once.
The bottom is shining.
It doesn't matter at all, even though it's over, spring has started and I'm going on my way.
Are you leaving?
I'm leaving. Maybe the mother will hatch more jam next summer.
Farewell and good health.
It's fun that we became friends.
Are you leaving?
I am Surku, your brother.
I have wanted to come to you for a long, long time.
I'm not very strong or brave, but I could be with you.
I guess I was mistaken. Then eat me. What's up with that?
Little Hauveli, Is this where you sit? Have you been waiting for me long?
We will have fun when we travel together.
Sell!
It's spring cannon fire. I watch the sea rush towards us.
Will Myy get back?
My hardware!
Sell! Jump on the back!
Thank you Myy!
It swims well Sell, don't waste it on people!
Sell defectors there!
Do you notice Myy? There's nothing wrong with doing as I say!
Not so! I won't save you a second time!
Moomin, you can do it! A little more!
Hey baby!
It's so cold here!
Grab my paw. Let's light the white immediately.
Ush!