Moomin had found an old homemade soccer ball outside.
About!
Ah! To!
Not like this!
Sell, what do you do?
I'm doing it.
Don't bother, birdie.
It seems to work well, but give it to grain and bait.
For that purpose I have nothing to give.
I can become an even further forward catcher!
It makes no difference.
New again.
I can become an even further forward catcher!
It makes no difference.
Another new story.
The beginning is the most important.
Come on now, come on now, come on now.
Share, share, my retinas are flooded with images.
This makes a great story.
The blue sky arched over the blue sea.
Or the green sea?
No, dear heavens.
The distant horizon with seagulls.
You sound good.
Or a flea.
You hear sounds.
Sad, bright.
No, it's a bit different.
Not blue sky.
The pictures go by so fast that I can't keep up.
I have to start right now.
How did this happen?
Wake up...
The chair broke.
Oh, I guess I got too excited.
What happened now?
Uh, my desk chair broke.
No you, you.
I take the chair out onto the porch.
I'll open the door.
Please.
Thanks.
Can you fix it?
It's not difficult, you just need glue.
Well, yes, you can.
Ha, you danced on a chair!
Yeah, if you need that information now.
Mamma, do you know where the glue is?
I remember seeing it in the basement.
I'll go get it.
Oh, I'll come along.
Psy, age is over.
Moominpappa can get new ones.
Will come.
Thus.
Baby, you're a lousy player.
Sorry pinch.
Is the pregnant pack a mess?
Birds startle.
Hey, what are you doing there?
We're going to the beach soon, are you coming too?
As soon as I catch the bird.
Hey, who can I feed.
Let it come.
Did you hurt yourself?
I hurt, what is dad's chair doing here?
The chair is perfect.
Isn't there enough here?
Would you put some warm water so I can melt the glue?
Yes, papa.
Jaha, where is the shoe pinching now?
When Nipsu kicked the ball too high and I would run to catch it...
It wasn't really our fault at all.
Nipsu kicked the ball badly.
Not when Moomin wasn't looking ahead.
Ah, what's the matter?
I don't think I understand.
Your office chair is nothing but stilts.
what did you say
Sorry dad.
It was an accident.
The chair was already broken.
And it's true, grandma brought the chair out when the gig itself was broken.
Is that so, dad?
Hey, just go back to playing.
Oh, what a relief.
I was quite worried.
Come on, to repair work.
Let's go then.
Yeah, there's a Moomin.
Father, I can stay to help you.
I'll handle this alone, thanks.
You can go and play with others in peace.
Dad was upset that the writing chair broke.
It's probably Moompa's favorite chair.
Couldn't granny troll try to find a new, better chair for her father?
It's not that easy now.
Oh, but my brother Niisk could know.
Let's ask the neighbors to bring their extra chairs to Mumipapa.
I'll get down to business right away.
Don't worry, your dad can fix a chair.
He is so skilled.
Don't be in the mood to get upset over one broken chair.
We'll come before.
It cannot be glued.
At least it's a goddamn big job.
I have to go write as long as the story is fresh in my mind.
I have already forgotten what quality faucet I connect to the sky if the sea is blue.
I need to write at least the body.
Huh!
Strangely, I'm not in the writing mood at all.
What can we invent here?
Well, let's throw away the old rotisko and have a new chair.
Ka's dad?
Not even a body is born now, but the first chapter has to be considered.
Share, oh oh.
Cheating.
It was already on my lips.
Jaa.
Don't worry, muvi papa!
Even the first bird remains uncaught.
Jaa.
The feed appears to be bad.
Sell, has it been caught?
Well no, the birds here are some stupid species.
The chair is still unrepaired. where is dad
I don't know, I don't know how to fix a chair.
Oh!
Father, I came!
Hello, Moomin troll.
Go inside.
Don't you have time to fix the chair?
Tomorrow. It doesn't take long when the plans are clear.
Dad, Can you write on that chair?
Of course, I'm writing right now.
Don't bother.
Oh yes, mom said the food is on the table.
Good, my stomach rumbled.
I'll just write a few words now that I'm up to speed.
Yes.
Come sleep well.
Doll, doll.
Korina has more sweets as well.
Come to sleep, come to sleep.
Who is there?
Oh sell, you're sell.
What are you doing there on the porch?
Wait, you can't come!
What? I didn't die what you said.
Don't come any closer!
Uh!
Are you still chasing bird parks?
Is Moomin Pekko home?
No.
Right? Well where has he gone?
I don't know!
Hello, little snuff.
You seem to be in a big hurry.
Yep, dad's writing chair broke.
Oh, that big dark office chair.
Yep, the backrest needs to be replaced.
This branch could be suitable for that purpose.
It was an ancient chair.
Couldn't Moominpa get a new one?
No. Writing only fits on that chair.
Well, not necessarily, but of course I believe what you said.
I'm kind of to blame for the chair breaking.
That's why I'm trying to fix it.
Aijaha, but listen Moomin peko.
That branch is not there to lean on.
Right?
Maybe the branch is curved enough,
but for woodwork you must always use properly dried wood.
Wet wood.
I heard from the seller that the chair with Moominpapa's writing on it has broken.
This was my father's favorite chair, but now Moompa gets it.
Thank you, Mymmeli.
This is old.
I have changed.
Thank you, Mymmeli.
This is old, but it is surprisingly comfortable to sit on.
Just try it.
Very friendly.
I have designed this special chair to suit all body types.
Can I take some measurements?
I estimated your dimensions correctly.
That's it, now the chair is adjusted to your measurements.
Thank you, Niisku.
I thank the gentleman for seeing the baby.
I can give it the argo it deserves.
Now everyone go in and have some tea.
Feel good.
First I carry the chair to Moominpapa's study.
Oh no, I'll carry it myself.
And you don't sit and write?
What a surprise to see Mymmeli here with the chairs.
And more people are coming.
Hemulik also had his penkovaiva.
Moominpapa!
Is what?
I place the chair next to the table so we can check the height.
Come up.
Ha, it's fine.
Niisku, miss, don't roar!
My bird's fathers are aiming again.
Ha, someone has tripped over the wire.
They would use their eyes.
Ha, I'm running out of patience.
They would even fix it.
Ha, come back.
I can't take it.
Who among you silly birds cares?
Stay in the sky.
That's the end of catching birds.
Hey!
Dad said it wasn't my fault when the chair broke.
But I think he's trying to comfort me.
If only another chair would suit dad.
I can sit on a chair like a chair when I read and write.
There is so much trolling in this world that when you get older.
And has always done the same way.
Some other way did not create any way, no matter how much you wanted to.
But I find it boring to always do things the same way.
We're probably not old enough yet.
Stupid or not, if your father thinks you can't write without his old chair.
He can't.
You get chocolate.
Oh thank you.
Warm.
Listen.
Bring the body of the crank behind your back.
Oh, is this what you mean?
Exactly that. What would you say about that?
How so what?
I thought it would make a good back for papa's chair.
So?
It is dry and in the form of the right law.
What do you think? Wouldn't that be good?
Snuff, Can I have it?
Of course you can. Do you want me to help you fix it?
No thanks. I'll try myself.
It was a day.
Oh, what a number of chairs came to the house.
I'd say something else, mom. Yes, there is still kindness in the world.
Dad, maybe you'll qualify for one of them?
Perhaps. Good night.
Good night.
Ai.
Ah, that's quite fitting.
It tickles.
Has it always tickled? Perhaps. I just haven't noticed before.
I should have oiled the mechanism anyway to maintain the chair better.
This chair has served.
This chair has served for a long time.
Hey.
Father.
Good morning, my boy.
Good morning. What are you doing here on the porch?
I could ask you the same thing.
What do you have?
I have made a new backrest. Do he pins fit?
Let's see. Beautiful work. You're such a sucker.
Let's try already. I absolutely can't wait.
Me neither.
They fit their jets.
Oh Moomin, you don't know what this means to me.
The chair has already come to life.
It still lacks varnish.
I try how it feels to sit.
What's up? Move a little further, my boy.
About.
Yes, it feels comfortable.
Did the chair turn out decent?
Of course there was. I can already feel the inspiration taking over me.
Thanks Moomin.
Think nothing of it. I hope your book turns out well.
Oops. Necessarily.
The Moomin could have gone.
I came a long way for nothing.
Hello! Take a break already!
Hey.
Hello, Snuff-muikkunen. Come along too.
We go to the beach to play ball.
Come after. Hello.
Everything was back to normal in the Moomin house when Moominpa got his old chair back.
Moomin was tired from nightly napping.
Nuuska Muikkunen played him this tune as sleep music.