beiwaterikko
How nice.
Mamma, I find it enjoyable to drink coffee at the same time every day.
Well, about me too.
Dad, why is it so enjoyable?
My son, it shows that the world remains unchanged.
At least in Moominvalley.
Why do you like immutability?
I don't miss the same thing twice!
Dad likes disasters and excitement, but he enjoys his cup of coffee just the same.
I would like to experience as many adventures as my father did back in the day.
Speaking of which, Moominpapa, you haven't told me everything about your youth.
I want to hear!
Tell me, father please!
Well, let's see.
Moomipappa, and you didn't even meet someone like me when you were young?
Like you?
Oh yes, I met.
Or what?
Does Moomimama know him?
Father, continue your story!
Well, it's fine if you really want to hear about my youth.
Remember where we left off last time?
You said your house was haunted!
Oh, let's forget the ghosts.
Support, your ear if you're scared!
Well, not now!
So we had settled down on King's Island.
And there we had to form a colony.
But I didn't quite understand what the colony meant.
I asked my mother what to do in the colony.
Well, what?
There must be many of you and you must live very close to each other.
Yes.
And then there was a fight here!
Why? Do we have to?
I don't like arguing.
Strange if you have to argue.
I don't agree. I have no desire to argue with anyone.
In that case, I'm going to live separately.
That's wrong!
Well Juksu, what do you say?
In my opinion, everyone can live and live in the settlement as they want.
Are you sure?
We are all completely free beings, and at least I won't start arguing.
Still don't live very close.
Ice cream!
Well who is he?
Sosuli! He lives in the southern tip of the island!
I think Hosuli has set his sights on her!
What is Frederikson talking about?
Frederikson is hastily building an amphibian.
On the king's order, Frederikson had moved to the surprise park and built feverishly there.
We barely saw each other.
A colony, but there are quite a few of us.
What is it?
Was it a ghost?
It was.
What is it?
Could it be a ghost?
Oh!
Tonight is Lea?
Embrace the revenge of the bones of the dying forgotten.
Do you have a cold?
I probably am.
It will pass.
Aren't you afraid of me at all?
It's hard to be afraid of someone who sneezes.
Really? No one can tilt chains in this kind of weather.
But to choose your fate the next time I come and slam my squishy paw down your throat.
Oh, are you coming back? When can you come?
I thought maybe next Friday at midnight.
It's fun. I invite my friends to the haunted house.
Your friend?
Exactly. I guess you want to haunt more than one person.
Well, yes, but that's fine.
So I'll be back next Friday.
Oh, it will be a very nice surprise for everyone.
Be careful!
Ipsu, hi Ipsu, Ipsu, you can listen again.
The ghost has already left.
Did the ghost return on Friday?
Oh, it did come back. That night I had decided to wait for the ghost outside.
I haven't really invited you because I'm offering you dinner.
Well, that explains the fact that the fish didn't taste like anything.
Why have you invited us?
That you might experience something really scary.
Oh, wonderful! I want scares!
Keep what you get. This is where the real ghost appears.
What?
Oh, did you hear that? Jukra, that's something!
Moomi, don't count the slider. I don't like ghosts. You do know.
I'm not counting the slider.
Look everybody over there.
You spoke the truth.
Where is it?
The ghost is right behind there now.
Unlock the Revenge of the Forgotten Bones!
It's wonderful to finally meet a real ghost! Will you take the deal?
It wasn't supposed to go like this.
When you saw me, you should have barked and screamed and yelled at them.
Oh yeah, he knows how to behave. Thanks.
No, don't bother coming any closer.
I'm a little disappointed too. I thought everyone would be scared.
Maybe I wasn't that scared, but I was really amazed at how that ghost hovers above the earth chamber.
I wish my amphibian could move the same way.
Listen Moomin, can't a ghost move in with you? The colony would get one more member.
Good idea. Could you scare us anytime?
I recommend!
The same if Moomin has proper heating. Disgusting catch a cold.
But Moomin, then I can't visit you.
You have to because you're the only one who's afraid of me.
Don't come any closer.
And that's how I started living with a ghost.
On Midsummer's Eve, I was reading a book and the ghost was sitting knitting. According to him, he calmed his nerves.
Moomin! Moomin!
Hey!
Fredriks has finally finished the amphibian.
Oh, is it?
The king himself performs the descent into the waters and then also consecrates the hosul and sosul.
Initiates the hosul. Wait, I'll come down.
Is hosulin going to get married? Since he decided it?
The king actually just decided it. He's so into weddings and stuff.
Tol molt is fine.
Toin you are halvalights!
In the second part we can eat uczitt strengthening.
Even if the floor glove is kann'Da to do the biggest kavaddaming Down.
What is Olen lyhotivealis ja.
Change the buttons.
Congratulations. Now you are husband and wife.
Good luck, Hosuli!
Thank you very much.
I didn't know about your marriage intentions.
I can imagine that the desire to get married strikes quite unexpectedly.
Not to me, at least.
Hosuli! You will have the honor of revealing my ship! It's my wedding cake!
Oh, thank you, Frederikson.
My dear foolish subjects.
We now solemnly launch our own invention Fredrikson's Amphibian.
It travels along the ground, dives under water and also flies in the air.
Long live Frederikson!
No, Hosuli ja Sosuli.
Tell me what you think of my new sea spray.
That's great, Frederikson.
Everyone step into the Amphib!
Clear!
Sosuli!
Does he fly this?
Fly... ...look carefully.
Let's go.
Make fun of us hitting the beach.
I'm just at peace.
It flies!
So fly! Fly for real!
Frederikson, you did it!
Amphibian works great!
We're not getting any higher, Frederikson!
Nothing will come of it.
It's nothing.
The engines did now no longer.
We're going down!
In Ke
I'm important.
We are not underwater.
Look.
What is a fish?
For you
A-la-la-la-la
Vaa
Wow, la, la, la
Elected
Let's surface again.
Which one was it in?
Edvard, hi!
What are you doing here?
Are you possibly coming to Hosul's wedding?
Sano!
Do you like weddings?
It's fun.
And then our colony got one more new member.
That fall, it rained heavily and storms raged.
The water was high.
Before long, everyone was in my house, which, needless to say, was the best built.
It would eventually be ordered to stop.
Good, here's the bed ready for you.
Thanks a lot, Moomin.
Funny, this house of mine used to be the wheelhouse of a sea spray.
We have never had such bad gale before.
Go out on an inspection tour.
I stepped onto the beach as if I had a premonition of something.
Baby!
My handbag!
Save my handbag!
It's on your arm.
The shin is here to see, Anki.
A puff of water plays from the tuba.
Vivawanambo Henri.
Even the hardest workers have to be there.
Oh, thanks for saving me. What is your name?
I'm Moomi.
I noticed the witch had a girl with whom I could start a colony.
This girl looked so beat up.
It was. Even without the bangs, he looked exactly the same.
And she was very attractive.
It was.
What happened to that girl?
I carried her to my house, of course, and there we began to live happily.
Moomi papa, I strongly doubt that girl was...
Nuskamuikkunen and Nipsu, are you going to eat from the air?
Is something crazy?
The girl was Moomin!
And so she became my mother.
I, Momi Mamma.
Dad, so you told them.
Yeah, I just told you how we met.
I'm embarrassed.
And this is where I end my memoir this time.
What happened to the baby?
And for Mymmel's daughter!
After meeting Moomi mamma, my days as an adventurer were over, and we have lived happily ever after together.
Now it's your turn to create your own stories.
And then Papa Moomi fell silent.
Moomi the goblin decided that she would follow in her father's footsteps and experience as many adventures in her youth.
Thanks for watching the video!