It had been raining in Moomin Valley for a week and a half.
Moomin had done everything that can be done inside.
Now he was engrossed in reading romantic stories.
Me here. May I come?
Moomin, suppose you are there.
Why didn't you answer?
Oh yeah, Miss Strike.
What's wrong with you?
No.
Does the rain get you down?
Not at all. The rain is nice.
It won't last weeks with these.
Has it lasted?
You haven't come to see me. It's so boring in the rain.
Not about me.
It's a lie.
I have read.
All these books.
Yeah, I borrowed from mymmell.
Contemporary stories.
Wildly romantic.
Cheap entertainment.
It works for me. All those gorgeous heroines.
Katinkonti.
Pretentious chickens.
Don't you appreciate me?
Huh!
I dragged myself to you in the rain because I thought you needed a follower.
But you don't notice me.
Sorry, hit lady, but the heroines of these stories completely draw me into their world.
I'm going home.
Huh!
You keep dreaming about silly heroines.
Why was Niiskuneiti angry?
Goodbye! I'm leaving now.
Well, you just came.
I don't want to disturb the Moomin.
Or disturb?
Oh shoemaker! Disaster!
Dude, what now?
Something horrible, right?
Yes, the whole circus has been swept away by the flood current.
What?
The Moomin house gets flooded again.
Do you know how the circus people have been?
How would I know?
They can seek shelter in this vicinity.
What are you imagining?
Do you know the attraction of the circus?
I know, that long-nosed prima donna.
They say she is very beautiful.
The current has carried him away.
If a prima donna swims in these corners I could save her.
I would be his hero.
Hey, you're waiting!
I will save you.
I'm Moomin, from this neighborhood.
And you are a lovely Primadonna.
I am wonderful, I can admit that.
But I am the Primadonna's steed.
Oh, where is Primadonna?
The road collapsed as the flood rushed over us.
I would be happy with the crackle of a campfire and brushing.
The Moomin is coming back.
Hi, where have you been?
Primadonna has sought shelter nearby.
This is his horse.
Come in.
Thanks.
I guess he's not kicking.
Father, here is the Primadonna's horse.
This is a great honor for us.
Please get better.
Moomin, what are you doing?
I will find the Primadonna and save her.
Prima donnas don't know how to take care of themselves.
Speak up.
Someone is smiling.
You must be a Primadonna.
I knew someone was coming to save me.
Did you know that I will help you out of trouble?
I didn't know it was you, but the Primadonna can count on that,
that some eager young man always saves her.
Speak up.
This is where I live.
Welcome back, Moomin.
Hi niiskunmi, I think I found Primadonna.
Here's my hand.
Thank you young man.
Too bad we can't eat in the dining room.
Fortunately, we are able to prepare breakfast without a kitchen.
Yes, when we have a stove, dry firewood and fresh bread.
Oh good time, I took the coffee beans, but forgot the coffee grinder and the pan.
It's okay, nobody wants coffee.
And whoever wants can chew coffee beans and wash them down with hot water.
Where are you going?
To wake up the Primadonna.
He can come to the breakfast table with us.
Moomin!
Prima donna! Prima donna!
In!
Good morning young man.
Good morning, breakfast is waiting.
Thank you, I start the day by drinking a cup of coffee in bed.
Coffee?
I can't imagine getting up until I've had a cup of mocha.
Dad, isn't the kitchen directly below?
Yes, yes, but what is not to do.
I don't understand this fuss.
The saw has an opening.
Oh, for what.
I have to get to the kitchen this red minute.
Don't fool around.
I got a coffee grinder and a pan from the kitchen.
Good morning.
Isn't the coffee ready yet?
This won't last more than a moment.
Mom, boil the water.
Your kitchen is a bit watery at the moment.
Don't you have flowers?
I don't eat anything else.
Primadonna has wrapped Moomin around her little finger.
Prima donna?
A prima donna does that for young men to be chosen.
I see you eat all the flowers.
I never want to see them again.
Why don't you?
Well, Moomin has carved into the frame.
Well, the writing is now under water.
The flowers are dedicated to Niiskunneid.
Eat the flowers, it's right for that creature.
I can't take it, and I feel like eating the tree bare.
Rauskuta, I'll scratch the writing off when the water has receded.
Here is the tree I told you about.
Beautiful flowers.
That woman is in Moomin's bag again.
Take my hand.
Whoops, the tree hums.
The roots have loosened from the flood.
The Moomin's screws have come loose.
What smell?
Young man, please help me up a little.
Joy of the mind.
Grab a paw and trust me.
But do you have enough power?
On, on.
Moomin retale.
Is this normal?
Let's shake the lady down.
Flea is good for both.
Do not release the grip.
Moomin troll.
Moomin, help me too.
Miss Strike, how are you here?
Give me a zero too, Kelmi.
Don't even talk to me.
What's gnawing at you?
He may be a jealous young man.
Jealous of whom?
Oh, I'm a strongman.
Good, good, more.
More, more, more, more.
Good show.
Now be careful.
I haven't been here before.
Where are we?
At the foot of the lonely mountains.
We have to wait until the water recedes.
Look, there's a moose and a mymmeli.
Hi, Moomin, Snow Maiden.
Hey, oh they're here too.
Strongman.
Primadonna.
Do you know Primadonna?
We are from the same circus.
Why did he have to come here?
I thought I would have been able to enjoy a moment of peace.
What the hell happened to him?
I remembered a literary thing.
If Primadonna asks me, tell me I don't know where I'm going and when I'll be back, if I do.
Goodbye.
Strange man.
Who was that? Stands well in hand.
So it stood.
Please, are you amused by the strongman's flat presentation?
Where did he go?
Not rare.
Not even a hint.
Lovely.
He went to get special treats for my lunch.
Discernment is good for him.
He didn't promise to come back soon.
Understandably, it's hard to find food that satisfies my taste buds.
Moomin troll.
What?
Make me old Entertain me while the strongman gets me something to eat.
I don't think I can.
You can't be so stupid.
Moomin, try standing on it.
How could I entertain you?
Scoundrel.
That's your headache young man.
Yes, but...
It's your fault I'm here.
Your stupid valley flooded and you brought me here.
This is where you organize these things.
Moomin, try standing on it.
Go you hippies.
Walk to the edge of the world so that you fall down too.
I feel like I don't understand women.
I feel that Moomin has a lot to learn about women.
I have a nasty feeling that Primadonna is selfish.
How can someone be so beautiful without being nice?
I hate women, I do!
I couldn't have said it better.
You are the strong man.
You've obviously met Primadonna.
The prima donna imagines that you are getting her food.
Ha ha!
Couldn't you go back to Primadonna?
He won't make it when I left too.
Ha ha, young man, Prima donnas are never alone.
You will find someone.
Thank you for taking care of him.
Now he can fend for himself for a while.
Will anything come of it?
What if he suddenly wants to drink a cup of Javanese mocha?
You can do without.
She's a prima donna.
Let it be Primadonna for me, this boy has had enough.
But he is so sweet when his big soft eyes fill with tears.
I know, she always has a piece of onion in her handbag.
I'm going elsewhere, I'm starting my own circus.
Ah, there comes a horse.
Aha, that's where the strongman is.
I've been looking for you everywhere.
What matter?
Primadonna told me to say that as soon as you've ordered lunch, you can start planning a new number.
He is tired of the old one.
And should I cook first?
Eat half first.
Tell Primadonna that there will be no new numbers, and no lunch, nothing.
I thought you'd say that.
Hey, you didn't want anything from a teenager, didn't you?
No, a delicious meal is now closest to Primadonna's tormented heart.
Hoho, you can wait for nothing, I would have tried to make you his running boy.
I don't think so.
Did the strongman really say that?
Yes he said.
He has done too much standing on top. Men are so weak.
Hey, it looks like you're already slipping from yours.
It doesn't bother me if you don't want a roof over it, but a thunderstorm is coming.
I have to get between the sheets.
There are no beds in sight.
If we help in the construction, then we don't have to stay in the sky.
Oh, what a charming lodge!
Yes, you are clever builders and there is plenty of space.
We all go to sleep comfortably.
There will be water soon. How are their resses going?
They know how to get wet.
What don't you?
Oltan proceeded.
For example, batch management is awesome.
Lu weatherman foundation!
Under the light of the sun!
Aarua, luovres...
For the love of this earth,
Painuka arrested!
Go to the store if your own skin is a goat for you!
Help! Help!
I'm going to run. I worry about others.
What are they?
Hats. Harmless but terribly electric in thunder.
Arousing terror.
I'm used to them.
There!
You are not needed here!
Hattivats have surrounded them.
Fuck it!
They don't seem to have any problems. There was no need to run the whole way.
Oh, how's it going!
Very! Your prima donna is missing.
Hattivati might have promised to make him coffee.
Prima donna!
The prima donna is here.
I'm running!
Up at the top.
What is he doing there among the branches?
Volo, he's scared to death of hatties.
Hoi, Primadonna!
No, he doesn't want to answer.
He is struck dumb with terror. I have to help him down.
Listen boy, it's my job.
I'm the strong man.
Strongman, be kind to him.
Clear.
I wish I could climb like a monkey.
Is Primadonna all right?
The prima donna is angry.
She waited all evening in vain for her strongman.
Forgive me, Hempukka.
Grab your strongman by the neck and you'll be down in no time.
Primadonna is a little strongman.
From now on, the prima donna is on a sweet head.
Always cordial.
That's good. The strongman has been very angry.
Aha, now they come.
Hey, strongman, look.
What?
Isn't there a tent stuck to that rock?
Oh, ah, a tent.
Oh, it's a circus tent.
Goodbye.
Come and see the strong man's new issue.
Don't you get tired?
Not a bit.
Sure can sit on your shoulders?
You never tire me.
Miss Niisku looks happy.
Moomin-Pekko does have to do a bit of bragging to light up Miss Niisku's heart again.
Or what, Moomin-Pekko?
Were you talking about me?
We said you're awfully strong.
Moomin-Pekko can carry me all the way to the Moomin house.
Well, of course I carry him sometimes.
Do not! Moomin-Pakko manly pride won't allow that, will Moomin-Pakko?
Of course not.
You impress us, Moomin Pekko?
Especially when the Moomin House is still an hour away.
One hour trip?
Moomin-Pekko carried Miss Niisku all the way.
And decided that he would never be a prima donna again.