In other words, Moomin is in the company of Snoopy these days even more than usual.
Winter would hit Moomin Valley any day now and the friends would have to part ways.
Moomin would hibernate and Snoopy would wander south.
Hey my, why is your face so horribly sour?
Where exactly are you staying?
To the lonely mountains.
Why are you two always sneaking somewhere?
Don't talk soft, we're not going anywhere.
You're sloppy, you're worse than usual, and you don't care about others.
Are we really like that?
Maybe we are.
Nothing maybe, I say you are very naughty.
We just go for a walk.
Oh now?
So.
It's going to snow in the next few days, and then there's nowhere to go.
We would like to create one last look at Moomin Valley before winter.
Visible story.
But really, I'm leaving for the south soon and I want to get myself a vivid memory of these regions.
You know, you hear that.
Oh Moomin, can we come along?
Of course not.
It just occurred to me that you two are hatching some conspiracies again.
Nipsu, don't bother.
You know that snuff Muikkunen disappears for months.
We have a lot to talk about.
Let it be then, let's go.
Here is a fun view in the middle of winter.
All in white.
Pretty for sure.
I doubt it.
Well, of course it's beautiful.
It's beautiful in summer.
I must get here in the winter, for sure.
You can't, you're hibernating.
That's true.
But this winter I'm trying to stay awake.
Just like Moomin and me last winter.
So.
You can't do that.
Moomin, what are you going to do?
I don't miss snow and frost, I'm hibernating.
Let's go home, I've seen enough.
Sell, we didn't ask you to join.
Listen Nipsu, let's go back to the lake where the goldfish was.
No, no, that's too far.
Ha, you're afraid of that forest, Nipsu.
And please, I'm not afraid.
Look who's over there?
I don't know him.
What are you doing here?
Well, sitting.
Don't be silly, Nipsu.
Well hello.
Hello, hello.
Why are you sitting there?
I'm waiting.
Who?
Grandma.
So far.
Grandma told me to wait by the big rock on the lonely path to the mountains.
But there are other rocks along the path.
Is there?
I have only seen this.
Now watch Grandma while I make you wait here.
Grandma's cabin is in the forest and it's hard to find it.
Or in the forest?
Wait, I mean that forest.
I'm not quite sure.
There are witches in the forest.
How long have you been waiting?
About an hour.
Grandma, you are not regular.
Maybe I came early.
Well, that's how you came.
Hi grandma.
Welcome, Alisa.
Who are these kids anyway?
While I was sitting here alone, they passed by and aimed to help me.
Just thanks, it was nicely done.
It was friendly.
Shall we go?
We heard that Täti lives in the forest.
I live.
Where there?
Come on, don't you, I live right in the middle of the forest.
Really.
I only know an old cabin there, where witches supposedly lived.
Or like that.
Share share, that's my cabin.
The girl's grandmother is...
...I guess witches.
But there are no witches.
I guess there are.
Well, at least grandma doesn't look like a bad witch.
Appearances can be deceiving.
That nice girl can't have a mean grandma.
Yes, we hope so.
Why do you think grandma is a witch?
Who would live in the forest?
No matter who, I can't think of anyone else.
I feel in my skin that grandma is a witch.
And thus the pretty girl is the witch's grandchild.
Ugh, that's right.
In.
Nisku, prepare food.
I'll come right away.
No wonder it's so bright. Full moon.
Miss Nisku, you'd better move into the Moomin house tonight.
For what the hell?
I'm not going to hibernate because of my career.
But Nisku...
I need to finish the Blueprint of my new aircraft.
My first aircraft was still plagued by children's diseases, but this one will be perfect.
The new round shape excites me.
Nisku-dear, you know you need hibernation.
I'm supervising.
All right. I'm going to hibernate with the Moomins.
Clear. Shall we go to eat?
Just leave your sister. We notice all the mokomi.
Thank you very much.
It's also fun for Moomin. He gets company.
Joo.
Well, honey, you can't socialize while you're sleeping.
It's much more fun when someone else sleeps in the same room.
When do we hibernate?
In a few days if this weather continues.
Soon?
Snow will be on the ground before the weekend.
Nisku, good luck with the new blue copies. I hope they will be ready by spring.
Yes, they will graduate. Next year at this time I will be flying.
Thank you for taking care of my inner rest.
Small trouble.
Good night.
Have a good winter.
Sweet dreams, little girl.
Good luck with your work.
Well, I finally have the opportunity to delve deeper into design work.
Yes?
I can't believe my eyes.
I see delusions.
A witch rides on a broomstick.
When Nisku gets something on his mind, there is no room for anything else in his mind.
I have a hunch that it will work out now.
That round tractor in my dream flew beautifully.
I often dream of flying, but when I'm awake I don't dream about airline companies,
Nisku has a new idea.
Low?
What is it?
Ajajajajaja, it's mine!
Have you seen again?
It laughed at me.
Who laughed?
It flew on a broom without an engine.
Are you talking about a witch?
I worked for nothing if flying is so easy.
Don't be discouraged.
Did you see the witch?
Thus.
Where?
Very close.
Nisku, I don't see anything like that.
Only the moon shines in the sky.
Was it really flying in the sky?
Nisku, I don't see anything like that.
Only the moon shines in the sky.
Witch in the sky now.
Nisku knows what flies and what doesn't.
At least I won't believe it until I see it with my own eyes.
Sniff me, if that old granny is a real witch, then what kind of girl is she?
A witch's child's child is, of course, a witch.
I don't believe it. A girl can be an adopted child.
We need to get to the bottom of it.
It is.
Up.
And again you are red-handed.
Where are you sneaking off to?
Sell, you can't come today.
And why?
Because we have no idea what dangers lie ahead.
Aha, then I have to come along to watch that you guys don't get into trouble.
Nothing exciting has happened to me since kite flying.
I can't resist adventures.
I have come up with a plan.
I'll bite the witch and while she's in a helpless state teasing the girl.
Nothing crazy, but we don't know if grandma is a witch.
Wouldn't it be pretty embarrassing for you too to bite an ordinary grandma?
Maybe the witch needs a lost girl for some of her horrible magic tricks.
Let's find out.
So in what way?
I don't know yet.
I hope you come up with something before we get there.
Let's hide as close to the cabin as possible and then ask the girl out.
What if he doesn't come?
No, sitten me improvisoimme.
Ha, snuff has different labels.
If the girl doesn't come out, we boldly go and knock on the door.
Once we get inside, we will see what the truth is.
What would you say to that? What if the witch cast a spell on us?
If we don't start hearing, the little girl will run to Moomin Valley to get help.
No, no, the Moomins can do it. I explored the cabin.
It won't even be heard. I'll examine the cabin, sell it.
Sell, why can't we make it so that you are left out and if we get stuck, you try to free us and when necessary, seek help.
So you would put your life in my hands.
You would be our last hope.
I don't like the idea that the little one is my last hope.
I don't help anyone who doesn't trust me.
Well, that's what you saw.
Shh, shut up.
There.
Very quiet. Is there anyone at home?
Let's wait a while and see.
Do we have to stand and stare at this?
That's fine.
After all, it's a piece of cake if the cottage is empty.
Where have Moomin and snuff Muikkunen gone?
I don't care much and the little one is with them.
The seller let us down.
I can guess where they went.
Ah, you guess? Well where, where have they gone?
To the forest, of course.
Yes?
Looks like you met the right witch for us.
It wasn't right.
Sent to see.
I'm pretty sure I know how to get those in the woods.
To, to.
What now?
Ouch, ouch, ouch, sick to my stomach.
Oh, oh, I can't leave. Ouch, ouch, ouch, ouch.
How long are we still waiting for?
Uh, this isn't exciting at all.
Let's wait a little while longer.
At least we will know if grandma is home.
Uh, he's on business somewhere.
It is very possible.
He goes to the well.
He keeps the girl as his slave.
Sell, where are you going?
Sell follows a girl.
Go along and find out what you get.
I'll stay guarding the cabin.
All right.
No Myy waits.
No, look, get a haircut today.
Wait.
I haven't done anything.
Then why are you running away?
I will help you.
And me!
Thanks. It is light to carry in three beds.
Your name is Alisa.
That's right, glad you remembered that.
I'm a Moomin troll.
And I Sell!
What are you here for?
Well actually we came because we were worried about you.
Worried about me?
Is that old man your grandma?
On.
Are you sure?
I am. She is my mother's mother. Why do you ask?
Well, when that...
Moomin would like to ask...
What?
Is your grandma a witch?
On, on.
I'm smitten.
It doesn't bother you at all that your grandma is a witch?
Oh no. He is what he is.
One day I will become a witch too.
Hard to imagine. You don't look like a witch.
I'm not a witch yet.
But if you are born into a witch family, you become a witch.
It does require studying.
Goes beyond understanding.
Aunt doesn't sound like a witch.
So what should a witch sound like?
To be honest, I have never met a witch before.
As a passport, you are simple.
Is that pretty girl really auntie's grandchild?
Sa hear, promising girl.
Honest and hardworking, she will make a great witch if she obeys me.
How does a sweet girl become a witch?
I didn't know you were home already.
Good thing you fetched water.
Who is it?
This simple chap has undoubtedly come to your rescue.
Oh, you're Nuuska Muikkunen.
I am.
Nuuska Muikkunen is here. Please come in.
Is Nuuska in Muikkunen's cabin?
On.
Muuska Muikkunen is here.
Muuska Muikkunen is here. Please come in.
Is Nuuska in Muikkunen's cabin?
Oh, he's got company.
Oh, Nuuska Muikkunen, what has been done to you?
I'll open the rope.
Wait, I'll do it.
This is small.
Huh, that was tough.
Hey, don't run away, I still need you.
Kärme freaked out when it was bitten.
Yes, yes.
By the way, what are you doing here?
They've come all the way from Moomin Valley to check that I'm okay.
So far away.
They came to save me from your clutches if you mistreat me.
Oh yes, it can be done.
Witches are thought not to be honorable citizens.
We apologize.
Nuuska Muikkunen, Alisa said that she wants to visit us in Moomin Valley soon.
He is welcome.
Have you gone to promise one?
I thought I'd drop by Moomin once in a while after I've done my homework first.
I don't want to neglect my studies.
Oh oh, but if you want to become a good witch, you must not meet ordinary mortals.
Oh, what a shame.
Just when we had time to become friends.
If only I started those studies next year.
Alisa!
This is a family matter.
If you don't mind, I would ask you to leave.
Snow!
Alisa won't be able to see us when Moomin Valley is covered under a blanket of snow again.
No.
Yes, and the snot, they're going south.
Winter is coming to Moomin Valley again.