Do you have a bag today?
It's not heavy.
Well, thanks.
We are about to reach it and there we can rest.
Remember the snitch and fan with the king's ruby?
They have returned to Moomin Valley with their suitcase.
Smoke rises from the chimney of the Moomin house.
Good, grandma is cooking dinner.
Moomins are so nice.
They lose our results.
When we have such a wonderful gift for them.
Yep, I'm sure the Moomins will squeal with delight when they see it.
Shall we continue the journey?
Joo.
I'm carrying a suitcase now.
Yes, I can still do it.
The oops
Sorry, lighter than I imagined.
The bag has...
I know, a gift for me.
No, there's a gift for the rest of us.
They have a house full of stuff, they don't need anything.
The suitcase is ours.
Count it down world. Thanks.
I show others a gift even if they don't need it.
What do we do now, Viutti?
I just don't know.
Does that Rogue live here?
I don't know. We won't see the last of him.
What advice?
This wretch is locked.
Putrid.
Why does everything have to be locked?
I want the suitcase open.
There is a small object there.
But little objects can be themes.
It opened.
I don't know.
Thanks.
What is this?
It looks like a tulip bulb.
True.
Oh.
A little different anyway.
You?
You name it whose suitcase it is.
Well, mine. What are you talking about?
Then why didn't you open the suitcase?
I was watching you.
I can go to you.
Or so.
You mean you locked the bag?
Of course I mean.
Do you think I'm lazy?
Where is that suitcase from?
Sano.
You have stolen a suitcase.
And I'm not.
I found it on the ground.
It just had this onion.
Outrageous.
Don't stink.
Au.
You can't eat it.
I've traveled.
It's not the tulip bulb.
What the hell is that?
I will give you the whole onion and the suitcase.
Windy windy windy.
Welcome.
Hello Moomin.
Nice to see.
Long time no see.
Healthy muuta.
Come in now.
Not standing here at the foot of the stairs.
To the end.
Father guests.
A very good day.
What a surprise.
Strong winds.
Haven't seen you in ages.
Moominpapa.
We brought you a really wonderful gift.
It wouldn't have been necessary.
You are always welcome.
Mummy Moomin.
We have come up with a great gift for you.
Goodness.
Thank you.
Do you like our gift?
Of course I do.
What is that gift?
I'm really excited.
Oh dear, sorry.
The gift was stolen on the way.
Stolen?
And it was such an incredibly fun gift.
I sure would have liked your gift.
How sad?
I would have liked to see it.
Mummy Moomin.
Can we have your nature as guests, even though we don't have a gift?
Of course.
Stay as long as you want.
Did you hear the fiddling?
I heard and I'm glad.
Oh thank you Moomin.
Can you tell me in more detail where the gift was stolen from you?
In this vicinity.
In Moominvalley.
That's right, it was stolen in the pass.
There aren't many thieves living around these corners.
Not so, and I know that one.
he i, still beautiful.
Don't bother.
You can see he's currently in the woods.
Return the item you stole from our guests.
Are you visiting?
Oh, from them.
Aha, you stole...
I don't know what you're talking about.
We are visiting a wonderful gift.
Give it here.
Give it back before I get mad.
Or I'll be responsible for the consequences.
We calm down.
Oomi, Peekko.
What did you say?
Give that gift.
Are you talking about a wonderful gift?
I spoke. How so?
A lovely gift.
Hey, hey, hey.
Someone just...
when laughing.
Aha, now it's clear who Haisuli has stolen the suitcase from.
The gift is not wasted.
No, but it's not here anymore.
Where is it then?
I took it to the hemul so that he could examine which plant it was.
I also took a suitcase.
Or is the gift a tuber?
So, some onion.
Absolutely. It looked like a tulip bulb, but I don't really think it is.
So a wonderful gift is an old onion.
It could be a bulb of a very rare plant. Hemuli doesn't seem to have felt it.
I wish the gift had been another ruby.
Ruby? Oh yes, Tiuhti and Fiuhti had stolen a ruby from a ruffian and hid it in a suitcase.
Taukku was familiar.
Did Tiuhti and fiuhti steal the onion too?
How do you know that? Let's go see what Hemuli is currently working on.
Hemuli!
Kasvar, have a good day.
Is that the onion I brought yesterday? Insignificant looking.
I'm just about to plant it.
What plant is that?
No idea. I've never seen anything like it.
Then it must be the bulb of a rare plant.
I'm just a little worried.
What?
The onion is damaged. Hopefully, the schools it has experienced will not prevent it from sprouting.
Ah, now I remember. The skunk tried to taste the onion.
Be roasted!
Hey Hemuli, don't plant the onions yet.
Oh, why not?
Let's take the onion to the one it's meant for.
Like, like that.
Here comes the water!
Well, will this work?
Go on, please.
Come on, tell us now, which plant's bulb is it?
Cracked from life.
Alright, let's see...
Wait, Tiuhti!
What now, fan?
Well, I want to tell the whole story.
So, what's up?
Better, of course, that you tell.
Tell me, yeah.
You see, if I start from the beginning, the onion doesn't come from here at all.
The onion comes from somewhere very, very far away, even further than the cuckoo.
Nice to meet you.
And that is why it is rarer than any other onion and an excellent gift for our friends or for us.
A unique onion.
And the most unique thing about it is that it starts to sing.
Phooey.
Yes, the flower sings very well, it has a good voice.
Sorry, just keep going.
And it sings special songs.
Thanks for the botany.
Maybe it's good that not all flowers sing.
Where did you find the onion?
Shall I tell you?
Alone.
We're not even banned.
Tell me already.
Who did you get the onion from, unless it came from space?
Well, from a magician.
Of course.
The magician liked the onion, but even more the ruby.
We did trades.
The magician already had a ruby, but he obviously wanted to match it.
That's right.
But you willingly gave up the ruby.
We had it for a long time and we were sure you would like to sing about the flower.
That's fine.
We were in a lot of trouble the last time we were in the Moomin house.
Right, we're fine.
We would love to come again.
Nice to hear. Thank you.
I felt that it would be wise to put the onion in a bowl of water.
That age for sure.
We are monitoring its development.
And when it bursts into flower, it begins to sing.
Not just next to the note.
How soon will it bloom?
In two days.
Oh my goodness.
Let's get it into the water quickly.
You you it.
All right. I'll dip the onion.
Only two days.
Grandma, can I stay here for a while?
Of course he can.
I'll stay too.
Two days had passed and then three.
And soon a whole week.
But the onion was just the same.
Ten days had passed and the onion looked as lifeless as before.
Our little guests went for a walk.
I almost thought I saw nobody singing.
Maybe the onion has received too much moisture.
It's very possible, Mom.
The skunk's bite did it no good.
There are now.
That's our only chance.
But dangerous.
I don't like this at all.
We are lost.
Bridges!
Oh, come help! Come help!
It didn't work out.
Don't worry.
Help! Tilti got into trouble.
Help! Help! Come and scare the crap out of me.
So you can't do it.
Unfortunately I don't.
Grandma could get an onion in her item, but I probably can't.
Look, I haven't fully learned those yet.
When will your grandma come back home?
Not for a while.
Otherwise, I wouldn't run here.
how are you now
Do you guarantee a hot drink?
Yes, it grows right.
how are you now
The singing flower grows and it still sings beautifully.
Believe me?
Oh, Tilti.
I am sure that one day the onion will still sprout.
It would be fun to hear someone sing.
Everyone has somehow given up hope that the bulb would grow into a singing flower.
Hemulik too, who was so excited about the gift of a fan and a fan.
Why don't you east?
Are there signs of germination?
It doesn't show.
Did you stop watching?
I stopped. Difficult observation when there is nothing to observe.
This came to mind.
What?
I have heard that some call the plants.
That they would grow better and that really helps.
So they say. Unscientific, though.
If you tried, and what kind of music would be suitable for an onion?
If it grows into a singing flower, you'd think any music would bring it to life.
Yes, without a doubt. Great, great.
Snuff stick, come on.
And don't just sit there. We have work to do.
But Hemuli...
Without you, this will be nothing.
What sound is that?
The snuffbox plays the harmonica on the onion.
For what the hell?
I don't know.
I guess we should gradually end the visit?
Our gift was a full wolf.
They are of no use.
Well, that's what it looks like.
Would you like a cup of tea?
Ah, yes, thank you.
Good idea.
Why didn't calling help?
The onion should...
Not used!
No!
Why didn't calling help?
The onion should...
No!
Use!
To sprout!
That hardly works either.
Coming already!
Well, what's happening now?
It's no use staring at that onion. It won't budge.
Shut up.
I hear something.
The onion sprouts!
It's growing.
Mummy Moomin!
Moominpapa!
The singing flower has sprouted.
It has leaves!
Did my lips make my harp do it?
Beyond belief!
How can I leave you?
I'm crazy too.
It really does look like it could sing.
Is that so?
It really looks like it could sing.
You were right.
That's what we said.
Nice plant.
Very comfortable.
Sorry I doubted.
It felt so incredible.
Even grandma would be surprised by this.
Oh, I hear.
Uuuuu...
I get hungry when I sleep.
New album.
Good appetite.
Uuuuu...
Hey hey!