Mymmeli is a real lust cleaner.
Sometimes Mymmeli cleans the Moomin house too.
As a thank you to grandma when she takes care of the small sale.
Oh thank you Mymmeli.
It can't last, oh I enjoy it so much when I get to do a proper Big cleaning.
You will still be an excellent family mother.
Well, mothers don't have enough time to clean.
Why wouldn't it be? Don't screw up. Do you have a crush?
Oh well.
There is now one potential groom here.
Who will come from there? Oh police chief.
He sells the day. Sister, it's here.
Did you come all the way because of him?
Don't be stupid. I came in the capacity of police chief, in an important position.
Ah, so you came to arrest Mymmel.
No, no, no. Can I see Mymmel?
Why do you want to see Mymmel?
Here's how.
Well, where did I put it?
Here it is.
Sarmus.
Diamond charm.
Oh, the charm I found and brought to the police station.
Sure enough. And since the law dictates we half a year gone,
without the owner showing up, the ring goes to the finder.
Is this Mymmelin?
Oh, is Diamond into me now?
On, on.
Police Chief.
And, what?
You looked like an engaged couple.
Oh, and please.
Ha, the police master blushed.
Oh, boys, what a luscious Diamond.
Shit, don't.
Nipsu, give me the ring.
Hmm, let's see. Big as what.
Is it glass?
No, glass doesn't sparkle like that.
Hey, show me.
And will Niisku be asked to watch it?
He can tell if it is a genuine Diamond.
Apparently glass.
Oh dear.
A scientist must stick to the truth.
On the other hand, I wouldn't want to disappoint Mymmel.
Well, what is it?
Did you find out?
Look, Mymmeli.
Hatch, look.
Did you find out?
Look, Mymmeli.
Glass doesn't cut glass, but Diamond does.
That's right, Diamond.
Fifty carats.
Diamond?
What will happen to my fifty carat Diamond?
Let the municipality take care of it.
This looks like glass, but it's actually plastic that can be cut with glass.
Hi, Are you going to keep it tied all the time?
If you got a nice diamond and want to show it off, let everyone see it.
Mimmel!
Good day, Hemuli.
Grow up, Mymmeli.
Is something bothering you?
Don't you see?
Of course I see. Have you hurt your hand?
Nothing is too much trouble, see how Dimantti shines.
But it's just a rock. I'm interested in flora. Rocks are boring.
That's right, Diamond.
It's coal, just like heating coal.
They say experts are boring.
Good day, Uskamuikkunen.
Grew up, hello Mymmeli.
You have made your decision.
What decision?
You're married, ring naming.
Here, naming the ring.
Naming the ring.
You noticed it, the ring. That's what Diamond says.
You can see that.
Indeed, 50 carats. Impossibly valuable. Take a closer look.
Thanks. I already saw it.
If I close my eyes, I can see it in my mind.
It will never fade from my memory.
That's it, got it.
Well, men don't understand the delicate aspects of life.
It's a known fact.
Vili, who understands.
Hey, come look at that auntie's ring.
You are a Diamond.
Yes, it's nice.
Mother, here is an aunt with a diamond ring.
The diamond is bigger than you.
Bigger?
Many times bigger.
Kars Mymbeli?
Good day.
I happened to pass by and thought I'd stop for a little chat.
Go inside. It was good.
Oh, if it's okay to open up.
Mymbeli is good.
Oh, what a lovely scent.
Oh.
A delightful stone.
A good big maybe.
Oh yeah, it's a fifty carat Diamond.
Oh, it's very pretty, but...
But, but what?
It's strange, but too big Dimantti is popular.
Popular and not...
Yes, yes, Tuomainen Diamond suits the duchess, but they come to you.
It doesn't fit my dress code.
I hope you don't misunderstand me.
Of course not.
Thanks for the tea.
Ignore my words.
I don't. Let's see.
Some imagine they are something as soon as they happen to own a large Diamond.
True it is.
The old dress didn't ring Dimantti.
Mymbeli, what are you doing?
Admiring himself in Diamond Finger.
I need to get a new suit that fits Diamond better.
Then nobody knows you.
Or even a Lenin fit for a duchess?
After all, I have a few silk aprons.
Please help me mom, please help me.
Let's see.
Good day.
Hello Diamond.
Good!
Mimmeli came.
He looks nothing like Mimmel.
Mimmeli, I think you took me too literally.
How should it have been?
Nice suit, although the isthmus is strange and the movement maybe...
Is there anything else?
Yes, your whole life should be in harmony with the Diamond.
My whole life?
So.
I have to be.
Push it!
Mimmeli, are you lucky ع demonsta cou
mahduin mm.
Oh, or you, Stinker. What do you want from me?
What's up with that fine Diamond?
I know one house where it would fit.
The house is located in the darkness of the forest.
No one lives there.
It's so dark here.
Don't worry.
Now you realize why no one else knows about this house.
Here we are.
It seems to be an old house.
Yes, but handsome, just what you need.
Oh, oh, oh.
Look, Takka. They don't do that nowadays.
Phooey.
Brother, who turns green with envy, I'll give you the whole house.
Oh, thank you.
The fireplace seems to be the only nice touch. Everything else looks rotten.
Are you having fun?
That you had to find that ring.
Treats wipe.
Tabeting is a big job.
But then we lead the 50 carat life.
You can want that kind of life.
I'm not sure about myself.
If you want me, you can keep the ring on Mondays.
It won't stay off my finger.
Well, put it on a necklace.
I don't like mowing.
Oh wonder. I didn't know anything about this castle.
This is the real duchess castle.
But so spacious that you will drown here.
Yes, it's a bit big for me.
I change my mind very well here.
The posh, posh life is not for you.
Sell, don't interfere with this.
I can speak my mind.
Lopetta of that, Hand.
Neat now.
Head over there, madam.
Duchess of the castle.
Mymmel's new apartment.
Hey, that looks pretty cool.
Did you hear what I said?
This is not possible.
Mymmelin is delicious.
Mymmelin, hey, you're getting a guest.
Good morning, Mymmeli.
Good morning, dear lady.
Kind to come from such a long distance.
It is such a spacious kitchen.
Everything is spacious.
Looks like you're doing the dishes.
I am.
We just had lunch.
That's right, duchesses eat too, but they don't do the dishes.
If you absolutely want to wear a big diamond, you have to live up to it.
How is it going?
Get the Maid.
Servant girl?
What?
I enjoy housework.
Summer mustaches.
Duchesses are for enjoying themselves.
A maid is absolutely necessary, absolutely necessary.
Mimmel.
Nice to see you.
What now? Show off.
I have a maid.
What?
Isn't it valid?
Oh, too worthy. There is nothing left for me to do.
It has a nifty Maid.
Is there a thief?
Gotta go check it out.
Who there?
Mrs.
What is the lady doing here in the middle of the night?
See what...
Or so.
Didn't I wash the dishes after dinner?
Yes.
I just have to get myself to do something.
Is my job not good enough?
The dishes have never been so clean.
But when I couldn't sleep and there was nothing.
Just like that.
Ma'am, yes I notice when my work is not appreciated.
I will understand when I am no longer needed.
No! Wait!
Madam, we are in Pula.
How so?
It's raining there now.
So outside?
Oh, it's raining my beautiful mate.
Mymmeli, it's raining inside.
I need a rain shadow over the year.
Nobody remembered to fix the roof.
Let it rain.
I've screwed everyone over.
I'm really starting to worry about Mymmel.
That guy is no longer himself.
It's all because of that stupid tip.
Why did Mymmeli find it?
It would be a relief if he lost it.
I can screw it up.
I don't think that would be appropriate.
What can we do?
Goodbye, Madam.
Where did he go?
Listen, Mymmeli. They are going to steal.
It's your Diamond.
Who?
I'm not a language watcher.
The diamond must be hidden somewhere.
No one can take a look.
I plant flowers as a sign.
Mimmel.
Snuff Muikkunen!
Nuuska Muikkunen, what are you doing here?
I picked mushrooms.
Snuff Muikkunen!
Hi, where are you going?
To see Mymmel.
Yes, it was a very sad day,
when Mymmeli found that 50 carat Diamond.
Let's face it, it's not Diamond.
I only said that to please Mymmel.
Stone is glass.
I guess I did it wrong.
Now let's go see Mymmel.
Mysterious! why are you crying
Is my Diamond lit yet?
Don't cry, you're better off without it.
Apart from that, Diamond was just glass.
I'm sorry, I shouldn't have lied.
Do you lie now so I don't mourn?
I do know.
I won't lie, the piece of glass I cut was actually plastic.
Mymmeli, give me the ring and I'll prove it.
Well, I can't, when the ring is illuminated.
Then I can't testify.
I have the ring.
Oh my Diamond.
Did you steal it?
I hid it in a bun.
I just found the ring lying on the ground.
I know who the thief is, come forward!
My ring!
Catch the thief!
Let it go.
I believe in the tide, you don't need to prove anything to me.
Are you absolutely sure?
I am. Antatati keeps the ring, so I can.
You can what?
To be my equal.
Oh!
Diamond! Diamond!
Stink, what are you doing at Timanti?
Is that Mymmel's ring?
Would you stop it?
Onata! Onata!
Mymmeli was able to move out of the leaky castle and was able to wear an old, comfortable dress.