It's fun to get letters, at least once in a while.
Letters are somewhat rare in Moominvalley, but there are mailboxes and even a post office.
Hi, hi!
Did you yell at me?
There is a letter for you!
Aputo, aputo!
Yes?
It's coming now! Help! Help!
Aha, Pepsi!
Did you dig the hole?
I dug and it worked!
Who actually pulled this prank?
I guess that's not what happened.
You brave, have you dug a hole?
Of course not.
Who then?
Yes!
Ai!
You too!
My postman, could I get that letter?
Stop for several songs!
Mom, there's a letter.
A good time letter.
Yes, from mymmell.
On.
Where is Smyy?
Running somewhere.
Tell me about the letter.
My sister likes it.
I don't know.
He left to take a vacation from me.
He'll come back now, won't he?
Won't come.
If he has any sense, I fell into the pit for the third time.
I know, but I wasn't there to see the first two times.
You're a piece of shit, you horrible bastard.
I almost fell.
When you just fall.
You horrible bastard, you're sick.
Mymmeli is back.
He feels that he can handle selling again.
Great stuff.
We should go and clean the mummy's house.
Does the little girl know that her sister is coming back?
No.
Apparently my postman is still chasing him.
Don't bother telling me why.
Moomivamva!
That the letter is from Mymmule, what is he writing?
After a few days, Moomin returned to Moominvalley.
Mymmeli is much bigger than mye and calmer.
There's Moominvalley over there.
Is it full of nasty creatures?
Not to my knowledge.
Look at the smoke!
Smoke means food.
It's a Moomin house.
Are you also on your way to the Moomin house?
Yes, we thought so.
That's what happened. I'll go there too.
The suitcase looks heavy. Shall I help you?
No!
Right?
Not then.
What kind of people live in the Moomin house?
Were you thinking of staying the night?
If they are nice.
They are really nice.
My little sister lives with them.
Well, shall we go?
What is it?
Go ahead of you.
In for a penny in for a pound.
Mimmel!
How are you?
Good! Have you gotten a break from me?
Have to! Everyone is waiting for you!
By the way, two little strangers are coming here.
Did it look better?
For you?
They are about the size of a mole.
Well-being.
And they're dragging a big suitcase.
And then to a very small double bed.
Thanks for the coffee.
Well, shall we go home?
Little sells. Come on.
Not yet.
We have to go and fix the places.
The rooms must be ventilated.
I swept the floor of your household the other day.
And I left all the windows open.
Thank you.
Isn't it already a relief that you've been sleeping almost the whole time?
Myy has been here.
I've had time to strain anyone even a hair's breadth.
I don't see the goblin.
Hey hey!
Yes.
Father, what does that Jaaha mean?
That I can hear my thoughts again.
When the sell is gone.
Hey hey.
You go and knock on the door.
What if someone comes and starts screaming?
Maybe they will open.
Go now, go now.
Hey.
Vomit!
Sorry.
What happened to you two?
Don't forget your suitcase.
What should we do?
I don't bite.
I'm a local police officer.
Services to Moomin for ages and times.
Police!
We are no longer thieves.
Has anyone claimed that?
Isn't it?
Aren't you going to arrest us?
Of course not.
Go say hello to Moomin.
This suitcase is ours.
Has anyone said otherwise?
Just take it.
That's where you finally are.
Are these your guests, the Moomin?
I suppose so.
And since they have a suitcase with them,
they are going to stay.
Fun.
Would it suit you?
Of course.
I'm a Moomin.
I'm Tiuhti.
And this is Viuhti.
Welcome.
Step inside and make yourself at home.
I think we can stay.
Let's hide the suitcase.
They really are weird.
They are.
How can I be of help today?
So let's bring it.
I heard that Mymmeli is back.
Well, it is.
Is he coming here?
No.
He left with the sale of his home.
Just now.
Clear.
You have to check all the little things with the police.
It is very important.
Goodbye then, Moomin.
He has a crush on Mymmel.
But has Mymmeli fallen in love with him?
I don't know.
What are the guests up to?
They look scared.
Thanks.
I have emptied the drawing boxes for you.
Where do we put the bag?
In the drawing box?
You can hide it here.
Oh look, we've got beds like this made for us.
Let's hide the suitcase in the drawer of the drawing.
We must be on our guard.
I like the rest of us, they don't scream at all.
Still, we must be on our guard.
Special guests like our house.
But those two are from the most special end.
Jaa, they are from the north.
Hence the names Tiuhti and Viuhti.
Not this suitcase.
They seem like refugees to me.
They give you the law.
Do you want to see them?
Well yeah, isn't he?
Ha, there you are.
What are they doing?
No clue.
There was nothing but rustling in the room.
We think that newcomers are refugees.
How is their suitcase?
My brother?
Or state secrets?
That they are not arsonists.
Let's hide the matches.
Enemies of society one and two.
They don't look like it.
Do you take a snus and a pinch?
Thanks.
Cookies too please.
Joo.
Tightly.
Also the suitcase is gone.
What do I do now?
Did you get up?
Oh, you were under the year.
It's the safest place.
Something small can fit.
What?
Seseminot woke up that it would come.
It can't know we're here.
You never know, and it's coming tonight.
It certainly will.
It's windy there.
And suddenly it's terribly cold.
Hey.
Did you take a sweet nap?
Join the club.
Ha, there they are.
Here's Nipsu and a nosegay.
You don't have to be afraid of them.
What is it?
It will come.
It will be.
Who is it?
It will come.
It will be.
Who the hell is coming?
Bogey.
It's creepy.
Creepy that bastard.
Do you know about it?
I haven't seen it, but it's a scary monster.
Scary monster.
And it follows you.
It will be here very soon.
Don't be afraid.
It's not like that moron starts arguing with me.
Isn't it.
But if it's a monster.
Monster or not.
Guests are always safe in the Moomin house.
You two go to your room.
You locked all the doors.
Thank you, Moominpapa.
Nobody gets through this.
No.
Hands up, family.
Rock.
Hands up, family, dear.
Anyone for more tea?
What is it?
A monster is attacking us, Mummy Moomin.
Jeez.
Mamma, get the frying pan in case of a fight.
Everyone has decent weapons, right?
Started.
Vendeirausta-
Dmm4
Tomi
Bare a fasten
Tell me
He took it off
R forward
Um...
Hoi!
Oh, midnight.
There is no such thing as a stupid sign.
I hope not.
It will come! It's here!
Very close.
Absolutely insane.
I'm going home, I'm sleepy.
We can't stay up all night.
All right.
I'm leaving now that you know.
Remember cell phone.
Just take the open road.
You're trying to scare me.
I don't get scared easily.
It's here.
And it's not!
There are no signs.
A sudden gust of wind blew the candles out.
There's nobody there.
There's nothing stopping the nips from going home.
Admit that there is no such thing as ice cream.
You just scared me!
Petipuetta!
Not a living soul.
Don't crash like that.
It's here!
Where?
There, right outside the door.
Don't open the door!
Forward.
Not a soul.
Right?
Do you just exist?
Are you sure?
I guess you're right.
Not a soul.
We pushed it through.
Marke put his feet down.
That's it.
Dude, we'd be happy if you went home.
You're making our guests nervous.
You frost the roses.
Leave mom's flowers alone.
You have to leave.
Leave before I count to ten.
One.
Two.
Three.
Four.
Five.
Let's see.
Eight. Nine.
Old man!
Are you OK?
Look at the country.
Stupid.
Roar's voice.
Hey, when it got cold.
So it happened.
Mörkö won't be back tonight.
Let's go in and get something hot to drink.
And Mörkö didn't come back that night.
But why was it sneaking around the corners of Moomin House in the first place?
Is it still coming?
When everyone is sleeping.