- They choose the right Pretty Pour...
– Hmmm...
OikeMusik
Ui.
Isn't it a beautiful flower?
There is. What could it be called?
I don't know, you have to ask Hemur.
Mamma Honey, it's your birthday soon.
I know.
I'm not thinking of a present for you now.
Cheer up.
You deserve a fun gift, a special fun gift.
Beautiful yard.
Moominpapa had no idea what he would give Moominamma.
And it was only a week until my birthday.
Oh my god, this is awful.
Extra fun, funny and special.
A fun and special gift.
I shouldn't have said that.
Wedding. And you don't want to give a gift?
Of course I want to.
But when I went to promise a special fun gift, I can't give anything ordinary.
True. Mamma hardly wants a model airplane.
No. But would you invent something once you've invented it?
I'm thinking about it.
Mom is coming.
Hello Moomin.
Hi Niisku, what were you talking about?
Not much of anything, really.
We don't judge the weather.
Well, I hope you came to that conclusion.
Well, I hope you came to the conclusion that the sun is shining.
Get out below watch out, I'm coming.
I must say that being small has its advantages.
Yes, it never hurts to sell.
Hello then Niisku.
Hey.
Now I figured it out. Birthday present.
What do you give?
A homemade bicycle.
Good idea.
Sorry to bother you, but would you have time to plan it?
And in a hurry.
Right.
A heavy person should be able to handle it.
And go fast.
Last year, daddy gave mommy a seashell necklace.
Mom liked it a lot.
What about next year?
As I recall, mom got a hammock?
But it soon broke down.
Mamma is pregnant.
What did mom get it last year?
Hello, here we are this year.
Oh right.
Let's give Mommy Moomin a skateboard.
I share similar to this mine.
It doesn't suit mom.
Of course not.
Skateboarding is not very feminine.
Mom can hurt herself.
Would a nice hairbrush be fine?
Mamma is bald.
Let's give horribly tart filled candies.
Nipsu, we know no one would eat.
Coming up with a gift is difficult.
Ah.
What now?
Now I know.
You know what?
Moomipapa has built something secret in Niisku's workshop.
Probably a gift.
It can't be anything else.
Let's hope so.
My wet brother helps him.
What can they do for mom with Askarre?
Our gift has to be even better than mummy papas.
I think you should ask what mommy wants.
The bike meets my expectations.
I included a blue copy.
A really solid act.
Mamma can easily get to things and get exercise.
Shall I set off?
Fuck off.
Here's how it goes.
In the popes.
Does it hurt badly?
No, but the bicycle went to pieces.
Now you mustn't strain your leg.
And, and.
I came. Father.
What has happened?
Father swatted the rock upside down.
Mercy only, but can lead to blood poisoning.
Mumimamma.
What Nipsu?
What would you like to get from us for your birthday?
Something you have done yourself.
Yeah, but what?
Come on, I feel like the pan liners are starting to wear out again.
Dad, do you already have a gift for mom?
Kind of.
We haven't invented anything.
Didn't mom say something about pans?
Mom has some stashed in her cupboard. What do we do?
Let's think, let's think.
Listen mom.
Wait, I'll take a little more time at the counters.
Oh, dishes, work, work.
Oh!
Sorry, did you say something?
No, I'm fine, mom.
What happened to him?
That's a nut to crack.
Remember.
Remember, no swing necklace, roller skates or chocolate.
Shut the fuck up. Muuska muikku, they are thinking now.
Let's give flowers.
Flower?
So.
It's not a proper gift.
Chocolate is also a better option.
Let's prevent a flower bed for Mamma Moomin.
It has germ. Mamma likes taking care of flowers.
I like the idea of mom getting her own flower bed.
Good thing I asked Muikku.
I have no idea what you are building.
Soon you will see.
Looks like a water mill.
Well, you can't go far wrong.
Vesimylly.
Sorry to keep you waiting.
What do you do on the plates?
Pesenne. This is a water powered dishwasher.
Good unusual.
Doing dishes with this puller is pure joy.
Do I put the dirty dishes in the grinder?
Yeah, they're screwed in and then we sit and wait.
Did you invent the tricks yourself?
I am and it works. Unlike your bicycle.
The bike was broken by the building, not because of a design flaw.
Well, show me already.
Starting.
Let's see how the dirt comes off the plates automatically.
Hmm.
Ooo.
Hey.
Haha.
So yes.
Moomin, Do you know where all the plates have gone?
No idea.
Papa, have you seen our plates?
Oh, he's sleeping.
Something particularly fun.
Less time wasted.
Moominpappa had thought his head off.
But finally he got the idea.
Ooo.
Well, of course it's a good idea.
Paper.
Dad, here's some coffee.
Oh, thank you.
Mamma!
What now honey?
Could you look at me for a moment?
Like this?
Excellent. I'm motionless.
I'm trying.
Stay in that position, you must not move.
What the hell are you talking about?
Thank you mom honey.
Pappa is going to paint a portrait of Moomin with watercolors.
Not a crazy idea at all.
Maybe flowers for Moominamma's birthday.
Of course. Take as much as you want.
Thanks. We will immediately take a couple of boxes with us.
What's up?
Hemuli!
So what?
What are these black flowers?
Black roses.
Roses?
Aren't they beautiful?
Unnatural to me.
We don't want those Moomin's gardens.
Or so. But black accentuates other colors beautifully.
Where were you going to plant the flowers.
We haven't decided.
Somewhere next to a wall, I guess?
No. I suggest we plant the flowers somewhere further away.
Mom deserves a surprise.
Mom! Mom!
what's wrong my dear
Do you know where my watercolors have gone?
I couldn't find them in the pyro box.
They drowned.
Ai.
Don't you remember last summer when we were at the beach?
Oh yeah. I devoured them.
You had to get new watercolors.
I'm a fool.
Se he Kerbera.
Yeah, I feel.
Do you know what flower it is?
I don't know.
If on Armory.
Amrileria, sure.
Don't mind the roots, little sell.
Remember that flowers are alive.
Oh.
Mom's birthday is the day after tomorrow.
And I don't know anything as a gift.
If I just say I love him.
A particularly fun gift.
Or at least funny or special.
Hey.
There's dad over there.
Isn't it?
Well, it seems so.
What's wrong with him?
Father!
What is it?
Did you get blood poisoning?
A Moomin?
And the snot nose?
A pinch?
So when it's sold right away?
Habits are the number of flowers.
You don't pack.
In.
We will plant her own flower bed as a birthday gift.
Make them a welcome gift.
Is your present a ready-made Moomin doll?
What are you building for us mom?
Nothing special.
I see.
You want to keep it a secret.
Yeah, that's right.
Shall we continue the journey?
Let's continue.
Dad, we're in a bit of a hurry.
So?
Where do you take the flowers?
We hide them overnight and plant them tomorrow.
I can help if you want.
Thanks dad.
Nipsu, or tiring?
Not guaranteed.
I estimate that we need you three more trips.
Jukra, I'm getting hungry.
Moomin troll?
Yukra?
Jukra, I'm getting hungry.
Moomin troll?
What father?
That's it, all the three things I had thought of as a gift went to waste.
Could I possibly be allowed to participate in your giveaway?
And I don't object.
Well, neither do I.
Yes, that's fine. We need help.
It's true, a pinch makes you lazy.
With papa's help, we created wonderful plantings for mom.
Thank you for your trust, thank you.
Stars, tomorrow will be a beautiful day.
Must come.
What do you mean?
Well, everyone likes beautiful weather.
Not really you.
We can do it.
Daddy, what's wrong with you?
No. Forget it, good night.
Good night, papa.
At the foot of a cliff?
Right.
But dad, isn't that pretty far?
I have a specific reason for planting the flowers there.
Good morning.
Where are the others?
The flowers are planted at the foot of the cliff.
It's so far.
I'll explain why we had to come all the way here.
Whoa, wait a minute.
So what now?
I have forgotten one crucial point.
Of course, blackberries don't exist.
Oh my goodness.
Or black?
Yeah, my whole idea goes to waste without blackberries.
Are there any?
Is there?
No matter how many black roses there are in my garden.
Don't, are you sure?
Well, I am, but they are kind of sketchy.
You see they are not.
I solved my problem after all.
I don't want what you're after.
Well, I'll explain to you.
We plant flowers at the foot of a cliff because...
Can you guess what the reason is?
Good luck, let the voice be at school.
Thank you, friends.
Määtikulta, we have yet another birthday present for you.
Is there?
By us I mean everyone present.
Oh, I thank you all.
Do you want to see the gift right away?
Of course.
It doesn't even look like it's here.
We will take you to the gift.
Aha, is it outside?
It's a long way to go.
Come on, mom.
Mom, we're almost there now.
Oh, I'm getting nervous.
And all for me.
Joo.
Beautiful.
There are pets here.
So?
Poppies, astles, cherubs.
Moomin mamma looks pleased with her present.
Even black flowers.
They are roses, difficult to cultivate.
I believe it.
Mamma, shall we climb up now?
Remind?
To the edge of the cliff.
Is there something there too?
Come after.
What have you come up with?
You will soon see it.
Step on the edge.
Hey.
Do you like the view?
You still ask.
We planted the flowers according to the portrait drawn by father.
And we got a handbag from the black roses.
How can I thank you enough? What gift?
Just like you said, papa.
A particularly funny gift.
Day.