Varian erected by the robot will not work
Next Next Next Next Next Next Next Next Next Next Next Next Next Next Next Next Next Next Next Next Next Next Next Next Next Next Next Next Next Next Next Next Next Next Next Next Next Next Next Next Next Next Next Next Next Next Next Next Next Next Next Next Next Next Next Next Next Next Next Next Next Next Next Next Next Next Next Next Next Next Next Next Next Next Next Next Next next next next next next next
next next next next next next next next next next next next next next next next next next next next next next next next next next next next next next next next next next next next next right place increase to get roasted once, implies a hate thirty Endless nightmare, you be a top afternoon on the beach at, and there's nothing for me to be, and it's always a square half Tomorrow so we ain't got it a night on the beach, this time on
There will be a big six with them.
What does Noide have in mind now?
Now I Tajo this family enchants the darlings to sleep,
I'm going to sleep, to sleep for a while,
so that you wouldn't wake up on a moonlit day and fall,
I was scared, I was scared, I was laughing, I was squirming, I was crazy, whoa!
Oh, the nose is trying again, even though there are stones in the ear.
Hope!
It looks like spring.
Moomin Valley also wakes up from sleep.
Spring is in the air.
Wake up!
This looks like a new species.
Good morning, Hemuli.
Nipsu, you're in the early stages.
Yeah, I woke up before the Moomin.
So, I haven't seen a Moomin yet.
I haven't seen a Moomin.
Moomin wakes up, spring has come.
Moomin!
Come on, it's easier for my mother to wake up.
I'm not getting wet!
And I thought it was hard to wake me up.
Cool sleeping bags!
Dude, what are you doing?
Oh what, use your eyes.
Idiot, why are you playing on a ladder?
Well, when Moomin and Snow Maiden have to be woken up.
Why don't you use the stairs?
No one seems to be awake yet.
Let's sleep.
Moomin and the rain mother, wake up.
It's spring now!
Oh you! Moomin!
A fat loess too! Wake-up!
Strange behavior even from a Moomin.
Yy open the window!
Huh, I missed you.
Why haven't you woken them up?
No life.
From Heps.
This trick always works.
Wake up Moomin, I know you're tickling.
Moomin, wake up already!
Hopeless!
Kutkutkut!
He won't wake up.
Remarkable.
Just don't say.
You can't scare me.
It's okay, hear how the heart beats.
He breathes.
I'm not the mother of the storm.
Wake-up! Sleepyhead!
I'm not getting wet!
They don't wake up.
Curious thing.
Mätänt mom and dad?
Shall we go wake up?
I can't stand it when others sleep while I'm awake.
Although the opposite is not good at all.
Moominpapa, don't sleep.
Moomin can't be woken up with an axe.
Wake up, Moomin! It's already breakfast.
Well, Moominpapa.
I'm starving.
No progress.
We're just still hibernating here.
Yes, and the eiti of Niskuk is also sleeping.
Well, that's weird.
He always wakes up before me.
Similarly, Moomin is usually more active than me.
Well, that's fine.
I'm going home and I'll come again to get the niisku eiti when we're awake here.
If we are...
We've done anything to make the Moomin goblins startle and wake up.
Tickled, tickled, torn, ears pinched.
This is so weird it's sickening.
Oh, don't sleep.
Day to the house.
Remarkable going.
We're still sleeping here, right?
Yes, he does sleep.
You are in such a sweet dream that...
Wake up!
Date?
Sure enough.
I guess we can't do anything but wait here.
Probably not.
There is no reason to worry.
The days are getting warmer, the Moomins will wake up soon.
Niisku's mother too.
Of course.
The Moomin is guaranteed to wake up when the Snuff Muikkunen returns.
Hear it!
About a week later, Nuuska Muikkunen returned from his annual trip to the south.
Snuff Muikkunen!
Ihihi!
Where is Moomin?
Still sleeping.
Moomin sleeps like a log.
Phooey.
You can't wake them up with any lynx.
What could be the cause?
Are they sick?
Possibly.
They have sleep sickness!
This is not really my field.
Somehow, it seems to me that Moomin and the mother of the storm are under a spell.
Ihihi!
Lumotto?
But who?
Oh, I know!
You mean the witch, Alisa Mummo? Why?
I'm dreaming of something like that.
How do we get through this?
I'm going to the forest to look for the witch.
Do you think the witch will admit what she did?
I don't know, but something has to be done.
We can't leave the Moomins sleeping forever.
I'll come along!
I better stay here to system things,
if the Moomins suddenly wake up.
Hello...
Did you hear?
He has woken up!
Moomin!
Moomin, wake up!
Change to Nissan!
It makes me sleepy just looking at him.
Listen, I will free you from the spell of the witch.
Hey!
About!
are you going are you going
I have done all the household chores and even washed the poison cans.
But go you go?
Now it's spring and I want to take some time off.
Those are not lazy.
I just go to Moominvalley.
Ha, I guessed that.
I want to meet the Moomins.
Moomin sleeping?
He doesn't sleep, winter is already over.
But the Moomins are still fast asleep.
Grandma, how do you know that?
The witch knows everything.
Or so, I'll take care of that.
Come back!
I can't do anything about it, taking care of the house.
I want to come back.
Come back!
I can't do anything about it, I have to worry about mummies.
I opened the window.
Wisely done.
Let them sniff.
The smell of the first spring flowers.
Why didn't you tell Hemul they were bewitched?
Well, that's just an assumption.
It would be disgusting if I were wrong.
Don't tell about my suspicions.
Alright, I'm leaving now.
I'm going too!
It's Alicia!
Hello! What are you going to tell him?
Best to tell the truth.
I'll say a few choice words to grandma.
Tees se.
Grandma has become impossible.
Grandma, how could you be so mean?
What's mean?
I did it exclusively for you.
I don't think so.
That's fine.
If the Moomins sleep with you, there's nothing wrong with them.
Or so you imagine?
You have made good progress in your studies as well.
And if you keep going, you could become a flying witch before you turn 30.
But if I meet Moomins, at 31, right?
You are a smart girl.
The Moomins have a bad influence on you and are so annoying.
Will you break the spell if I promise never to go to moominvalley again?
That's right, kind girl, promise my girl.
Well, I promise.
Fine, I'll break the spell.
Nuuska Muikkunen.
What?
There are two ways to remove the enchantment.
Another way is for me to go to Moomin Valley myself and mumble a counterspell.
Grandma!
That it will work.
Oh, oh.
So if they notice me, rumors will start circulating in Moomin Valley.
Let's rather have Nuuska Muikkunen remove the enchantment on my side.
Uh, me?
Do you have a harmonica with you?
Certain.
Give it to me.
Oh, I jogged, I kölketed, pilleren, pölleren, kespesu...
My magic won't work if you're standing around pushing it.
Alisa, you bring the pig to drink.
Joo.
Oh, how boring.
I jogged, I jogged, or is it not allowed to stare?
You have to do something.
You are the police.
That, waking up is not part of our actual duties.
Don't explain it.
You are our last, only hope, if only you would blow the whistle.
No.
It's a gizmo indoors.
Just a pretense, then bang with a teddy bear gun.
Heaven forbid, I haven't.
Hi, Muikkunen, sell.
We still sleep soundly in the Moomin House.
Well, snuff, Muikkunen, let's control it.
Please change.
Snuff, Muikkunen.
Get angry, Konnipsu.
Niskuneiti, wake up already, it's spring.
Spring has come.
Good morning, papa.
Good morning, honey.
Like I slept too much.
Are the kids awake?
About.
The witch hunted you.
Shut up, Nipsu.
Do you trust witches?
Snuff, Muikkunen.
Good morning, gentlemen.
Niskuneiti.
I'm so glad you're back.
Nipsuk is up early.
Did you hear?
The thing is, you got up late.
Me?
Hello, hello.
Moomin is awake.
Hello, Nisku.
Dear brother.
He had to sleep forever.
I was asleep when I last saw him.
That's true.
Besides Moomin, mamma and papa.
What kind of meeting is here?
That's about it.
Everyone is awake.
I don't understand now.
What don't you understand?
We were worried when you didn't wake up at first.
But Hemuli, you know that we hibernate.
I know, I know, but when...
But Niska.
Yeah, it was a bit of a problem to be honest.
Snuff, Muikkunen.
You're already back.
Yeah, can you hear me now, Moomin papa?
No acceleration.
Let's go inside for a cup of tea and talk about your problem.
The problem is yours, not ours.
Well, but we don't have any problems.
Now everyone go inside the makom.
Nuuska, Muikkunen and the children too.
Better, please.
Please let me know!
Muikunen, what has happened to us?
Alisa, Alisa!
Oh, Moomin!
We came to greet you.
Oh, what fun!
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey, hey!
To greet you.
Oh, what fun!
No, isn't your grandma at home?
No.
Let's play hide and seek.
I promised grandma that I wouldn't...
Yes, Nuuska, Muikkunen told about your promise.
You did great, but you just promised not to come to Moominvalley.
So?
But you didn't promise not to play with us.
If we come here to play, you don't have to break your promise.
Isn't that right?
That's right. It's absolutely true.
The puzzle is solved.
Eight, one...
Hey, hey, hey!
One, two, three...
You mustn't spill the beans!
Four, five, six, seven...
Oh, that's good.
Nine, nine, nine, nine...
That's good.