Let's talk
Oh, the horror, the tail My tuft has thinned.
If I don't do anything, my tail may soon be completely hairless.
What do I do?
I don't think Mrs. Niiskunne likes him bald.
Moomin, breakfast is waiting.
Yeah, yeah.
Good morning.
Now don't stop there.
Porridge freezes Moomin.
I don't want anything, I'm not hungry yet.
Oops, doesn't sound like Moomin.
Is something bothering Moomin?
I don't know.
He seems strange.
I'm going for a walk.
He walks strangely.
He is not himself.
Oh, I'm in trouble.
Moomin troll.
Moist way.
Hello Moomin.
Sell tomorrow.
Like you freaked me out.
Startled? Not now anyway.
You are used strangely.
Go you are going.
Just for a walk.
Listen, Moomin, what are you hiding behind your back?
I'm not hiding anything.
You're hiding a lie, right?
I already told you, I'm not hiding anything.
Yes, you are hiding.
Well, I don't.
Too.
I can't.
Yes, yes, yes, yes.
Did it hurt you?
Did you notice that Moomin was out of his place?
He was quirky.
Hurry now, Niiskunneiti.
Oh, it was spot on.
Thank goodness and praise they didn't see my tail.
Fortunately.
But I can't hide the tail forever.
Oh what I do.
Hey, you're up early.
What's wrong with you?
No.
Good morning, Snuska, Muikkunen.
Why are you feeling so weird?
You're just imagining.
Jaha, would you like to go fishing with me?
Another time.
I'm a bit busy now.
Moomin was amazing.
I have to go see Kaino.
He has a lot of hair.
And he may well know how to make hair grow on his tail.
Who's that?
Moomin?
What business can you have with me?
No-kun. . .
All...
Tell, don't chatter.
My thing is about that hair.
That...
I mean...
Oh, but you don't seem to have any hair.
What...
Can it be done not to become bald?
Not to become bald.
I was just thinking, what do you do when you have such thick hair?
Oh, I do, I don't do anything.
I only have healthy hair because I live a healthy life.
Baldness is caused by destructive lifestyles.
Hi, hey.
Just ask Hemul.
He is bookish and bald besides.
I've never been able to get bald people from there.
Aha.
Or kaljuusvaivaa.
Try this hair lotion of mine.
Could it be good?
There is nothing better than that.
I have been using it for over thirty years.
Just like that. Just thank you.
Thirty years.
Moomin, Are you trying to grow hair?
Who said that?
Kaino, of course. He told us.
Why can't I be left alone?
Even once.
What the hell do you need hair for?
Mind your own business.
Hey, Moomin, wait.
He has snapped.
It is.
Sticking their beaks everywhere.
Moomin!
Moomin, come play.
I was waiting for you.
Sorry, but I'm busy.
I came, yeah.
What's wrong with the boy?
He is not himself at all.
Moomin trolls around like a crab.
Runs away.
Mummy!
Moomin!
I'm coming now.
Moomin, what's wrong?
I guess you don't have any worries.
Maybe you're worried about something that starts with the letter h?
How did you guess that?
Well, I'm your father after all.
You know you can tell us everything, right?
I know, yeah.
So what about it? It's your tail.
Look at the tassel on its head.
What for?
It has started to go bald.
Yeah, I see. It has thinned out.
Now it is much easier to keep him clean.
Absolutely. And you get rid of burdocks and resin and many other annoyances.
The father is such that he can't come up with good things.
Fortunately, I thought of it.
Don't try to comfort me. This is a serious matter.
I'm sorry, of course. Is it because of him that you behave so strangely?
What if all the tufts fall out and he becomes bald?
So what do I do?
My Moomin Park.
Could she find a cure in her grandmother's recipe book?
Could he be found in your grandmother's recipe book as a cure for the ingrown hairs that are bothering you?
Could he? Go see it now.
I'll go.
It's scary here.
Not nearly as scary as the fact that you'll soon be walking around bald.
How can these help? They look like normal plants.
They are common, but you have to pick them at the time of the new moon in the glow of the stars.
Grandma knew a thing or two about medicine.
Did grandma make this medicine for someone?
It may very well be.
Now these are probably enough.
I think the soup is getting ready.
This smells good.
The liquid is still hot.
It's hard for me to believe that the drink is going bad.
After all, it's grandma's medicine.
I don't notice any change.
Moomipeikko, he just took medicine, but tomorrow morning he will have a thick tail tuft again.
Yeah, so we'll wait to see what the situation looks like tomorrow morning.
Well, and now I got to bed Moomin.
Good night.
Hey, oh no! Wake up, mom and dad, it's horrible!
Good morning, Moompeikko. What now? Isn't this supported?
It is, but look.
Good unusual.
Heaven's tallow candles, how did that happen?
Good.
Hey, look.
Hey, look, how did that happen?
I've never seen one of those.
Hi, golden tail!
Doesn't do anything, I do!
Amazing thing!
I guess it wasn't a big mistake for mom.
Golden tail.
Unheard of, we do we Gitu!
Oh, Muu mipiikko. It's over!
Why did you come? I don't want to meet anyone today.
You are rude. I came to see if you're still bald.
Nothing bothers me.
Don't be a tree palturium. Show your tail.
And I don't show.
You show.
Look then.
Looks golden. Be careful not to have your tail stolen by a snitch.
I can't understand this. We followed grandma's recipe exactly.
It's really a mess.
Hello news.
Sell, shut up.
Moomin has a golden tail.
I didn't tell you that the medicine can cause side effects, but they will go away in a couple of weeks.
Ai.
At the next full moon, your tail will no longer be golden.
Everyone is here.
They are.
Dad, come here. We're busy.
Sell, why did you go tell everyone?
No need to hide.
Or vice versa. Everyone wants to see your golden tail.
I don't want to be a showpiece.
Moomin looks golden.
Let's go.
I promise that everyone will get to see the golden tail in turn.
Don't stand there like anything. Now turn around and show your tail.
Yeah, but... Roar now!
Do not touch! If you have already seen the tail, you can hand it over to the next person in line.
The situation is starting to get out of hand.
I think you're right.
I can't admire it enough.
You can get a lot of money for it.
My Moomin has a wonderful golden tail.
That, you know...
No two tails are the same.
It's true. You have become world famous overnight.
Come on, you don't know.
At no point should you show off your tail for free.
I have an idea moomin troll.
What have you come up with?
Nipsu, talk to me, then I'm the managers of Moomin!
Those who want to see the golden tail bring something of the size as an entrance fee.
It doesn't work for free anymore.
Hello Snuff, do you want to see Moomin's golden tail?
Well, I don't really think so.
Why not, it's u...
Moomin, believe me, fame is only a shame.
Go dip your tail in tar and the people will leave you alone.
Ah, do you really believe that?
Nuuska Muikkunen, you're sour and still so stubborn that you can't give up a single fish.
Not only.
Well, stay in line.
The world's only golden tail hides under this raspberry cotton fabric.
If you want to see the tail, place your bringing here on the cloth.
Here's how.
Pie.
All right.
Nipsu, are you ready?
Here it is.
Oh!
Ahead.
Don't be stuck with others.
I want a golden tail too.
I would shave it once a week.
And then I would take the golden herons to the bank.
Yes, it looked like real gold.
Her tail was amazing.
We get awfully cheesy this way.
Moominmamma doesn't need to do after-use.
Of course.
The audience gets to see your unique tail.
Yeah, but still.
Make sure nothing happens to you.
Mummy Moomin.
What is it?
I would like to ask a favor.
Well, what about the service?
I would like to.
What service?
Well, what about the service?
I wish I had a golden tail.
Just like Moomin has.
Just like that.
It's not yet a new moon.
But I can try.
Lovely.
Oh, thank you Moomin.
Yes.
So I only drink a magic potion made from these herbs.
That's how I get a golden tail.
What?
Exactly.
Aha, or nothing else is needed.
Then I'll try it too.
Oh, what a tease.
Now the soup has boiled.
They know each other.
And after I've had a drink, tomorrow morning...
I make the potion in the same way as for Moomin.
Now I taste.
Tomorrow morning I will be completely golden.
My tail.
Oh, it scares me to look at it.
Oh, I hope the tail has turned golden.
Yours.
Didn't change.
I guessed it, I have been deceived.
But they become golden in some other way.
My tail didn't change either.
Anna, sorry I couldn't help.
It's okay, Mummy.
It seems that the herbs must be collected at the time of the new moon after all.
Golden tail is not for everyone.
Moomin troll.
I'm going out for a while.
Oh yeah.
Moomin, come along.
I can't make it, I'm busy.
Moomin has a very tight schedule today.
Neesa Kun Id Rukka.
I feel somehow guilty.
Nipsu, are you still eating?
I already finished. The plate is empty.
Bye.
Go you go.
I'm going with the deer and Nipsu to show my tail.
We don't want dessert today either.
Your day, there's no way you'd want to turn your tail into gold.
Who are you?
I must not have met.
I am the creator of famous magic tricks.
I came here to fulfill my maiden wish.
Do you know my wish then?
I knew it the moment I saw the young lady's face.
She wants a golden tail.
Miss is coming along so make her a golden tail.
Will I really get a golden tail?
Absolutely.
Let's go now.
Settle down, everything is fine.
Well, bring yours out if you want to see a golden tail.
Put the imports here, please.
Good.
Moomin, Goblin, I don't think it's appropriate for you to accept treats for looking at your tail.
That's not why I looked for your grandmother's recipe.
Sorry.
Dude, where are you going?
Children, tomorrow this fun will end.
Tonight is the full moon and the gold is disappearing.
Has it been two weeks already?
Yes, fourteen days.
Well, I don't really care about desserts anymore.
A pinch!
Leave the treats there and go with me to find Miss Niisku.
I'm getting wet, aren't I?
Has he disappeared?
And I'm sure to be golden, right?
Hey, how far do we have to go?
Here we are.
Ha!
Help! Help, Stink!
I apply glue to the fur and sprinkle gold on it, and hear me take your anklet.
Skunk, don't come any closer!
Ring here!
Another one!
Give it to me!
Help! Help!
I'm getting wet miss! I'm getting wet miss!
Help!
I'm getting wet miss!
Mom's boy!
I don't want to meet you.
Huh?
Goodbye!
Wait!
Why do you have a golden tail?
Keep going!
Is everything okay?
Yes, Mompiekka.
I just wanted to be golden-furred, Stink. This is unfair, unfair!
So your tail becomes normal.
So?
Now is your last chance to touch the golden tail!
Oh, how sad. That joy lasted only two weeks.
What grief?
When the gold disappears, can Momipeiko become a complete fool?
I bet it will!
What shall we do?
Mom, do you know what's going on?
I'm afraid grandma won't have any mention of it.
But then we'll see.
Crew cut! And that's it!
Listen, Momopeikko.
What I want to tell you is that everyone loves you and not your tail.
Keep that in mind.
Absolutely.
But I liked that old tassel tail.
The moon is rising! Full moon!
Momopeikko, now you can make eye contact.
Whoa! The tail is intact! The tassel is here again!
Thank you!