I can't believe my eyes.
What has happened now?
Well, look.
The ant has a child on its foot.
It is a cut moth bush.
Did it put the child on itself?
In no way.
But if it is, then it is a super intelligent ant.
Hmm.
Dad, what's wrong?
There's a bowler hat in that bird's nest.
If it has been put there to keep the eggs warm while the mother birds are away.
Yes.
Emo has flown the top hat here.
Yes, she is a sharp-headed mother bird.
Ants and birds have suddenly become super-intelligent.
About ants?
Hey daddy, come here.
Short.
Hey.
Why are there bees here?
Sweetheart.
When I went to get it, I found a broken honey can on the floor.
Yes.
Even bees have become super-intelligent.
What do you mean?
Bees are logically much easier to get honey from the cellar,
like making it yourself from the nectar of the flowers.
Bees can't handle heavy honey cans.
Not one bee.
But if there are thousands or millions, or who knows how many.
You always want honey with your pancakes.
It's serious.
Hey, let us have some honey.
Be careful.
I'll take care of this.
All of a sudden, all in.
Bees have become super-intelligent.
Now this is a serious matter.
What is so serious?
Birds and insects seem to have changed.
What if they have allied with each other and gradually start attacking us?
They have been able to decide that they want to live in a Moomin house.
It's really serious.
Good heavens, I don't want bees in my bed.
Now it's time to get down to business. Moomin comes to help.
Clear.
We're safe now, Dad.
Joo.
We can never ventilate the rooms again.
That's right.
Birds can fly into the chimney.
Who's there?
That's where Houska sits.
Bun.
Hmm.
The sun is too bright.
A bunch of parsley.
Under the shade is better.
Hello everyone.
I placed the parasol over the parsley.
Now it's happy.
Have you had anything to do with honey?
Oh yes it is.
I make the bees so happy.
Yes.
And did you take the top hat to the bird's nest?
Even the birds want to be free from time to time.
And you apparently put a splint on an ant's foot.
So.
The anthill showed its severed leg.
Hey.
It was a relief.
Birds and insects have not changed.
So.
And they can't change either.
We can continue living here or what dad?
All items must be put back in their original order.
Will you help mom?
No.
Moomin Troll.
You scared me.
That Houska is a bit funny.
Not you too?
On the contrary, I find him comfortable.
It doesn't seem funny to me.
Look at her pretty nose.
Where are you looking?
Look at the nose.
He has such a characteristic nose.
Beautiful nose line.
You rarely see a girl with such a beautiful nose.
Oh right?
So.
I need to fix it for tomorrow.
Let's go home already.
Did you hear Nipsu?
I want to stay here.
Stay then.
Ooo.
Hey.
What has happened to Nipsu?
He promised to come.
But it won't.
He has gone to meet that guy.
Oh again?
Absolutely.
Has he abandoned us?
What was Nipsu really thinking?
If you know Nipsu, then hardly anything to mention.
Oh dolphins.
Hey.
Muvibeikko is competing.
My dolphin is shy for us.
Clear.
That's speed, Muvibeikko.
Speed, speed, speed.
That's Nipsu now.
A pinch, hey.
What drives you?
You feel depressed.
Nipsu, don't sit there and sigh.
Then I want to look even more stupid than usual.
I have us.
You'll probably have a fever.
You look kind of sick.
Do you have a cold?
Oh poor.
You must go to bed.
How do you feel?
Are there any pains?
On.
In the chest.
You look miserable.
Ai, ai.
It can be.
Just thank you.
Fun.
What exactly did you say?
No.
I guess I didn't say anything.
Yes, you said it.
Fun.
Did he really say that?
Fun, Fun, Fun.
As soon as I think Funny,
the heart feels so bright
and in members from spring.
I have never experienced before
no similar feeling.
Then it must be love.
Wax.
Nipsuko in love.
In that case, you can feed me to the hedgehog.
Love.
Is this what real love is like?
I don't like it.
Moomin, tell me what to do.
You shouldn't ask your Moomin.
He has never been truly in love.
Nobody.
Am I not?
Et.
Well, if you have experienced that
tell Nipsu what to do.
to lower,
Couldn't you tell?
Well, maybe I can.
Come here Nipsu.
Try to tell Hauska
openly about your feelings.
It makes you feel better in every way.
Do you have to reveal your feelings?
All right.
I'm going to tell you right away.
Nipsu do your best.
What's wrong now?
What do I have to say?
For example.
I like you a lot.
i love you
I love you a lot.
Yeah yeah
That's what I say.
Yes, I can.
Oh no, I can't.
My tongue goes into knots immediately.
When I see him.
Nipsu has a serious disease.
Moomin-Pekko,
maybe you should go with him.
Huh? Me?
Well, that's fine.
I'll stand behind you so I can whisper the words into your mouth.
Good.
Now is not the time to be shy.
Tell him your case in a clear voice.
I started to go.
Kas, hi Nipsu.
How can I help?
Dude, what happened?
Nipsu, hey listen, wait!
Houska, listen Houska.
I love you, I really do.
It doesn't sound like it comes straight from the heart.
Right?
Pants dear!
I love you, I really do.
Houska, Houska dear!
Bun, Bun, Bun!
I won't let you go, no, no!
Pinch, Pinch, stop already.
I think that's powerful enough.
Is it?
I gained your confidence myself.
I'll do it, I'll do it!
Come on, Nipsu, it's fine.
I'm ready.
Are you there?
I love you!
You scared me and the flower arrangement, didn't I...
and the flower arrangement sank into the air.
Now I know. I help Ouska collect flowers.
I will collect flowers for you.
Tel!
Ouska! I collected flowers for you.
What have you done, Barbarians?
I help collect flowers.
I pluck away the rich food so that the flowers can grow freely.
Little flower holes, a purse robber, a spoiled brat and the unlucky ones.
You can grow up yourself.
The murder of that and...
And don't ever appear before my eyes again.
It must have hurt you.
A pinch!
It must have gone bad.
I don't think you are meant to be a first lover.
Don't cry!
Ah!
Ouska muikkunen, don't play such a sad tone.
Nipsu got the gloves and needs something to cheer him up.
Oh, sorry.
Niu is you, what we do to Nipsu.
I don't understand.
That usual shock has never hit me.
I don't want the shock to happen to me either.
Besides, it's not the usual one, but an individual mine.
I don't want to grow up.
A pinch!
Nipsu just has to try to forget Ouska.
I don't know of any other cure.
A pinch!
where are you from
Where has Nipsu disappeared to?
Oh honey, why do you have a frying pan with you?
A frying pan?
I give Nipsu all ears.
It is the best way in the world to teach to forget.
Oh yeah.
A pinch!
Isn't that Nipsu?
What exactly is going through his mind?
Oh, the horror!
I never thought he would be this desperate.
What?
Of course not.
We must thwart his intentions.
A pinch!
Don't be a hata, Ousu!
You know a lot yourself!
You deserve to go in the water!
A pinch!
Oh, oh, oh! Grab my paw!
Moomin, what did that mean?
What did you try?
We thought you were going to go into the water.
We would like to be saved.
What did that mean?
It meant you were going to go in the water.
We would like to save you.
I would go in the water?
Are you shaken?
I can't even swim.
So why were you on the platform?
I came to wash my face with cold water,
that I would forget the heartaches caused by fun.
What?
You weren't going to drown, were you?
Of course not. It's stupid.
I don't waste money in a frying pan.
Thus!
Ai, ai, ai!
A frying pan helps better than cold water.
Aaaah!
You noticed that I was able to escape.
Blows help you forget.
Aaaah!
You won't think twice before falling in love the first time.
Head!
And that's what you get! And about that!
Don't miss out!
Oh!
A pinch! A pinch! Did that occur to you?
Nipsure sock.
Yeah, it came.
I just remembered that I haven't eaten a single crumb since yesterday.
What discipline! What discipline!
Well, you finally got things in the right order of importance.
A pinch of health!
Here comes more pancakes.
Thank you very much. I like it.
Long order, Rahmi!
Hauska probably wouldn't have been able to bake as good pancakes as her mother.
Thank you!