Before it starts to rain, we made it to the shelter of the tent.
While looking for new plants one day.
Hemuli crashed into the tent.
From the circus.
Oh, what black clouds.
Good thing we got to the shelter of the tent before it started raining.
Joo.
Good afternoon, Hemuli.
Is that tent yours?
Yes, I'm going to build my aircraft in it.
Oh, so the drawings are ready and you've solved your problem.
Kind of.
Well, now what? You are usually more confident yourself.
My first flight was such an undercut to the bar that I'm now trying to stay in the lifts.
I look forward to seeing your new aircraft.
The thunder is approaching, I keep going.
I'm going home too.
Uh, swim wretched.
So what now? What is it?
The tent is in the wrong place.
How so?
It should have been set up somewhere in the darkness of the forest.
Here anyone can see it and find out if my new aircraft will fail too.
Don't be a douchebag. Why does it fail?
Why did it fail? I'm sure you were when we set up the tent.
Yeah, but then the hemlu and who knows who else came up.
Your aircraft will be a real smash hit. Exactly.
All right.
I'm going to work now. Come again in the middle of the night so you don't eat.
Lovely.
I'm going to trot home now.
I swear my plane will fly.
Oh, it started raining now.
It's not worth it. Wetting yourself can catch a cold.
Isn't it because mother still hasn't woken up?
No.
It's time to go to Salaman.
That's what the snuffer said.
Is he blue?
It doesn't look any different on the surface.
So I'll let you know.
Father went to tell.
I brought you tea.
Thanks mom.
So how did you eat?
It hasn't moved at all.
Well, that's sad. He was sure he would have recovered from the blow by now.
He is so pale and motionless.
Don't grieve.
What if he doesn't wake up until a hundred years from now?
Are you awake?
I don't. I haven't bothered to disturb him.
Repeat his name.
A lightning strike has made us deaf.
No gentle talk will probably work for him.
A wake-up call!
So mom, please wake up.
A little bit more.
You better wake up or I'll bite.
Later on.
He says something.
Now he wakes up.
Well, mother.
Jana. So when mom hears our voices.
Luckily I didn't scream even louder when I woke him up.
I could have blown his brains out.
Drink tea, so when you eat, you can open your eyes.
What has happened?
The snuffbox found you lying on the bed.
Lightning had struck you.
Snuff box.
So. He said that Lightning had knocked you to the ground.
I remember it was raining. It was raining really hard and then there was a loud bang.
So yes. You're crazy with shock right now.
Oh, I have to thank Nuuskamuikkus.
He said he would go fishing when the rains stopped.
Where was I going?
I don't know. Hardly far from his tent.
Oh, he's gone elsewhere.
What now? Why are you staring?
Where is it?
That...
You just said that Snuff has gone elsewhere.
It is. He's gone to far trouble.
You've been in a dreamland for hours. How do you know that?
I know because I see it.
I'm selling a roar.
What?
You roared so loudly that Niiskunead's sensitive mind was shaken.
I didn't really have much luck when Lightning hit him.
Don't be a jerk. There is nothing wrong with Niiskunead.
He has just had a dream and is not quite awake yet.
I assure you that I am fully awake.
You are, but stay in bed for a while longer.
Obey the head pillow.
I'll sing you lullabies.
Sell, don't bother.
I sing if I want.
Well, now what?
Snuff-muikkunen.
What about snuff?
I have to hurry if I'm going to save him. I have to, I have to, I have to.
Moist way.
I'm still waiting.
Wet!
Sell, see.
Snuff-mum, come out.
Away!
What if Niiskuneiti really knows something about snuff?
Niiskuneni, where is Nuuskamuikkunen?
Straight ahead. Still a little way to go.
what is Kimis was dangerous.
Well, we'll find out when we get there.
Niiskunmi, what are you trying to do?
I'm going to save Nuuska-muikkusen.
How do you know he's here?
I just know.
Oh, look. There.
That's where Nuuska-muikkunen is.
Right on Rokos.
Look further.
I made a steep climb to the top.
He's hardworking in his way.
What do we do now? Do you want to roll?
Wake up, Snuff-mug, wake up.
He can't hear us.
You don't know what my voice is capable of.
Snuff-mum, wake up.
There's a swamp lady.
He has survived the lightning strike.
Get out of there, snuff-guy.
What matter?
Watch out, Snuska-muikkunen.
Hurry away, Snuff-mug.
Tel!
Thank God that Niiskunnie wasn't injured after all.
Physically, he is fine.
Spatially?
He rushed his way to claim that Snuff-muikkunen is in danger.
I don't think I understand.
Niisku-neiti therefore foresees what will happen.
I was thinking about snuff and then suddenly I saw him on the fishing rod and...
...I knew something terrible was going to happen to him soon.
You are a clear seer.
Do you really think so?
My roar made him a clairvoyant!
Salaman, take a bath!
So sure.
Although I've never heard that Lightning could affect that way.
Niisku-neiti is a special case.
I don't really know what to do now.
So you really did see a snuffbox fishing, and it wasn't a dream.
I was awake.
But wouldn't you think it was just some miraculous coincidence?
Well, what can I do about it?
I saw what I saw!
In that case, maybe you could tell me if your aircraft will succeed or not.
Let's see if I can try?
Absurd.
I'm a scientist and I shouldn't believe in anything unscientific.
You don't have to believe, but I'm a clear seer regardless.
hey what are you doing
I'll try to see if your new aircraft works out.
Niisku-neiti, stop!
Why?
You don't get to predict a recession if I know my plane is going to fail.
Well, you don't believe in this.
I don't think so, but...
Hear the breeze, I'm sure I'll see your aircraft succeed.
What I hope.
No, no, no, don't go, I don't want to know.
Mixed sweet?
Let's say it fails, then you can know something else.
Yeah, but the problem is that I don't want to do anything but tinker with my aircraft.
Drive.
Forget the whole thing, niisku-miss, I don't want to know anything.
Oh, good unusual.
Hey, go home now.
An exciting edge is in your nest.
Oh, leave at once, and the house will be spared.
Niisku, I brought the last statement.
Thank you very much, this is going smoothly.
Even yes.
You are a great help, thank you.
Well, I can't wait for your aircraft to be finished.
Where is the niisku lady anyway?
He would have wanted to come and help, but I refused.
Why?
If Ms. Niisku were here, she would see before long whether my aircraft will succeed or not.
All the joy would disappear from building.
I do understand how you feel.
You know what?
Well, if I'm being completely honest, I don't dare to ask the niisku girls about the aircraft.
If I knew it was going to fail, I'd go with it.
Pee!
Ah, you saw me coming.
I knew you were looking for me and I also know what you want from me.
So what?
That I use my clairvoyant abilities to make money.
Great, you're a real clairvoyant.
I don't want to be your business partner.
Don't you want to get rich?
Oh, I'm not getting rich.
Wait a minute.
Not really.
You're a bum too.
Ha ha, I'm changing our future.
Come with me.
All right.
I won't do that either, even if I reject you, I'll follow you to the end.
I give up.
This way sir, this way.
Can he predict?
I guarantee that.
I am extremely worried about my health.
I am terminally ill.
Very healthy.
Tell me straight up how much time I have to live.
We all die sooner or later.
In a way, it's a relief.
Am I going to die soon?
Wait and see.
You have about 90 years left.
Then I get sick.
Are you sure?
You will live a little longer if you exercise and follow diets.
Oh my god, that's really fun to hear.
Look at these, special medicines.
I thought my days were numbered, so I invested all my money in expensive drugs.
Good day, Rauva-Viljonkka. We have been waiting for you.
Good day, Nipsu.
You're looking to see clearly, aren't you?
Well, how do you know that already?
I know I can see clearly.
I am clear to see.
I already know that.
I know everything because I am the manager of the famous clairvoyant.
If you're his manager, no thanks.
No, no, no. Wait a minute.
I don't even trust your clear vision.
However, didn't we know how to correctly predict your arrival?
And if the prediction does not come true against all expectations, you get your money back.
This way, madam.
The convalescent place looks murky.
You see, you don't need a nice office.
Whoops, there's a customer here.
Moist way.
Good day, Mrs. Viljonkka.
I don't really understand now.
Lightning struck Niskunneit and in that moment he gained the ability to see into the future.
That you predict?
I? Unfortunately.
To sit, to sit.
Well, that's fine, you'll get your chance.
Yes, we would like to collect the payment in advance.
Well, you want to.
Yes, we don't do anything for contraception with drugs.
What are you doing?
Hey, I'm fine.
Five of it.
Well, Mrs. Viljonkka, please ask clearly now what you want to know.
Mistress of Niiskun, predict my future for me.
Yes, yes.
Now I see.
And what do you see?
I clearly saw Mrs. Viljonka.
Do you see, Do you really see me?
I can see very clearly.
And what do I do?
Shout out with an umbrella.
Huidonko?
Yeah, and you look very hot.
And then?
You asked something like an umbrella.
Forget the parasol already.
What else do you see?
I don't see anything else.
That look is all.
Niiskunkunnie, you look more closely.
Now I see.
What do you see?
I see I'm running with Nipsu.
But Niiskunneiti, how do you explain Mrs. Viljon?
Oh, terrible.
What?
Us.
Don't screw up.
Are you making fun of me?
Let's go to the ticket office.
Don't be surprised by me.
Just as I predicted.
Yeah, I notice.
You are frauds and nosy.
Mrs. Viljonka, don't now.
Moist way.
Please wait.
Help.
Mrs. Viljonka, don't.
Money is added in the air.
Niiskunnetti predicted this correctly.
You can't run away from me.
You see.
We won't get rich with this shit.
I have a couple of coins in the pivo.
They do not have to withdraw money from the lottery.
I think?
Yeah, you're allowed to peek into the future that much,
that you can tell me which number wins.
I can't see anything in your eyes yesterday.
No problem, I'll lead you.
Did closing your eyes help?
It helped, but the number is terribly long.
Come on, I'm ready.
Six three eight.
Two five four.
I want my money back, take it now.
You shut up.
Hey, how did that number go again?
Six three eight.
Six five four.
Two five four.
Art is a spy on a sekopol.
Six three eight.
Six five four.
Two five four.
Fuck us.
Six three eight.
Two five four.
Hi, are you, are you okay?
I am, but Niiskunneiti passed out.
Niiskunmi, wake up.
Hi Niiskuneiti.
I'm sorry the tent is collapsing. It was my fault.
It is easy to rebuild. He didn't hurt you.
Nothing bothers me. Hey, Kola just took my head.
Well good. What is that young man?
What now?
I can't see the number.
Try it.
I can't see.
I don't see anything in the future.
Have you lost your clairvoyance?
That's how it looks.
This partly caused it and...
Good, so.
Very bad.
Lovely, Niiskunneiti.
What a relief.
On the right, I think it's a shame.
How so? Humidity.
He would have liked to know if the new aircraft would fly.
You said you didn't want to know anything.
I know, but really I would have liked to know.
That's why I don't need to see into the future.
Uh.
I can answer that question anyway.
I know your aircraft will be a great success.
I trust you.
Oh, thank you, Niiskunneiti.
Come on, Niisku.
I'm putting up the tent.
Good.
Work heals all wounds.
This time I want to help.
That's fine.
Ipsu, up to help.
Ah.
Arpa.
When the partnerships work hard together, the aircraft will surely be completed.
Thumbs up.