Pooh, Miss Nisku, look!
Oh, the storm of the last one has thrown all kinds of debris onto the beach.
Would he be among the treasures?
Hey, let's go see.
Wait a minute.
Why?
Little sell is not.
Tel!
There you are...
Aaaaaaa!
Et...
that I freaked out...
What has happened to the sale?
Did I say something wrong?
So.
Strange.
Hm...
myy is in trouble again at Takuu.
Night...
Uhh...
You said you would come with us to the beach.
The sea may have brought these shoes to the beach that you like.
Oh, how cute. I'll make a lanyard out of shoes too.
You have already found a lot of shoes.
Listen, Moomin-Pekko, do you know what day tomorrow is?
Well, what?
Tomorrow.
Tell me, what day is tomorrow?
No idea. You just have to.
Huh? There is Sell!
Hey Sell! Cock Luuru!
He didn't notice me.
Myy is somehow awkward.
Really.
Where are you going?
Let's go after it.
What is Myy sitting on the beach for?
Myi is suffering from a stomach ache.
Nipsu, you usually suffer from them.
Sniff, muikkunen, don't bother.
Shhh! Be quiet!
Hey, look.
What do you see?
Look what Myi has in hand.
He knows how to calculate.
To love, not to love, to love!
Myy is in love!
What a joke! I'm going to die!
Love is no joke you know.
Se he wires!
Myy is in love, the best joke in the world!
Nipsu, the small shop is also a woman and every woman has the right to love.
Of course, but Myy doesn't.
A pedant can't love.
A pinch, the pangs of love can wreak havoc on a little girl's heart just as painfully,
when they run into my heart too.
Well, let's leave it at that.
By the way, do you know what day tomorrow is?
Well, no, no information. You'd already say marshmallow.
Oh, oh you foresters. Valentine's Day, of course.
What day is it?
Fools! Tomorrow is the only day of the year
if you can express your feelings to the object of your love.
I think Myy is fighting with himself.
Is Koha hiding her love, or are we letting it out?
I don't think so, but what's wrong with the small shop?
Well no, I just understand.
As long as I'm not the object of Myi's love, it's okay for me to do the same.
It would be right for you if Myy loved you.
It would be so, but it doesn't seem likely to me.
Myy has loved to the core.
He can't sleep at night, but tosses restlessly on his mattress.
You just saw how he sighed while he was away on the beach and didn't pay any attention to his surroundings.
Sighing is the first sign of unrequited love.
Young hearts reach out longingly towards each other.
Overwhelmed by fearsome enthusiasm, the young love-sick person grabs one petal after another from the day's poop and guesses.
Will he find love? To love, not to love, to love, not to love.
I think that Myy woke up too late in the morning because he couldn't sleep at night because he was afraid of the thunder.
And the sigh was because he missed breakfast and was just hungry.
A pinch!
What?
You're not going to be the least bit romantic.
Selling doesn't make me romantic.
Phooey.
Now you say what you think.
Listen, I think there could be another explanation for Myi's behavior.
But what it is, it's hard for me to guess.
You are right.
Myytok also seems as if he is in love.
You're right.
I don't agree to believe it.
Oh, you knit.
I'm knitting, tomorrow is Valentine's Day.
Is it really?
And you knit me something for Valentine's Day.
How is it?
But what are you knitting?
I guess I'll get it.
Tell me, mom, what will happen?
Then you'll see it.
I have a feeling today that I am writing a successful chapter in my memoirs.
What's bothering you all?
You are so quiet.
Yes, when...
Now where is the problem?
Well, that...
where is dad
Yes?
Dad is inspired and wants to eat dinner in his study.
And he wants to eat in the evening.
Tell me what's the matter?
Eh, nothing.
You're weird.
Dad is working, good.
Yes, by the way, how does the little one sell?
How little does it sell?
Are you feeling better?
Did you hear Nipsu?
Mummy asked, can you sell better already?
I heard, I heard, but what did he mean?
I sell unrequited love.
What are you whispering?
The small sale must be used alongside.
It is a clear sign that he is in love.
Don't be a joke.
I feel uncomfortable when the seller is so quiet.
Better to keep your mouth shut.
I haven't seen it sold like that.
Myi has fallen seriously ill, namely from love's disease.
I don't dare.
So, so.
Did you hear that Moomin mom is asking how the little girl is doing?
Invisible.
So I must have said something to Mummy Moomin.
Of course!
I'll go and ask him right away.
Oh, you've noticed too.
So when you don't get lucky you jotkyvänustera.
I really have a feeling that little Myi is in a lot of pain.
I really have the feeling then that my little one is in severe pain.
habitats
He has completely lost his reed lock.
I guessed it.
It's good to be kind to the little ones.
At least I try.
I see! Catching up!
Experience!
Vain! There is no secret behind other doors.
Yes, but the door was open.
And the seller is not in his room.
Oh, how is it still outside?
That's what I've been wondering a bit about here too.
No, you can't.
Moomin, don't empty or I'll go through the door.
And now I'm selling the room.
You played an ugly trick on your leg.
You can't go into other people's rooms.
What does this mean? What's there?
Miss Strike, come here.
Short.
What is it?
Did you find something? Is that a letter?
Wait and see.
You read it out loud.
How could I meet you, O my love.
I want to be your people day and night.
I could throw to strong arms and forget all about it.
i love you i love you
I love you the most in all of Moomin Valley.
I love.
What does this mean?
See what this means.
It clearly looks like a love letter.
And you didn't write it?
What?
I knew.
Tail star.
Wasn't I right all along?
I suspect that the seller did not write it.
But the letter was found in the seller's room.
It would be fun to know what the guy selling is like in love.
Nipsu, what's making you laugh?
I haven't heard.
Can you imagine? What?
The guy you hate.
What is he like.
No, no, no, Nipsu. Don't be mean.
I shouldn't laugh, but I can't help it.
Myy is in love with me as a crack.
My stomach skin is tearing.
Dude, don't laugh.
At least we know a lot of people who are out of the question.
What do you mean?
Myy could only have fallen in love with someone weird.
Like who?
Well, like a skunk.
Joo.
Why don't you sniff around?
How about hemu?
Or from a hat rug.
Why not? I'm thinking now.
They're the same size.
Don't joke. I can think.
The sensitive youngest maiden cannot fall in love with the hattivat.
Let's think another way,
who Myi's age lives in Moominland.
You are the only one of the same age.
Don't count playing.
If not you, then who?
So.
Is Myy in love with me?
Why not.
Who else is left.
Hey.
The door is open.
We wondered here.
We were worried when you weren't home.
We just got stuck.
Anna, excuse me.
Would Myyn have fallen in love with a Moomin?
It's impossible.
If I love Moomin, why doesn't Myn love him too?
Now there is no waiting for an answer.
Act and I'm ready to fight.
Anna, forgive us for trespassing in your room.
I'd like to talk to you about that connection.
Is the Moomin...
Do you know that you are in love with a Moomin?
I hope you are not.
Say if you haven't.
That would make it easier for me.
Tell me quickly, please.
Short.
Nice.
Myy.
Sorry for bothering you.
Oh, that cold look.
Freezing silence.
Not a word in response.
Of course, myi could not confess.
There is no catalyst.
My dear, dear Moomin.
Oh the chosen one of my heart.
I won't give you to anyone.
Come on, come here.
Juhi!
I hear these are for you.
Thank you.
A more fun gift than a card.
I can't thank you enough, papa.
This package is for you.
Thanks, mom.
It's nice that it's Valentine's Day.
So do I.
Nipsu, here it is for you.
Thanks.
Get wet, miss.
What?
Aren't you going to open your own gift?
Yes, yes I will open.
About.
Oh yeah.
There's a sale right there.
I'm going to take a present.
Because he has a package with him.
Then I sell the groom.
At least it's not a Moomin.
Whoah!
What happened to you?
No. I'm just so happy.
Come on.
Is the boy going to his friend's house?
Of course, today is Valentine's Day.
But who lives there?
We're finally standing up for what the seller is fighting for.
A pinch!
Be careful.
Doesn't love anyone Moomin.
What?
Nothing.
i love you
Look.
Pikkuu sells Marsi the tent of Snuskamuikkunen.
Hardly a daredevil.
Uskamuikkunen wants to be involved in this story.
Probably not.
Now the seller gives a gift.
Five iron.
Not even red.
Is the sale going?
It's like selling if you see us.
Daredevil!
Pretty!
Hi, nice to see you. How about you guys?
Don't try.
Isn't today Valentine's Day?
Or what?
It probably is.
Who did you get such a nice package from?
This one?
Just recently from a small sale.
For sale?
What's so funny about that?
Now don't bother being silly.
I got a small gift from the seller here.
But it doesn't mean anything.
Really?
But this is just a custom that happens once a year.
This time it's a much more serious matter.
What do you mean?
Oh, that men know nothing.
That men can be blind and cruel.
And you haven't noticed how the sale is suffering because of you.
Yeah, so kill once a year.
You dare.
I am deeply disappointed in you.
Same words, boring too.
Wait a minute, I don't understand what you're talking about.
Listen now.
Little My is in love with you so deadly serious,
that he can't even eat anymore.
The only daredevil, you don't get cold blooded.
A recent day.
punk-faced, you don't get cold vermniej
fight against petty love.
Not now, wait...
I don't understand...
... What are you talking about.
I knew!
I said from the beginning that I would destroy the snuff window.
Oh, unload
Sell and snuff responsibly
I'd just come for a couple.
Iksik eato3
sus refuse
And the little shop brought me a present from Moominma.
Then again we have lost the clue of who the seller loves.
I'll tell you, the little girl has never loved anyone. That's the truth.
You must be wrong about that.
I can detect the symptoms of pet diseases in my eyes.
There is not the slightest doubt about it. A woman's instinct never fails.
Well, maybe so. Could be true.
But why secretly sell his love?
The harder he tries to hide it, the more clearly he sees it.
Ai!
Please explain in more detail.
The more natural it tries to be, the weirder it is.
I tell you what. Let's ask the seller directly and see how he reacts.
Here he is.
Hi sell.
How are you?
Niiskunnunnie, you ask?
Neither do I. Moomin can ask.
Me? In for a penny in for a pound?
Hi myi, we heard you're in love.
We are so excited. Who is that? He must be nice.
Could you tell me his name? Would you be so kind?
Nipsu thought it was about snuff, but it's not.
Do not. Did I say that?
You said.
Moomin, it was you who suggested it.
Did I propose?
Well, snuff Muikkunen and Stink are at least out of the question.
I thought it was terribly funny when you claimed Hemuli and I sold as boyfriends.
Nipsu, that's what you said.
I didn't say that.
Do you remember who was the funniest candidate for my boyfriend?
I remember Hattivatti.
Mö and Hattivatti together. Oh, what a ridiculous thought.
I agree. Hattiwatt parka.
Don't bother selling the parka.
Now you are allowed to stop.
The hats are mute. At least it would be calmer.
Just a one-on-one call.
Hey, let's stop now.
Quietly! Don't pretend. I can't bear to listen to your kisses.
What a relief. I can talk. The throat is healthy again.
I didn't know that myi had burned her mouth in the soup and couldn't speak.
It's terrible to listen to other people's speech when you can't even get a word out of your mouth.
Sell, forgive.
Fortunately, the seller didn't burn his mouth any worse.
I forbade him to talk so that he would heal faster.
Thanks for that. The day has been calm.
A terribly frustrating day.
Because every time I even saw you, I felt like talking terribly.
So when Eiti thought you were in love when you were down.
I thought you were aware of my throat.
No, but wait a minute, how to explain a love letter.
So yes. What do you say about that?
What letter?
A love letter I found in your room.
Has anyone seen a single strip of my manuscript?
The script slips?
It happens to be the most important page of the entire novel.
A page of a novel?
Well, now the riddle of the love letter was solved.
Light up a little.
Lost strip in the salesroom.
In the salesroom? How the hell did it get there?
Hi, hi, hi.
Oh, the love book was part of the Moominpapa novel.
You know that you can die of laughter.
It was the worst Valentine's Day in the world.