When the frost had finally melted, grandma sowed the pumpkin seeds.
Why are the seedlings not budding?
I got the seeds a long time ago, if they were out of date.
Yes, they will remain.
There should be two kinds of flowers, but nothing is visible yet.
Without flowers there is no pollination, and without pollination there is no fruit.
Not a single button is coming.
Then there's no need to wait for pumpkins.
So yeah, that's what it's starting to feel like.
Oh, what's over there?
Wait a minute! Here is the bud of the mother flower, when there would still be a few stamens.
How little button? I guess nothing will come of it.
Before long, three stamens bloomed.
Mom, we haven't had a pumpkin yet this year, have we?
Well no, it looks like the whole crop will fail, there won't be a single pumpkin.
Not a single one?
Fear the worst, Moomin.
Pumpkin pie is good.
Shawl!
Terribly sad.
It looks promising, the bud has opened.
There will be pumpkins.
Well, one may well come.
Even better than nothing, if you can get one meal for the family.
Only one pumpkin started to grow, but grandma was very proud of it.
Today I harvest pumpkins.
Prepare the pumpkin carefully.
I know a good recipe, everyone can at least taste it.
Great, I've never seen a single direction pumpkin in my life.
Just yesterday it was this small, what has happened?
Very strange.
The last rain maybe?
Unbelievable.
Can a pumpkin this huge even taste good?
Listen to hemul.
So?
Just like the pumpkin is still growing.
It's the only pumpkin in the entire bench.
Maybe it gets power from other seedlings a bit like electricity.
Non-botanical.
Will the pumpkin grow as big as it wants?
Fixed plot.
I want to keep the pumpkin a secret from the family for the time being.
All right.
I want to surprise Papa and Moomin.
I won't tell anyone.
Thanks.
Mom, I remember you saying a long time ago that there would only be one single pumpkin this year.
Oh shall I say?
Or am I remembering wrong?
No, that's what you said and promised bread from pumpkin pie, everyone's favorite.
May be.
It's been weeks. The pumpkin must be big enough.
Big and big.
I guess it's not rotten.
I wouldn't say that much, but...
Is it still too small?
It needs to grow a little more, then it's...
Yes.
Dad's out for a walk.
In the garden?
Go to Viljonka.
And you don't believe it, do you?
I'm going to Viljonkanluo.
You went there yesterday and the day after.
Why couldn't I go to the same place three times?
You can, honey.
And now I'm going to Viljonkanluo and not anywhere else.
Remarkable. What happened to mom?
Oh no. I'm bad at lying.
Hi Moomin mom! Get running!
Oh, Hemuli!
Is there something wrong with the pumpkin?
Not exactly.
But look, the pumpkin keeps growing.
What do I do?
It's already so big that you can see it from far away.
It's true.
No one will find out about the pumpkin.
Share, there may be other puzzles.
What puzzles?
Someone can steal it.
Oh, who the hell would steal my pumpkin?
We have to be on our guard.
Let's disguise a pumpkin.
Joo.
Well, you can't see it now, but you know him.
Who would have guessed.
But some poke their noses everywhere.
You.
Some people feel like taking a peek at what's behind the fence.
I'm not meant to keep secrets.
Oh.
What was it?
Mother?
Oh, I was a bit careless.
In.
Yes.
What's wrong, boy?
I'm worried.
Whence?
From mother.
He is behaving strangely.
Oh, you've noticed too.
What's wrong with mom?
I just don't know, but he sometimes tells obvious emergency lies.
Oh.
And you know, today he broke one of grandma's plates.
What does he have?
Couldn't you ask mom directly?
Me?
So who else?
Mmm, you're right.
I'm asking.
Don't show that you are worried about him.
Would he go to mother?
Joo.
Is Moomin at home?
Yes?
Moomin, what's on your mind?
Far away?
You're weird.
What do you want?
I'm just asking if Moomin is home.
Miss Niisku is sick right now.
I am very worried.
It's nothing serious, just a cold.
Uh, I didn't mean niisku-mistress.
Who are you worried about?
Well, about mom.
What's wrong with Moomin?
I don't know, something is weighing on his mind.
Mmm, mommy was distracted.
Did you notice too?
Don't worry, the old one will be gone.
Mom is not old.
Moomin looked at the sky.
What then?
Well, my mother is just worried about the weather.
No, it's about something bigger.
Papa, do you think it will rain tomorrow?
I don't know, probably not.
Oh-oh, I hope not, or else...
Or else what?
I'm going to make dinner.
Mamma!
We are married.
Well, what the hell is wrong with you?
Isn't it only natural that if the wife is in trouble due to marital partnerships, the man wants to help her.
And I want to help.
What?
Well, you.
Why?
Oh why, because you're in trouble.
And I'm not, I'm not in any trouble.
Yes, but...
Moomin thinks you're in trouble.
He's got something wrong, just like you.
Everything is excellent.
Say what you say, you're in trouble, I feel it.
Oh, I don't have to show that I'm worried now.
Tomorrow you can finally get up.
Oh, I could have enjoyed it already today, but my brother didn't give permission.
Does the breeze cook for you?
We are in the whole.
One thing at a time, Moomin.
You looked kind of miserable.
He is worried about Moomin.
Momma Moomin has gotten into a lot of trouble.
Really?
In!
It's a bit early, but the food is ready.
Oh, thank you.
I cooked you food.
Thanks.
Mummy Moomin!
What are you pushing so hard for?
I almost caught you.
I didn't notice at all.
Well, why are you in such an impossible hurry?
I'm worried.
It's such an impossible rush.
I haven't been to see it.
Watching what?
I have to tell you before you crack.
Cracks?
What's going on there?
Stink, don't touch it, he didn't spoil it.
No, I was just looking at a pretty big pumpkin.
Pumpkin?
My secret is behind the fence.
I wanted to surprise the family.
That's why I've been hiding my pumpkin.
But now Haisuli has found it.
Isn't the pumpkin already so big that it surprises anyone.
ha ISu Li, black!
He knows how to be clever.
Where are you going?
Giant pumpkin.
Is it still growing?
I can't say.
Now I understand why mom was so weird.
A big thing to hide.
Can it be eaten?
Of course. It could be sold at a high price.
You only think about money.
There is enough pumpkin to eat for a year.
Let it grow some more.
Let's make sure no one steals it.
The skunk has already seen the pumpkin. You can't keep your mouth shut.
Moominpapa guessed right.
People came from all over Moomin Valley to see the pumpkin.
Sorry. Do you know where that giant pumpkin grows?
This way.
He's in the car.
It can be overwhelming.
It can be harsh.
It can't be harsh.
Stand tight in line and wait your turn.
Moomin's garden must not be messed with.
What darkness?
I told Moominma that she must demand the entrance fee.
Nipsua, don't be a toupee.
Even Moominpappa didn't think it was a good idea, but it's worth paying to see a pumpkin.
Niisku, step forward, you will be amazed.
Thanks.
Oh Brother, you're not much bigger than I knew the dreamer.
Oh, and Niisku, the pumpkin is still growing.
Amazing. Scientific observations must be made about it.
People have come from far away to see the pumpkin.
Mamma is becoming famous.
Dad, why don't you go to bed already?
I think I'll push.
I am old enough that being on duty is a bit of a burden.
Let's hope the pumpkin doesn't grow anymore.
Let's hope. Good night.
Good night.
I'll pay a hundred gold coins.
Because of that pumpkin.
No, no, it's...
Someone has already offered a higher amount than that.
It's good. 200 gold coins.
Pumpkin is my wife.
He has grown it and has no intention of selling it.
Bring your wife here quickly. Where is he?
Doing the dishes. We can't sell the pumpkin because we're going to eat it.
Pumpkin is good.
What gluttons! Now who would eat a show piece?
An exhibition piece?
Pumpkin.
The pumpkin is stored.
That's right, it's my shift a lot.
Father, father.
What happened now?
Nothing. My shift is starting.
Oh yeah. Glad you came. Otapa on the stick.
Dad was fast asleep.
The pumpkin has disappeared.
What?
Look!
Stop! Six!
That too! Aisuli!
AI Suri!
You can't have Aisuli.
Not my pumpkin now.
Pumpkin.
The pumpkin was such a picture that grandma's knife didn't work on it.
You can take a pumpkin and carve it for help.
Pumpkin.
A big pumpkin party was held in the Moomin house.
Pumpkin pie jelly, hight and cake were served
have pumpkin lemonade to drink.
You make cookies.
I've never had such good pumpkin.
Overdrive!
Very good seller.
Little My wanted a pumpkin shell for his hut.
There was still enough pumpkin malt left on the walls,
that Pikku Mylle was left to be hawked for dinner.