No, what's going on now? Help, help, help, help!
How did you do?
Not how, but...
Then help me!
Love broke!
Time machine!
Niskuneti sells! Did it hurt?
Plastic knife! Hey look!
Well, that's awful! The star turns black!
Oh no, then it won't help Jennität anymore.
Maybe the star only twinkles in cold places.
So it is not the medicine that Jennitäti meant.
Phooey.
We must try to find the twinkling medicine that the star needs.
I don't care to search anymore!
We're leaving!
I'm hungry.
Awaiting heat!
What place is this?
We had to come to Moominvalley.
Not that little sense of yours!
When has Moomin Valley been in the jungle?
Hello Moomin! Let's go home already.
No way. We can't leave until we find Jennität's medicine.
Wow! Why did you stop?
I saw something shiny!
I love anything that sparkles!
Hey!
Alligator!
Hello! Don't eat me!
I have bad taste! I am, I am!
Wait, Beast!
I'll take care of this!
Mii!
A pinch! You don't have to fear anymore!
I trust you sell!
Now! Then let's start fighting!
You won't bite us with those dirty teeth of yours!
Mee! It's serious!
Bite this stick!
It has strong teeth!
You can be wise in the back!
Haa!
Hello Alligator! A pinch is a much bigger bite!
I don't!
Are!
I'm small and toxic!
Just be you!
Sell and Pinch! Come here!
Humi, Troll and Ladybug!
I'm jumping!
I guess it won't sink!
Hurry up!
Jump here!
But when I can't swim!
You have no choice!
Oh God! Oh God! Oh God!
I see! Try to catch us!
Oh no! It goes after!
That's where it comes from!
Good luck!
Try to take it!
Moomin, Goblin and Nipsu are scary!
Faster! Faster!
Hurry up!
It catches us!
Help! Help! We sink to the bottom!
And I can't swim!
Don't always be a joke, Janis Housu!
Oops! What happened now?
I think we were saved!
Hi! Come here on the ferry!
Oh, thanks a lot!
Which machine would work?
Otherwise we're in trouble!
And we'll never get home!
It's a time machine!
Let's hope!
Let's hope and hope!
We'll see if we try!
Is it a modern sculpture?
Absolutely not! This is a time machine and our valuable property!
A combination of a watch and an onfel machine equipped with an umbrella.
We can't go home without a time machine.
Yeah. I'm not interested in new things.
Only old things are beautiful.
He is a pleasant gentleman.
What are you doing here in the jungle?
Oh what?
What do I look like?
Very suspicious!
Did you see?
Wedding! The golden fish!
It flashed beautifully!
Good! The golden kingdom is near!
A golden kingdom?
Right! Finding the Golden Kingdom is my lifelong dream!
No! Explorer!
Well, what is there in the golden kingdom?
There rises the palace of stars at the top!
There are tears of the sun and the moon!
There are star drops!
Drops of stars!
How romantic!
It sure is beautiful.
You could find a sale there!
You just wanted to go to the palace.
It's a trifle after everything else!
Maybe we will find Jennitän's medicine in the golden kingdom.
Hey explorer, can we join?
There is always company for those traveling alone!
Hey!
What is it?
It must be the gate of the golden kingdom!
Hold tight!
Hey!
Terrible!
Oh finally stop!
We survived.
What do we do now?
Let's go forward on foot.
This seems like a dead end.
There could be a palace wall there.
The sun and moon of the stars!
The Palace of Stars, the holiest place in the Golden Kingdom begins here!
How do we get in?
Where is the palace door?
Oh, sails!
Why do those characters look so angry?
Because their purpose is to keep intruders away.
Aha, just scaremongering.
You don't scare me!
You can't go after like an alligator!
Come on! Run away!
What did you want?
Hey, leave me alone!
Help!
Stupid sweeper, get your nails off me! What exactly are you going to do? Help!
Was a loud and argumentative creature.
But on the inside, he's definitely kind and affectionate.
We are not to be taken back!
We have to get to the other side of the wall so we can save him.
Where are you taking me?
I will not be food for your chicks! You get to see!
Did you still want to keep me in the air?
Too high. No dice.
So.
That you could look for an open door?
Oh, did you get hurt badly?
Curious thing. It was moving.
The wall opened!
I push in!
Wait!
Let me down! Still wanted to play with me?
Teach! Don't try to peck!
If you don't believe me, I'll wring your neck out!
I'm not to be played with!
where are you
Where exactly are you all?
Movie-Veikko!
A pinch!
how are you there
We must have gotten lost here. This is a labyrinth.
Oh, I guess not.
How dare you bite me in the rear!
Apologize immediately!
Because you won't let me fuck you!
Do not! Do not!
Oh, after all, the soul gold remained!
Sell, where are you?
The same condor that caught Myy.
Since Mytta is nowhere to be seen, it has already swallowed him.
And not!
The condor flew that way!
Let's go there!
These dogs are set to guard the doorway.
Now join us to open the door to history!
Hey, we had to save the little shop.
How do you open that door?
Would that statue move too?
Too scary.
I'm looking into this.
Nipsu, can you find anything?
There's something in this dog's mouth!
What now?
No sweat.
What's in this mouth?
I'm afraid I'm getting wet!
The palace I've always dreamed of!
Now I found it!
This is the fulfillment of my life!
Poke us!
Hey, listen!
Yes, that voice!
It must be.
You go home and leave me hanging here!
You are fine!
All the blood has gone to the head since you took so long!
You didn't hurt yourself!
Help me down now!
Sorry!
You can get out right away!
I was afraid that Kondor had already poked you in the cheek.
Haha, that kind of old scum won't eat me!
I bit it!
I'm so glad you played!
Shit, stop it!
You and I, we don't care about each other!
Hi, hi, hi, hi!
Oh this happiness!
This is pure gold!
Look!
Of course it's gold!
It looks even stupider now!
Wow! There's Diamond!
Maybe a real Diamond!
Maybe it's a ruby!
Diamond is colorless!
And that blue is Safiri!
Amazing!
Oh so beautiful!
I'm rich, I'm rich!
It is wonderful to own!
What was it?
I got a weird feeling!
Come on, don't hang around there!
Deafness out there, come out boldly!
No, no, don't come!
Niskunnetti, don't be a joke!
What do you really want?
If you touch us with your paw,
I made you a fur coat!
Who is that then?
Who exactly are you?
You don't seem to be those greedy adventurers,
whose heads can only fit one thought.
I wish I had gold!
Why have you come here?
We are looking for medicine for Jennität.
Jennitätti is in severe pain!
Aunt Jenni, I feel familiar!
A long time ago, a couple came here,
and Ropva had such a big nose,
like you too.
They had lost their guide.
Ah, so Aunt Jennitäti has been here.
So what do you do?
I've been here.
So what are you doing here?
Me?
I am the gatekeeper of the palace.
I have been for five hundred years.
What?
Five hundred years, right?
Or are you Jenni's relatives?
Come on, go ahead.
Are you sure that cat won't bite us?
What here has fatter morsels of taste than you?
Don't hint!
At least I'm not fat.
Just like a winter sky!
This is how the ancient peoples saw space.
Full of dreams!
This is so romantic.
I feel so good.
We are in the middle of a fabulous nebula.
Serttainen Jenny was as excited about everything as you were,
but he must have gotten awfully old already.
It is, and he suffers from a witch's arrow.
Go for it, right?
You're looking for that sparkler.
Yeah, can we have it here?
Page allied?
Are these all medicines?
Oh!
What beautiful quilts there are here.
They are all generic drugs.
Neule increased Libya Lagi
They can cure any disease
or end the pain in the bear.
There's that red, twinkling initial medicine.
Haitzus dreaming!
Can I have a peek inside?
Yay! An acrid smell!
Oh, oh, oh! Is the medicine so old that it has become invalid?
Oh! Is there another medicine?
It is the only medicine that takes away the pain. Unfortunately.
Or so. Then we must return to Jennitad empty-handed.
It was that twinkling medicine that could have made him well again.
Ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha!
Quiver moon
Where have the children gone?
Eat is mine. I shouldn't have told Moomin and his friends about the twinkling star medicine,
If only they were safe.
Oh, of course they are.
Oh! Hey!
Hello again!
Oh, praise!
It's fun to be home.
So there is a place that looks like a glimpse of the rest.
What a relief.
I was very worried about you. Glad you made it home.
Grandma's medicine helped.
Auntie's witch's arrow has healed.
We found a flickering medicine, but it had already gotten old.
Sorry.
Don't do it, Surko.
And after all, we got to see many exciting things.
So much lovely sparkle and glitter.
Everything was in one piece.
You can hear about everything we saw on the way.
Thanks in advance.
And now we celebrate that Aunt Jenni has recovered.
Oops, because it has happened.
Hehehe, funny cures. Here, please.
Hi, hi.
Does Moomin mom need an entrepreneur for you?
I hope you like star flower.
Oh, how kind.
I'll give you some stardust that I once found in the desert. Here.
Oh, oh, thank you.
For this reason I gathered from the sea.
Oh, thank you.
Oh, thank you. I thank you all.
Share, here's a little memory.
You shouldn't have taken them.
Thanks Nipsu, but I just keep them myself.
Oh right.
Hi, yes that's fine.
They are not you.
We keep them Christian, you know.
And no, no.
Nipsu, give me one gem.
Give me too.
And not.
Ha ha ha.