Dad, what's the matter?
My leg hurt.
Did you fall?
I fell and broke my leg.
Fortunately, Moomin-Papa's leg didn't break. Just sprained.
Are your feet still hurting?
Joo.
Yes, sprains can develop into a long-term problem.
Yeah, I guessed it.
Sprains tend to be painful. Have a good time. I happen to prepare for a long sick leave.
Well, oh, oh. Is this such a bad thing?
A hot spring could help.
Oh right?
There are different types of hot springs.
Some take one or just others to the other.
There are no hot springs in Moomin Valley.
As far as I can tell, this should be Moominvalley.
And it probably is.
There is no hot springs terrain.
Experts are of the opinion that you have exactly them.
There are some kids over there. Let's stay away from them.
Hi kids.
Nipsu, I'll be backpacking.
I have a question.
What is it about?
Are there zoom sources out there?
What are those?
We have never needed hot springs.
Hot water gushes out of the earth's crust into a spring.
Who heats that water?
No one. As far as I know.
Remarkable.
You could quickly make tea from the spring water.
No, no. Sow in a hot spring. It heals.
Can it be bad then?
Me? I don't.
Just find the source.
For what the hell?
Sources are rare.
Are they?
Own.
We are driving to build a hotel in Moomin Valley.
And then all the people from below flow into the hot water.
Great. A lot of rich people come here.
If you help us.
And I rent them towels.
Let's continue the journey. We have a tough job ahead of us.
The scholar's time is wasted.
Keep your fingers crossed for these.
Hey wait.
If you find a hot spring, can dad bathe in it?
He has sprained his ankle.
Certainly.
Help and communication.
We are hot.
This is also fire.
Will come.
Hot spring.
Or will they build a hotel if they find a hot spring?
Yeah, isn't that a great idea.
And in what sense?
Well, because people come here in droves to take a bath and I get to rent them towels.
Then here we start selling ice cream and sausages and you know what.
And we will be marked on the map.
Yeah, but Dad, a hot spring might be nice.
You could soak your feet in it.
Share, I'd rather have a sprained ankle than a hotel full of tourists.
Don't worry, there are no hot springs in Moomin Lax.
If there were, we would surely have found them ages ago.
I believe there are.
The men must have had a reason to come here to look for hot springs.
We haven't explored every place.
If I find the source, I won't tell the men.
But listen, I won't get rich if I only rent towels to you.
Whoops, you don't need to get rich.
Shall we agree not to tell the men?
I don't think you will find sources before them.
They are experts.
Besides, I already got permission to rent towels.
This is good.
This is mette.
Well, apparently it is.
If we could find a hot spring the size of this pond,
we could attract a Moomin square full of tourists.
If the water is not hot.
It seems to me that the word of the experts can no longer be trusted.
How so?
If it were hot hot here,
if there were hot springs here, someone would have found them.
Not necessarily. If they are hidden underground, we have to dig them out.
What can I say to that, I'm starting to get into other moods.
This Moomin Lauks is the kind of place that really makes you think.
What the hell is wrong with you?
If I were staying here, I would hardly care for the hotel to disturb the peace of the valley.
Have you eaten something inappropriate?
You think so.
Heartburn can do tricks. Let's go east.
I hope we don't find anything.
Put a subdetector.
Nipsu, Are you going to come along?
Moomin can get to the world map.
That's the last thing we'd want. Don't get it?
Moomin, don't snort.
Thanks to the hot spring, Moomin Valley would become world famous.
That's not what we want.
And besides, I've finally decided to get rich by renting towels.
Moomin troll.
Nipsu is a real tease.
I don't want tourists here, but a hot spring would be fun.
It is said to be good for the skin.
Oh the discipline.
There are no hot springs here.
I wish I could be sure of that.
Snuffbox.
This matter must be negotiated with Nuuskamuikkunen.
He's gone.
I haven't seen snuff in the last few days.
True, he is staying invisible.
He has left.
Stinker, you know where Snuff is.
I don't know, but he left two days ago early in the morning.
Oh yeah.
Why do I look gloomy?
We would have asked the muikku about something.
Please ask me.
I don't ask even if I'm aware of the book.
ha Isu Li, black.
I wouldn't answer you.
Do you know anything about a hot spring?
Hot or cold.
Hopeless.
Hey, what's that hot spring?
There is a hot spring.
Wait, you have to tell me.
A really good find.
If it gets late, I'll stay the night.
And you don't, wait, Alipa.
Alisa!
Oh!
Sniff, little one!
We haven't met for a long time.
Alisa.
I'm on my way to Moominvalley.
What about grandma?
Grandma cooks herbs.
Have you joined the ranks of professional witches?
Grandma thinks it's still too early.
I guess you don't want to be them.
I want to!
And I still get that emission certificate.
Sofio, you'll show us around tomorrow.
Certainly.
So what?
How about my towel rental?
Wake up!
We thought you were joking.
I never play for money.
You promised I could rent towels.
Hardly.
We never meant it.
It was a joke.
I'll figure this out.
We meant we could let you
buy a license to rent towels.
I don't have any money.
We will print a gold coin for you.
And I own it.
Leave alone. Let's ask someone to help me.
No, no. Yes, I will help.
I'll see you early tomorrow morning, Nipsu.
Alisa, you stay with us for the night.
Yes, please.
I'd really like to.
Moomin will be happy.
Moominpapa, how's your leg?
Better all the time, but horrible
slowly it will get better.
It still hurts.
Ah, would my hot spring help?
Hot spring?
Yep, I just found one
from the river bank to the east of here.
Wake up!
I soaked myself in the spring and enjoyed it heavenly.
A wonder and a wonder.
How so?
You haven't heard the news.
What news?
There are men here looking for hot springs,
that they could mark Moomin Valley on the map
and bring tourists.
It would be exciting
if they found your hot spring.
That would be really creepy.
Don't you want Moomin Valley?
building a big hotel?
Not really.
Would you like to?
No, and neither does grandma.
The witch should move out then.
I can imagine what that would entail.
Guided tour of the witches' cottage,
where people would line up for fortune cookies
and to Alisa's corner
a public toilet would be built.
Elf!
Who has done this and why?
Why?
This is really no laughing matter.
Well, it's not.
Sniff, Muikkunen!
Hey!
Oh, Alisa is here.
Hi, nice to see you again.
I heard you were laughing just now.
So we laughed, although there is nothing to laugh about.
What were you talking about?
Muikkunen, have you already heard of those men?
I am.
Snuff, Muikkunen, has found a hot spring.
Wake up!
Good morning, Nipsu!
ha I Su Li!
What now?
What's wrong with you?
How so?
You always march straight ahead of Muubitalo.
Why today?
I'm at Takuu, something on your mind.
Looks like you're as sharp as ever.
Yeah, and I'm proud of it.
I got the wrath of the Moomins on me.
Good!
Don't hang on to them.
They are high-spirited slobs who are up to no good.
And your fate is my cover and I reach for the lock.
I'm not like you.
If I do wrong, my own feeling bothers me.
Just like a hot spring, right?
Don't run around.
I'm proud of it.
Don't run around me.
I believe that in this situation the most important thing for us is to prevent men from finding my hot spring.
It's not easy.
Second, we have to convince them to abandon the plan.
But how?
And you can't waste any time.
Let's take action now.
It's already too late, but first thing tomorrow morning before the sun has risen.
What must we do?
What can we do?
Where is Nipsu anyway?
Helps in hot spring searches. That's covered by the warranty.
The Stingray Society.
That bit.
I tell you what.
Grandma is our only hope.
The problem?
Sorcery is clearly needed now.
I would help if I could, but only grandma can help.
I'm sure everything will end happily with your grandma's help.
I don't know. It would be in the witch's interests as well.
Without further ado, let's ask the witch for help in a very nice way.
Yeah, let's put Alisa on it.
Grandma will definitely help us.
He doesn't want people to start flooding here.
Don't worry at all.
Do you want me for support?
What do you mean?
Well, that your grandma would believe better.
But remember, I'm talking.
Tell him all the trees would be cut down and the sun would shine on your cabin all day.
Tell them that they would build a public toilet in the yard.
Stop worrying already. I'll tell grandma everything.
He is not shy at all.
Don't tell me we set you up.
I'm not stupid either.
It can be nice to drop by the hotel.
Yes, but all the trees might have to be cut down before the hotel could be built.
True. It would be fun if the trees didn't block the view.
You are lying!
It's so quiet and boring here, tourists would bring a little change.
It could be difficult.
It can be tricky.
Repeaters would make a bit of a difference.
I could sell them something to drink.
Grandma, don't!
I'm thinking now. The music refreshed day and night.
People would throw so much garbage that we could use it to heat the cabin through the winter.
Grandma, don't talk about hay.
You don't mean what you say and that pisses me off.
Moomin troll.
So?
Does your mind say anything about how the ancestors of the source could be expelled?
Oh, are you willing to drive them out of here?
Well, for sure.
I think witch-like powers are needed.
Maybe you could scare them away.
Hmm, you could try that.
You would let them understand that Moomin Valley is not really a pleasant tourist destination.
It's not an easy task.
If you slipped into their tent sharp, hissing, disgusting-looking, slithering spikes.
I'm all for sharpies.
Nothing more crazy, but you can get rid of the sharp ones.
Maybe you could do something about the weather if you made them think that Moomin Valley has a miserable climate, always disgustingly cold or hot for tourists.
Hmm, ugh, dangerous.
Is it too hard?
Nothing is too difficult for a witch.
Mmm, a beautiful day will do. I'm in a great mood.
Hey, get out of there, beautiful...
I can't hide now.
A typical holiday.
You dumbass!
Tent!
Back!
So much laccase.
Tent!
The tent was gone.
I've never seen anything like that there.
No hail!
Ax!
Raikkuura from a clear sky.
Good luck.
Salamoi.
Hard to believe.
Lunto this is clearly.
How cold?
Live, live.
Oh dear. I should be there for my friends, but today might be my only chance.
Good morning.
I can't take it anymore.
Now don't let it.
I'm starting to have enough.
Hello, beautiful day.
Nissu, come to the rescue.
Yes?
You were a piece of cake when you ran through the snow.
What? I don't see snow anywhere.
Söfeera, I've never seen snow like that again.
This is the end of it all.
God!
I plodded, plodded, pill, pöller.
It's okay, it's okay.
Those looking for hot springs never returned to Moominvalley.
Moominpapa can't stand to stay away from the hot spring, even though his ankle has been healed for many weeks.
He doesn't even care to start writing his memoirs again.
Thanks for watching.