A box with seeds had washed ashore.
A tropical forest grew from them.
Some seeds sprouted carnivores and plants.
Only the music kept them going, but no one can play forever.
Snuff, don't stop calling.
Gluttony and plants attack us again.
My desire to play is about to take forever.
Maybe they have already been tamed by the sound of Snuff.
Hemuli be careful.
I have my own weeks.
Hemuli, you're looking behind!
What?
I warned you!
Snuff plants aren't tame yet!
What?
I still have tame ice!
You have to put something heavy on top of the floor lock.
Absolutely.
What do you do on meat night?
I still have tame ice.
I still have tames.
What do you do with muscle plants?
The snuffbox tries to attract them to the basement with a beautiful song.
Aha! There they come!
I mean, something else.
If we leave carnivorous plants out, they can eat us alive.
It's night.
In my opinion, it must be very hard.
I still have tames.
The thought of carnivorous plants crawling on the floor below bothers me.
Mamma, always have a kettle of boiling water handy.
Children play tarzan in the jungle.
Glad they've come up with something to do.
Sowing the seeds may have been a mistake.
I am happy. Moomin Valley bursts with tropical plants.
I don't like traveling.
It is much better that the plants have come to me.
All I can do is thank you.
Of course, trees beautify the landscape.
But carnivorous plants are disgusting.
You are just like Tartsan.
Tartsan loves Jane.
Oh, what bliss.
There's Stink over there.
Or Stink? Tartsan gives a lesson to the mischievous.
Oh, oh, oh.
This is a stupid game of tarzan without wild animals.
Animals do not grow from seeds.
Not like that, but I can get you some animals if you want.
Really?
Nothing is too much for those who block.
Well thought out, but don't get animals that are too wild.
A chimpanzee could fit.
Know exactly what you need.
Then the breads.
what are you doing
I'm still uncomfortable with carnivorous plants.
Pappa and I used to sleep in the bathroom.
I sleep outside, in the hut we built.
What if you don't know how to sell them?
Well, they also come to the lodge alone.
Only Hemuli stays in the house in that case.
He says he still wants to look at the plants.
Mamma, is everything ready?
Yes, papa.
Are you leaving?
Yeah, see you later.
Not only.
The skunk promised to get wild animals in our jungle.
Whence?
I don't know.
Be careful that Haisuli hasn't put a hedgehog in your sleeping bag.
This is where our lodge is.
Very well built.
Look, it's an amazing place.
A real jungle.
We don't want a park anywhere.
No, no, it's a jungle.
About.
Oh.
It feels like new to run free.
It's wonderful to rush to Moominvalley.
I certainly have the largest collection of rare plants in the yard.
It will become famous.
New plants are popping up all the time.
I'm not a zoologist.
See the chimpanzees that Haisuli promised us.
I'm smitten. I wouldn't have believed about Haisuli.
How sweet.
Now I feel like I'm stuck.
What was it?
So.
Oh.
It sounds like Haisuli has caught real wild beasts.
Pekka.
Just like in our home back in the old days, although the jungle is not big.
The mind becomes sensitive.
Moomins are going to prey here.
Don't lick before you drop.
Real tigers!
Did you see something?
Nothing like that. Don't be afraid. There are no wild beasts here.
Right?
Picture, Pekko!
Homemade barley bread!
Wild Tigers are coming to eat you.
Don't now.
Somehow protect the Moomin house.
No way. The tigers are almost here.
To the bathroom.
Pekka.
Shall we eat him to pieces?
We know that your stomach is upset with hemule.
Where are the Moomins?
No, I don't study animals.
Father!
Dad help!
What do you have now?
Two ferocious tigers are chasing us.
And you don't have fun?
Maybe Haisoli has told us that we have good taste.
We certainly are.
The tigers are approaching.
I have an idea.
Moomin Pekko goes to get a really big stone.
This work.
Is this okay?
It's really good.
Now go back to the bathroom.
That's where they come from.
Are you really going to eat the Moomins?
Necessarily.
I'm hungry. They would hide in the booth.
They are too quiet. I don't like this.
Ha, they don't scare the hell out of you.
Why is there a rock in there?
Dad we made it.
Of course, honey.
My husband is about to drown.
Oh, how sad. Papa let's save him.
He was going to eat us in his mouth.
Probably won't try again.
I have an idea.
A young one
From the moon
Now if only we could drive this to Laituuri
Tie a rope around him, and we'll pull him up
Good idea!
Hey, wake up!
Are you okay?
Did we Moomins eat?
It wasn't us Moomins who saved you.
The Moomins are in that booth behind your back if you still want to eat them.
My appetite has completely disappeared.
Well then jump over here.
All right, I'll defect.
What is yours?
I don't dare to jump, I've been in the zoo too long.
Well then try to swim across.
Clear.
The tigers are leaving.
It's funny that the tiger didn't drown.
I don't think the tigers ate us.
Shall we jump into the water and swim home?
Alright please, I'll be the first to jump.
I had to be the first!
Don't beg!
Be careful mummy, be careful look over there!
Oh, crocodiles!
Moomin, swim to the sly swimming ladder!
How can there be crocodiles in the sea?
Oh, my dear, you can't get out of here in the eternal world.
I have to wait for the ferry to pass.
It can take a week.
Ship traffic is not very busy.
Oh week, my nerves can't stand being around that long.
Oh week, my nerves can't take being in the dock for so long.
Ships usually don't even call at our pier.
Good morning!
Snuff can be made to order.
I was thinking of fishing in salt water, but I changed my mind, I don't want a sea monster on my fishing line.
Come to the tree! Come to the tree!
Hemul's voice. Maybe the tigers are chasing him now.
What annoyed you so much? I just told you not to eat my plants.
Help!
The rhinoceros is a skunk.
Can we help?
Hardly.
Hemuli, is everything alright?
Well, it's gone. That's all.
Who's that there? What do you do with a Rhino that is stuck in its horn?
I guess I have to get rid of it, but remember to be careful.
Let's try.
Astartsan!
You brought the beasts here, didn't you? Recognize away.
I guess so. After all, he wanted a real jungle.
Know him. After all, we have tamed the beasts.
Tamed!
Wild beasts can be tamed into adorable pets.
Hi! Snake!
What do you want?
Rhinoceros and tigers have become pets for the Moomin family, but you're from a different country, aren't you?
I am.
I'll bring Niskuned and Moomin here.
Don't eat them, but bite them across the tail.
Clear.
I was really dumbfounded. It was so big you could have both sat in it.
I would like to see that giant snow.
You didn't just sow tropical seeds for these.
We sprinkled the past here and there.
There must have been an awful lot of seeds in the box.
If there are enough of them everywhere.
Where is the snow?
Those where?
There.
Hey, how wonderful.
You'll notice by now that I don't always speak slang.
The moon is so soft and delicate and beautiful.
Moon in a boat is wonderfully romantic sailing.
Our former swamp seems to have turned into a luxurious mangrove swamp.
ha I Su Li!
Haisuli, hey!
I disappeared.
I don't see him anywhere.
Lummet seems to be riding the wind.
The dark night is approaching.
We need to get out.
Remind?
I don't know.
Look, there's the sea over there.
You show crocodile roads.
Niskunemi, look.
Or a boat.
We have to make it to the ship before the ship catches up with us.
Where?
There.
Niskuneiti, the ship is not far.
Good luck.
Moomin trolls swim as hard as they can.
They had a head start, but as you know, stingrays are fast swimmers.