This year, Nuuska Muikkunen, who lives in his own conditions, has set up his tent on the bank of the river.
He intends to stay there until winter, in all harmony with the world.
Moomin sometimes feels lonely and enjoys being surrounded by Nuuska Muikkunen.
Snuff Muikkunen!
He's not here, he's not!
He has forgotten and gone wandering.
How can he be comfortable alone?
I, too, miss solitude at that time.
Shall we each go our separate ways?
We'd rather leave tomorrow.
We decided to leave today.
That's how we decided, you can't live from a joint decision.
You decided, not me.
You were involved in deciding, you also have to come and collect shells.
I'm already going.
Moi!
It's Ipsu!
Where are you going?
I envied Nuuska Muikku.
Why?
Otherwise, just.
So he's gone?
Maybe we'll find something as exciting as that hat.
Yes, it was just a joke.
Did you really throw it in the river?
We shouldn't have.
It seemed dangerous.
The hat turned me into a ghost animal.
But eggshells to clouds.
Yeah, it was fun.
Go see if I can find a pearl shell.
Muvi, Pekko, wake up! Nisku's mother is in trouble.
What? What? What is it?
Nisku's mother fell into the antlion's pit.
When we were playing hooky. Come on!
Apply a little more!
Give me a hand! Give me a hand!
Antlion!
Are you trying to mess with my pit?
Well, I don't. I'll leave right away.
Stop yelling now!
You're scaring my game!
Niskun's mother, is everything alright?
I'm not like him at all.
I don't necessarily feed the antlion.
Oh, Pekko, help.
Nipsu, fall into the pit.
What? Me?
Don't be afraid. I am your safety.
Nipsu, you're big enough for this job. Start going.
I'll blow you in the mouth.
Snap, quick.
But I...
Get down, you scumbag!
You yourself are a liar.
Hoppita! Help!
Nisku's mother grabbed Nipsu's leg.
Help, it's eating my tail!
I'll take the sale of the soup!
Thanks.
Are you ready?
Let's go!
I know the secret.
Tell me.
The magician's hat has drifted with the current onto the sand bar.
Really?
Terrible things happen every now and then.
Oh.
Maybe we should have thrown our hat elsewhere.
The hat is stuck in that tree trunk.
I can't really see, but can you.
Speak up.
But, oh my goodness, the water has turned red.
I guess the water has changed into something else in the hat.
Hats off.
Hopefully redness.
Are you angry?
Speak up.
Did you find the hat?
I found.
Mp createisteka palk dominance
Puh Works
What the hell are we doing to the hat?
You can never leave it anywhere.
You never know who's crawling in there.
But we can drink vaapukka juice every time we pour water into the hat.
It could be that the water turned into vaapukka juice because it was from this river.
We have to do it now.
Swimmer, you look tired.
I woke up in the night, and I couldn't catch up with the dream anymore.
What exactly are you implying?
I know what you were doing. I supervised too.
You were with the snot.
You've been dreaming. I'm in a hurry. Thanks for the breakfast.
I know what you did. I tell you what.
It's terribly boring to listen to others explain their dreams.
What exactly is the matter?
Not at all, grandma.
Ah, he left again.
Pah, little sell, no secret, funny things.
Nus cam Ichinomiya year.
I know who the hat belongs to.
To whom?
For the magician.
Magician?
I just saw Hemul, and he told me he saw the Magician.
I've had a dream about a flying witch.
On the back of a black panther.
A magician cares about nothing but the magician.
The magician cares about nothing but rubies.
He chases them around the world riding his panther.
And when he lost his hat...
He must have been on Moomin's leg looking for rubies.
Does the Magician have more than one hat?
I don't know.
The magician may not know where he has lost his hat.
Maybe that's the way it is...
All the same. I want to try one thing with a hat.
What's up? Tell me.
Antlions do not live up to their reputation at all.
It takes hours for them to dig themselves into the sand.
It only takes them an hour.
Only now you're narrating.
After all, one hour is a long time to dig in the sand.
Are you talking about me?
We're talking about how fast you can dig into the sand.
Faster than you can imagine.
Moomin said you dig in the sand when you feel it, but I don't believe it.
Snuff claims that you need hours to dig in.
I can show.
Pretty fast. Can't say anything else.
Yes, it was a secret, but he has a pre-dug hole hidden.
And it isn't.
You've got it.
I can just dig in there. Just go.
This is a good place for me.
I agree. Under this rock.
Huh, show me that place.
Well dig into this.
Fuck this.
Take your time.
Hey, a second and a half.
After all, there is something.
It really is.
I sit on a rock just to be sure.
Good, try to leave now.
So you trapped the antlion.
Little sells.
I'm left.
Did you follow us last night?
That's fine.
Have you told others?
Silly, but next time wake me up too.
Or languages, for that matter.
Is that what you mean?
You wake me up because I'm nice.
Come on, that's a different matter of course.
Hey, turn off the water.
The hat is not visible here.
You can't really see it.
Where did you last use it?
How much water?
I think the sand has turned to water.
You'd think the leech lion had already turned into something.
You would think so.
I've sat enough, jump away.
You can't move a stone on your own, can you?
Do we have to help him up?
This is disgusting.
I'll get it done.
What has happened to him?
Let's turn the hat upside down.
Languages of life!
Jelly.
Shape, see?
What chocolat?
It's poop.
Hahahaha!
Tasteless Peikko!
Don't push!
Hahahaha!
I just saw a magician.
What?
It must have been him.
Are you looking for your top hat?
I fear the worst.
Did you hide it well?
To the basement?
Is it a safe hide?
Only me and Myy alone know where the hat is.
A piece of yarn.
It could even turn into spaghetti.
It wasn't exactly spaghetti.
Mumimamma!
Grandma, you should know one thing.
What thing?
Something is happening in the house.
In our house?
A tree grows in the basement!
Well, it's fun.
What the hell have you done?
I just put a piece of thread on the magician's hat.
We threw the hat away.
We retrieved it and took it to the basement.
Who are we?
Me and Moomin are growing up beautifully.
We need to tell Moomipapa before it's too late.
In. The door is not locked.
Don't worry, just keep growing.
Jukkara that I became a green thumb too.
Sanokku, you need water and make Piani fruits.
In.
Sorry to bother you.
What's the matter?
Sad news.
Or bad news?
I think you need to connect.
I think you should come down and take a look before it's too late.
Too late? Sounds threatening.
But don't worry, I'll take care of you.
Come on Grandma.
Leave my husband's desk alone, you hear?
I'll come my darling.
Oh!
Would you bring me a saw? This is truly a disaster.
Unfortunately. The thing is, the saw is in the basement and you can't get there.
Back to nature then. I break the branches in my hands.
Moomin house.
Come on Miss Nisku. This is funny.
But what has happened?
I've only taken care of the wood shark. Change.
Ilua.
Disasters shouldn't last this long.
I want something from the morning.
There is a bright side to this. We no longer need to fetch firewood.
Yes, you still learn that you don't take over the Moomin house like that.
Moominpa, Moominpa, look at the flowers.
Oh, and fruit.
Moominpappa, take and taste.
Kamala.
Pikkumyu has put something in Takuu's hat.
Moomin, where are you?
I am Finland.
Low-no-go.
Oh Moomin, I was afraid you weren't in.
Dad, mom, sell.
We need to get saws and axes.
Saat and the axes are in the basement, and there is no going there.
I run to get help. You don't have to.
Are you a magician?
I am. I see you have found my hat.
It was on top of a mountain.
A remarkable thing. I give thanks that the oin of the tree flourishes.
But you must wither away.
Mother!
Mr. Magician, you have quite a hat.
That's right, I apologize.
We are thankful that we were saved.
Kindly said ma'am.
Have you ever seen unusually large rubies?
The fact that my hat landed here feels like an omen.
Here you are? My husband has gifted it to me.
It's really great.
However, it's not the king ruby I'm looking for.
King ruby?
I've been looking for it for hundreds of years.
It haunts me and I can't find it.
We light a beacon if we see it.
I think it's friendly that we meet again.
Not even a madder magician.
Hey, let's start spinning firewood.
Clear!
From the branches!
Oh!
So the magician's hat finally disappeared from the Moomin trap.
Moomin's parents were happy with it, but
Moomin needed an inexhaustible supply of baby juice.