I haven't accomplished anything in my life yet.
Something should be done.
Moomin troll.
He said.
Breakfast is covered. Didn't you hear when I called?
No, sorry.
But I don't like anything now.
What's wrong with you? are you sick
In.
Do you have a fever?
There is no fever.
Mom, listen, you always cook for us.
Yes, yes, yes. I will, but your father will get all the groceries.
Well, what about this house?
We built it together with your mother.
It took ten years to build.
It was a fun time.
I guessed it.
What did you guess?
Let it be.
Mom and Dad have always done everything for me.
When I have been sick, they have taken care of me.
And I haven't done anything like that myself.
Good morning, Nuuska Muikkunen.
Good morning, Moomin Goofy.
You're on the move early.
I have a question.
About what?
Well, I wish you would tell me how I could become as independent as you.
I'll tell you now what the matter is.
I want to do something of my own.
I'll lose myself if I don't get to control my life.
You tell me.
What should I do?
Listen now.
Don't ask others what you need to do.
Father!
What's wrong now?
Dad, I have something to do.
Oh, well, tell me what's on your mind.
The one when I would like to decide my own life.
What do you really need?
What exactly do you mean?
You and mom have done everything for me so far.
I do understand that.
Ah, so what?
Well, I would like to know how I could decide on my own life from now on.
Oh, that's why you were like catnip this morning.
You have reached a new milestone in your life.
Oh, am I?
You are, Moomin.
You have now stepped on the threshold of a new life.
You start opening your own yard as a time worker.
You are laying the first foundation stones on the highway of life.
I think I have a little tip for you.
Namely, a book about Robinson Crusoe.
You read that book.
I will definitely read, thanks dad.
Hurrah!
Come on, Moomin.
Oh, this all reminds me of my own youth.
Not this, and not this.
Here it is.
I found it.
Well, Robinson Crusoe is adventures.
The fury of the storm became more and more terrible.
Two nearby heavy cargo ships had their masts snapped.
While the wind was still blowing furiously, one morning a cry was suddenly heard from the mast in sight of the land.
Hardly had we all made it to the deck when our ship hit a sand bar and came to a rest.
After getting myself an apartment, my biggest concern was to find a place where I could tune the white.
I can probably live with worse shortcomings here.
Oh, how fascinating.
Robinson Crusoe lived on a desert island on his own terms.
Would I be able to do the same?
I'm no worse.
Robinson was just an ordinary boy.
I can if he could.
I go to sea and make sure my ship gets wrecked.
Hey, mom.
Hello, Moomin. Are you feeling better?
Yes, I have decided to go to sea.
I'm going to follow in Robinson Crusoe's footsteps.
Are you serious?
I am.
I get shipwrecked, but I land on a deserted island and start living there.
Mom, he's not blocking me.
I have made my decision and from now on I will live my own life.
I'm not blocking you.
Mother!
Sounds fun. Good luck on your journey.
Well, I have to go pack. A very busy day.
First of all, I need a diary where I can write down everything that happens to me.
Then I need a pen and a large drinking glass, scissors, a nail, a clipper, binoculars and a towel.
Now I'm ready.
Mom, I'll have some dinner.
Just take it.
Now fit into it.
Sweetheart.
So what now?
Moomin goes to sea. He is going to live his own life in the same way as Robinson Crusoe.
Or will he start living like Robinson Crusoe?
But it's really great.
Dad, can I borrow the boat?
With pleasure.
I probably can't return it in the same condition.
Oh, for what?
Because I have to get shipwrecked.
Ooo, we live in exciting times.
Absolutely.
Mamma, did you hear what Moomin said?
I wish I could be young again.
I would immediately go on an adventure without a trace of fear.
How exciting?
Hey, over here, over here.
Here, here, here, here, here.
Moomin, where are you going with such a big backpack?
Don't say, you've invented a new game.
Let me guess what game it is.
Moomin, what game is that?
First of all, the question is not a joke.
So what?
I will go to sea and start living on my own.
Hohoho, and can you go to sea?
Have you egged yourself on?
I'm going to the seas, to the seas, and not to the destination.
Oh, to the sea.
Yes, I will move to a deserted island and live like Robinson Crusoe.
Why?
Sounds original.
Moomin, can I come along?
Yes?
If Niiskuneti can come, I will too.
Is a lot of money needed there?
Of course not. What can you buy on a deserted island?
Aha, well then I can come too.
Yes, but like Robinson Crusoe lived on a deserted island without companions.
It doesn't matter if you have a few friends with you.
Let's help Moomin to carry the luggage.
It suits me.
And to me.
Hey, wait.
GP.
It happens.
Hey listen.
We go to the seas, to the seas and we also get there.
To the sea, to the destination.
Um, why did they have to get involved in this?
To the sea, to the sea, to the sea, bye.
Wake up.
The boat is already fully loaded.
There you go, now it works.
I fixed it, the rudder and now it's fine.
Do you notice how handy I am?
There is no such fault that you cannot fix.
Mummy Moomin.
Welcome, Little Myy.
I can't take them with me.
My whole life depends on this thing.
I have made my decision.
I'll let them know it won't work.
I go to sea alone or I don't go at all.
That's what I tell everyone.
I'll say for sure.
Moomin, hurry.
Don't leave your own trip.
Oh, Mom and Dad, what are you doing here?
Moominmamma and Moominpapa go with them.
Kasku, I want to join your youth.
I also want to participate in exciting long-distance sailing.
I can come along.
Well, me and my mother.
We would like that.
Oh.
I wish you a happy journey.
Thank you, Aren't you coming?
I don't think so, but I hope everything goes well and the winds are favorable.
I mean I wish you a real shipwreck.
Oh, thanks.
Let's go already.
What's delaying it?
You let go.
For sailing.
Moomin, baller?
Upward facing.
Sail up, Moomin. Let's go on sea adventures.
Take care of yourselves.
Now delicious sandwiches.
Our sailing trip has begun, children.
The best feed you can get.
You just sink to the bottom like a rock when we run aground.
You want my bread?
This was not supposed to be a picnic.
Oh, there's an island over there.
Moomin look, there's an island.
Let's go ashore there.
And no, we're not shipwrecked yet.
Still thinking about the shipwreck?
Of course.
Oh no, I can't even swim a meter.
Mamma, look how the moon shines.
Lovely, I'm glad we went along.
What was it?
We clearly hit something.
Oh, papa, look at that.
What is this?
Must not.
Remarkable.
Odd.
At least this is a magazine, right?
How could deciduous trees suddenly grow in the middle of the sea?
Oh, how beautiful.
Father look, trees grow straight out of the sea.
Yeah, I can see that.
It's very strange.
It really is.
We ran aground.
The boat sinks.
Good luck, now there were problems.
Shipwreck, shipwreck, the adventure can begin.
I don't want a shipwreck.
What is it?
The pinch calms down, the water doesn't come in anymore, see?
Branches and leaves block the leak.
Surely we don't have to worry?
We will reassess the situation after the sun has risen.
Oh yeah, we were shipwrecked.
No one is visible, where everyone is.
Moomin troll.
Hyperys, we're down.
Good morning, Moomin.
Good morning.
Hey, how did you get there?
Moomin land here.
Robinson always got up on time.
What has happened?
Where is all the water?
Oh, I guess it didn't happen to you.
No.
Surprisingly, here is an island.
Is it?
On, on.
Last night was probably a higher than usual high tide.
Let's go.
The water reached almost to the top of the trees.
We are on an island.
What a stroke of luck.
I was shipwrecked.
I get to start an independent life on a deserted island.
It tastes good.
Moomin comes to eat breakfast.
Come on, my darling.
I don't want any breakfast.
What for?
Because I'm starting to live alone now.
Share, just like that.
Don't bring your own breakfast.
I live my own life, bye.
Moomin, let him go.
Which of our Moomins just wouldn't get into trouble.
How lucky I was to find breakfast like this.
I am very fine.
I'm great.
Great drinking water suddenly.
Now I have to go fishing.
I catch a really big fish.
Moomin, we're going to the swimming pool.
At the same time, we will collect something to eat for you too.
Blacksmithing.
Hei isiteden!
Dad, what do you think?
How will Moomin survive?
Don't worry, he is our son.
He always makes it!
He is our son. He always makes it.
I'm bored.
What was that sound?
It would be fun to know.
I have such a feeling...
Dude, what happened?
Mom, I think there's someone behind us.
I think so too.
Cry?
Oh!
You can probably make a good soup out of these mussels.
You can! Are you sulking!
Hey.
Where is your camp?
In the forest, by the stream.
But don't come there.
Oh why?
Because I have to survive on my own, like Robinson Crusoe.
I don't have time for you.
Hey are you?
Now I'm freaking out. It's a big fish.
Car talk.
Monsters!
Moominpapa, what happened?
Wake up, Moominpapa!
What was I doing?
Who has been here?
Look, a tent.
Now I remember, monsters!
Monsters!
We have to tell Moomin about them right away.
Monster!
A real monster!
Oh my tent.
The monster did this.
More monsters!
What would Robinson have done in this situation?
That book didn't talk about monsters.
Moomin!
Sell and niskuneiti.
Aha, you monsters scared Moominmamma and Moominpapa.
Myy is careful.
On top of everything, you still steal pots and pans.
Give them back.
Pots and pans back.
It's too late to regret now.
All the goods back right away.
Did you hear?
What is it now?
Myy monster seems Weird.
Just when he wanted to tell us something.
Now they go away.
Can you have us come along?
Let's go anyway.
Yeah, sure.
What has happened to this?
It's stuck between the roots.
Mite!
I guess it won't bite.
I'll stop by and see.
It is in poor condition.
I feel sorry for you.
It has such a big belly that it can't move forward.
I think it's expecting a baby.
Baby! That's just fun!
We have to get the monster out.
When you just take it off, you're the Robinson Crusoe.
And you do everything alone, that's how it was.
Yeah, yeah, but wait.
The other monsters were in the water.
Last night when we came.
The morning dawned and there was low tide.
The monster stayed on dry land.
Water!
Water is salvation.
The monster seems to do poorly on dry land.
The other monsters try to make it easier.
Hey, let's do our best.
Clear!
Mummipeukko, let's go ask mummamma and mummappa for help.
Let's do that, and now everyone to get water.
Clear!
Uh!
Sell, is it ready?
It is, it is, it is, let it come!
How is it?
Much better!
Fun!
Cold!
Hey, look at the egg!
An awful lot of flushing for one egg.
But yes it is huge!
How many omelets would it make?
Torvelo!
Now our monster would be able to get away with it!
Yes, you did great!
Can't say more!
I've gotten the idea that monsters come from far away to spawn here.
Will.
Mamma, we have to go.
I guess so.
Sell, is the rudder ok?
All right.
Pipsu, hurry up, the water will rise soon.
I know.
Moomin has changed a lot here.
Yeah, he's suddenly grown big and sensible.
Nothing is as useful for growing up as reading good books.
He still has some learning to do.