Next week
Hi! Where is Ninni?
Ninni said she wants to play with us.
Nini! Come and have fun!
Now let's go and...
Ninni, who had become invisible because of her ironic aunt, was now visible up to her neck,
but the head refused to appear, even though Mamma Moomin poured grandmother's medicine into it.
See what the invisible child looks like!
Good morning everyone!
You too, Fatfish! It's past twelve o'clock!
Let's play hide and seek in the forest.
Great! How are you, Ninni?
Very.
Um, stupid. If I could see you, I wouldn't have to ask.
As for you, you always act like a fool!
Hey...
This place is great for playing hide and seek.
The bigger the more exciting.
However, let's adopt a new rule...
What?
That you can't change your hiding place in the middle of everything.
Did you understand, Ninni?
Nipsu, you will be the first.
Why always me?
We have to practice because Ninni is with us.
No need to practice hiding.
You see, Ninni has never played hide and seek.
Oh, right?
Ninni has never played hide and seek or anything else.
Even when it looked like it, huh?
Oh, anyway.
Is it okay for you to stay?
I won't stay.
All right, I'll stay.
I'll slowly count to ten so you can hide.
One...
Two...
Hurry up and hide, Ninni.
Three...
Four...
Go further.
Five...
Six...
Seven...
Eight...
Nine...
No, Ninni.
Don't be afraid of me.
Go hide behind that bush.
I started looking.
Thanks.
Au, au, au!
I found you in a pinch.
No, no, no, no!
Wake up!
The sale has been found.
Where is Ninni hiding?
Wake up!
I found you.
You had a good hiding place, but it got you.
Your bow showed.
No longer a swamp lady, but she's never hard to find.
Niiskunneiti wants him to be found.
Niiskunnetti was found.
Three...
Four...
Five...
This is my gasoline.
Six...
Seven...
No, Ninni.
I'll give you a good hiding.
You will never be found there.
The mouth here is a bit tight, but inside the corridor is wide.
Hurry, or Nipsu will find you.
That's how, when you stay there until tomorrow, you become completely invisible.
I want out.
Tomorrow we're going to rob a bank together.
I didn't want to.
That's it from me.
You're half... a quarter of the booty.
So.
Good thing I figured out how to bring Ninn here.
It's funny that you think so, Tuutikki.
You are so special that your strange behavior can make Ninn visible again.
And of course you are kind.
Please share. We should be flattered.
Necessarily.
By the way, Ninni is already talking. His voice is really good.
Has her voice always been like that?
Who knows, even if it is.
Otherwise, many people get along just fine without using their heads.
It's fun when Ninn has playmates. He's never had them before.
But I don't think he knows how to play.
I think some sort of shock would be necessary for him.
I found you!
Phew, there were spikes in the gasoline.
I was the last to be found.
Ninni is not found.
Movement.
You hid in the same gas station as Ninni.
Ninni is clever.
Come on, maybe Ninni is lost.
I have searched everywhere but he has become invisible again and therefore I cannot find him.
Nipsu is in bad trouble.
Where could Ninni be anyway?
I don't know, I haven't seen it.
Ninni, come out, we're going home.
Which one is he in?
It's your job to find him.
Not anymore when we're done playing.
Yes, I think we need to find Ninni.
Let's all go find it.
Hi Ninni, come out, the games are over.
Ninni, we're going home to drink juice and eat cookies.
Nini! Nini!
where are you Nini!
We shouldn't have gone this far into hiding.
Listen, if Ninni is really lost.
Nini! Nini!
Come forth!
Ninni, help me, I'm here!
Did you hear?
Did you hear something?
Perhaps.
I'm here!
Ninni's voice.
It sounds close.
Ninni, where are you?
Here, the expensive one is inside.
Ninni, can't be far.
Let's hurry.
Ninni, I didn't understand what you said.
where are you
I'm here, here.
Burn, burn.
Say louder.
Kalli is inside.
Say it one more time.
Here, the expensive one is inside.
There.
Hey, I've never screamed so loud in my life.
Ninni, are you trapped behind this rock?
I'm Stinky closed the door to the opening.
We'll get you out. Let's move on to reason.
Are you OK?
I'm Moomin the goblin. Thanks.
Your voice has become stronger.
Recovered?
Or so.
Grab my hand and I'll pull you out.
I will come.
Ahoy! What has happened?
Ninni was in the cave.
Oh, great. Ninni found a great hiding place.
Did I say something funny?
It's clever to think of Ninni robbing a bank.
I guess so.
The stench was quite a shock for Ninn.
But not only he became invisible.
And his voice is much louder now too.
Ninni screamed as loud as she could.
Did you scream really loud?
I screamed.
Moomin told me to scream so he would know where I was.
And you screamed loud too.
Dear Nini.
Those who speak loudly are usually also visible.
Remember that.
Scream, I want to see you.
Good idea. And try to get angry too.
Tuutikki would be happy if you started showing up again.
Get mad at Haisul.
The stench is so awful.
It shouldn't be. Let me be careful.
Stink wait.
You can't catch me.
Stink, I have something to do.
I have nothing to do with you.
Did it hurt you?
Stink, you can't run away.
The forest is my home field. You can't catch me like this.
ha Isu Li.
You can't do this to me.
We will do to you what you did to Ninn.
I needed Ninn's help.
He didn't want to help.
I brought him here to change his mind.
And would be so shocked that it would become completely invisible.
The skunk insists that he is invisible.
Let me out.
Shouldn't be heard. Tomorrow.
You scoundrels are doing this out of sheer malice.
This will be remembered.
Despite everything, Ninn's face was still invisible.
Then ten days later.
The nails are sticking out in this weather.
I've never seen anyone stare into the sea like that.
I guess Ninni has never seen the sea before.
Well, now he's coming.
Nini, what's wrong?
The sea is too big. Way too big.
I don't need you.
Mummy mom hello.
So?
What's wrong with Nin?
There's nothing wrong with living.
He is amazed by the size of the sea.
Yeah, there's an awful lot of water in the sea.
Haa.
For my part, I haven't been surprised or excited for weeks.
Mom is bored.
Probably.
Mother never is.
Now he clearly is.
He hopes something surprising will happen.
Mom is bored.
Do you think?
We have to arrange a surprise for mom.
What kind?
So that he is really surprised.
Dad, don't just say you're going to dump mom in the ocean.
What could be a better surprise?
But the water is terribly cold.
Hey, when we were young, the water was never too cold for us.
Did you push each other into the sea?
All the time.
Father.
So what?
Nothing.
Don't worry.
It's going to be a lot of fun for mom.
Must not!
Dare Lappas push Moominmamma into the sea?
Let me explain.
There is no explaining the mischief.
Moomin would get drenched.
You can't do that!
bother?
The nipple is visible!
How fun?
Finally we see Nenn.
Dad, did something happen?
Well, not really.
He has amazed.
Dad, did something happen?
Well, not really.
He's the meanest and sharpest kid I've ever seen.
I finally became visible.
Yes, and you won't disappear anymore.
I will never.
A playful girl and obviously with good teeth.
Nenni, be so happy.
Don't bother.
Mamma.
I'm happy too.
Oh.
Don't laugh you evil brat, you toothy monster.
What's so funny?
Did Nenni really laugh?
You have truly changed him.
Yeah, he's almost as bad as the little one.
I've never heard Ninn laugh.
But the best thing is that he has become visible again.
Tuttik!
And so the tuttik took Ninn, as he had brought.
But now Ninnin was visible and was anything but timid.
Ninnin was reportedly ready for anything except going to her aunt's house.
Thank you.