This year let's see next let's see next let's see next let's see next let's see next let's see next let's see next let's see next let's see next let's see next let's see next let's see next let's see next let's see next let's see next let's see next let's see next let's see next let's see next
Moomin valley bathed in the sunshine again, lazy and relaxed.
But that's not to everyone's liking.
Inside.
Honey, Would you like a cup of coffee?
My insides are literally screaming for coffee.
Oh well, it's time.
Memoirs huh?
Writing sucks.
How could you write in this dormant cheap?
How so?
The dull phase of my youth is passing.
Goodness.
You are exaggerating.
I wrote poetry.
Your poems must have been good.
Terrible.
But my duty to posterity requires me to record everything, the inspiration is just lacking.
How would inspiration be possible when nothing ever happens here?
Good unusual. Do you miss adventures?
I miss you. I miss something big, something scary.
Hey mom, what's up now?
Your father craves adventure.
His writing is floundering again because everything is so boring.
And nothing ever happens to him.
Is Moominpappa missing something really exciting?
Yes, I think so.
Maybe I can organize something exciting.
Now it looks like the footprints of a huge monster.
Hey, hey, hey.
Oh, that it will be good luck for me when I can bring joy to others.
A few more tracks.
Fortunately, I don't often have to do honest work.
Oh, rougher than I imagined.
Back, back, back.
Wake up, Moomin, wake up.
Hooi, Moominmamma, Moominpapa, get up.
Awakening, awakening, monster.
A monster has happened to you.
Come quickly before you are eaten alive. Come already.
Huge footprints.
I succeeded, leaving a mark in my heart.
A monster from the unexplored depths.
Very strange. What business would a monster have in a Moomin house?
I don't know.
The footprints lead straight to the Moomin house.
Someone has told the monster where our house is.
But have you noticed that monster tracks don't lead back?
In that case, the monster is still here.
If the monster has retraced its tracks, it must be pretty smart.
And it has stepped very precisely in its old tracks.
There's only one here, but why would it have done that?
Of course, it's also possible that the monster is still here.
Cat containers, my mother would say.
Why does the monster want to believe that it has gone away?
It's furrows.
Furrows?
What does furrows do?
Something secret.
If we knew what, even the monster would be a good furrow.
I think the monster is still here. Or what?
Tonight maybe.
What? What tonight?
We are being attacked.
The monster has gone to report his information.
Dad, how do you know?
That's why he's trying to make you believe it's still here.
Mother! Mother!
What's wrong, Moomin?
Terrible things happen.
The monster attacks first and us.
And dad is so excited about it.
Oh, I'm happy for papa.
Work diligently.
The monster will be here next night.
Pull!
Well, now it's up.
Father, wildly high authenticity.
It is, but it may still be too low.
They are so gullible that they almost spoil my joy.
If we catch a moose, we sell it to a zoo.
And I can do business.
I want to tame a monster as my pet.
Well, the monster could be harnessed as an attraction.
I invented selling the monster to the zoo.
It's only fair that I get half the price.
That the monster could polski, huh?
Splashing in the water keeps it calm.
I'm a monster.
If the monster doesn't show up until the next night.
We share shifts.
The entire Moomin Valley is watching how we handle the duty that has fallen to us.
Hey, oh. The trouble was worth it, oh, those crazy people.
Oops, they've put food as bait.
Moomipappa seems overworked.
He snores so hard the house shakes.
I'll take these treats.
Oh, what's going on here.
They've dug in here, it's full of water and...
Opsist.
Oh, what was that.
The monster is here, the gate is closed.
No, no.
Oh, the rope had to be pulled.
Intelligence.
Let's stop.
It's just me.
Oh, from dad, unit bite.
Oh, where's the monster?
I'm just here, I stink, and I'm not a monster.
ha Isu Li.
Speak up.
Beware, it is a dangerous monster.
Look, I'm not a monster, I made those footprints.
Oh you.
False, your feet don't make that big of a mark.
Don't skimp.
Moomin papa.
I'm snuffling.
Why don't you let the skunk go, it's a skunk.
Is it?
Stink, skunk, and he made those footprints.
How do you know that?
I happened to be in trouble at the beach late last night.
And I saw him creeping here.
ha Isu Li.
Why don't you come in, Stinkbug?
I'm fine here.
You were kind to make the footprints.
It's been so exciting for Papa.
But yes, I was able to work hard.
Making Onna's hooks is not easy.
You said that I'm yummy.
Dad, where are you going?
Not much anywhere.
What?
Mamma.
What now, papa?
I'll tell you a secret.
Should I sit down first?
I have made a firm decision.
Of course.
I'm running away on an adventure.
Are you going far?
It is a journey without a goal, full of setbacks and dangers.
And you come along.
Are all the children included or just the Moomin?
No children.
It wouldn't be an unusual life at all.
I'm thinking of running away.
I've always wanted to escape.
I will once again become the adventurer I was in my turbulent youth.
And when you're by our side, we'll experience romance and everything.
But what if Moomin gets angry?
And don't get angry.
Besides, it would be time for Moomin to gradually learn to take care of himself.
And grow into a man.
Come on mom.
Oh papa, wait.
We can't take any more stuff with us.
No no, but I forgot to leave a note where the sugar is.
Children can survive without sugar if they can't find it.
But then they can't bake crackers and the theme is terrible.
And they can't find cinnamon in the eternal world?
Those women, I wish we had gone alone.
Now let's think about cinnamon, when the familiar is calling.
An adventure isn't worth much if you can't tell from behind.
Huh, that was a lifesaver.
Dad, what else?
Nothing, let's go.
The day is dawning.
Let's go.
We have a long way to go.
That's right, let's let the feet take us where they take us.
My legs say this way.
Good morning, mom.
Is mom still sleeping?
What is it?
Father and mother are missing.
Have you searched?
I am.
That's it then.
I'm starting to get hungry.
So do I.
Don't cry, Goblin.
I'm pretty sure at least your mom will be back soon.
But where could they have gone?
Well, I guess they left a message.
Have you eaten yet?
I won't crumble.
I am alone.
The head can be a Moomin, Goblin.
You get these fish.
If you want, I'll come to the Moomin house to make them for you.
Just thanks for the offer, Nuuska-muikkunen.
But there are already two enthusiastic cooks in the kitchen.
It's fun when you can try on your own.
If you give me a taste of my sorghum, I'll give you a taste of your bun.
It's fine.
I am alone.
I'll taste you in your ass.
It's fine.
Which one are we in?
No idea.
It was dark everywhere.
The sun must have already risen. Why not get brighter?
From mamma, you see.
I'm afraid we're trapped.
What do you mean?
It's just that we've wandered into a whole network of caves.
Oh my, you burn it to the bottom.
Mind your own business, if I'm going to stick to burnt food.
There can be nothing worse than your first soup.
Phew, practice has made me an excellent cook.
Where is Moomin lurking anyway?
Moomin, whoa! Come and taste, come!
Mother! Father!
Huh?
What was that? Daddy, wake up!
Hey!
This is brackish water. The sea can't be far.
Huh?
A big fish.
I got you!
Moomin, what are you doing so far from home?
Daddy, look!
I caught a big fish. Mother, come quickly!
Don't let the fish get away.
I have never met such a big fish.
Me neither. Maybe dad will see.
Yes, papa. This is a Moomin trap. Looks kind of familiar.
Of course. We are at the mouth of the cave.
Eh, it could be prevented. I'm afraid your father cheated.
where is dad
That... Father went in search of adventures.
Where did he go?
I don't know exactly somewhere.
I would have liked to go along. When will dad come back?
He didn't say anything. Maybe he will come home in the evening.
Or tomorrow, or next week, or Christmas. Who knows?
Dad is currently experiencing some wonderful adventure. That's right.
Mom! Hi, where are you?
Mamma has disappeared.
Mamma!
Mom answers!
Oh edible sea.
Now this just...
This is it.
God forbid.
Dad is back.
Hey, daddy's back home.
What? What? What?
Good morning dad!
I'm home again.
Welcome home.
Thank you mommy.
How did the adventure go?
Unexpectedly. That's exactly what I would say.
Is there food?
There is! I would taste my sarsel.
My food is a four-star delicacy.
I'm hungry.
Tell us about your adventure dad.
Sometimes repeated. Were you in mortal danger?
How to understand that now?
Tomorrow papa doesn't seem to be able to talk about his adventure right away.
That was the end of Papa Moomin and Mama Moomin's escape.