It hadn't rained in Moomin Valley for weeks, and eventually the river dried up.
Dad said this is almost a disaster.
Uh, I guess not.
Well, ompa, Moominland is turning into a desert.
Moomin Falls is now turning into a desert.
I doubt it, it has been dry before.
There hasn't been a man to remember, something has dried up.
That's what I'm worried about. I can't fish anymore.
But I've noticed while traveling that dry times are always followed by wet weather.
At least for me, this air is too hot.
Huh, it's so hot, you can't even think.
I can always think.
Oh dear, even the weeds are dying.
The sea will never dry up.
Tampeli, where would the fish go?
I'm going swimming.
Oh, I got dressed.
Let's look at it.
What's that stupid box doing here?
It's always from somewhere far away.
Naur gets totta ja kiva.
Select your menu item.
Hi, he stayed so picsyn reik materiara.
What is it, a treasure chest?
Hardly a hit lady, it's not heavy enough for a treasure chest.
Let's open it.
Will you push the box ashore? Hey speed up!
I think it has jewelry.
Just not fruit.
What are they?
Seeds maybe.
What seeds?
I've never seen seeds like that.
I would say tropical plant seeds.
Really?
But what seeds?
Even a banana or a mango.
A banana?
Mango seeds.
Well, yeah, I haven't studied tropical tumors enough to be sure.
Mother, let's plant the seeds.
That's a good idea.
However, nothing grows from the seeds.
This is not a tropical climate.
I'm not so sure about that.
They may sprout, but that's about it.
This climate seems very tropical to me.
You can always try it.
I want to see what papaya looks like.
I want banana and mango to grow under my window.
Let's start planting.
Banana and mango are tropical or subtropical plants.
Mamma seems to be full of enthusiasm.
No fuss.
Maybe, but trying something new is always exciting.
Moomilaakso turns into a jungle.
Hey, Hemuli!
Hemuli, would these seeds grow into fruit trees?
Joo.
I'm not sure, little one.
I think this is a mango.
Well, thanks.
Why do you necessarily want to know?
Because I'm planting a secret garden.
And I don't want anything stupid to grow there, orchids, but mango.
Hemuli, what is a banana seed?
I'm not quite sure, but I thought it was this one.
Are you also planting an orchard?
I don't. I just want to plant a banana tree in the best place.
Banana is Moomin's favorite fruit.
There is no way a banana tree grows this far in the north.
Hey, is this air some kind of air from the north?
I can hardly wait for the sunset to cool off a bit.
It's wonderful to wait for sleep while looking at the stars.
And it's not so hot anymore.
I'll sleep like a log tonight.
Don't you always sleep like a log?
Tonight I sleep like a heavy log.
Well, my dear, why don't you sleep with the others under the tree?
Well, because you can't see the stars from there.
The stars twinkled so beautifully.
You'll get absolutely soaked if it starts to rain.
Mom, are you kidding me?
I really don't.
It hasn't rained in weeks.
The sky is full of clouds.
Yes, but the toothpicks fell on the floor and it predicts rain.
Mamma, the wet lady doesn't care, even if you get soaked through.
Oh why not?
Well, no, because if it rains, his Tree will start to grow.
That's true.
Good night everyone.
I'm sleepy.
Good night.
Don't snore at home.
Oh, it's too hot.
Why don't you go out and sleep?
Yeah, why not, to the hammock.
Thunder!
It's raining, toothpicks know.
Hello hundred, my orchard.
Moomin little one, wake up.
Is it morning?
The sun dazzled.
No, it's raining now.
Rain?
Just look?
When you look at it.
I don't want to get wet.
What a wonderful rain.
Wake up, wake up.
I don't want to get wet.
Sleeps like a princess.
Wake-up!
Is it raining?
Well, reel attention.
Mamma really knows a thing or two.
You know. Let's go inside.
Not yet. I want to feel the rain falling on me.
Someone, you've had enough of the rain.
Thanks.
Is he a rain chicken?
These are mangoes.
Out.
Through my tail.
Jungle, jungle.
Get up.
It's a jungle here.
We live in a jungle.
In the jungle.
Are you trying to claim that the seeds have already germinated?
Big trees have grown from them.
That's remarkable.
I'm going to the jungle to play tarzan.
My lettuce would grow just as well.
There is magic here.
Let's go explore.
The water is gurgling in the stream again.
Weird.
Get up, little one.
What has happened?
We sowed tropical plant seeds in the evening and a jungle grew out of them overnight.
The seeds must have been bewitched.
It looks amazing.
Shall we go on a safari in the jungle?
Never seen before.
What flower is that?
It looks like an orchid to me.
We have a real jungle here now.
Not exactly.
How so?
Well, in a real jungle there must also be wild animals.
Lions and elephants, of course.
Our jungle is a tropical botanical garden.
They are for Moomin.
He gets killed.
Stop it.
Don't mess around.
what you
Well where is it now?
What are you looking for?
My helmet.
Sorry what?
Heat on my helmet. I need you in the jungle.
Do we have one?
I wore it to a masquerade once and I know I put it in one box.
Here it is.
You look brisk.
That's the purpose.
God forbid.
Oh!
The helmet is a great invention.
Father.
What the hell are you doing?
I want to get to the basement.
For what?
To get my gun.
Only fools wander into the jungle without a gun.
I don't think you need a gun.
And why?
Because there are no wild animals.
There might even be an egg among the seeds.
They look animalistic too.
It's a strange animal.
I would rather say that there is a strange plant in it.
They have eyes.
Probably a carnivorous plant.
A carnivore.
Help! Stop helping!
They're trying to eat me!
Stay strong longer!
No!
They were cutting my tail off!
Thank you, Pikkumyy. You saved my life.
At least I saved your tail.
Hello! Hello!
Get something sturdy for the door!
Hurry up!
Whoa! Make it work!
Will they get through this?
They are not that strong.
You don't know that. They gripped him impossibly hard.
Is something wrong?
Hear it!
The basement is full of meat and plants that are trying to make mummipapa hot!
Oh horrible!
What now?
The basement leads directly to the kitchen.
Save mommy!
Oh!
That was spot on, Dad.
What the hell have you come up with?
We do nothing.
By the way, try grandma's recipe right now,
if you know how to get a tropical fruit.
Wake up.
By the way, try grandma's recipe right now,
if you know how to get a tropical fruit.
I don't think this is a tropical rain forest.
Transkendentia megaloides.
I dyspepsia floribunda.
I can gather tropical flora from here in mummy valley.
I estimate the garden spade.
Borrow from Grandma.
I must say that this family does not care about the broth order.
Ha ha ha.
Do I look funny?
Viirakonkoninga weather.
Tartsan has plumper muscles.
Tartsan loves Jane.
I'm disappearing.
Before I start attacking.
Ai!
Help! Muscles are growing on my heels.
What? Have there been more?
Oh!
They were in the basement.
Did you open the door?
I opened. I was going to borrow a shovel.
Listen Hemuli, since you know everything about plants,
maybe you also know how to get rid of carnivorous plants.
A botanist does not try to get rid of rarities,
but hearing music affects them.
Music?
Calling down, Nuuska Muikkunen.
They started dancing.
Call, Nuuska Muikkunen.
What if Nuuska Muikkunen quits?
I just don't know.
What's going on here?
They are even attractive when they are not in a bundle.
Just like that, a jungle grew up around the Moomin house overnight.
Does the jungle ask and what carnivorous plants do,
if Nuuska Muikkunen stops playing?