Lama, lama, la-la-la-la.
Hey, I'll start looking.
Quickly hide.
Not yet, snot-nosed kid.
You can't come yet. And not yet.
Let's wait.
Striker, this way.
Joo.
Stay tuned. I'll try.
Sell, you can't come. This is our hideout.
Don't take advantage. I came to it.
So I go?
Don't make a fuss about nothing.
Uh, I guess we have to give up.
Let's go somewhere else.
Where else?
And don't give up.
What would be a good hide?
Let's go there.
Clear.
Suddenly, suddenly. This is a good hiding place.
Oh, that's right.
Sell again. Go away.
Come on, and now fade away.
We have to run after us all the time.
What can I do if you want to hide the same thing all the time as I do?
The sniffer will find us if we don't hide already.
True. Go elsewhere.
Don't laugh what you somewhere else.
This is my and Nipsu's hiding place.
Huh? Unfair.
Shh, shut up. The snuff-muck can hear.
Stupid. As if they want to reveal that they have gone to the basement.
I suggest you find another hiding place. And suddenly.
When you recommend it.
We'll see the barrels at the gig.
Varukaa.
It was on point. It was.
I was startled wildly.
What now?
Help. The barrel starts the time machine.
They must be here.
I found you guys.
Weird. I could have sworn I heard their voices.
Hey.
Where are we?
What place is this?
Just some creepy place again.
Juukeli, what is our home here?
It looks like some kind of machine.
Can't hear. Let's go right back.
Shut up you jerk. Let's find out where we are and when.
But we still have to be careful. Isn't that right?
After all, we have a time machine that we can use to escape if there are hot spots.
Could it be that we have come to the future?
To the future?
The future may look like this. Maybe we'll start making wood again.
Yes, these are indeed strange machines.
Basic looking.
Let's explore them a little.
Hey, don't leave me here.
This looks like a studio.
I don't like those pictures.
Not even an artist, because he sewed them.
A painter must like what he has painted.
What are we doing in this room?
Looks like some kind of laboratory.
What is there?
The color suggests some kind of fruit juice.
Fruit juice? I taste.
Please don't.
I am very thirsty.
It smells awful.
Do you smell it too?
I smell.
What was it?
Nipsu, you need to be more careful.
It's true, Nipsu.
What happened to your face?
Just look at your own face.
Trinket girl, look at yourself.
So do you.
How can beauty thrive in the midst of this mess?
What beauty are you talking about?
The one who has eyes in front of you.
I'm completely covered in some kind of powder.
Oh my god my experiment.
It failed again.
This was already 100.8. times.
Why does this always have to happen to me?
Let's think that the biggest difference to these is that I constantly fail.
Where the hell is wrong?
Wait a minute! What's in it?
Could this be it?
This is what you thought.
This might be real gold.
The biggest difference is Bernard de la Pinche.
You won't be digging gold now.
Trinket lady, look what's in her hand.
That's my anklet that I just took off.
Sorry good sir.
Sorry, but the ring is mine.
who are you Where have you come from?
I want my gold anklet back right now.
Your ankle bracelet?
Ha, bailiffs. I don't understand.
What exactly is babbling?
So yes.
Look at this, dear bailiffs.
The biggest difference is that Bernard de la Pinche is this rich today.
Or upporikas?
As a great alchemist I have finally resolved,
how to turn lead into gold.
I'll pay it all back.
Herrada Pinche, we are not bailiffs.
You are not bailiffs.
It then means that you are tax bears.
It went wrong again.
What, don't you?
Only then I know. I know, I know, I know.
You have come to learn from Bernard de la Pinche, so...
Wrong.
Oh, for what the hell.
We have tried to explain,
you don't have that kind of thing back for you.
What? Oh, what object?
My anklet.
I took it out and put it on that table a moment ago.
In that case, the gold didn't come from my experiment either.
Well, not really.
Gold has never been born from the juice of any Korean-colored fruit.
I, the unfortunate one, failed again.
Don't go any further.
It is impossible to make gold from any other substance.
Thank you for those words.
Even geniuses needed comforting, although you are completely wrong.
By the way, who are you and where do you come from?
Hey!
He could have left me a little piece.
Stuck everything on his cheek.
How would you have been hungry for a long time.
Yes, Master Pinci is a painter.
But lately he has been experimenting.
And there hasn't been enough money for food.
And no one seems to be buying his paintings either.
Absolutely.
He calls himself a great genius.
But frankly, he's plain.
He's a genius.
The master is a great genius.
Great that you are defending your champion, but start looking at a new job.
My master is not bad-mouthed.
I can understand your feelings.
Believe it anyway.
The name of this painting is Mona Lisa.
And the duke has ordered it from the master.
Hey, the painting is really mediocre.
Not from much of anything.
The Master started it fifteen years ago.
So long ago.
Hey, what does that guy think he's doing?
Hoi, black!
Genius, stop cooking already and finish painting your board.
Dude, it's too late now.
How come?
In the meantime, the Duchess has grown old.
Not even a genius can paint him from memory.
There is always another model. Some young and beautiful girl.
Even hotter, I could use someone as a model.
Here would be one with a Turkish.
Where?
Right in front of your eyes.
Kaskunen didn't immediately catch my eye.
So yes.
The excellent model Mona Lisa is completed in that place.
This is a great honor.
You look exactly like a young Mona Lisa.
That man does not recognize true beauty, even though he is an artist.
Not going to be famous.
Good without moving. This puts me in a good mood.
Delightful. You are a great model.
Could you smile a little just like that?
Good.
A work of art that will live forever is getting ready.
Oh no. Smile, smile, smile.
Well, now the master continues his work.
Hustling like crazy. That's good.
Oh this joy. It's the first time I see a master painting so happy.
That's more fun than messing around.
No more finishing touches like this.
Is the painting finished now?
Can't move.
I have just finished the finest work of art of the century.
I wouldn't have been able to do this without her.
I would very much like to see the painting.
Oh luckily, let there be only a champion.
Will you bring the old lady?
Nothing. The appearance of one.
I want to see too. Shall I?
It doesn't remind me at all.
Not so. Niskunneiti looks quite different.
So about the face.
But I didn't mean to paint the face of the little girl.
But only his soul.
Ai.
Oh, I didn't know there was a soul before.
Hey, let's go back to Moominvalley.
I can't bear to watch this shit anymore.
Good lady. You may only see ruins.
But these widgets are the great inventions of a master.
Is this some kind of invention?
But what the heck is in the office?
I have to admit it's not finished yet.
I think that inventions must be ready.
Why don't we go home?
This is the machine with which you can travel from time to time.
So. My father built it.
Right. Then your father is also a great genius.
There is. Planning took ages.
For once your speech makes some sense.
Don't now.
Tell me why there is a clock face here?
It must not be removed.
You can't take it as a joke. Time to machine.
What if it breaks? What about us then?
Don't panic. Trust me. I'll separate it.
Now we might not make it back.
Hey master is going to break the time machine.
The keys separated it from the trick.
Oh horrible.
Oh, are you okay?
Was the master hurt badly?
What happened here?
It was an electric shock. The master was electrocuted.
I see. Or electricity. Electricity is produced with the help of a magnet.
Absolutely. If I use electricity, I can complete all my inventions.
I see. Here is the current approach and this turn should be connected to that pole.
This trick will eliminate all transmission problems.
And so I am on top of science.
Oh, the time machine seems to be from the past.
I don't understand anything he says.
This is the right part. Sorry. Could you borrow this for a moment?
What is it?
It looks like a huge bathtub.
It is for automotive, land, sea and air use.
Oh, nothing.
We want the time machine back to the way it was.
Yes, I know.
Oh, we trust him.
You have nothing to worry about, I'll fix the time machine even better.
Hmph!
What was it?
What exactly happened?
It's a burglar alarm.
Then you have thieves.
I'll go check.
It scares me terribly.
That's where those thieves are.
They visited the master's recent work.
Monoalisan vai?
That they dare.
The board must be recovered.
Not waiting.
Master, I'm going out for a moment.
What has happened?
Oh what happened.
Someone just stole the painting the master was so proud of.
Proud?
A master should not play in bathtubs. Did you hear?
My board was taken.
The curse of genius.
The thief is some jealous painter.
Listen master, something has to be done and quickly.
Don't jump.
This is the most welcome opportunity to chase thieves and test my car at the same time.
Don't stand there like a log.
Hop on board.
Does the tub even move?
Well, I'll tell you.
Maybe not anyway.
It works!
Help! Just jump in the tub! Help! Can you hear that?
Help! Help! Help!
This is fun. I drive the world to hell.
A brisk ride could be fun.
But weren't we supposed to catch the board thieves?
You are right. I really wanted to come here.
Well done boy. I'll take the reins now.
Tartu kepälän!
Ven champion!
Six! Six!
The thieves turned to the alley!
So they turned. I saw.
Well, the cancellation was successful.
That's where the thieves are.
Speed up!
Let's catch up!
What?
Get the rag off your face and quickly!
The river is ahead!
Short!
Six!
Look what's down there!
Wise thieves planned everything in advance.
We almost caught them.
We'll get them!
Don't be sad! This situation is no problem for Bernaduda pintz.
Look!
Shall we go in the water?
Stop! I don't like the river and I don't like water in general!
Crazy!
Moomin!
What if this went wrong?
Go now!
A Moomin would laugh at that blue obscenity.
Is this it?
Very inspiring!
The vest is the biggest difference!
Now you see my invention in the right light!
Crazy!
Where are the thieves headed now?
Pick up the pace!
Trying to escape. Now seems to be the right time.
Suitable for what?
Moomipeiko won't you pull the red vivo now?
Clear! From red!
Pick up the pace!
Hey look!
Bernarduna Pinchi did what I expected.
Flying in the air is fun!
I feel like a bird.
Let's hope the cart doesn't break when we land!
I have painted the most beautiful picture in the world,
built the world's first land in water
and airborne.
I have painted the world's first on land in water
and a means of transportation moving in the air and thanks to you.
It was just a pleasure to be of help,
but the master will fix the time machine.
That we can get home again?
What? What the hell time machine?
Don't pretend!
No, I'm faking it!
You can stay as my apprentice!
Where have they gone to hide?
Now I'm going to look for it.
Hey, we're home!
What is hiding?
I found you all.
Hello, Snuska-muikkunne!
How did you find that?
Don't you remember, we play hide and seek, do you get bored?
Well, it was, and we had to go into hiding.
I had forgotten it all along!
I must admit that Bernardo da Pinci was no mean talker.
He even knew how to fix his father's time machine and just playing.
Such was the great genius.
What makes you laugh so much?
Now I imagine myself in the world's most famous painting.
Naturally.
Hey hey hey!