Oh hell!
Ai, ai, ai, ai!
Hey!
Hi, hi, hi!
Come help!
Ai, ai, ai!
Sai!
Ohoho!
What is it!
What is auntie?
Ouch, that hurts!
The witch arrow struck!
You have to take care of yourself.
I'm trying to travel to the bottom of the trunk, which is too heavy for my strength.
Bad back, you shouldn't have carried it.
Your back can be done for good today.
We help as long as you ask.
Excellent, then bring the trunk to my side.
All right, I'll take it.
It weighs terribly, what's there?
The coffin has expired.
It is, and it's the old stuff in the bottle.
All the memories from my dear Sulhonen's and my many trips abroad have been collected in it.
Yeah, I don't have many memories.
Please open the chest.
Oh, what a lot of rubbish.
They may look like junk, but to me each item is a precious memory of my Fiance and happy times past.
Oh, how sweet.
what is today
Leather, we once caught a venomous snake in Africa.
Do you care?
Oh, Traveling was my whole life.
If only I could one more time.
Oh, yes you can, as long as your back heals first.
Can't get better without a secret medicine.
I have strong doubts about that.
What medicine is that?
And where do you get that medicine?
Ah, if only I could remember, that medicine sparkles beautifully.
A drug that sparkles?
I like shiny things.
Quietly!
Does auntie remember what kind of sparkling medicine it was?
Oh, how romantic.
My memory has become very fragile.
I think of a twinkling star somewhere in Asia or South America.
It probably was.
Just like that.
You promised to help me, remember that?
Yes, yes, but...
Aunt Jenni looks so tired.
We'd better leave him alone for a while.
This created a puzzle. What are we doing?
Aunt has become a child.
Oh, oh, Moominpappa has fallen into the wrong hands.
At least I don't know the sparkling star medicine.
And rubbish Aunt Jenni is an old fool.
I would like to help aunt.
But if he doesn't remember more, it's hard.
Ah, that's about it.
Nuskamoikken, what are we doing?
Could it be this?
What?
What do you mean?
Hey, look at the glitter.
Oh, boys, stars!
Amazingly beautiful.
Phew, the reflection of the stars!
And the water is just river water.
And it won't change.
I don't understand how Sanko can heal Aunt Jenni.
I don't understand too much.
Hey, Nuskamoikkunen came up with a better answer.
Something that sparkles.
Once upon a time, perhaps a hundred million years ago,
stars often fell to the ground.
Much more often than nowadays.
That's what I've heard it said.
Oh, a hundred million years ago!
Then it's clear.
Thank you, Nuskamoikkunen!
Hi, what happened to you?
You mean if we go in a time machine
far enough into the past,
we can collect star pieces from the ground.
Absolutely!
A medicine that sparkles and sparkles.
Oh, how romantic.
Good, let's go then!
Sound!
Let's go then!
What exactly happened?
I don't know.
The time machine started as if by itself.
What was that sound?
At least I heard Moomin scream.
The sound came from the basement.
What what?
The time machine is gone.
I guess it's not just Moomin who has gone there.
Yes, and where has he gone?
Help!
Where are we?
Beautiful star flights.
Looks great!
Is this just an order?
Rhino!
What makes the rhinoceros gallop Tuomainen?
I can guess!
Varukaa!
Help!
Volcano Eruption!
Beautiful!
The star flies fiery red.
Let's stop stargazing!
If a star strikes us,
we will be flat as a flat!
Sound!
We will be flat as a flat!
At least we don't get stars from here!
Hold on!
You hurry! You hurry!
Sound!
Quick deposit!
You hurry, you hurry!
You hurry!
Sender of the Snowman!
The sender of the snowman?
Hi, you're so white! You remind me of a wild snowman!
And I'm a charming snow queen, am I?
So when you start to feel like you're so excited, you're so silly!
Ah, food!
Tasty, but cold!
Slips, don't bother! It's never so cold that you don't like food!
It just makes me wonder what we've gotten ourselves into.
We may have entered an ice age!
Ah!
What was that sound?
There it is!
Lumimies!
Help! The snowman is coming!
No!
Hey, don't leave me!
Please help us!
Open the doors!
Please be kind and help!
Snowman, eat us now!
Help, help!
Snowman, eat us!
Let's break down the door!
Now!
Oh!
Apparently, our dishes have been suitable for a snowman.
So you're not snowman messengers, are you?
Certainly not!
Snowman, why did you bring us here?
Yes, why?
It might have been a bad idea, but I have a feeling that the snowman will lead us to something Dazzling.
To the glittering one?
What exactly?
Quick!
You came to us from heaven!
Are you messengers of the stars?
Oh, messengers of the stars!
Oh, how romantic!
I'll give you some advice!
Stop whining!
You must have come to save our village!
So it must be!
Save us from the clutches of the snowman!
Are we saviors?
Yes, but...
The Snowman has been rampaging here for years!
Unless we offer him Antim, he threatens to destroy our village!
We live in constant fear!
How on earth could we small and helpless people do anything?
You are looking for a shining star!
They say the Snowman has a star that can destroy our village in the blink of an eye!
Is it the same star you are looking for?
Would you mind?
It must be Aunt Jenni's returning star!
It is very possible, but how do we get the star?
I think we should at least try to help the villagers!
Good luck with your business!
You can come along! Not much use to you, but better!
I won't come! I don't want to be eaten!
I trust you! Remember to be careful!
Good luck!
Those who wish us luck, but don't understand how we feel.
You can always beat it!
They even said that we might never come back.
Don't always be so pessimistic and negative about everyone!
The Moomin troll is our refuge, and you are not.
Miss Nisku, you are a jerk!
I'm careful! It's slippery!
You should have said it earlier!
Stop me!
Oh horrible!
Nipsut
What a bitch!
Oh, what a hoot!
Edifice!
A real castle! Oh, there could be a charming prince living there!
Christmas man probably! And the castle is full of chains and prisons!
Well, I don't mind going to the castle.
You are allowed to leave!
What for? We're going to the castle!
Phooey!
It's too late to live now!
Oh, we're high!
Yay, let's restart.
What if the foot gets wet?
I have lypeiko being restarted!
What?
What is it?
I didn't do anything!
What a hurry!
What's the hurry?
Go all out!
Hurry now!
What the hell is going on here?
What happens now?
Johan, now it's strange!
We're going down!
Vuvi, Pekka, what are you on your way to?
I don't know!
Somewhere!
Up!
Are you all right?
Don't look down!
Alas!
Now we're going up!
Vuvi, Pekka, help!
Don't scream, just climb!
That's the point!
Slip, do something!
Be brisk and active!
Wow, Pekka!
Go all out!
Where are you?
How have they been?
Have they derailed in that broth?
Of course they aren't!
But...
We can't stay here!
We need to find Pekko and the little girl!
Oh my!
Wait!
Are Nipsu and myi safe?
I suppose so!
There's the star the villagers were talking about!
I guess so!
You finally found your way here!
Help!
Help, luvibies!
You guys look delicious!
I'll enjoy you for dessert!
Muvi Pekka, help me!
Help me, Muvi Pekka!
I dare you to stop touching my little girl!
No, it was the sound of a deer!
What are you trying?
There's news!
What on earth?
Hennona now had such huge amounts of food!
I imagined you were tall,
but you're a jerk!
Forget about appearance,
but you were brave
when you dared to come here.
You're a hearty beauty, Maiden.
It's also so guarded.
Are you keeping us in your stomach now?
I like that style.
Oh right?
Maybe you're not that stupid
than I thought.
He is stupid!
You obviously don't know retail yet.
Quietly!
Oh, is your name little shop?
Please stay with me!
If I threaten the villagers,
we get exactly what we want.
Please stay!
Well, let's hear it!
And you don't keep the villagers in a state of fear anymore!
Are you really a snowman?
Do you live alone?
I live!
I found this castle,
but I had no food and I was hungry.
So that I...
You always go to the valley
and you demand treats from the villagers!
i have to say
that taking food without working
is indecent.
He snipsu!
You promised anything, I'll take the star!
Oh no, if you take it, castle gnome!
You promised anything!
Anything?
Watch out, castle gnome!
What now?
I didn't do it!
You pushed me...
Everyone get out of here!
Wait!
Don't leave me alone!
Start!
The castle crumbles to nothing but dust!
It's no use trying to pretend to be a snowman now
and threaten others!
You get to start working
for the benefit of the villagers.
Do you have to?
Nipsu sometimes speaks sense!
Am I talking?
Hihihihihi!
Are you going back to heaven?
Yes, we found the cure.
We're in a hurry, better or worse.
I could still stay here, but...
Ah, ah, ah, ah, asiuuu!
It's way too cold here.
Hihihi, start telling the story that messengers from the stars saved your village.
That's what we do.
Goodbye, Little Myy.
Goodbye.
And permit man, please remember your own.
Be well.
Bye!