All last week, the wet lady had been lounging on the couch reading fairy tales, but that day Moomin finally got her out.
Yes, fairy tales always win.
You're glad you came along, niiskunnie.
Moomin, look! Alpine star!
Alpine stars don't grow here. It can't possibly be an alpine star.
It's an alpine star like in little Heidi.
It's not humid.
Oh let's go pick it up.
Don't go, it's dangerous.
You get to pick it up.
It's just a white anemone.
A clear alpine star appeared. I want me to pick for me.
You could try down there, but the alpine star is not a flower. Alpine star grows in the Alps.
It's an alpine star.
Carefully.
Fairy tales don't care about dangers.
That's why they are called fairy tales.
Beautiful princess, accept a humble gift from the worshiper.
This good you will be thought of. Voisi is not an alpine star.
What did I say? It's not easy to get down from here.
Aren't we going back to where we started?
I think that's the easiest way to get down.
You could be right.
At least this route is shorter.
And easier too.
I am frankly surprised that you are such an agile climber.
Oikoninkalians are agile wherever they go.
So when you don't shut up.
How many emmies are there in this flower?
One, two...
Good lord, a snowball in the middle of summer.
Well, it doesn't move the horticulturist.
Let's count now. One, two...
Have you ever seen a lady like that?
Well, I don't. That just left a size snowball.
That was when Miss.
Not when the lady is made of snow.
Niis this is a neiti.
Weapons are nice.
Thank you beautiful. He breathes.
He just got a kick and passed out.
Moomin, what happened to him?
He bought the wrong way.
What are you trying to do?
Money him home to mom.
Heavy, sturdy tulle.
Maybe he will if we pour cold water on his face.
How do we get water here?
Tear off that fallen birch tree and make a cap.
Clear. So I was looking after a lady at that time.
Niis kun neiti, hoi!
Cold.
Did he wake up?
No.
Good, he's off duty.
Is everything alright then miss?
How do you feel?
Where am I?
In the lonely mountains.
Who am I?
Well, the princess of the lonely mountains.
Oh princess?
Well, of course.
who are you
Prince of the Lonely Mountains.
What?
Such a ridiculous looking prince.
You are a teddy bear.
And I'm not.
Don't laugh, Kallirenki.
Yes?
So when the lady has lost her memory.
It's not, he pretends.
There is no whispering in the company of Kunin Kalliste.
Excuse me, Your Highness.
Oh, you poor bastard.
Your castle, princess, good.
Oh, the royals don't live in heckles.
But then, miss.
Fool, don't use that dreaded name.
Sorry, princess.
My real castle is elsewhere, isn't it?
That could be a hunting lodge.
Absolutely.
That's what it is.
Good. I can accept that.
Let's go.
I can accept that.
Well, what are you staring at?
Courtier, send the Maid to my room.
Camarinate?
And what did that courtier mean?
Speak up.
Dad, have you seen my aunt?
I am.
He's become a chump.
Mom, would you like to talk to my cousin?
Are you in conflict?
Emme.
But my mother has got it into her head that
she is a princess.
Ai.
Oh, Nanette.
Come here.
Vai Nanette.
I am a Moomin.
Let's stop this name mess.
You are Nanette.
Ai.
It hurts.
Oh, my swan and crown embroidered nightgown.
How's your little sister doing?
Otherwise fine, but he's imagining things
being a princess.
Could it be dangerous?
I don't think so.
I called her princess,
but only in my play.
Glad you didn't coloraturate as a soprano.
So is my mother sleeping?
I wore crowns and swans in embroidery
in a nightgown, but now
so my mother wants to go to bed
of baltakin.
What is it?
A bed canopy with a canopy stretched over the posts
and tassels in the corners.
So my mother got nervous when
the baltakini was not ready.
As long as tomorrow morning
wakes up, his memory has been able
to return, and no baltakin
then no longer needed.
Let's hope for the best.
What if his memory is not
back?
We'll see then.
Baltakins are hardworking.
Let me try.
Trying what?
How?
As soon as my mother remembers who I am,
then everything else comes back to his mind.
Sell, listen.
He doesn't even remember me.
How would I remember you?
Because you can't forget me.
That's true.
Sleeps like a log.
Glad we did though
baltakine. It seems
wonderful.
He opens his eyes.
Are you awake?
Up, then, ma'am.
Shall we go to the beach?
Who is that person?
You have to remember.
I bit you yesterday.
Terrible fun.
Do you remember me?
Of course I remember.
What did I say?
I am...
My other courtier, of course.
You are such a fool of yours.
Better than that fatter jester.
Better?
he i, ha Isu Li.
What things do you move with?
Moomin has invited me
here to propose to a princess.
Even the Moomin has squealed.
There must be a point of comparison for us.
That what?
Are you there?
my competition matches or?
Yeah, Kosia has to answer
actually that
I have winked.
I've winked.
The suitor must answer correctly
to three questions to get the princess
and half the kingdom.
Not at all original.
Exciting.
Is the kingdom worthy?
The first competition
to try their luck.
I'm going.
Good day, princess.
Is that person
Kosia?
Yes, princess.
He did not greet me properly.
I'm sorry
your royal highness,
but this Kosia is
a foreign countryman.
Just like that, maybe from a strange country.
It's good to prepare
to the first question.
It's not difficult.
Yellow with four legs,
who sings.
What is it?
Kannaria bird.
Who has four legs.
I don't know any four footed bird.
Who said it's a bird?
What is the correct answer,
get down?
Let him be public.
Slap him on the spot
knock out.
The stresses of the trip have taken their toll on Kosia
temporarily out of business.
Hey, wait a minute!
You're out of my way, but Niskuneiti is.
What is the correct answer?
It's none of your business.
I believe you are of low birth.
Sorry you have to put up with this.
A funny looking young man.
I have the honor to close
to popularity.
For him I must
questions.
I ask you,
what is the number that
i think
Two.
Well done, brave knight.
Next you may need a word,
which is just on my mind.
Love.
Amazing.
This Kosia is indeed
knowing face.
You will hear the third question.
I have two figures in mind.
Two.
Was that right too?
No.
Correct chapter 22.
I should have said
that the answer was correct.
The young man was very kind.
Now it's your turn, skunk.
I saw the princess
and you half the kingdom.
What if the memory of the fallen
not coming back?
Yes it will come back.
He does not match the image of Nicosia.
His heart
Hug and pay attention to them.
Well, just like that.
Well, that's the first question.
What a number
I'm just thinking?
Stupid question from Samper.
Time passes, time passes.
no ha
Six.
I intend to figure 3 million
598.765
Ai.
Hi vi, Nikos already.
This is not fair.
Outrageous, head off.
Another stupid question.
Just go home.
Kill half the kingdom.
Oh, what a rude way to propose.
I'm not in the mood to get married.
An excellent idea, Your Highness.
I reject the remaining suitors with sadness.
Please tell me to come home.
Yes, Your Highness.
You are the kind knowing you who feel miserable.
From now on, I dedicate it to good work.
Hey!
Whoah! Now, what kind of excellent little girl has she got on her head?
He meditates upstairs and intends to devote his life to higher things.
Like worth what?
Niskunneiti dedicates herself to good deeds.
He obviously wants to enter the pages of history.
Shhh! He's coming down.
May I assist your excellencies here?
At that time, a young lady came to me.
Your maid is busy.
Someone else could make the soup nutritious, but not great.
Do you agree?
That's right, Narini.
I'm going to distribute it to the poor of mummy valley.
What kind of deal?
I don't know.
Keep eating and cooking.
The poor are fine with whatever the princess is willing to bring them.
Niskunneiti wants to catch up.
The poor don't eat much. This is perfectly fine.
I don't know anyone as poor in these lands as your highness.
The poor are the backbone of the kingdom.
What, hovinarini.
What now?
I take soup to the poor, which I have prepared with my own tender fingers.
Where are they?
Oh, the poor! I tell you what.
That's good. Oh, lead me now the poor life of the kingdom.
All right, princess.
That house!
It's nice to know that the poor in my kingdom are so well off.
Oh you there. Please come here.
Who is there?
A lonely night princess.
One moment, Your Highness.
Don't make me wait.
I'm coming, I'm coming.
I beg your pardon, Your Royal Highness.
What the hell is that swamp lady?
That mean-spirited name. I'm a princess.
It would probably make you feel better when you come here as one of the better ones.
Or my betters? Are you the queen?
I'm Mrs. Vilijonkka. what do you want
I'm just doing my royal duty.
By bringing comfort to the poor of the kingdom.
Here, eukko parka.
How dare you call me poor.
You who don't even own a sweater.
The intoxicating smell of sopa has apparently thrown you off your tracks.
Eat your soup yourself!
Fraud! I want to guard, so Pertuska will take me here right away.
I don't see, I don't see. I don't see anything, I don't see anything.
That's right for you, niiskunkunnie.
Wet!
Don't use that name again! Don't, don't!
Stand your ground your highness.
Don't, don't, don't, don't, don't, don't, don't!
Don't, don't, don't, don't, don't, don't!
Stand your ground, Your Excellency.
Knock him down.
Bowl and catch up now.
It is.
Oh, light up the royal hippie.
I will free Niiskuneidin. Now I strike.
Little sell don't. My precious family will be shattered into a thousand pieces.
I'm thinking of Niiskunneidi's day thief.
Don't get stabbed, release me.
Clear!
Oh, it's so humid.
You shouldn't have hit that hard.
You don't know that. I've never helped a broken soup bowl before.
Is everything all right, Your Highness?
My Lord.
Would cold water help with this?
Mrs. Niiskunne hates it. Niskunkunnemi.
I don't think he'll wake up eleme talk to him your highness.
My Lord.
Here it comes!
Now he wakes up.
It's fun that the princess is with us again.
Does it hurt your highness?
Oh, where am I?
Uh, where else but on the ground?
Come on, I thought I was hiking in the lonely mountains with Moomin.
Niiskunnen, you remember me.
What do you mean, are you screwed?
Niiskunneiti is normal again.
How so again? I've been normal all my life.
Yes, of course, Niiskunneiti gold nub.
We are happy for you.
All's well that ends well.
How did it end well, all is well? I don't understand.
Five, that's all we were afraid of was that you hurt yourself when you fell.
That's how Niiskunneidi's short princess career ended.
Everyone was extremely relaxed.