The temperature in Moominvalley is usually sub-zero, but sometimes it gets too hot.
The Moomin troll is coming!
Let's dive marshmallow lady!
Wow! Or did you think they could leave without me?
Glad you noticed the note on its door.
Why didn't you tell me you were going to the beach? It took me an hour!
Sorry my, papa decided to leave suddenly.
Snap decisions are disgusting.
I know, I know, but when I went to write my memoirs in the morning, not a single thought flashed into my head.
Of course, this rarely happens, but then the only salvation is to go to the sea.
The sea soothes and reminds me of the adventures of my youth.
Continue the story you started.
Do you want to hear?
I think it's fun to figure out what's true and what's false.
What do you mean? It's all true!
All true, sweetie!
Except for minor details.
Tell me more!
Oh tell me!
Can I hear too?
Well, if everyone wants to.
Hurrah!
I don't object, even though there is no one like me in the memoirs.
This time there is a small sale.
Is there?
There is. This happened a day after I had foolishly saved Torpokodi with the headmistress.
Sting and burn! The day is half over! Up, up!
Wake up lazy, Jaakko! Up, hosuli, now!
Don't freak out!
Now you can forget all your troubles, because I will take care of you and the ship.
Look how outrageous the cover is.
You are hogging it to the customer.
Listen.
What? Are you talking to me?
The cover is not dirty, it has a protective layer.
Bosh! Don't try to deceive me?
Bosh!
likely mechanism
Yes
you guys
J great
pala
stay
And no hiccups, and no trouble cooking.
Come down!
You are cooking the ones, go away!
Number 13 is about to start, stop!
Get your sticky paws off my shirt!
Where are you taking me!
Disconnect, disconnect and apologize immediately!
Rude behavior!
Great women, no fear!
After all, I am the headmistress of the Löyska orphanage.
Did you hear?
Aren't you going to save him, Moomin?
Everyone has to look fate in the eye at some point.
Wise talk.
But maybe, on the contrary, sticky paws should be saved from aunt's claws.
How do you, Hosuli Parka, manage to sleep among that scum?
Don't deface my property.
Too hard platform. I would like a soft mat.
Fredricksson, why do you have a mast but no sail?
I thought a ship should have a mast.
I'll definitely be planning an Amphib next.
Amphibin?
Amphibin is a craft that moves in air and water and on land.
No, would you rather be an adventurer or an inventor?
Well, it's clear to figure it out.
What is this now?
Hosuli, wake up and watch.
What?
I can't see anything.
There seems to be something strange in the bow.
Oh well, yeast.
What is it? It looks like a cloud. Is it?
On.
What does it show?
It looks like a cloud. Is it?
This is the softest mattress of my life.
Was it the same cloud that came from the Magician's hat?
It must be.
Don't bounce.
Something terrible can happen if you fumble that hard.
Don't be afraid, Hosuli. Try it yourself. It feels fun.
What did I say?
What the hell. We move.
Hey, look.
The situation seems threatening.
A severe storm is coming.
Because of that, the sticky paws ran away and the cloud...
Prepare for the worst.
Hey!
The machine is too weak.
Help!
We are above the waves.
Oh, Huumi, look at the mast.
Frerriksson, the cloud has turned into a sail.
What?
I hadn't planned this.
Frerriksson, now you already have an amphibian.
I can't believe this is true.
Wake up!
Oh, beautiful.
Oops, the cloud is tearing.
It took as long as it needed to.
A friendly cloud.
Everyone in their own places, we do a forced landing.
Hello, land in the rocks!
There!
I hope we don't bump into each other. I can't steer.
Hey!
We are going to the mountain.
Don't worry. Hold on.
Hey!
We just managed to land.
Pahtia, Hosuli.
It doesn't work for you.
I'll definitely take the booth.
Jump.
I said it's okay.
What if someone steals my jar for that time?
Who would steal it?
Those who live here.
Although hardly.
The island is apparently uninhabited.
Why has a stone wall been built here?
I don't know. I'll have to ask someone in the back.
Sell. Then we met one who had appeared as you.
Like me?
Is there someone there?
There is no one at home.
Remarkable. So who just answered?
Go your way. This is how you can open the door when mom is gone.
But you already half opened it.
Which girls are you?
Mymmel's daughter.
No wonder he reminded you of Myy.
For she was the mother and almost as small as you.
Where is your mother anyway?
He went to the king's feast.
What king is that?
Why didn't mommy take you with her?
Because I'm naughty.
Oh how naughty?
I always narrate.
You also practiced the fact that there is no one at home.
I can't do anything to my character.
You guys look funny. Come join the party.
To a party? I've never been to a party.
But what does your mother say to that?
Remember you told me to stay home.
He immediately forgets everything he has said.
Is that a lie too?
What do you say, Hervikson?
Let's just go. I have never met a king before.
Do you think we'll get a chance to greet the king?
Certainly.
Unhappy me. I don't even know how to address the king.
What does he look like?
He is terribly old and wrinkled.
I don't imagine the king like that.
Just don't believe a word that girl says.
This is where we enter.
What does that sign say?
King's party!
Everyone is welcome to celebrate our 100th anniversary.
A big surprise party.
Don't panic if something happens.
A surprise party.
Don't be scared. Terrible things happen there.
I tell you what. At least it will be fun.
Many guests have disappeared completely.
Did you hear that, Moomi?
You said you shouldn't trust the girl.
I'm not sure.
Now he left a little.
Let's run away.
Skinned.
Aha. Just as I thought. Artificial.
The legs are steel springs and the eyes are flashbulbs.
Did you freak out?
Who spoke?
Why are you delaying? Hurry up. There is water here.
I want to know whose voice it was.
Forget it and paddle carefully forward.
Careful paddling. This doesn't help.
More horrors, eh?
Fountain.
Now you've passed.
Bad voice. Pasta, who are you.
How far is the party?
Another surprise. Mechanical Bull.
Someone thinks that we can get high with just about anything.
Who's Afraid of the Mechanical Son?
Please wait for me.
You didn't expect this.
Who is there?
Hurry up.
Oh poor.
Is there paper pulp?
You're almost there faster.
The sound comes from that horn.
It's a loud sound.
Loud sound.
The scares are now over and the joyful part of our celebration can begin.
The sound comes from that horn.
It's a loud sound.
Loud sound.
The festive fireworks are starting!
Big party.
They are. You will get to many more parties.
Can I have some pie?
Yes, please.
Does the juice taste good too?
Yeah, thanks.
Well girl, show him where your mother is now.
There he is.
That big round one with the same hair cycle as me.
Is that old man with the crown a king?
He just.
I wouldn't believe it.
He is not too precious. Let's stay more distant.
Come on, no one here is afraid of the king.
Hey mom!
There you are.
New friends!
They look like new.
Good day your majesty and congratulations on your anniversary.
We come from far across the seas.
I'm Fredikson, I'm an inventor by profession.
And this is how...
And you are Moomi, the adventurer.
On the other side is Juxu and that other one must be Hosuli.
That voice!
I've been watching you for a while now with a telescope.
It was very interesting.
But now to more serious matters.
We consider you worthy citizens of our kingdom
and thus, by royal proclamation, you will remain on our island.
Great honor for us!
Hey Fredikson, I already gave the order to move your ship here.
Meren huskeenko?
Absolutely. I want you to keep inventing in our surprise park.
No crazier.
What about our adventure, Fredikson?
We can go on an adventure whenever we want.
This is how I build the Amphib here.
Moomi, Hosuli and Juxu can settle wherever they want
and build houses for themselves.
Oh, build?
Great declaration isn't it?
That's right people. The grand style celebrations continue.
.
I am I want to get and I am I want to get and I am to get and I am to get.
I built my house by the sea and the sea spray control core became the ground floor.
There I lived by myself.
How was Hosul?
Well, of course he was still in the coffee can.
So what happened to you?
Well, after the king owned both the ship and its captain, I couldn't move anymore.
No adventures!
What?
Prolonged living in the house.
You must have been listening with your mouth and not your ears open.
A settled life does not offer any kind of excitement.
But the house was not ordinary. It was haunted houses every night.
Nope.
Tell me about it!
I might not want to hear it next time.
Can't stop like that!
Wow, now I feel the call to the horizontal position.
And Moominpappa went to Nokos when he noticed that he had aroused the listeners' interest again.
What's wrong with keeping your audience in suspense?