Moomin is fast asleep. So are Moominpa and Moominma.
Moomins are so sensible that they always sleep all winter.
Their ancestors centuries ago did the same and the Moomins are tradition lovers.
However, something unprecedented is happening now. Moomin wakes up and never sleeps again.
What time is it?
17 more than two evenings during the day, I think. Although it doesn't matter when you hibernate.
The clock has stopped.
Cold and dark.
Mom, mom please get up.
Father, father.
Mom, mom, I woke up suddenly and I can't sleep.
It's strange, you shouldn't wake up from hibernation.
Dim, dim, Corona stopped talking, 张國式力力
J
Oh, snow, the Moomin House is buried in the cinemas.
This is not Moomin Valley.
Mouse quiet.
What is it?
Maybe I should go back home.
No, it's even worse at home when everyone is asleep and the furniture is dusty.
If only snuff Muikkunen were here, but he's far in the south.
Sound.
What the hell is that sound?
Then you plunged like a whirlwind towards me.
Yes, I know that, Tollo.
But what do you do for a living? Why don't you hibernate like everyone else?
I don't know. I just woke up.
Why are you going down the slide? You yourself should be sleeping.
I also woke up at times, apparently so that I could shepherd you.
I tried to wake up my sister too, but she just snored. I like snow.
I don't. It's cold and slippery and too white and quiet and there's snow everywhere.
I saw the grunt.
Oh that creepy creepy monster.
Mörö should feel at home in this weather.
By the way, Mörkö was on the mountain.
Then I heard a grumpy voice.
Frame! Mörkö is so freezing cold that I didn't even want to bite into it.
There's a puddle over there.
I got chills.
It's natural in a snowstorm.
The grub gave me chills.
Look at my skin. It looks different than in summer. Doesn't it look like it?
But my cold is not caused by the snow, but by the sleet.
I'm afraid too.
It tasted good.
I'll drink as much as you want.
Last summer, my mother and I collected more baboons than ever before.
Thanks.
Help me get that down.
A silver tray?
So.
For what the hell?
That I can count even a hill in that game.
The tray is our family treasure.
Which you never use.
A polished tray is much better for rioting than Hutera's cardboard box.
They sleep like April honey.
I still think it was terribly unfair that I woke up.
What do we do now?
I'm going to see the sea.
Do not! At least there is no snow on the sea.
Isn't it okay to leave it to the lady?
Jumpers
What's wrong now?
I forgot the tray.
What do you need it for now? There's no point in it.
Oh yes it is.
What do you mean?
Now you can see the sea.
My beautiful Sea is frozen.
You can glide over the sea.
What is that?
I feel it.
Tuttik!
What! How are you?
Aren't you hibernating too?
Before. I haven't had time to sleep in months.
Little mye and I just woke up. And we couldn't think of anything to do.
Use your imagination.
Let's try.
I have never seen an ice-free sea before.
Have you made a horse?
I am.
Can I ride a horse?
You can't. I have molded a horse for the ice lady.
Oh for the sake?
I guess you've heard of the ice lady?
It's me. She is very beautiful, but whoever looks into her eyes turns to ice.
Mrs. Ice is a badass.
It is. And spring won't dare to come as long as the ice lady is here.
Will that ice lady ride this horse on her way?
At least I hope so.
He squares north.
And then he doesn't come back until the following winter.
The horse doesn't look very sturdy.
So. That's why I lied with the horse's water.
The frost makes it rock hard.
Well, when will the ice lady come?
I don't know. Tonight maybe.
The weather seems to be getting colder.
Tuutikki, what has happened to the sun?
When will it appear?
The sun is now in the south and warms up the snuff from the muikku.
But soon it will come back and will be visible a little longer every day.
Good.
But tonight is the full moon. Admire its glow.
Humdinger. Then I see get the tray.
Which tray?
Moomin mamma on a silver tray.
Attach a sail to it and then sail with it on the ice.
Leave it for tomorrow.
I don't leave anything for tomorrow that I can do today.
Ice can suddenly melt.
I like this apartment.
Especially from colored window panes.
Papa has built a bathroom.
He will be happy to hear that you live here.
Our papa is so clever.
He creates a swimming room that is suitable even for winter use.
Mother will probably say.
Aren't you hibernating too?
Doesn't fade away.
Creepy ice grass is coming.
If he looks at you, the eyes will go away.
Moomin week! Tuttik! Listen!
Hit it! Muumiveikko!
Sell! We are here!
What the hell are you doing there?
Tuutikki is here fishing.
He is going to cook us dinner.
Then I'll start the ice pick immediately.
I'm going to see what Myy is doing to mom's tray.
Just go.
Uh, the fish eats.
Uh, ran away.
Oh boys, it's cold under the ice.
How is it going little Myy?
Yes, this is going to be a dick.
Why is it possible to be under the ice?
I guess that's because the water is low.
Why does ice sink?
The ice does not sink because it is attached to the shores.
I would guess so.
Well, there is an explanation.
Tuutikki eats fish soup every single day.
I'm going to see if the horse is frozen.
Don't miss the tail Ove.
I don't think it's strong enough.
The horse will surely break if the ice screw tries to ride.
It suddenly got freezing cold.
Bogey.
Don't just say you want to ride.
You better not try.
The horse is meant for the ice lady.
No one can say what the ice lady does, but she probably looks into the eyes.
The ice lady seems to be too much for the grunt.
The horse has turned into ice.
Wasn't it wonderful?
It was. The old tray is absolutely useless.
Will you give it a try?
I'm too heavy.
Coming in already. Fish soup is ready. It doesn't taste cold.
Hot fish soup. I'm leaving again.
Don't you?
And why?
Don't you remember? I told him that the ice lady can come.
It happens.
But I want to see him. I'm not scared at all.
I can be careful-
Sell. What if he looks you in the eye?
I won't let him meet my gaze.
What if he is fast? And you don't have time to dodge?
Let's watch the ice lady from the bathroom window so she doesn't see us.
Oh, oh. Quick back in, Myyy. There it is now.
I want to see the ice lady!
Sell!
You can't go!
Come back!
What now?
Well, let's even stay safe inside.
Ice lady!
Oh, oh, oh.
I saw you grow up ice lady!
I saw, I saw, I saw!
I hope Myyy will survive.
Yes, Myyy always does tricks like that. He is absolutely like that.
I hope Myyle doesn't go though. You should just keep your mouth shut.
Oh, oh, oh.
Myyy, myyy, I saw you grow up, ice lady!
Blow wind, blow!
I'm in trouble!
Sell!
Oh, oh, oh.
Please little Myyy, wake up!
Sell!
Myyy, honey, wake up!
Don't worry Myyy, we'll melt you down in no time.
Oh, you're taking my leg!
Myyy, you're done again!
So Myyy really was.
Little Myyy will not disappear from this world.