I'm talking mummy play.
Red Riding Hood wouldn't be the craziest idea.
Oh, Little Red Riding Hood. What exactly do you mean?
Don't bother, wet lady. Have you forgotten?
I'm talking about mumilaaks, one of the program numbers of the party.
Oh, that's how tomorrow's suit came out.
Our best investment is a party.
Let's face it, it's tricky.
Our best ranking is Fifth place, but this year we will win.
Certainly.
Our victory is certain. The first prize goes to us. Or what, Nipsu?
Victory is ours.
We surpass ourselves.
That's what we do.
I just have to decide who is going to wear it.
I think Little Red Riding Hood is the best.
I'm best suited as a red riding hood.
I'm the only real red riding hood.
And you're not. I'm a red riding hood.
Do you even feel sorry for Red Riding Hood?
Of course I do.
A dire wolf attacks the same girl and eats...
No, no. Little Red Riding Hood is a good girl who kicks her glass slipper.
And then it's the cone itself that reprimands him.
And then he runs to the gingerbread house.
And then he puts his finger on the shaft.
Or something like that. And just talked.
Oh, was it really a mummy?
That...
That's why I have to be a red riding hood.
I thought I had read that fairy tale.
Sell for a moment. You made up a whole new fairy tale.
Or am I so small that a wolf can eat me?
Well, let's start with the past.
I'm a big mom then.
Who am I?
Hunter.
Hunter, e.g.
That means I'm...
Maybe it's sushi.
I don't want to play a wolf.
Moomin is a wolf.
The dress doesn't fit me well?
Maybe it's big after all.
Better like too small.
The wolf's head is cramped for me.
Oh help, wolf.
Pum pum.
A brave scavenger shot the bad wolf.
Don't do that. You freaked me out.
Moomin Pekko Do I look like a big mom?
You are so fat that a wolf can't eat you.
That's a bummer, too. I am full.
Am I okay like this niiskunkunnie?
You don't look very scary.
The wolf should be thin and is hungry.
Absolutely.
Oh poor.
Stink, what are you doing here?
Tell us what always makes you make a fool of everyone.
Oh, what's stupid?
Let it be sold. Skunk, you can play a wolf if you want.
I don't want to be a wolf.
You will be an excellent wolf.
Don't think so.
Do you want to be a hunter?
I'm not fit to be a hunter.
How about being a grandma?
No.
What do you want to be?
Well, the red one.
You mean you want to be a red riding hood?
Hey, didn't mean to be silly. Little Red Riding Hood is a bitch.
Oh girl?
Hey, you don't know anything about little red riding hood.
I'm just, I don't know.
Alu, look ahead.
ha Isu Li.
Catch it if you can.
Seis, Haisuli.
Stink, let's wait.
I get mad if the suit falls.
What mischief?
Back, Stinker.
Did you hear?
You imagined everything.
The squeamish chicks over there on Haisuli.
No, let's wait now.
Which way did Stingray go?
It's dark here.
What?
he i, still beautiful.
I'm a skunk.
It's dark here.
What the hell has Haisuli gone to?
Ha, there he is.
I got you.
Get loose.
And I can't.
I'll stop already.
You won't fall.
No, no, no.
Help.
I'm not stupid enough to get caught.
Don't think so.
I really thought I was chasing Haisul.
Weird.
But who is running there?
Reminds me.
Am I behind myself?
Out.
I've turned into a skunk.
It probably happened when we got relegated.
And Haisuli has turned into me.
What do I do now?
Moomin doesn't follow me.
It's sad.
Moomin, what are you doing so far away?
Moomin, where is Moomin?
Don't bother joking, Moomin.
Aha, I understand there is some new play in the question.
It can't be true.
Oh no, I've turned into a Moomin.
That game can be fun if it doesn't go on too long.
You know welcome home and say hello.
What do I do? Me who was so beautiful.
Now I'm begging and short-legged.
I'm quite bald and ugly and ugly looking.
Hey, it might be useful to think I'm a Moomin.
I'm off to the Moomin house to devour Moominamma's delicious moonshine.
Moominma cooks huge amounts of food all the time.
I treat everyone badly and I'm always mistaken for Moomin.
Excuse me, but have you seen any skunks around here?
What are you talking about, you're a skunk.
No, I really am.
Start a new life and be as energetic as Moomin.
For the hundredth time, I'm not a skunk.
Aha, you have something on your mind again.
But I'm not easily tricked.
Oh shit, what do I do?
Oh Moomin, what are you doing there?
It's funny that you saved Little Red Riding Hood's costume from the skunk's eyes.
Thank you Moomin, you were brave.
Tomorrow we celebrate.
The skunk is a troublemaker, a low scoundrel and a miserable coward.
Stinky or awesome?
It's possible, but I'll beat the skunk.
That's for sure, Stink must be banished from Moominland.
I'm all for skunks just plain annoying.
Stink is the only one I really hate.
Hey, don't, me, I think Stink is nice, really.
What's wrong with you, he didn't like skunks before?
Oh yeah, I guess not.
Moomin, what's wrong with you, you're very quiet today.
Moomin did a real feat, all by himself.
He managed to grab my red hat from the skunk.
Oh well, that's good.
Moomin, you'll have half of my piece of cake.
Huh? I rarely smell.
Oh, you get my piece too.
Really, it's fun to be so popular.
You've always been popular.
So am I.
Hey, listen, I'm there.
What?
Don't come to make villainous hooks.
Don't you ever get tired of teasing?
Hey, don't, I'm here.
Go away and don't come back.
Don't clap, you hear?
Don't you understand?
I'm me here.
How am I going to get through this?
I'm a skunk.
You've already seen the weight of the suit leg.
ha I Su Li!
Don't mess around, you're a skunk.
I am Moomin.
You're not, you just look like a Moomin even though you're actually a skunk.
We have changed, I am the real Moomin.
Don't lie.
Moomin, what are you foaming at?
Oh sorry, I lost my temper.
Ride, Stink away like you've done before.
Yeah, hi, I'm Moomin.
Was the skunk clear?
Get out of here.
If you don't go away, I'll bite you.
You have to believe, I am Moomin.
Go away you skunk, there is no place for you here.
Hazel, say cardboard.
Don't you believe me?
Stink, I don't know what's on your mind, but this isn't funny anymore.
Dad, Don't you understand?
Ha, start blabbing about it.
Go already if your life is dear to you.
Off, as you already are.
Why don't you believe me?
I am Moomin.
Well, well, well, let's do this.
Moomin and Stink are both allowed to stay in the Moomin house.
Over the course of the day, we'll see which one is the real Moomin. Does it fit?
Mamma, it's a fixed problem.
A problem?
There is no problem. I hate you guys.
Glad you understood at least five times.
You guys are mean.
Hihihi, what a relief.
True. Moomin mom, isn't it snack time already?
Muikkunen, snuff muikkunen.
Did you stink, do you have something to say?
Tell me, do I look like a skunk?
Your voice sounds a bit strange, but who else could you be but a skunk?
So yes.
Moomin, you lost again. What's wrong with you?
Moomin is the only one who loses.
Here I am good with patanos like a good friend.
okay?
That's exactly what I hate.
Yes, we are home again.
I don't feel embarrassed somehow.
Goblin, don't sleep. Your turn.
Card table!
I'll stop, what fun is this?
You are a rascal.
Listen, what's wrong with you?
I'm going for a walk.
In the middle of the game.
Weird.
Let's leave him alone.
My head is already spinning.
Moomins are so freaking nice and kind.
I can't stand it.
Hello, Moomin.
Is something crazy?
It wasn't my fault.
Now tell me, what's the matter?
A burglar has broken into the Moomin house.
If you hurry, the thief can be caught in the act.
This burglar is on a criminal spree.
He might be armed. I'm already going.
Moominpappi and Moominamma, here we come.
I came out of there, hands behind my neck.
Another koura koppaa senut.
The game is played.
Come out of hiding before I get mad.
It doesn't show.
Chief of Police, what the hell are you doing here?
Moominvappa, where is the burglar hiding?
What burglar? I haven't even heard.
Moomin just said that I have to come here to arrest a burglar.
Moomin troll.
Out.
We haven't seen any burglars.
Moomin claimed otherwise.
Well, now the lily plants have been treated.
The next tribe.
Moomin, what's up?
Hello, Hemuli, what are you doing?
Here is a species of sage that is very rare everywhere.
I have been collecting these samples for 20 years and I am now putting them in order.
May I help you?
Clear.
What is the function of these dry plants?
Then the next plant, tribe.
I have never tasted a rare plant before.
Moomin, what are you doing?
It tastes bad.
Oh stop!
Moomin, what are you doing?
It tastes bad.
Oh stop!
Please, Moomin.
It's stupid to collect bad plants.
Moomin, run away!
It was fun.
Damn what he did.
My hard-earned plants.
Moomin came.
What's nice on your lap.
This is my new doll.
Give it here.
Hey, give the doll back right away.
And I won't give it, take it if you like.
Moomin, what are you doing here?
Take your doll.
That was fun, bye then.
The doll was completely destroyed.
I have told Moominma that free education is harmful.
Hi, do you eat fish well?
Hello Moomin, there will be a big catch today.
Right, good. I'll help you get an even bigger catch.
I told you so.
What's wrong with you?
Now.
Mother.
Father.
Moomin is not himself.
To put it mildly, she has become an impossible-to-grind Moomin.
I like Moomin, but some actions are unforgivable.
Unfortunately, Moomin hasn't followed law and order.
Hey, try to calm down.
That's asking too much.
I got hungry.
What's wrong with this?
Probably equipment for tomorrow's costume party.
I guess you can get some flavor from this?
Stop, Aisuli!
Oh you Moomin!
Aisuli, don't go!
Let's go!
Here it is now seen the fruits of free cultivation.
I haven't accepted it at all.
Aisuli is still fast, even though our paws have changed.
You're not holding me!
Wait!
Oh no dead ends!
Now you're hooked!
Let me go, let me go!
You stay!
No, no, no!
Moomin mom, what measures are you going to take?
Pictures are needed now!
Moomin destroyed my precious collection.
What a wonder he's gone.
He used to be nicer!
Moominpapa, help Aisuli, she's babbling again!
Wait Aisuli!
Moomin!
He chases after Aisul.
Moomin, I have something for you.
Yes dad.
For you too, Aisuli.
Oh me!
I am Aisuli.
AI Suri.
Father.
Because Moomin is there.
Because Aisuli is there.
I am my former beautiful self again.
What luck, I'm my old self again.
Lovely!
Moomin!
What father?
How could you do that to me?
And why are you playing with children's dolls?
What the hell is wrong with you Moomin?
I don't understand what I did wrong.
You must not call the police unnecessarily.
I guess it's best to run away.
Aisuli and I bumped heads together so that we switched.
Yes?
What do you mean?
Are you trying to avoid responsibility?
That explains everything.
I knew Moomin couldn't have made those black ones.
Aisuli did naughty tricks in my character.
And you all thought I was the culprit.
Where is Aisuli anyway?
There.
Ha ha ha, bye Moomin.
I got a really delicious pie from you.
So the earlier Moomin was not Moomin.
I can't believe it.
But you are the real Moomin.
I am.
I'm Moomin, mom.
My beloved Moomin.
I have to go and complete Aisuli's criminal record.
I wish this had been known.
We believe that things are as they seem.
Moomin, how did it feel to be a changeling?
Lonely. Aisul has no friends.
Aisuli is lonely because no one likes her.
You too were lonely like Aisula.
So you were! And now you can't run to Moominamma's arms for comfort.
Whenever I feel like it, I try to make myself turn into Moomin again.
Thanks for watching the video!