Moomin troll
Miss Niisku runs happily towards the Moomin house.
He plans to go to the beach with Moomin.
Moomin!
The Moomin
Ah, the sun is already rising and tells about that step.
Kehveli.
No... see...
Dad, what's wrong with you?
Yes?
Well what about you?
It sounded like you had been raining.
Yes?
Ha ha!
I am currently writing a play.
A play?
The previous play was a great success.
I savored the turns.
Ah, the sun is already rising and it's telling there steps.
Nice line, but could it be improved?
Rosalina.
To the heavy basket.
Moomin!
Really cute.
Ha ha ha!
Did you find something?
Well, nothing to mention.
Oh beautiful.
Are you still empty-handed?
I'll go look elsewhere.
I think this is definitely the best place.
I'll go somewhere else.
Ha ha!
Oh how wonderful.
Moomin, what are you doing?
Well, at least it's not invisible now.
There isn't.
Moomin!
Well, at least that's not the case now.
Well, no.
Why did you dig it up?
I have to see what it is.
Looks like an old item.
Not too weird.
Now it already looks like something.
I've dusted it off.
It's an old lamp.
Alatid's magic lamp.
Now don't bother, little lady.
Don't rub the lamp yet?
Tried not put.
Moomin!
Wow! No fuss.
The magic lamp is just a fairy tale.
Well, I can try.
Don't mock.
To tell the truth, I'm already rubbing the lamp into my numb hands,
but no spirit appeared from there.
You didn't massage properly.
Men can't even whip cream.
At the same time, you have to cast some kind of spell,
for example hipsis, hopsis, genihoi,
came out of the lamp.
That's not a real spell.
Say, Sesame is coming out.
The sky is awful.
Watch out, little lady!
Jaha, how may I serve, sir?
Did you come out of this lamp?
I came.
Are you the real spirit of the lamp?
Of course.
In the fairy tale book, the spirit of the lamp has a different appearance.
I testify that I am the spirit of the lamp, if you must.
No, maybe the picture in the book is bad.
I am the only true spirit of the lamp.
Then you can make any wish come true.
Their wish, not yours.
I dug you out of the sand.
It doesn't matter at all.
Miss called me from the lamp.
What are we going to do now?
Ask spirit for something we've always wanted.
Wait a minute...
Kalkor!
Their wish will come true.
Wait!
I still haven't had time to say what kind of necklace I want.
If you don't like it, send the jewelry back.
If I like the necklace brought by the spirit, then you get to wish for something next.
Clear.
Where did you rub the lamp?
From here.
Very, very average.
Aha.
Hips, hops, spirit, hoi.
Out of the lamp hummed.
Hey.
The spirit returned.
Miss is good.
Beyond belief.
That's exactly what I thought.
Thank you spirit of the lamp.
It won't last, good lady.
I'm just doing my job.
Are you sneaking back into the lamp now?
Yes.
Then hurry up, I'll let you out next.
I would like to ask you a favor.
Wait a minute.
If it's difficult to walk between the lamp and the outside air, you can hear my wish right away.
It doesn't work, I have to be called out every time separately.
I'll save you the trouble.
You can't hope right away.
Why not?
I can only grant one wish a week.
I need rest sometimes.
Just like that, fulfilling wishes is of course terribly exhausting.
It's not that I'm not capable.
I can do many things.
Like what?
It's a secret.
Moomin-Pekka, don't tell anyone about the magic lamp.
Of course not.
Day.
The names mean nothing.
Five tulips or hydrangea.
Something about it.
I'm not a wretched knee or a thimble flower here.
Hopeless.
Thank Aladdin that I didn't tell the kids that I could get to midnight from the lamp on my own.
Otherwise, I wouldn't have had much peace.
Good thing I can read minds.
So I know what you wish for.
It's nauseating. No wonder the young man has worries.
I'll rewrite the scene.
Come on, play someone else.
It must be rewritten.
After all, the whole page is entertaining us with stupid things.
Who's here?
I am Finland.
Don't bother us with nonsense.
What a paralyze.
Who has done this?
Mamma, you haven't been there.
Someone tampered with my text.
Why, counsel?
What am I asking and still in the middle of the night?
Well, even that is remarkable.
Moomin, it wasn't you, was it?
I don't know anything.
Of course not, aah, who who!
Ugly trick, I'm not at all surprised you're hurt.
A pretty ugly trick, especially when the repairs have been made to areas that I knew needed polishing.
Paappa, you can write well enough yourself.
Yes, but when my play got better from corrections.
Well then, be grateful.
Exactly, no no, a playwright can't be a basket case.
Oops, they tasted like a necklace, if you like pearls.
Hi, thank you, I got the necklace as a gift.
Very beautiful, can I try it?
Just trying it on, I'm sure it will wear you too.
Maybe you'll learn to like it from strings of pearls.
I will ask you for a similar string of pearls.
Do you have a friend, Antelias?
Oh, my, I've searched the whole house, but it's nowhere to be found.
No need to worry, Rovabilionkka, the thief will surely be caught.
Good day, police chief.
Well, day.
Hurry up so my thief doesn't run away from the Moomin trap.
Oh good time, catch the thief already.
Calm down, Rovabilionkka.
Has something been stolen from Rovabilionka?
There is a string of pearls.
It has 87 beautiful pearls, just like you.
Little sells.
You can't, don't.
Incredibly hot, the string of pearls is my thief caught.
What?
Stop it.
Petty crooks are often the biggest of all.
This string of pearls belongs to niiskunneids.
When you laugh, you're trying to shove the blame on the necks of the niggers.
I am not called a thief without consequences.
Niskunneid's necks?
Niiskunmi, are you sure the string of pearls is yours?
There is. I got it as a gift.
From whom?
It's a secret between Moomin and me.
Secret?
Nua brats have stolen my pearl necklace.
Rovalionkka, they never light up.
It is not preached in the church.
Their shell is messy and dusty.
No need to drag.
You will regret it if you get in between.
I want to ask you one thing.
Ai! Ai!
Like they're already off.
The spirit is at home.
I don't know who has been on it, but he is clearly a pencil sharpener.
Just listen to this, snuff mumbler.
Ah, already Auriko is getting up and Kerttu is walking there.
Now that didn't sound so great.
No, I wrote like that.
Oh, sorry.
No problem. This way it is fixed.
The light that shines through the window is east and Juulia is the sun.
Get up in a charming day and slay the envious moon.
Tired and worn out from grief.
What daybreak?
How to cleverly change Kertu's name to juuli?
It's much more romantic.
The heroine is worried because the parents do not approve of her beloved ethekar.
I had written like this.
Names mean nothing, tulip or hydrangea five of them.
But listen to this, where is the meaning of the name.
What is called a rose would smell just as sweet by another name.
Oh my gosh!
So does Roomeo, even if it has been given a different name.
Nicely said, even if I had left out Romeo's scent.
The promising author said it right, papa.
A lot of words, maybe, but Roomeo is a good name for a hero.
Leave a note for the author to continue your play.
Maybe it's not that necessary after all.
He knows that all good corrections appear at midnight, when I was in a sound sleep.
I'm sitting at your desk, right?
There are people who wander in their sleep, remembering nothing the next morning.
You mean sleepwalkers?
You were very sleepy when you woke up this morning.
Ha ha, sleepier than usual, that's right.
When did you wake up in the middle of the night and correct the play in your sleep?
Some little things in my play had been bothering me.
I have literary talents hidden in my subconscious, which I'm sure you are aware of.
Oh, they came to my rescue so that I rushed to my study in the middle of the night,
I grabbed the pen in full sleep and unleashed my gift.
This is it.
Now this is the first lamp in my possession, you can do anything.
No wait! Stop! Told you to stop, did you hear?
Police! Heavens, how do you know to chase the menu?
The bird of bad air is disappearing!
Disappear yourself! I guess you'll regret it! I'm being chased! The police are on their heels!
Wedding? Sell stops!
Put you on the tube stops!
Oh, they give me chills!
I know why you were in a hurry! You stole what you hold!
What's up with you? Not yours!
No, but somebody's got it! So yes it belongs to me!
Thief! Catch the thief!
Give it back!
That's the lamp I found.
Did you get me to bite you too?
Our lamp.
Oh grandma, Peikka, Stinker walked like a magic lamp.
Heavens, Stink mustn't take the lamp, or something terrible will happen.
Did you hear the hum? It's supposed to be a magic lamp.
After!
Police Chief, catch Myy!
Stink, run over here and I'll help you.
Turn, come back! Did you hear? Shoot ours!
Give it back!
This lamp is my manger from the beginning, I will not part with this.
I succeeded!
Are you the spirit of the lamp?
I am, my Lord.
Or sir?
I let the spirit out of the lamp.
I am his master now.
I can't believe it.
Tales of a thousand and one nights.
Unbelievable, but true.
I saw when Niskunnetti asked the spirit of the lamp for a pearl for herself.
Oh, just like that.
Miss wanted Pramea's necklace.
I have to think about what I would come up with to ask.
Listen Stink, the spirit can only grant one wish a week.
It's not true!
May I ask where you stole the string of pearls from?
I stole.
Well, or where did you get it?
Apurista.
Mrs. Viljonka from the house?
I don't know who lives there.
The spirit stole the string of pearls.
Well, stealing is easier.
I want a magic key that opens bank vaults.
I have a few questions.
A sack of gold wouldn't be half as much fun.
Did you make corrections to papa's play?
I? The text was so flat.
You don't just need to grind.
Besides, this young Moomik was also worried about the play.
He wished his father success.
Moomin troll.
Then there would be no need to break into the profession with pride.
Father, I saw how you suffered in your play.
I hope it will be good.
But of course I don't want Lampu's spirit to write your play.
I want the key!
That's right, Lampu's spirit didn't come up with corrections on its own.
Didn't the text sound somehow familiar?
Oh, right.
The spirit of the lamp lent you excerpts from a play by a world-famous author.
Oh, miserable me.
I've read a lot.
I'm going back to Lampu now.
No wait, I want to make you a wish.
I beg your pardon, good sir.
See you next week.
Next week.
Not next week, not next month.
Not next year, not ever.
The lamp is not your skunk.
And besides, I know what you wish for.
Universal key.
Uh, I'm going to hide the Lamp.
But there is no place where I can't find it.
Moomin, Lampu is too shy to be kept here.
Yeh, you're right.
Nuska, muikkunen, what are we going to do with Lampu?
A week is expenses.
The police chief is coming!
Snuff, muikkunen, let's start.
Manager!
Yeh, you're right.
Or again, what do you want now?
Can you bring the Magician here?
Or the Magician, of course.
What do you have for the Magician?
I think that a safe place for Lampu can only be found on another planet.
And only the Magician can take the Lamp there, no one else.
It was hard work, the Magician will be here soon.
Oh, thank you.
Well, see you again in a week.
The magician agreed to take the Magic Lamp to an unknown star.
And it was good.
It would be boring if all wishes came true.