There had been loud bangs in the Moomin lakso lately. Usually only one a night, but sometimes two.
Did you wake up to a commotion?
Yeah, and when I think about those sharpies, I can't sleep.
I'll see if there's another one.
The shocks come from the north.
Oh, I thought from the east.
They hardly come from the mountains.
I doubt the witch has anything to do with it.
Why should they make such a fuss?
You don't know that. Witches are Slytherins.
I'm going to see the chief of police tomorrow. He gets permission to put an end to the fuss.
Dad, I don't think that makes sense.
Why not? The first jolt wakes me up and then I'm left to follow another one that might not come.
It could be that the thuds are an echo from somewhere further away.
Ai.
Right. Nuuska Muikkunen thinks so.
Do you mean the pounding is coming from the sea?
Yes, Nuuska Muikkunen thinks. You know, even if the pirates were banging.
I'm still betting on tins. The rustling sounds come from the woods.
What are you two talking about here?
We await another rumble.
You may wait in vain.
How do you know that?
There were two crashes last night, and there have never been two crashes in consecutive nights.
Except now.
Did you hear the sound clearly coming from there?
From the east.
No, it came from that direction.
There is no doubt about it.
Good morning, Moomin Pekko.
Good morning.
You look tired.
You too would show if Yrinä had supervised you.
They are quite remarkable thuds.
Hey listen, will you go on a witch hunt with me?
Dad is sure that the witch will cause a chill.
That's where you go wrong.
That's what I said too, but I couldn't convince dad.
I'm going to find out about it.
You can tell that from the thumps, but maybe not tell us.
Let's ask.
Witches don't have to lie.
And sell again.
You go again!
Hi my, are you shadowing me full time?
Only when you're trying to sneak away somewhere.
I'm just taking a walk.
Yes, but even now you're walking sloppily.
The witch just kept you from waking up.
And now he's trying to prevent you from sleeping.
But Moomins aren't the only ones who suffer from the bumps.
I consider it possible that the Moomins are not the witch's target after all.
I wake up, you just once and I don't know anything about the thump.
You're thick-skinned too.
Are there witches at home?
If not, we can play with Alisa.
If we want to know the truth about the thuds, it's better to ask Alisa.
It is.
The fact that you seem to understand that this is a witch's cabin.
What do you mean?
The fact that my reputation will suffer if I am seen in the company of such vällers.
Huh? Your reputation is long gone. Because of us, we...
That... We have a few questions.
Then we'll go home right away.
Is Alisa's chamber in the attic?
There it is.
Is Alisa at home?
There isn't.
Where is he?
Looking for herbs.
When will he return?
Was that your thing?
No. I will answer honestly. What is all the fuss about?
Ah, that's it.
Ho, you know. You make those thumps.
Well, not really.
Who then?
It would be fun to know.
Then why did you say that?
The jerks bother me too.
Are they coming close?
Not far away. Maybe facing the sea.
Muikkunen thinks the same.
All the sounds from the sea echo off the lonely mountains.
Senate kid!
I went to the beach a couple of days ago to see if there was anything there?
A witch needs a night's sleep after all the witching and casting spells.
Well, did anything work out?
No. There was only one thunder that night, and nothing was visible on the beach when I finally got there.
At least it wasn't you.
What makes you think it was me?
When I really fart, it's really not a camel fart.
Oh camel fart!
Thank you, Miss Niisku.
I am going to grow black tulips this year.
Are there any?
Well, they are quite dark red.
Yes.
But somewhere in the world you can grow cypress tulips.
Let's go and ask Hemul right away.
Let's go.
Likes me.
There's nothing to be ashamed of.
I wake up to that noise every night too.
Are you making a fuss?
Well, exactly.
Oh yeah, that's it.
Do you know anything about it?
I don't know.
But I won't try to take over because of those thumps.
So?
So.
Do you know anything about it?
I don't know.
But it's not because of those thumps that I try to keep watch.
I am waiting for an answer from the botanical society.
Really?
Joo.
Very good answer.
Haven't I told you?
In these I have sent a new species to the botanical society.
Previously unknown.
Or so?
No one has found it before.
It is a wild rare palm.
Or have you sent a new species to the botanical society?
It's me.
It would be a greater honor if you named it Hemulensis.
This is Hemuli Formis.
Certainly.
That's why I've been spending sleepless nights on them lately.
I see.
The answer should have arrived ages ago.
Where the hell does it stay?
Maybe the jury can't decide.
Should it be called Hemulensis or Hemuli Formis?
What now?
Aha.
Now I understand.
There is no answer because I haven't found a new species.
Of course not.
Someone already found it.
Don't sleep.
What a fool are you, a catty man's career tag?
Hemuli, calm down.
You can call me Mr. Hemulensis.
Listen now, Hemuli.
The answer will be delayed because the plant must be examined very carefully.
All source works must first be browsed in order to draw scientific conclusions.
Would that really be the case?
Does the research take that long?
Of course it will last.
When did you send the sample?
A month ago.
Trust your abilities, Hemuli.
It is neither time nor nothing.
Trust itself is everything.
Excellent. Everything is fine now.
Great news, Mom.
Hemuli has invented a completely new plant and its name will be Hemulensis.
That's great.
Good luck, Hemuli, honey.
Well, the cardboard is missing.
Don't be needlessly modest about it.
We have to organize cookies in Hemul's honor.
Really.
When? Today or tomorrow?
There is no such rush.
Why not?
Hemuli.
So?
Does the plant you found have flowers?
Everyone has it.
Are they beautiful?
Very beautiful. Just as beautiful as the old lady.
Oh, thank you.
Muikkunen, let's go find out about those jerks tonight.
Most of all.
Do you need me as a guide?
Do you want to join?
It's to be heard.
Bangs come late at night.
I don't go to sleep at all.
What do you think?
Sell or does he decide not to convert at all?
Phooey.
Remember to be careful sell. This can be a dangerous sell.
Of course it is. I guess I wouldn't have ruined my night's sleep otherwise.
Stick to kinder.
Remember.
I was at the beach last night at the same time when the witch was flying there on her broom.
I couldn't detect anything out of the ordinary.
Were you? Why didn't you take me with you?
You are so big and white.
I'm not big and I'm not white.
There's someone over there.
It's Alice. Hi Alisa.
Alisa hi.
Well hello.
Bye bye.
Hold the towel.
Did you come here to play?
We have other things in mind. More important.
Listen.
What?
Has your grandma been nice to you in the last few weeks?
Of course it is. Nice as pie.
When I stopped going to Moominvalley.
Well, that's great.
Yeah. I better keep my promise.
At least for a while.
What are these?
Herbs. Necessary for a witch.
As well as the stomachs of frogs and the tails of groundhogs.
Hmmm. Just licorice.
It is.
Well it is. Good snuff, little one.
Helps with heart disease and cough.
That's great.
And it also makes cows go belly up.
Don't be shy, Alisa.
Um.
Ooo.
Maybe an answer.
Good day. Aren't you a wonderful air?
Good day, Hemuli.
You work hard every day.
I guess so.
Wait a minute.
Well, what do you want?
A letter. I want my letter.
It wasn't.
Yes, but when it wasn't yesterday. And not the other day either.
No one has written you a book.
But I should have received a letter.
Are you absolutely sure that it's not in some pocket of the bag?
even then, there would be no book for me.
Please take a look.
The ice melts. See for yourself.
In.
Well, if you don't seem to believe otherwise, check it out.
Try it all out.
No, yes I believe, but...
Well, let's just be quick.
I don't think your soul park will find peace otherwise.
Come on, that...
Oops. He has a lot of letters today.
I really should get a better salary.
Abdominal strain.
I could go and get something for the rest of us.
It makes me tired. I think I'll doze off.
Can't collide.
Sorry. I didn't see you.
You didn't see, although there is nothing else to see here.
Sorry.
Strange. What's wrong with you?
Is this a Moomin trap?
There is. Of course.
Finally. I thought I would never get here.
Excuse me, but are you sick?
Miss.
Get up.
He has a terribly high fever.
Let me be.
You can't stay lying here. You need to be put to bed.
Do you happen to know hemul?
Of course. Have you come to see the hemuli?
Doesn't hemulia live here in Moomin Valley?
Yeah, he lives close by.
Great. I need to meet him.
Hey, don't get dizzy again!
Hey, help! Help is needed here!
Oh heaven!
Help! Hey, help! Help!
Father! Father!
Moominpappa is upstairs in the guest room with mom.
Or so?
I just saved one girl.
A girl?
Did you save?
A beautiful girl who is sick. I put her on the bed.
I want to see!
So do I.
I could take a look again.
First you have to get the fever down.
I guess so.
Fuck it.
Nipsu told about the girl. Is he still sleeping?
Joo.
Where did it come from?
We don't know, but Nipsu said he came as Hemul's guest.
Yes, and Niiskunnemi went to get hemul.
Isn't it cute?
It's like a flower.
What did the witch tell you?
Do I have to live somewhere?
Must. You have received a young girl as a guest.
By the way, you give them medicine.
I don't know any young girl.
Run, don't panic.
I said I don't know him.
If he has grown?
I have never known young girls in my life to which I said.
Then why has he come to see you?
Well, he's obviously a herbalist.
And has heard of me.
Joo.
Goodness.
Well, he'll tell you when he wakes up.
Let's wait for grandma's medicine to work.
I think I'll go home.
No, you can't leave like that.
It's up to you.
No thanks, I have to compress the tumor.
Come on, you really don't know him?
I don't know young girls.
Good continuation.
I think he didn't forget the thuds.
I don't, we're going to track them down tonight.
I would come too, but...
I'll go with you, so where did you go?
Are you going to sneak off to the beach in the middle of nowhere?
Yeah, and as soon as we hear the thumps,
we run up the headland in their direction.
And not so?
I would really like to go.
You guys are coming.
What restraints would you have now?
I have responsibilities at home.
What about Nipsu then?
I'm not leaving.
Yeah, but if the girl is...
Well, here's something to eat if you get hungry.
Oh, thanks mom.
Bit of a night bite, eh?
Get jealous.
Dad, why don't you come along?
I'd love to come, but tonight I better stay home, huh?
Necessarily.
What could I do here alone if the girl gets worse?
Me too.
I'm waiting.
I think we should eat sparingly, fin.
It could be a long night.
Are there going to be bumps?
In the end, don't take any more for me and give me a good night's sleep.
You can't take it anymore.
I can handle it. Muona's old ones like every three equal parts.
I think it would be fairer to divide the muona according to size.
Oh hey.
What was it?
Went from there. Now keep an eye out.
There.
What is it?
Oh!
Actual fireworks.
It came from the sea.
Someone is shooting fireworks.
There's a boat over there.
It finally has the Syylnen we were looking for.
No! Come to the beach!
Isn't that Hemuli?
No. Looks like Hemul, but much younger.
That's how the night hikers found out that the thumps that kept everyone awake were caused by fireworks.
But the creature that fired the firework rockets dissolved into the darkness of the night.
Thanks.