One day, Moomin and his friends went on a trip to a special, completely round island.
You have a long way to go. I put extra food in my backpack just in case.
Thanks. Come back at low tide or you will have to stay on the island for the entire high tide. And be careful.
If you set off now, you should reach the island.
So what if the water rises when we're halfway there?
Nipsu, it doesn't happen that fast. We will leave for the return journey in good time.
But how do we know what is early?
Don't do it, Muredi. When it's time to come back, I'll let you know with a proper thump. You can even hear it on the far shore.
Are you absolutely sure?
I'm always sure.
Bye.
Have fun.
Take care of my sister.
Fool. I can take care of myself.
Too difficult.
Pinch, come on!
What's wrong with you? You look worried.
What if the high tide falls on us anyway?
Is that why you wear a stupid life jacket?
The tide follows the moon, and the moon never knows where it is going.
Nipsu, you are amazing. Are you not interested in a treasure chest buried on an island?
Ooo, aare?
You haven't heard, have you?
Wake up.
Hey.
Oh round island.
I tell you what. The water has already receded. I'm running a race to the island.
Y, you, you, ny.
Most creative, Pekko, you stole.
I don't even have access.
It's a hill.
Ha, ha, ha.
I'll tell you what to do with me.
Hey.
Oh.
Moomi Pekka.
Oh dear Pekka, look how cute I found some nice shoes.
Wow, they are beautiful. Especially that pair of glasses.
Then you get it.
Oh, thank you.
Ha, ha, ha.
Ha, hooray, I caught it.
Look, Nipsu, a real octopus.
Up.
Nipsu, what are you standing there mumbling about?
I watched the sea so that it wouldn't suddenly sneak up on us.
You can't even see it, you idiot.
I'm going to look for a better spot.
A pinch.
Loggerhead.
At least I can't see anything from here.
Ha, Kalli is going in every direction.
Hard to climb.
Ha, real amethysts.
Where am I?
Haa.
Oh, how beautiful and precious.
And how much.
Haa.
Luck.
I got it.
Haa.
Do you think these are enough?
Yeh, thanks.
What exactly are you doing?
Can't you join?
We are building a lodge. Come help.
The house is too small for all of us.
What's in the office?
Strange, I haven't seen Nipsu at all.
Me neither, it's wonderfully peaceful.
Let's go Nipsua gone.
Curious thing.
Hi, Nipsu.
Pinch.
He has gone home alone.
And no, he would have said.
Nipsu, hi, where are you?
It rained.
About.
It's now ten past ten.
Aha.
I want to see how your cannon works.
It works well.
I designed it for the launch of my aircraft.
Well, plug your ears.
Wake up.
Moisture.
So yeah, I didn't take the rain into account.
Pinch.
Nipsuu, where are you?
Come here.
Where has he disappeared to?
The water has started to rise again.
Oh-oh-oh, help, help, Moomin!
Oops, water has entered.
Aa.
Ah, amethysts.
I didn't even see a wish.
I have found an amethyst cave.
What a stroke of luck.
More valuable than a treasure chest in a cave.
Wake up.
How do I get out of here?
Moomin!
Hoi!
Help, help!
I would have loved to know that gunpowder gets wet in the rain.
I didn't expect rain.
Hurry up, let's get to the island.
There is currently a full moon and the tide is particularly high.
Evil!
Pinch!
Nipsuu, where have they been?
Listen!
Have you found a trinket?
In the meantime, the water is so high that we can't get back.
What?
We are lost, good fellow.
Niisku he promised to bang when it's time for us to return.
But the sea is rolling towards us.
Building a house was not the craziest idea after all.
You have to find a pinch.
So.
Pinch!
Come forth, Rumilus!
Water is flowing.
If the water gets in, I get out.
Uvi papa, we can't get to the island at high tide.
We have to come up with something else.
Yes, we will get to the island.
Let's kiss only those who are more pontificating.
Hey!
Ai!
Moomin papa, nothing will come of this.
Did you come up with something?
The current seems to be getting stronger.
Cave mouth rescue.
Ai!
To the profession!
Moomin goblin, come help!
It sounded like Nipsu's voice to me.
Ai!
I didn't hear.
Moomin troll!
Your nip is...
Pinch, where are you?
Moomin goblin, help!
Moomin goblin, come help!
The sound comes from the cave.
A pinch!
How did you get there?
It's not important.
Help out!
Fun, at least the rain stopped.
How are you doing?
I won't come.
The books advise you to do this.
But have the authors tried?
I'm terribly hungry.
Did Evaskor have something to hawk?
Left.
Let's heat the leftovers with a campfire,
when Moomin has first started the fire.
Finally, the deer collects dry leaves.
Clear.
Nipsu, you're coming to help me.
Neither do I.
I'm going back to the cave to get more amethysts.
There is no time for that.
I'll help or eat your share.
You're so lazy.
Hold on.
Will anything come of it?
Absolutely.
According to the bills, I can fly from here.
I took the rope with me to the island.
When I got to the island,
I'll pull the boat over there.
The plan can't fail I swear it.
All right.
Now I'm leaving.
Good.
Slaughterhouse, slaughterhouse.
Gathers its wings.
Piemälä on the island.
This works as I designed.
I have misjudged my own strength.
Don't worry, Nisku.
Don't fall.
Please help.
Nisku, are you okay?
I believe so.
Thanks for the help, Snuff-muikkunen.
Think nothing of it.
What the hell are you doing here in the middle of the night?
Moomin and his friends are on the island relying on their own luck.
Blocked by water.
We have tried to save them without success.
Or like that?
Please wait for the next low tide.
I'm sure they'll find some shelter from the rain.
Hopefully.
It's not even cold now.
They have spent the night under the open sky before.
Well, they are.
We are waiting for low water from tomorrow.
Snuff-muikkunen, what things do you use to move?
I came to see the round island.
Why?
You can see the incredible.
In case the fog clears up a bit.
What was that sound?
There was a rumble somewhere.
The waves are roaring!
And not.
The sound comes from underground.
Thanks.
What was it?
The ground shook.
Would you mind?
Omi-Pekka!
The sound is coming from here.
Don't go there, you will be in danger.
Please wait for me.
The sound is close.
Hats.
Hattivats compete.
They have fun.
LKKK
Am I still asleep?
I don't do that...
They must have left.
The water is falling! We're getting home, hooray!
Collect!
Sniff it up!
Moaning!
Father!
And Moisture!
Dad, hello! Wake up!
Niisku, what's yours?
There is! It's morning!
Moomin!
Sister, why are you loitering here?
Moomin, are you all right? Didn't he catch a cold in the rain?
Of course not.
I brought you beautiful shoes too.
Thanks.
You look at this.
It's beautiful. Amethyst huh?
Absolutely.
I had many amethysts, but they fell into the water.
Let's go get them sometime.
And we see something extraordinarily beautiful on the island.
Ice. Let's go home. Mamma must be worried already.
Let's go!
Stay tuned!
No!
Moominpapa, you have a cold.
And you look very tired, good police chief.
Let's go drink some cocoa. You too, Niisku.
Joo.