Oh! What is this? Wasn't this supposed to be an archaeological dig?
There is nothing but rubbish here.
That's not true. Don't always marise.
The mummies' ancestors settled here thousands of years ago, as dad told me.
True. This is where we dig our roots.
It's here.
Did you find something?
Treasure!
Landfill!
Hats.
I guess these are your treasures.
Sorry.
We put everything in place.
Look! This item shows the handprints of the ancestors of the Moomin clan.
This is indeed a remarkable discovery.
Is that a vase?
You can smell ancient history.
I only smell too much.
It's just a teacup shard.
I have seen that pattern somewhere.
You certainly aren't.
Are you absolutely sure?
Now I know. We can find out if the shard is antique if we go back in time.
You made a clever decision, Moomin.
We will see what kind of teacups our ancestors used.
History calls us to our roots and we respond to that call.
Are you going to go back in time?
Tell me which one.
Oh, I have to make you some sandwiches.
From what I hear, this isn't going to be any fun.
Yet.
That the machines can be tricky when they get on top of it.
Does not start. I'll help. I repaired it a little while back when it was still a slot machine.
Oh, that's right, my dear.
Excellent, but the engine seems to have little power.
My ears don't hear the slightest hum.
The batteries have weakened.
I guess so.
Hey, I made it up! Flash!
Unfortunately, the thunderstorm has already passed.
We just have to wait patiently for the next thunderstorm to come.
We have heard about our plan. It will be a wonderful adventure.
Would you like to join the club?
Oh, no, no. I'll skip this one.
If it happened to return, there would be no one to take care of my garden.
Does it mean that there is no way back from antiquity?
There is no reason to worry. I designed the time machine myself.
We've seen what a technological marvel you are.
It's really not a reindeer thumb.
Oh, cotton wool! Thunder in the air!
Listen, dad.
How is this going?
Stay in your fields.
Hattivats gather.
Lightning strikes here!
Help!
Let's launch!
Do you ski?
There they disappeared.
It's crazy to think that they are now history.
I hope they find that cup of tea.
Goodbye, Moomins!
Oh, we're there.
So this is the ancient Moomin trap.
A real desert.
Oh, it's so romantic.
With the roof! Too hot and you get sand in your shoes!
I hate romantic fluff!
I think we are in the right time.
The place has moved from the lightning strike.
Then this is...
Most likely the desert.
Yes, but which of them, my dear?
Whatever, it's too hot here and I'm thirsty.
Me too!
Oh...
Myy!
Myi stays here with mom.
We go in search of water.
Clear.
Moomin, you are so brave.
Be careful, Moomin.
It's hot.
I'm thirsty.
I'm hungry.
Just a sand desert.
Hey, look over there!
Oh, it looks like an oasis.
I'm going to drink as much water as I can.
We should have brought field bottles.
Hey hey hey hey...
Hi hi...
This was definitely an oasis.
Who stole the oasis?
Bring it back!
It was a mirage.
They were found in deserts.
A mirage?
Yeah, just keep calm.
This is not what the emergency looks like.
I'll eat my old hat if there isn't an oasis near here.
Oh!
Where do they hang out?
Where have they gone?
Soon now before I dry up.
Don't now.
Then the water tastes even better.
Don't try!
I'm dying, dying, dying, Janu!
Wake up...
Oh dad, there's an oasis over there.
The fabric, I guess.
May be.
This is an oasis.
Maybe a real oasis.
We were approaching an oasis!
Let's drink!
The spring has dried up.
Walnuts!
Nuts contain a lot of milk.
I climb too.
Me too.
Now I'm almost done.
I guess it didn't happen to you either.
Oh dad, the walnuts are too high.
Don't mourn, the stones will go down.
Oh, good idea.
You can't even see the stones.
Just sand.
Hey dad, the desert is moving.
Yeah, that happens in the desert every now and then.
The wind is always shaping the desert.
It's amazing.
Camel, it might still be of some use to us.
Keep your head up, please, and keep your head up.
Oh, please, Kameeli.
Good.
A little further up.
Too bad you're not kira.
Six.
I'm in terrible pain.
Control yourself, Sikameeli, good.
Oh.
Hey, we luckily came back to the time machine.
But where's Moomin's mom, mom?
Yes, and where is the neck lady?
Sell, where are you?
Proverbs.
Hoi, niskuneiti.
Cultaseni is a mother.
Oh, help.
Oh heaven.
Has a hungry eagle caught them?
Wait, where have you taken mom?
Mother, little girl.
Myy.
Moomin's mom.
Oh, footprints.
Moomin's mom and Niskuneiti have gone their separate ways.
What, didn't the bird rob them?
It's starting to look a bit like that.
Let's follow the footsteps.
Whoah, whoah.
Desert, help.
Women traveling alone across the desert.
Can I be of any help?
I know what's on your mind.
You're not fooling me.
Oh, what my eyes see, sweet princess.
Sure, I'm pretty, but you're not exactly a princess.
That's flattery.
A beautiful flower that blooms in the desert.
Oh lovely princess.
You are fooling me.
Oh yeah, you didn't even talk about me.
A lovely flower belongs to a lovely palace.
Follow me.
Let me take you to the palace.
Does the call apply to all of us?
I offer you some fruit.
Herctaista
What about us? This is not fair.
We also want to come to the wonderful palace.
You cannot leave us to the mercy of desert sand storms.
Please take us with you.
We will come.
Did you hear what I said?
Excuse.
You become overweight, the camel collapses.
Nice camel, you like women after all.
Nice camel.
Hey, wait.
Sweet princess, we are there.
After all, this is a palace.
Be nice now.
Moist.
Good day everyone, isn't it a hot day.
Leave it, good people, that the princess has arrived.
Yeah, seasons have been received.
How far do footprints really lead?
Hot as hell.
Creepy place.
Mom, where are you?
Never in the world should I have jumped into a time machine.
Mitsu, don't bother crying.
You lose all the water in your body.
I'll take the time machine and go home.
And you don't take.
I have a real friend there.
Best to say.
Riita Halki win between.
We need to help each other.
Let's go looking for women.
Big interiors!
So.
Let me know if you want anything else.
Make yourself at home.
Thank you.
He's nice, it seems.
Yes, but what is his ultimate purpose?
Yay! It tasted refreshing.
A bunch of Moomins and papa would enjoy it too.
Where could they be?
Mouth-watering ice cream.
I dream about ice cream.
I'm lined up with ice cream cones.
It looks like a tent village.
Oh, and it's not a mirage.
Now we get water.
Up!
A beautiful vase.
I would know what flowers to put in it.
A lovely necklace.
Oho! Light! Taikalampu!
The spirit of the lamp emerges.
Eh, there's nothing magical about it.
Sit down.
Fly, fly! Magic carpet, fly!
Sell, use now neatly when you are in a foreign place.
Hi, if this was a Magic Carpet, it would be easier to find others.
Water, water...
Look!
The water is good, I revived.
So do I.
Ha, ha, ha...
You can keep the others.
The more pleading is quite tolerable.
He's not exactly young, but no age is the end either.
I then take the small one, which is always at the end of the mouth.
Are they talking about Moomin's mom?
And from Niskunet.
So they have been disabled.
We have to do something.
I can't get it out of my head.
And now I'm stuck too.
I don't see anything.
It's about marking.
Don't be horrible!
What if we stay here?
Take care, Martin.
Ah, what's in that?
It's some monster.
Or a monster? It scares me.
It's going to eat us away quickly.
Whereabouts?
This way here.
Where did you appear in it?
How did you find us?
We must escape.
Why? We are so friendly here.
Mamma, you don't understand.
These bandits have kidnapped you.
Hurry this way.
Don't leave me!
Moomin and Nipsu, hurry up.
Hurry now, or you can stay here.
Yes, but when the delicacies are not eaten.
Camel!
Camel can help.
Where is that monster?
Where?
Who are you and what are you going to do to my princess?
Thanks for the food.
I am now taking my wife and children away on a trip.
Come on, Kameeli.
Don't go! Wait!
Hold tight.
Let's go, honey. You were so heroic.
Was I?
Closed!
Give me the princess.
Aplu!
Not you my love...
Who is that low-status, shameless naked scumbag,
who do you think is the princess?
Something like that. You are the light of my life.
Katska...
As soon as the eye avoids.
Anna, excuse me. I will never again.
Bring your hat, however proud it is.
And those eyes, so full of sleep.
Just like that. Just thanks.
Remember where we are.
Yes, we really have to go. Goodbye.
A large white codling moth!
Wow, what a day. Let's go back to Moominvalley.
It doesn't matter that I was called a princess.
And who was that shameless scumbag?
I have stopped trusting in the future.
Steal to eat just in case.
Might be wise.
hey what did you say Leave it to me too.
And luckily, I have a long way to go.
Don't worry, because we're heading for Moominvalley now.
Thank you.