The snow cover strengthened during the day. It was high time for the Moomins to hibernate.
what are you doing
Alisa!
Why do you collect needles?
We eat them every year before we hibernate.
Are you going to hibernate now?
Tonight.
Already now?
Joo.
I was lucky. If I had come tomorrow you would have slept.
You knew how to come appropriately.
We usually keep the small cookies the night we retire to hibernation.
Moomin, can I have some cookies?
Do you know those by the way? Oh, forgive your granny for coming to Moominvalley.
In my opinion, adults don't need to know everything.
You are right.
Grandma doesn't really like me coming to you.
And why not?
I guess he's afraid that I'll have more fun playing here than studying the witch's subjects.
Aren't you a witch yet?
Well, I don't. Today, it requires seven years of study.
Are you sure you want to be a witch?
Study something else.
I'm going to be a witch.
Yeah, but look, witches aren't always popular.
Don't they? I will be popular with everyone.
Are you going to join us?
I'm going.
I thought you'd already wandered south.
I promised the Moomin troll.
You promised what?
Well, I won't leave until he hibernates.
Full representation.
And one extra.
Cry?
Well Guess.
Ah, the witch's daughter's daughter, of course.
Ah, guessed right.
O-was it?
But you must have been sneaking around corners and such, Alisa.
Well, no, it was just a guess, believe me.
Alisa wanted to come and greet us.
Father shows him the house.
Are there any here?
No, why would you?
It's good, really good.
Hello, little snuff, I'm finally here.
Hi, this is Nipsu.
Do you remember him?
Of course, hi Nipsu.
Hey, Rooster, Luuru, listen.
Didn't she just bewitch me?
In.
Moomins didn't just eat needles.
Moomin mamma had prepared a lot of different delicacies.
I apologize to you.
Why?
You decided to postpone your departure because of my selfishness.
I'm leaving tomorrow.
The snow is thick.
It's okay, I'm used to the snow, but it might be hard for Alisa to get home.
He could sleep with us, but when we no longer wake up in the morning.
Someone is at the door.
I'll go see.
Good evening.
Evening, evening.
I guess he's here, huh?
Who the hell is there?
Hi, hi, hi.
You must be Moomin papa.
Now listen, Papa Moomin.
I absolutely do not want my daughter's daughter to come here to play with your children.
Alisa enjoys being with us.
Grandma.
We're going home.
Can't I stay yet?
Join us at the dinner table.
I'm a Witch, I can't eat your baby butt.
Alisa's food was good.
It's because she's not a Witch yet. Come on, Alice.
Go ahead of you.
Not at all, miss. Witches don't associate with people like this.
Nor do you try Witches.
Why? They are nice.
That's the fault. They are incredibly kind.
Let's continue this topic at home.
Come now.
More snow has fallen and the frost is getting tougher.
Well, I'll come then.
Thank you, Moomin papa.
Whence?
At least we understand each other.
I don't think so.
Well, that's it, but without further ado.
Don't ever talk to Alisa again. Is it clear?
But grandma.
If you disobey me, the vengeance of Osiris will fall upon you.
Cheap threats don't work for Moomin Pappa.
You are mistaken if you imagine that your Antics scare us.
I have three diplomas.
Anyway, how are you even going to get home with Alisa in this snow?
Pih, a child's job for Noida. Come on Alice.
Have you ever seen the Hiulu people on a broom here before?
Right Witch's broom huh? Does it fly?
Let's get closer.
Come on Alisa, hop on board.
Joo.
Looks like a bone to you both?
Well, hardly, the broom looks pretty flimsy.
Don't freak out in this weather.
Alisa, be careful not to fall.
You're horrible liars, shut up already.
Are you ready?
I am.
They are guaranteed to take off.
Tel.
Broom the pipe.
Eight.
I guessed they are too heavy.
I could take Alisa's place. I don't weigh that much.
Grandma, I'm walking home.
Don't talk crazy, you'll sink into the snow if you walk into the forest.
I wish I had skis.
You start coming, I'll try again.
Grandma, does the audience make you nervous?
Shut up, help me.
God's concoction.
Let's go.
Goodbye Moomin, Goblin, goodbye everyone.
Grandma, don't.
A skilled witch despite three diplomas.
They would come down so I could get on board too.
Let's go back to the table. Food is waiting.
Oh dear, I didn't remember to thank you for the dinner invitation.
I don't think you're the right witch.
But I want to become a witch.
I know and I will help you, but the road will be bumpy.
Oh grandma!
Musakamoikkunen
When the underlings had flown their way and the Moomins had gone to rest for the winter,
Nuska Muikkunen started to wander south.
The Moomin would probably have slept until spring,
unless something unexpected happened.
Since after Nuska Muikkunen
they would probably have slept their spring.
Someone is spring.
There is someone behind the window.
Frame frozen shut.
Hey, why did you wake me up?
You can't sleep. Christmas is coming.
Not a moment must be wasted.
Or is Christmas coming? Who is Christmas?
What? You can have time for banter,
but i don't have. Nothing is ready.
Everyone was hooting and hollering.
Christmas is almost here and I still don't have a moon.
From the moon?
Hey, wait!
Wait!
What today?
Christmas is coming and we have no moon.
Protect!
Christmas is coming.
Yes, and there are still six more to apply for.
What do you need the moon for?
Maybe the moon is needed as some kind of protection against Christmas.
That thing didn't become clear.
It is some horror that must be avoided.
I'm going to go find a spruce right away.
It was also time to lift up.
Good day, Kampsu.
Let your trees grow old.
Thanks.
May I ask what the moon is used for?
Well, but you can make fun of granny priests to their face.
Joking?
Sorry, I still have Christmas food to cook.
Or was I making fun of a familiar story?
Uh.
Would you like some more?
No thanks. I'm warm and good to be again.
I saw granny papa and granny elf money, but a big month.
But what to do with the spruce?
Don't you know?
Emme.
It must be dressed as beautifully as possible.
Just like that.
Thanks for the tea, it was delicious.
Are you leaving?
Yeah, I have a long way to go.
Have a nice trip.
Good day.
Goodbye.
Who was that?
Someone who was very busy before Christmas came.
I gave him tea.
That was nice.
He advised us what to do with the fir tree.
So what?
Six are dressed up beautifully.
Why? Why do you have to wear it?
I think Christmas has to be softened somehow.
Yes.
Let's start dressing right away.
Yeah, we're going to be busy.
Joo.
Oh, mom.
What honey?
I hear you have to prepare a lot of food for Christmas.
May I be protected. So that Christmas doesn't eat us.
Here.
Thank you, my mother.
Oh, the ship has a sense of value to me.
It looks great on the tree.
Really handsome.
Oh.
Hey, put this on top.
Mother's still rose.
Don't mourn.
Mom doesn't need decorations.
Hey, listen.
I just heard that for Christmas you also need gifts.
Nope.
What does Christmas look like?
If it's an ugly monster, like a moron.
Don't be afraid.
We give gifts and plenty of food for Christmas.
Have you come up with a present for Christmas?
I don't. is that you
I give this.
A beautiful shoe.
Mom, look what I'm giving you for Christmas.
A handsome lure, although bad at fishing.
I'll give you a picture book.
Great. Christmas will certainly be happy and will not harm us.
Christmas can come at any moment, whatever.
I guess so.
I hope Christmas likes pumpkin pie.
I'm sure it will.
Every creature trembles and waits for Christmas.
So.
Are you dreaming?
Dreaming. I can't be afraid of Christmas anymore.
Christmas should come before all the food freezes.
Christmas is coming.
Who would have thought that Christmas is so small?
Have a great Christmas.
Do you think Christmas is fun?
Well, it's usually welcome.
All my life I've dreamed of seeing this up close.
A wonderfully beautiful fir tree.
I brought my little friend with me to watch.
Welcome, everyone.
Thank you. Did you hear what Moominpa said?
How much food.
It's all for Christmas.
And are they gifts?
They are.
Gifts have always fascinated me somehow.
Dad, I don't think they are Christmas.
Me neither.
Mom, you seem sleepy.
I am too.
It's already well past midnight.
Where is it Christmas?
Aren't you sleepy?
Oh no, who could sleep next to such a beautiful tree?
Dad.
What?
Do you think the same as me?
I'm just together.
Not even Christmas is angry this late at night.
Let's close the doors and go to safety.
Let's do that.
New foods and gifts are all yours.
What? All of them? All?
Right.
We are so sleepy that we go to sleep.
I'm together.
Yes, there must be one for the night when Capturen is closed.
Kas scales
Which and also varriage
it's just to show the implementation of the kokoorder Wissen
Do not!
I thought there should be a star on the top of the Christmas tree.
Is there much of a difference? The silk rose is very, very beautiful.
You look over there!
Oh!
The Moomins slept peacefully all night, and Christmas did not attack them.
I guess it went somewhere else?