One, two, three, four, five, six, seven, eight,
One, two, two, three, four, five, six, seven, two.
It's a beautiful day in Muunilaakso. Mild but not too hot.
It has been decided to eat lunch outside.
Kids, the food is ready!
Seventeen.
GP!
Moomin's pancakes are good.
Thank you for your courtesy.
I'm addicted to pancakes. We always have them.
Yes, but you seem to like it.
Pancakes always taste good.
I didn't say pancakes are bad.
But it would be fun to eat a new dish once in a while, wouldn't it, Moomin papa?
That...
Dad doesn't need a change.
He got to eat enough foreign foods on his adventure trips.
For example, what?
Grilled monsters as fokonas! Mushroom with jelly!
Oops! did you eat
No, I don't. Nothing of the kind.
Tell me about a dish.
Joo...
Once I really ate a special treat.
Do not! How did it taste?
It was the most wonderful food in the world.
Although, of course, not about the taxes on mamma's soups.
Tell me what it was.
Mouthpiece!
You are also interested in food.
No kids, let's stop talking about food.
No, no, no red for heaven's sake!
I think it's a beautiful color!
Kids, are you up yet?
It's not too late.
Right, I thought...
Mamma Honey, what's wrong with you?
Ah, I was just in my thoughts.
Turn off the lights when you go to rest.
Yeah, good night.
Mummy has worries!
What exactly do you mean?
Mumipappahan said that he once ate the best food in the world.
I didn't mean it like that.
That's how grandma understood it!
You started that topic.
Well, no one takes my words seriously.
Oh, oh, what did I do?
Not here either.
Where have I put it?
Here.
Ui.
I know I've seen it here.
Seen something just ask?
You can never tell.
You can find just about anything in Isoäini's recipe book.
What could it be?
Isn't mom looking for instructions for some particularly delicious food,
which he has never offered us.
Here it is.
What to do when the family is tired of your food?
Good.
Oh.
Tumor.
The soup boiled over.
Oh yeah.
Good morning, I'm snotty.
Good morning Moomin mom.
Shows Prepare van snacks.
Anyone going on a trip?
Well, I'm leaving.
Oh, you?
Oh.
Dear Moominpappa sells Moomin trolls.
I'm going in search of a rare substance,
which is needed even for special food.
Oh.
Hm?
I have to leave you for four or five days,
but I have prepared for you dishes that you can easily eat.
The mornings are still cool.
Remember to keep your neck and feet warm.
There is another jar of pumpkin jam on the top shelf.
Oh, snort, little one.
Don't go looking for me.
Please take care of me.
See you soon, best regards mule mamma.
Hm.
Yes.
Snuff changes.
I'm snuffling.
Moomin mamma, let me help carry.
No thanks, I have to survive on my own.
My family is not allowed to follow me.
I live in Teuta.
And I don't really belong to the Moomin family.
Oh yeah, you don't.
Well, where are we going?
South of the Lonely Mountains.
Yeah, over there.
There is a secret valley that no one knows about.
Clear. Let's go hiking.
Hm.
So we went.
Did you hear about Moomin mom?
I heard. Let's hurry.
Au.
Where is Moomin-Pekko?
In the kitchen.
Moomin-Pekko!
Everything happens so quickly.
I was gone for a measly five minutes.
What happened?
Moomin papa tries his cooking skills.
The purpose was to bake pancakes.
Really nice pancakes.
Could you have done better yourself?
One pleasure, why are you mourning for nothing?
In the cupboard there is bread, juice and syrup and raisins in whatever measure you like.
How's the soup doing?
Well, then you won't eat soup or pancakes for lunch.
What if Mummy Moomin doesn't come back?
Why not come back?
Mom said she was leaving for four or five days.
For five days?
We will have to starve for almost a week.
Moomin papa, we need to find mommy and bring her home.
Oh no, we can't do that.
Mamma went on a trip because she needs to get ingredients for the recipe in grandma's recipe book.
Mom knows what she's doing.
Don't worry, today I will cook for you.
do you cook
Are you sure you can?
Well, I cook food for my brother every day.
Great, together we can get through somehow.
Ah, good smell.
I found wild apples and mushrooms and you apparently caught fish.
Are they fried or steamed?
How only when you cook.
No one in Moominvalley eats as well as I do tonight.
Oh, you're on your way.
My sister Parka has seen far too little of me.
Besides, maybe you want to face the ordeal in peace.
Well, I don't necessarily want to intrude either.
Don't cry baby girl, we know you tried your best.
Well, that's the worst part.
The color of the soup is just strange and the smell unusual.
Or what?
Right, but the taste is definitely excellent.
I saw that it is not mentioned slyly.
Father?
It's a bit salty, maybe.
Let's add water and it will be good and last longer.
Not at all now.
Oh mamma, come back soon.
The stars twinkled beautifully, I haven't been on a hike in a long time.
It's like I'm a little boy scout again, this is really fun.
I thought you'd miss the Moomin house.
No, no, once in a while you have to sleep under the starry sky.
Beautiful.
Moomin wakes up.
Father.
My son, the day has begun.
We follow the mother's usual command come what comes.
What does that mean?
Listen, would there be enough food for me too?
Of course, and my sister can make decent fins.
Good morning, Moomin and Moompapa.
Morning, morning.
Lots of laundry.
Did you wash everything together?
Yeah, my paws are all wrinkled from the water.
Go in and dry yourself off, you're catching a cold.
First you have to wipe the whole house dry.
What now?
Nothing, has mom always done all this alone?
Yes, and we still have to clean and wash the windows.
Cooking and sewing.
Father!
Got it clear, I didn't realize there was so much homework.
Would we eat canned food from cardboard plates?
The road ends here.
We have turned somewhere in the wrong direction.
The book does say that the road goes here.
Would you cut some reeds for me?
Yes?
What exactly are you going to do with the reeds?
I'll wait and you'll see.
What are you going to put in those giant pots?
What do you think? Us, of course.
Oh, of course.
Are you serious?
That's right, grandma said it has to be done this way.
Or would you rather stay here?
Well no, I can't let you go alone.
Come on, let's get on the boats. Y, ka, ko.
Isn't that awesome?
You won't get into trouble if you follow grandma's instructions.
Well, what should we do next?
Hmm, now almost nothing.
What is that sound?
Can't you hear?
I guess not.
Hold on tight Mummy Moomin.
So do you.
Guide me here with my hands.
Oh, sorry.
Moomin mom, hey wake up.
Wow, I slept so sweetly.
So this is the secret valley you are looking for.
At least it should be.
Oh, delicious looking cherries.
What makes a good pie?
Or what do you think?
Probably, but those are ordinary cherries.
Weren't you looking for rare ingredients?
True, but it doesn't matter what you collect as long as you collect from this valley.
Now let's get home.
Or does it not matter what is collected?
Snuffbox.
Oh, sorry.
Isn't this enough already?
But how?
We get back upstream.
There is no climbing over the mountain.
Oh yeah, that's true.
Skinned.
I'll have to look in the book.
Aha, here.
Moominvalley is full.
Moominvalley is steerwaterkaSO näsä.
Muumilaakso on steerwaterkaSO achieve numeral officially filled.
In Moomin dialect, boil oncia is used.
Moomin varmentation target for 1 minute.
Muumilaaksi var linguistic key taimel-د bored system alas.
Oh, we came here?
To the open sea.
A bit confusing.
Ah, hey mom!
The bathroom, we're actually at home already.
I don't understand.
If we were this close to the secret valley all the time,
why didn't we use forward?
I don't understand.
If we were this close to the secret valley all the time,
why didn't we use this road?
I think it will take many days to reach the valley.
Otherwise, the secret power of cherries will not work.
No power?
So.
Well, let's paddle now.
I already miss Moomin Valley.
No?
Almost a real pancake.
I'm making progress.
I'm already getting tired of just jam and pickles.
Sell, don't be lazy.
You have many squares left.
Yes, I know that.
I have never washed my own windows.
Shut your mouth and swing the wheel!
Too clean window panes are dangerous for birds.
Mom has been gone for four days now.
He said he would stay no more than five days.
Father, Miss Niisku, come quickly.
What is it?
Look.
Mom listens.
Mother!
Movie momma, movie momma!
Let me help.
I'll take the backpack.
Not me!
Thank you, thank you.
That was the end of Mamma Moomin's private trip.
She baked a huge cherry pie.
And fried and cooked one thing and another.
The Namias!
Fairytale cherries!
Yes, it was worth going so far to get them.
Moomin papa can bake pancakes.
Really?
Well, of course I'm not nearly as good as you.
Stop it!
There is enough food.
Mother!
Stop it! There is enough food.
I want the last pancake.
You were so tired of pancakes.
Or was it?
Yes, but I'm not anymore.
Moomin mamma's trip was worth it.
The little one liked pancakes again.
And Moomin Pappa had almost learned how to fry them.
Thanks.