Once again, a lazy day is celebrated in Muunilaakso.
A bit boring.
Very boring. I miss something new.
Everything here is familiar through and through.
We should go on a long journey.
Traveling must be fun, right?
However, I am not tired of Muunilaakso.
Why do you always leave?
I don't really know, I guess I have to.
If I didn't go away from time to time, I could forget that Muunilaakso is the best place in the world.
Funny! Hey, someone's coming!
Weird looking guy.
Doesn't know good.
Good morning!
Good day!
Is this Muunilaakso?
There is. Are you possibly looking for a specific person?
Yes. I would have to meet Mr. Moominpapa. The name sounds strange.
He is my father.
Show the way to him.
Good day. You had something for me.
Unfortunately, I bring a message of sadness to your home.
Ai.
Baroni Grille has moved from time to age.
Are you crying?
Don't you know your own relatives?
Maybe it's your relatives, mom.
No, I don't think I've heard that name.
I can't fathom this kind of algal origin, Mr. Moominpapa.
Baroni Grille was a fairly close relative of your little cousin in the sixth generation.
God bless the man.
So. I can't tell you that it was extremely difficult for us to find you, Mr. Moominpapa.
Five years of full-time work was wasted on that.
No use because of the trouble time!
Not at all, my lady.
All of Baroni Grille's close relatives have gone to mananamajos a long time ago.
We have found out that Mr. Moominpappa is the sole heir of Baroni Grille.
Or inherit?
It has a list of Grille subscriptions.
Could you kindly certify with our signature that we have fulfilled our obligations?
What does this Grillenkartano mean?
One of the last large farms in our country has passed into your ownership.
Cultivating it will be a duty greater than demanding challenges.
Japa! I don't mind any challenges.
There is enough to take care of in the Moomin house. I don't need a farm.
Mind your words, Moominpapa.
I care little for farmland. I don't even like gardening.
Couldn't the mansion be given to a non-relative?
For many, that would be a nice surprise, I'm sure!
Oh well, good time. That would be against the spirit of the law.
That, sorry.
So what?
My name is Nipsu and I am very similar to Moomin. You could say I'm kind of related.
And you don't belong! You should be ashamed!
Why?
Are you saying that if no one takes care of the krill manor, you'll take it?
I don't see anything wrong with you. Don't ruin my chances.
Young man, just being friends with Moomin doesn't make you a badass.
It must be said that the refusal of inheritance is exceptional.
I'll have to go back and look for precedents.
Sorry, we always seem to go against expectations.
This is not what I meant to tell you, but perhaps you chose wisely.
I am happy for you.
No one has taken care of Krillen's mansion for five years and rumor has it that it is haunted.
Haunted?
It's haunted!
They say strange things have happened there.
The ghosts are excited and so on.
No living creature dares to set foot in the mansion's rooms anymore.
Real ghosts, huh?
Real ones, of course. You really like me. It's a haunted mansion.
There could be a crash or a torture chamber!
It's hard to notice at first glance, but the floor of the building is soaked
and the garden is simply awful.
How so terrible?
No one has mowed or weeded for years. The garden is an almost impenetrable jungle.
Jungle?
Jungle!
To tell the truth, scary sounds are coming from there.
Sounds fun.
The jungle is wildly exciting.
A castle covered with vines from Rovantti.
A ghost in a harajuku suit.
I think I sleep next to the Moomins.
Dad let's go already.
I want to go! Is ave's armor transparent?
Mom, shall we go?
Dad, I think you'd enjoy being there.
Well, let's go then.
Let's go!
I live in a torture chamber!
There must be an aari there.
Absolutely crazy crowd.
Why did we see such a terrible speed in Porha?
I want to rest and eat bread.
But we took a break from our snip roots.
Nuuska Muikkunen was wise.
He is currently sitting drinking tea.
You would have stayed home.
And it's still not too late to turn back.
I'll kick you so fast that you spin all the way!
Isn't this Krillen's mansion?
Should be.
It must now be called the Moomin mansion.
Hey, you can see the main building here!
More fun than you imagined!
Hi, I'm so sorry. I didn't know you were in it.
By the way, this is not your sleep shirt.
Kalpis was pissed off about it.
Help!
Oh, out of the way!
Oh, come on, don't get in the way like that!
Hey, don't be kidding, peck! Stop cursing!
Amazing jungle, visit man-eating chickens!
Help!
Ai, ai.
Ai, ai, ai.
Nipsu, you hold on or you fall.
You are very forward.
This is how it wants to be, go ahead.
Oh!
Cujut, cujut, cujut.
No, no.
Jump on the horse when Nipsu has gone upside down.
Plow it.
All powers...
Aha.
Gentleman-looking.
Cook.
Don't shout. There's nobody here.
Ghosts at most.
Ghosts.
Uli ice ancestors.
Ai.
Help. The door just beckons me.
All kinds of things are always hurting you.
I would like this library room.
So to Moominvalley.
May I come?
Just come.
I'll start looking.
Hi, hi.
I would really like to take a kitchen like this to Moominvalley.
Not a soul.
Oh, no, no. Must not.
I'm not starting anything.
I found you.
Nisku-neiti and the fox sell in the same hiding place.
What makes you think that?
I heard how popular they were.
Inappropriate.
Did you hear the Moomin troll?
I heard. Takuu didn't have a nisku-miss or sell.
So who was it?
I don't know.
We could ask.
No. I don't want to know anyway.
Why don't you want to?
I don't like invisible voices.
Let's go away.
Oh Moomin, what now?
You look over there.
There's something strange about that bed.
How is that?
How so weird?
Miss Nisku and myi are hiding there.
I don't like it here.
Don't feel like playing hide and seek.
Let's go out.
Hey, I found you.
You too, little girl.
I found you both.
And you didn't find it?
Just like that. What do you say now?
I guessed. In the same hiding place.
Don't run away.
Oh, make-up, don't use it, Tirti.
You break into Gravi year.
That voice again.
What now?
Get out of Gravi Freirik's bed.
Let's obey the voice. Get out of bed, everyone.
But the bed feels solid.
Oh shit.
How do I get a bandaged white?
Trees as if on order.
It sounds like the younger generation has invented it again.
Where is the little one?
Hey sell!
I am Finland.
I am myy.
Myy went with the bed.
I'm here.
Thanks and praise.
I should have known that we never have to worry about small sales.
No need!
I'm so small that nothing can happen to me!
There's someone here. I feel it.
Hey there!
Hey, don't go!
Your voice saved us from falling with the bed, didn't it?
We would like to thank you for that good.
I tried to save for a year.
Pity the bed, and sorry for scaring you.
Here.
I haven't experienced others in a long time.
700 years ago.
For 700 years, although I would have to say a long time here.
Well, I was a little scared actually.
If you think about it more, I was scared.
Good, you look very interesting.
Your shape is just so white.
I probably would have freaked you out more,
unless I had seen ghosts before.
I have experience with them.
Oh, right?
I saw one ghost on a lighthouse island.
It had come there on a ghost ship.
How romantic?
Well, sort of.
And my father knew a ghost in his youth, and they were good friends.
I envied a happy papa.
Why?
I'm the only ghost left in Krillen Manor.
Others went with the wind in the black night,
while the Christmas storm rages.
1634.
And one morning Gravy Freric was gone,
without me noticing anything.
Then you probably haven't talked in a long time.
For two centuries.
It's horrible.
Yes, and I like to talk,
Gravy Freric thought I talked too much.
I'm sure the wind took Grav too.
A headwind maybe.
Well, now you know how badly I miss aadinkoni
keen listener and sympathizer.
Sounds incredible.
Did you really talk to a ghost?
I spoke. His name is Black Gravitar
and he misses company.
I could talk to a ghost
through forgotten bones
or the trembling shadow of a thousand graves.
The ghost wants to talk to me.
I like a man of few words.
Let's have a ghost for dinner.
How about some cold cuts?
In the light of day, I too could meet a ghost.
And you couldn't. And why?
Because then you'd be too scared.
I'm not afraid in the light of day.
Black Gravitar does not want to be seen during the day.
He is afraid of light.
I tell you what. The light of day turns him into a pumpkin.
Hehehe.
Aaaaaah!
Sorry, Goblin, I thought you were a pig.
Portrait of Fredrikulla.
Fredrik had his faults, but he was really shy.
It looks like that.
Of course, but a bad listener.
He stuck wax in his ears.
I feel like we need to address that.
You're right, otherwise Voovi-Peikko can never sleep.
Oh, nocturnal bone shaker.
We urgently need your help, come now
the host of the moomin house, your ancient neighbor.
Now the letter is ready.
Well thought out.
I'm sure your Ghost friend will answer the call.
So do I.
I hope he still lives in his old place where you met him.
Our hope is now in the letter.
Move, fools, rascals, go there.
Excuse me now, but you have to move.
We have a guest and we have to clean the place.
Enter Herta and Heluna.
Don't try to play tricks on me.
I'm not a jerk.
You tent untidy in a tree.
Get off it now, like you already are.
Dad, what's going on here?
Well, we kind of have a project.
I'll talk about that later.
Now we need your help.
Look what I found in the barn.
Oh, he came.
I think he likes the mansion.
I have to say that I am very disappointed.
But for what the hell?
I want to meet a scary ghost.
You always think only of yourself.
I hope everything goes well.
It'll probably work.
The manor park has been cleaned so nicely.
We thought that the first ghost,
not suitable for the value of the estate.
Kindly thought of, Moomin.
Oh, actually it was dad's idea. I thank him.
Oh, you can look.
I see a ghostly hamo.
Aha, father's letter worked.
He has come to see you.
Me?
Joo.
That's our father's ghost friend.
Father said that he was born from behind,
blue blooded.
Oh, and I haven't even done my hair and my outfit is.
There is nothing wrong with your new vision.
He seems to be looking for you.
Oh, oh, I'm blushing.
Calm down, Nervous.
Your opportunity has come.
Oh, oh.
That's where the black count is now.
You're glad we sent the letter.
Of course papa did.
Thanks.
Of course, papa listens.
Hit the joints. This is how the beloved Moomin valley looks like.
And it looks like the best place in the world.
Hey wait. Do you have to run? Don't leave me.
You'll get something to hawk as soon as we get home.
My foot doesn't budge.
Then roll down the hill!
It was again a beautiful and relaxing day in Moomin Valley.
The weather was excellent and no one complained about getting bored.