This is the kind of thing where other people say that other people say that other people say that other people say that other people say that other people say that other people say that other people say that other people say that other people say that other people say that the other says that the other says that the other says that the other says that the other says that the other says that the other says that the other says that the other says that the other says that the other says that the other says that the other says that the other says that the other says that the other says that the other says that the other says that the other says
that the other tells, that the other tells, the other tells.
Hurry up!
Huh? Why don't you thread it yourself?
Oh goblin, you're not a romantic at all.
Give it here. Reach out.
Slip the ring gently on my finger.
Anonymous? Now.
Ankeksi.
The ring must be threaded gently and solemnly.
Why?
Because this is a significant moment in a teenager's life.
Well, if you say so.
You should say this. Niiskunmi, do you want to wear this ring on your finger forever?
What if the owner of the ring comes?
Tasteless Peikko!
All right. Niiskunmi, do you want to wear this ring on your finger forever?
Oh, oh. This came so suddenly.
What do you mean? You yourself told me to ask.
Oh Moomin, I want, I want forever.
Anonymous, yes.
Did it come out right?
Oh, I'm so happy.
Oh, now we're engaged.
Engaged?
Or is Moomin engaged?
Engaged.
Excellent.
Moompa, this is no laughing matter.
Your son is about to get married.
Might it be wise to try it in practice first?
What would be wise to try? I didn't hear.
Grandma, you don't even know what happened.
Something unusual.
Shut up, I'll explain.
Listen, Moomin is engaged.
He is going to get married.
Or so, and with whom?
Wait until you hear.
Imagine, a rainy Eid.
Niisku with Eid.
It's not that bad.
What do you say, honey?
Our son is getting married.
That's really good news.
Oh, I don't understand Moomins.
Niiskun Eidi is fat and stupid and gullible.
He's on the water and syrupy and childish.
How can Moomin wish for a rainy Eid when I exist too?
Good luck, Moomin and Niiskun Eiti.
Niiskun Eiti, you are so beautiful today.
Let's take good care of Moomin.
Congratulations.
Good luck.
Niiskun Eiti, you look pretty.
I guess you'll make a really good wife?
Yes, I will definitely be the best.
Good luck.
Niiskun Eiti, you look pretty.
I guess you'll make a really good wife?
Yes, I will definitely be the best.
Moomin, I would like to remind you that even the beautiful ones need careful care.
I'm trying to remember.
Good luck to the young, bald guys.
This is a true landmark case in Mumilapso.
It is.
Can't say anything else.
May the happiness of these young people flourish forever.
Listen Niiskun Eiti.
So what?
The whole thing is starting to make me a bit suspicious.
Don't joke about being stupid.
I told you this is just a joke.
You're a joke at weddings now.
I had no idea it would get this big.
Everyone knows it's a joke.
Nobody takes this seriously.
No, no, no.
Is that so?
Oh, what a terrible day.
I'm just fine.
It was the last wedding game.
My dear husband.
You don't mean me.
Honey you're catching a cold, here's a blanket.
Don't, I can fetch a blanket myself if I'm cold.
And don't call me honey, that's ridiculous.
I am your wife.
I have to take care of you.
What? Is that game still going on?
Of course.
You can't stop a fun and affectionate game like this right away.
Oh no.
Here you get a small piece.
Thanks niskuneeti.
Would you like another piece?
This tastes good.
Ah, they are like husband and wife.
I could want a wife too.
Hey, don't get me wrong.
Our marriage is just a joke.
Yes, I know that.
We know.
Well my son, how does it feel to be married?
Dad stops.
Niskuneti may get confused.
And I don't get confused.
I'm enjoying this as much as the rest.
Good, so.
I too have mostly enjoyed being married to my father.
Or what?
And yeah yeah.
Ha ha ha.
Oh, I wish I had an apple.
Mother!
Mom brings ome...
Will you take the apple?
What made you think I was in the mood for an apple right now?
Wives sense such things.
It was good.
Wait a minute.
I want to sit next to you.
When I finished it, you'll be more comfortable eating.
I can eat myself.
All right. Thanks.
You don't have to thank me all the time.
I am your wife. Does it taste good?
It tastes good.
Good. I already went to make your bed.
Oh, oh, thank you.
Oh yeah, I brought you some clean pajamas.
If you are put to sleep, you can go to sleep as soon as you want.
Thanks.
Newly washed and ironed pajamas.
Niskuneiti is an overdrive.
Tastes good.
No crazier. This game has many good points.
Is married life really like this?
Today was a wonderful day.
Moomin wasn't embarrassed at all.
Aha, there.
Ring.
The ring is way too big.
Why does the little girl get ice rings and not me?
What is wrong with the law?
Oh, the ring I gave to the little girl.
He has forgotten it.
Aha, without a ring he can't pretend to be married.
Good morning, Moomin. What are you doing?
Not much of anything. Good morning, little lady.
Did you sleep well?
Oh, I thought I left my ring here.
Curious thing.
Have you seen it? What's wrong with you?
Well, that ring.
It got stuck in my finger so I can't get it out.
I don't think the ring looks small at all.
No worries, all you need here is strength.
Dare!
Oh, sorry.
That's right, Moomin. What are we going to do?
It hurts.
Dad.
The Moomin.
Metal expands when heated.
Maybe we can get the ring off if we heat it up first.
That's a great idea.
Niskuneiti, will you come and help? Let's get hot water.
Let's come.
I guess it's not too hot.
Probably not.
Does it burn?
Oh, it burns.
are you a man
Well, that's fine.
Does it feel like the ring has gotten bigger?
I don't think so, dad. Rather the opposite.
The water is too hot.
My skin can't take it anymore.
Miserable.
All limpsahten.
Yes, the beginning is enough.
There's nothing wrong with you.
Oh good unusual.
Will the ring come off?
Not the other way around, papa. Moomin's finger has gotten thicker.
Tough shit.
There must be some way to help Moomin.
Would cold water help?
Well, of course.
Objects shrink in the cold.
But we should get a mere finger cold.
What would such a substance be?
Icing helps. I have ice cream.
A pinch.
I'll be right back.
Take a little while longer. Try to think of something positive.
I'll try.
So much trouble for one ring. Ha!
I would say something else.
Hey, here comes the ice cream.
Moomin's Nipsu came suddenly before it melts.
This is where I come from as far as I can get off my feet.
Speed, speed.
Let's come. Thanks, bud.
Cool your fingers here.
It feels good.
I tell you what.
Well, does icing help?
Either way, that's enough.
Not yet.
Nipsu, you can't.
I have melted away.
The finger is already cold now.
Oh! The ring went off.
So it seems.
I am free!
Yay! Moomin!
I am so happy.
Nipskuneiti!
What to do with the ring?
Give it to me.
Now we can pretend we're married again.
Huh? Do you want to continue?
Don't you?
When I don't...
Do you think you don't love me anymore?
Well, not quite that.
Are you trying to say I've been a good wife?
No, that's not what I mean.
You don't like me!
I didn't say that.
You said it above.
Well, I certainly didn't say.
That I had to find that Mokoma ring.
Oh guys, what would it be like to live really married to a trinket girl?
Snuff, would you like to get married?
Have you ever wondered?
I can't answer that.
So you're going to stay a bachelor, aren't you?
What? Yeah, I guess.
I've finally settled into the marriage game.
I'm going to go on a short hike tomorrow.
Would you like to come along?
Of course I want to.
What's wrong mom? What are you watching?
And the Moomin trinkets seem to be at odds.
Nipskuneitt, I'm trying to understand now.
I am a man and I must not be shackled or pampered.
I need adventure and danger and adversity.
To be happy.
That's why I have to leave.
Your words make me sad.
But it doesn't matter if that's what you want.
Thanks. I'm glad you understand me.
Moomin, are you coming back in the evening already?
Not so loud.
Moomin!
Hear it.
Goodbye my love.
It's fun to go on a trip with you.
But you have way too much equipment.
Well, of course.
I understand.
But I'm glad I don't have to carry your backpack.
Moomin!
Are you sure you can go along?
Of course.
Wait a minute.
I'll leave some of the stuff here.
Let's see.
Horizontal.
At least I don't need that on a trip.
And then the radio.
For weather reports.
More fun to be surprised in the morning.
I don't think you need a cake pan either.
And not all these pans.
Oh, as a harpoon for pirates.
But maybe it's not needed.
Sorry to keep you waiting.
It feels much lighter now.
Let's set up camp.
Then let's watch the sunset.
Okay, I'm done.
Just the sunset.
Don't get emotional.
First we do the work.
Help tighten the strings.
Uh, let me sit down for a second first.
The sun is setting fast.
We still have to stay the sunset.
Don't get emotional.
First we do the work.
Help tighten the strings.
Uh, let me sit down for a second first.
We still have to stay the sunset.
Just like that.
How do you feel?
Did you enjoy the trip?
Oh, I enjoyed it very much.
Are you absolutely sure about that?
Of course I am.
But it's really tiring.
No wonder the first day.
Hi, do you have anything?
Yeah, a really big one.
And I don't eat fish at all.
Well, that's enough.
I can't eat more than this.
Are you leaving?
Try to get a few cents.
The rip is just beginning.
There is no shortage of time.
I caught fish!
Look at this!
Awesome catch.
Yes, but smaller than your fish.
But they are your own fishing rods.
That's all that matters.
Let's say.
Sit down to eat.
Thanks, how about you?
I have already started here.
Oh guys I'm hungry.
They say that when you're on a trip, you have to get your own food.
That's what we've done with you.
We're leaving early.
Come to the tent after you have eaten.
Genuine.
Well, let's go.
Beg a little!
Mother!
Wake up!
Hello, you snuffling!
What's wrong now?
Look over there!
The stuff I took out of the backpack.
Oops, well then I've lost my way.
And we have come back the same way.
We could turn around.
I wouldn't go astray anymore.
We won't turn around.
Niskuneit!
I already came!
Moomin!
Did he come back from a trip?
Mom, that marriage game is a lot more fun than hiking.
Marriage game?
Oh, that's old stuff.
Is it?
Hey, let's play football!
I want worlds.
Please!