What an early awakening.
Sniff, little one!
Good morning!
Moomin and his companions are going fishing, and only Ani eats fish early in the morning.
Good morning Snuska muikkunen!
Good morning!
Hello Moomin and Myy!
It will be a beautiful day, we will catch a lot of fish.
Mmm, I'm taking you to a good place.
Good, I'm right! I'm a fish!
Mmm, about done.
Low!
I'm coming!
H2O+, potato starch, polymer and mix, catalyst, C2H5OH.
Jaha, have you been up all night?
A dispersion is formed and then the reaction et.i.
Low!
Here's how it goes.
What the hell is that?
Niskun meat.
Now look, such a simple formula.
What formula?
The glue formula I invented.
And it's not any ordinary glue, it seems to glue just about anything.
Just what?
Fabric, wood, metal, plastic, everything.
I'll start making the glue right away.
Listen, Niska.
Look, I'm going out with Moomin and the others.
can you hear
The food is ready on the table in the kitchen.
Are you listening to what Nisku is saying?
Good morning, Miss Nisku, good morning.
Good morning.
Hey there you are.
Is it meant to wake up a twat?
Joo.
There's something to be done, that's what I'm saying.
Well, let's go already.
Long from the waters.
Uska muikkunen, will fish come up from this place?
Absolutely.
Nothing has come yet, I want nothing but non-existent fish.
There is something else.
Even if it's an old shoe rack or a really great bunch of algae.
Hi, I'm hungry.
It's a big fish.
Don't push it away.
I dare you, little one.
Don't take it easy on the hoods.
What's wrong.
The fish fights fiercely.
Pulled it.
Kala.
Ha ha, valaaskala.
Moomin got his fishing rod in the right fish tank.
Moomin can.
We only caught one fish.
But there is enough to eat for everyone.
Yes, Nipsu's boyless stomach bag will be full for once.
Mii.
Moomin, are you really going to cook the fish yourself?
Yeah, cooking doesn't look difficult.
Maybe it doesn't show.
I'll help if Moomin has a finger in his mouth.
Koituskipa, help is needed.
I am available.
Why does everyone think I need help?
I can read a cookbook.
There's no need for you to ask me to eat.
Fish baked in the oven is good,
but there's no reason why fish tastes worse.
Neither will you if I don't make it?
Well, see you tomorrow.
Hey hey.
Wake up.
Oh, good unusual.
Where does the smoke come from?
Oh, here you are.
What are you doing in my kitchen?
Hello, my sister, I'm about to finish boiling the glue.
Didn't I say that you would only do the tests in your own room?
Oh, how is this?
Yes, remember to be careful when you walk.
I spilled a little glue on the floor.
Remember to be careful.
Delicious miracle glue.
Hey, little one.
What's wrong now?
Stop this startling rambling now.
It doesn't work, you have to boil the glue so that it thickens.
You're not ruining my hella.
Oh, what a mess.
My new miracle glue.
You know that's my best pair of boots.
The only thing suitable for glue.
The sappa I just cooked for you.
JA took off his pants.
This is my favorite glue bowl.
Well, it happened to be on the table.
Oh my gosh, how could you.
Deliver your disgusting substance immediately.
The test is in progress, as I said.
I mean nothing to you, do I?
Of course mark, try try try try.
I'm try try try.
Nothing for me, right?
Mark of course.
Try to understand that the exam is more important than my bowl of glue.
Oh, you're destroying our home and you dare to talk about stupid tests.
You can be sure that everyone will get along without your glue.
Just like before.
I'm leaving.
When you leave, right?
Don't come back.
Could he not be serious?
Wow, what a catch.
I have rarely seen such a big fish.
Can I make it myself?
Well, sure.
Can we manage to eat the whole fish?
Hardly.
That's why I thought of organizing memorable fish cakes tomorrow.
I'm a great idea.
I bake a melt-in-your-mouth pie for dessert.
I have tasted your pie.
And when the oven got too hot.
Yes, then.
Father's bread plum pie.
The way you like it the most.
Let it cool down without.
Well, that's fine.
Oh, You're not cooking are you?
I.
I don't cook food for the damp.
Don't you?
In.
I.
Yeah right.
The glue is ready.
Now the food tastes good too.
Strengthen that glue again.
I have floated palm and mouth.
I'm getting wet.
Tomorrow boy.
Aren't you awake yet?
Wake up, yeah.
It's a lot of time.
Today we are organizing those fish crackers.
Let's work no matter how much.
The weather is wonderful.
Breakfast is ready. Come down.
Like.
Delicious ash.
Who is behind it?
Oh, I'm getting wet.
Oh, good morning grandma.
Good morning Grandma.
Well, tomorrow.
You have already prepared breakfast.
I thought it was the least I could do.
Sell tomorrow. Why are you up so early?
None of your business.
Tomorrow's rolls.
Appetite.
Oh good.
Processed.
Tastes like aini.
Niisku front. Someone will make you the perfect wife.
Ah. Isn't it Ihaa?
What do you mean?
Guess.
Oh my gosh.
I'm so quick in my turns.
Oh.
I want to do everything myself.
From the start.
You would have cut the wound on your finger.
Little sells.
Today you have to help us.
Who? Me?
Because you live with Moomins.
You should help sometime.
Don't sleep.
You don't need to help either.
I'm getting wet.
It's better for us to help.
Niisku front. It's better for us to have you as our guest.
Hey.
I might stay in the mummy house for a longer time.
I don't want to burden you under any circumstances.
I'm getting wet.
Is something wrong?
No.
There isn't.
I'm not going to go back to insufferable brotherhood.
Nice to have a little helper.
Ai.
About arrest warrants.
Mamma.
What's wrong daddy?
I think I'll stop by Niisku's.
I'll find out why Niisku's eti is angry with him.
Even Niisku feels better when he knows that Niisku's eti is with us.
That's fine.
See you soon.
Good luck on your journey.
Share or that's the way things are.
What should I do?
So.
It's not very easy.
How about baking a pie?
Or a pie?
Exactly.
You say you're sorry.
And you offer reconciliation...
...hand.
And then you realize that you are really sorry.
And but Niisku's eti is so stupid.
In for a penny in for a pound.
But I can't guarantee the pie.
I have never baked anything in my life.
Don't worry Niisku.
I'll help you with the baking.
Take it as a science experiment.
As an experiment?
Well why not.
Good.
I suggest we start right away.
Ready for dawn.
Moomin is such a toupee.
Even jump to dig if Niisku's eti tells you to.
Moomin, when you have hung the lanterns...
...gather flowers for the table.
Moomin suddenly.
I still need to cook the broth for the sauce.
Great.
Grind pepper on top of the pieces of fish before putting them in the oven.
Did you understand?
Did you understand friend?
It's worth listening to.
Wow dad.
Hi sell.
What are you blowing?
You are picking plums.
Plums?
Yeah, I'm baking a pie.
Huh, ollu.
Papa Moomin has promised to help me.
Yes, to agree with Ed of Niisku.
Then I want to help too.
That's unheard of.
Are you familiar with the secrets of cooking?
I know how to bake a pie even though I've never baked.
Should have guessed.
Or so?
I bake a worse pie than you.
Is that so?
It's been bad luck so far.
The oven got too hot last time.
But now I can.
Or so, well.
I read the instructions carefully.
Is everything ready now?
There is. I wouldn't have made it without your help.
Oh, you did most of it.
You are such a different character when you do household chores.
Oh, is it me?
It's all Niisku's fault.
Is it because of the humidity?
He doesn't care about anything but his exams.
He doesn't mind housework.
Oh yeah, but he's a bit of an inventor.
And he will become famous.
Niisku is a different country.
Ai, ai.
Yes, I know.
I think I have been too demanding.
I apologize.
Good idea.
It is already ready to sell.
And not! The dough is kneaded for a long time!
Why hasn't a machine been invented for this job?
About.
Hilno is ready.
The oven is hot enough.
The dough is not ready.
Yeah, it looks pretty good to me.
But it isn't!
Well, it is.
But I'll tell you what to do then.
Share, next we will hit the dough with a rolling pin.
Am I not?
I'm ready.
Dough with a rolling pin.
Not spread first?
First we hit with a rolling pin.
Sounds weird.
But once you know...
The seller may be right.
Baking is the job of pop men.
Why does the dough behave like that?
Curious thing.
Now I remember what to do.
We sprinkle flour here so it doesn't stick.
Absolutely. That's how it is.
Isn't selling enough already?
Suffice!
That's it, spreads well.
It's starting to look like a pie.
Moominpappa's blows to Myy were like making a pie.
Hey!
debts
Where did father and Little Myy disappear?
Well yes. They should come soon.
I shouldn't come soon.
Hello, Moomin Goblin.
Evening.
Welcome to fish crackers. Thank you for coming.
Hello everyone.
Hi, Nipsu.
Have you started? I'm hungry.
Moomin, would you be so kind as to bring the juice bottles from the kitchen?
I can apply.
I'll come along.
That's where dad comes from.
And the little one sells.
And Niisku.
Aha.
Come to the table.
Thanks.
Let's get started.
Miss Niisku, your brother came.
What Niiskuka?
So suddenly.
Put the juice bottles on the table.
Tule.
Great.
Small.
Niisku, you haven't been seen.
How is your ship progressing?
Thank you very much.
An accurate miniature model is already ready.
Oh miniature model?
Joo.
Good smell.
There's something delicious about you.
What is it?
Nothing much.
Moisture.
Wet girl.
The one from yesterday.
I...
I know, Miss Niisku.
I was wrong and I'm sorry.
Oh Niisku.
I have a little surprise for you here.
Oh Anka.
Jak's new invention, huh?
Not exactly an invention.
Soon.
Oh lovely.
Someone would suggest that you like
plum from the top so that...
And I did the dishes
your favorite dish too.
Oh, thank you, Niisku.
I am so happy...
Moisture,
i love you
wet girl,
don't stop, everyone is watching.
Let's see.
When Niiskunneiti and Niisku had made up, the parties could begin.
And surprisingly, Moomin's fishing line didn't turn out to be too big at all.