The day looked calm. It felt and even smelled calm, but it turned out to be anything but calm.
Today's lie in a hammock.
Good morning.
Little sell, good morning.
You seem satisfied with your life.
I am too. The housework is done and after breakfast I throw myself in the hammock. I listen to birdsong and maybe take a nap.
Moominpapa has the same guarantees.
So be it, but I'm going to make it first.
I will help you. I'm fighting papa.
It's hardly necessary.
Who comes this early?
Good morning.
Oh my sister!
Hey mymmeli!
Are you here already? Well, one child you here.
Oh what do you mean? Don't belittle me!
Good morning, sorry to bother you.
Nothing can disturb me today. Does the coffee taste good?
Thanks.
Go to the bottom. You look worried.
I'm in dire straits.
What is it?
My mother came to visit unexpectedly.
What concern is that?
Mom didn't come alone.
But with my sister and brother.
There are a lot of them.
I don't understand how I can fit them in my little house.
No sweat. Let's invite them here. We have a lot of rooms.
Well, the little one already lives with you.
I could take him home.
Myi is part of the family. There's nothing to worry about, mumbled.
Moominpapa!
Bring the cat anytime?
Well, to be honest, they're already waiting behind the door.
Let's let them in.
What amount?
Be tidy guys!
Hey mom!
Hello alte.
Welcome to Muuni House.
Little baby, you've grown up.
Mom, can I have Moominpapa and Moominma on the flyers?
I hear you can stay here.
I hope there aren't too many of us.
It's just fun.
I hope you have a good time with us. Make yourself at home.
Sot canteens in bills. How in the world has my life blessed you?
There should be ten of them, unless I've missed someone.
It's hard to keep them together.
Or ten? You'd think there would be more.
Someone is sleeping here.
Fun! And the sheath!
Here is something big and round.
I'm dreaming.
Many to sell, what a nightmare.
I can't even dream.
Hey, get those crooks out of my face.
Wait a minute!
Ah, I caught it.
Good mummy!
Hey, who are these rascals?
Good morning mummy.
Who are these horrible brats?
Unfortunately for my siblings, they stay here.
What for?
Oh, it's so peaceful here.
Children have quite a workplace.
I let them be free.
Yeah, I totally understand.
Sometimes I have to intervene in fights.
Come on, how?
You won't take it from me.
Just take a minute.
For example like this.
did you see
Joo.
Mother, mother.
That too.
Moomin, you there?
Mom, what are those wild trolls?
They are sales fields and sister series.
Will you help to slice?
What's wrong?
The kids were here for a while.
They probably had fun.
I also sell too thick ones from relatives.
Be patient.
They are only staying here for a day.
It is not certain whether their house collapsed.
What are you whining about?
Collapsed like a house of cards.
The walls couldn't take the games of these idiots anymore.
Don't they have anywhere to go?
Apparently not.
Mom, the kids like the Moomin house because it's much bigger than their old house.
Yes, and it's still standing.
A little nugget.
Let's be nice to them.
Let's try at least.
Is it clear mummy?
I'm terribly tired.
This is my bed.
Go your way.
We like this.
Doesn't move me.
And not another bed.
There's one more here.
Little sells.
Kiisee, little sister and that's why I came here.
I need rest sometimes too.
Don't laugh.
I couldn't sleep for a moment and now I'm shaking everywhere.
Oh, the little rascals from them have fallen home.
My foot scraper.
I can't stand another night like that.
You happy live alone.
Well, move out of the house.
Me?
You could build your own house.
I have no idea about construction.
How do you know you've never tried?
You don't just build a house like that.
Most houses are built.
Wouldn't it be great to own your own house and wouldn't it be fun to snitch?
I don't even know where to start.
Your father has built a Moomin house.
He has books on the subject.
Dad's?
It sure is.
That's what I want.
Not bad.
Myy.
Do you want to build a house?
Joo.
Your beastly sisterly brothers have been spinning around my legs all day.
I would like to live alone.
I'll be a helper.
Thanks.
The book says that a house starts with the cornerstone.
There are suitable stones there.
These are fine.
Oh.
Terribly heavy.
Don't get caught up in it.
Hey.
What? Now this is olevida.
I didn't realize it was your home.
Sorry, stinky.
The saw thing.
Myy.
Enter a new one.
How many saws do you need for one frame?
Everyone seems to be stuck in the middle.
It's the last saw.
What do they have in mind?
Hey.
Now.
Pumi Troll Are you trying to crush bones?
Aha.
The cornerstones are gone.
You haven't moved them.
Of course not.
You have moved them.
Build it yourself.
Myy.
You hurt me.
I'm going home.
Oh.
Goodbye.
Good to go.
I build a house without anyone's help.
Oh.
Be careful.
Will you stay intact?
Boomerang.
Dammit girl.
I fancy.
Nuuska muikkuinen told me that you are building a house.
I am.
What a wonderful surprise.
Our common house.
Otherwise, I have a different night snack.
Now I'll leave you alone to work.
Dammit girl.
Thanks.
It won't last.
I imagined that Miss Niisku would have come to help.
When the house is ready, I will make fun of the people who come into the house.
Haa.
Good morning, Pumipeikka.
Have breakfast for you.
Ah, morning.
Sell, now I don't need help anymore.
Do you remember the job well?
The roof is just missing.
Pumipeikko, where is the door and windows?
Oh yes, the door and windows.
We are often built from behind.
Is that a door?
The door is a bit of the wrong cocaine.
At least it's not tight.
Why is there a track here?
You can get through it.
Uh, just thank you.
But I always wonder if there is a door and windows?
There isn't.
Is there a door and windows?
But I could have passed under the door.
It rained.
And I haven't done the roof yet.
I run to get some kind of tarp.
I'll help with the roofing.
It would be better to do this on a rainy day.
Sell, hold tight.
Sell, how do you cope?
Very.
Is the door and roof starting to fall into place?
Is the roof really in place?
On, on.
But the skylight leaks.
Oh, you have one too.
It's a little chilly here.
I think you need to build a furnace.
Tuuskamuikkunen. Tuuskamuikkunen.
Hi, I'm on the roof.
It's almost ready here.
Yeah. Horrible.
Oh, Moomin, the chimney is crooked.
Look.
I refuse. I like it this way.
It balances the house nicely.
Thoughtful thing.
Really?
Oh, boys.
A very unusual house.
What is this needed for?
I'm waiting for a while. I'm coming down.
Joo.
Well, what do you think? It's really easy to get down.
But how do you get from downstairs to upstairs?
Yes, when I haven't built whores.
I had a brilliant idea.
Do you mean diga trees?
I don't. Much more fun. Leave it to me.
Lyy, is it ready?
Of course it is.
Well, not difficult at all.
It isn't.
It isn't. For one as small as you.
But how do I get here?
That was the last nail.
Well, now the house is ready.
Oh, looks a bit strange.
Look, mom and dad have to be invited to watch.
I guess so then.
Joo.
Six.
What, either the house is ready?
Good luck, Moomin.
Now wait until you see it first.
Let's take a look right away.
Let's go away.
Is it okay if I come along?
Of course. Where are the gold nuggets?
True indeed.
Well, they must be playing outside.
Hopefully.
There you are and everything is saved.
Dwarf-sized monsters come out from under me.
Please wait.
I'm next.
This is not an amusement park.
I have never seen my children so happy.
Moomin has been clever.
Verily.
What?
Would Moomipeikko let you live here when you get a new house?
Would it work out?
Moomin, do you agree?
Of course. Then I could move back home.
Oh thank you, Moomin. You have a great son.
Well, he happens to be a natural-born nigger.
I'm kind of glad we didn't have to live in your house.
Sometimes.
So.
I will build us a good house.
Oh great. That's where I want to live.