It was raining heavily in Muunilaak, as if someone had pulled a plug from the sky and made it disappear.
It was very, very wet indeed.
Mom, can I borrow this?
Of course.
Can I borrow this too?
You can, but what do you need them for?
Secret.
Or a secret.
You can keep the can, but I want the strainer back.
It was raining heavily in Muunilaak, as if someone had pulled a plug from the sky and made it disappear.
The heavy rain has made the ground wet.
Oh, I'm a hemuliparka.
Hemuli!
Good morning, Moomin.
The water is cloudy.
What are you up to?
I make important observations.
Great.
It's funny that botany interests you too. What are you going to research?
I'm sure I saw a handsome crab.
Young man, it belongs to zoology, which is a rather uninteresting field.
There it is.
I got it.
Good morning!
I got it, I got it.
Oh, Junkku.
Father!
What now?
Nothing.
Everything feels so fresh after the rain.
So.
Go show the snuff to the muikku. No one can see this before him.
Wake up.
Ha!
What's up with you?
Nothing. Nothing at all.
No need to pilot. I saw.
Just an empty jam jar given by my mother.
There's something in that.
I say it isn't.
Then why are you piloting?
The cat will take it. Why did I have to come across the little sale?
Salmon finger. I was right.
It must be a baby salmon roe.
It has come with the rain and it is the last salmon head on Earth.
How fun.
I hope I didn't scare you.
Let's open the lid to get some air.
Well, is it better now?
Moomin's little poplar tree.
What?
Hear it burned.
You're a raging little salmon snake.
I will take you into my care.
You sleep on my pillow at night.
Help. Of course you are very hungry.
Wait. I'll get you something from my nightstand first.
I'll take you from the nightstand.
Choose. Raisin cake is good.
Oh...
My little mutu mutu.
Granny goblin, to eat.
Joo.
Wait here. I'll be right back.
Don't worry, little crumb.
A small crumb.
Isn't Nipsu here?
He is collecting fishing worms.
He will come right away.
Shall we start?
Some keep secrets in glass jars.
In a glass jar?
Oh! Secrets that sizzle.
Moomin, I found this by the puddle.
My favorite Siivilä.
Moomin, you promised to return Siivilä.
Sorry mom, I got so excited, I mean I forgot.
It's clear who that someone is?
Did you catch something in Siivila?
He got something that he has hidden in the room.
Goof off.
If it's a secret, he might not want to talk about it.
Yes, when his pet bites.
Have you been bitten?
I would bite back.
Will it bite your secret?
The one that fits in the jam jar is so small that you can't take a bite.
Some keep poisonous scorpions or earthworms in a glass jar.
They are very small or inspiring and resourceful centipedes that multiply and multiply every week.
And then those expectations eat, encourage us all in the mouth.
I don't have centipedes.
There can be such things in outer space.
Honey, we live on earth.
But they could have fallen to the ground with the rain.
It really rained hard yesterday.
And it was no ordinary rain.
No, there's a lake-sized puddle outside.
What now?
It's not a centipede.
I think we are on the right track.
Glad it's not a poisonous centipede.
Moomin's little cult
Oh, you're sleeping.
Moomin's little cult.
I'm going to meet the snus muikku.
did you eat
Yes mom, tell no one to enter my room or I will not be responsible for the consequences.
Not a single living soul can open the door to your room.
He goes to tell the snuffer.
I hope we find out too.
Good friends always first.
Hello, little snuff.
Hey.
Going fishing again?
The cards said that somewhere to catch five roaches, I'm going south.
Oh, to the south, don't be silly.
You know I'm superstitious.
But winter won't come for a long time.
I know, I know, but the cards told.
That would be horrible.
I would be terribly lonely if you left.
Who would I talk to, who would I tell secrets to?
Oh yeah, I have something to show you.
Now?
So.
I can fish later.
Fishing is stupid.
But I have to get five roaches.
It won't work, it's been raining so hard lately that the fish won't eat anyway.
Maybe you're right.
So what's the secret?
Have you ever seen a salmon roe?
Of course not.
Salmon snakes already disappeared hundreds of years ago.
What if there was one more salmon snake alive somewhere?
Out.
So small you could put it in a glass jar.
Looks like a napping mummy, Pikko.
I won't believe until I see.
But if I see, I believe, no matter how pointless it was.
Where is it?
Mom wasn't supposed to let anyone in my room.
Not here either.
Holy shit, you were right.
There it is.
Real salmon fillet.
How did it get up there?
It must not fall.
Be very quiet.
Wait.
Don't, don't, don't say anything.
The tail can be broken if it falls.
Little one, don't be afraid.
Come now.
Fall down the ghost will trap you down.
Very carefully.
Just, just, just calmly.
That's not a good way.
You scare it.
Let's leave it alone.
It comes down when it wants to.
Salmon snakes are not helpless.
But it's so tiny.
Come on, granny.
Come, come, come.
Don't, don't, don't.
Look at my salmon snake fly.
It can fly.
I did see it.
Come down to my salmon skinned beauty.
You won't fly into any gap.
Don't, don't, don't, don't.
Don't, don't, don't.
Snuff Muikkunen it Bite me.
An amusing creature. What is it going to do now?
It seems to like you.
Oh.
A very unusual home life.
What piece of cake? What is its name?
It doesn't have a name.
Not even a bite to begin with.
Small but wild.
Just like you.
Do you think so?
No.
Oh.
Stop.
It seems to fall on deaf ears.
It doesn't bother Snuska Muikkunen's ears.
Why doesn't it bite the snuff?
Goodness.
I think it's trying to heat up Snuff Muikkunen's coffee.
It's bigger.
Whoa. What a perfect lighter for pleasure trips.
Well, that's enough.
Is it just big?
We can keep it in the basement instead of the heating boiler.
It's out of the question.
You damn.
Terrible lizard too.
It thought you were trying to take that fly.
If it bites me one more time, I will show it.
Come to the goblin.
Oh.
Thanks for the coffee.
Let's continue my journey from here.
It suffocates in that area.
It just likes sniffing.
After all, we all like snuff.
Stupid salmon roe.
And it isn't.
Moomin, I'll be so kind as to take the salmon snake to your room.
Neither do I. That's better.
Oh dear. Will it come?
Will it ever come back?
We could have kept ear muffs.
You can go and say hello to that snuff muikku's tent.
It's sitting on the shoulder of a snuff snot.
Nuuska Muikkunen is leaving for the south soon, so let me go with him.
My troll gold.
The worst place.
Fall back to the Moomin.
House, mene pois. House!
Don't do that. Back to Moomin.
You're nice and it would be fun to keep you company.
But think of Moomin.
Oh, another one.
The fifth roach. It even is.
Now what?
That's what he brings. Going far?
Well, for a while.
You will get a unit.
Let's go.
Are you far away?
Well, for a while.
You will definitely get hungry.
Do you catch fish?
What do you want in return?
A small favor.
Carry this pitcher as far as you can.
And then I leave it?
So. Somewhere nice where there are a lot of flies.
Oh flies?
So.
So what's in this jug?
Salmon finger.
Even something. Does it bite?
It is possible. Keep the lid closed.
But open it then the salmon snake can catch flies.
You are asking for a great service. And I don't even like roaches.
They are delicious when fried.
Hey.
Where is it?
What is it?
Salmon finger.
I guess it came here?
No. I thought it was in your room sleeping.
No. I let it out the window.
Oh well. The salmon roe are stunning.
They don't really care about anything else as long as they get it.
Did you get five roaches?
I don't. You were right. The fish won't eat.
Right?
So I don't think I'll even go south.
So you're staying here?
Ice. I'm superstitious. I dare not oppose the cards.
Oh. It's good there. Oh, what fun. Top. Lovely.
Hey.
Top. Lovely.
Maybe I shouldn't have painted the ridge red.
It can spook the fish. Shall we go back?
Joo.
The salmon finger was really stupid.
Salmon snakes are stupid. They are probably the worst domestic animals that exist.
True.
I just thought it was an amusing case when a salmon snake would bite a small mullet.
Moomin was very happy that Nuuska Muikkunen still stayed in Moomin Valley.
And who cares about a fool's affection for salmon snakes.