The moon has turned red.
Look how the moon cancels out in red.
Amazing.
Maybe the moon is a shame elevator for some reason, or what do you think?
Oh, Nipsu, you really are a bit intelligent.
How so?
I am.
Count, count, count, count, count, count, count, count, count, count
Good evening everyone. Isn't it a wonderful moonlight or what?
Huh, is it amazing?
Don't you think the tree is somehow a bad omen?
Not at all.
Or rather, the most beautiful moon I've ever seen.
I've always wanted to see a real red moon, and tomorrow is a full moon to top it off.
The blood-red hearing room, that's just a sight.
Is it red at six in the evening?
That would be so much fun.
May the red moon bring you no misfortune.
For example, a volcanic eruption.
Nipsu, you mustn't scare me.
The red moon is ahead.
Judgment day is coming.
Have you ever seen such an eerie moon before?
Believe it or not, it's a bad omen.
Dad, are you sick?
I hear you're getting a vertigo attack?
I wonder what that red flaming moon is trying to tell us.
What makes you sing so much?
Ohikas, good evening, Moomins.
Hemuli, you purr with satisfaction like a cat.
Why wouldn't I be satisfied?
Didn't you see what the moon was like yesterday?
That's me, don't kid me.
But how about that ominous color?
Ominous?
That's right, you shouldn't have a reason to grin.
I would say that the moon was quite an attractive color.
Or inflammatory?
Hemuli has always been strange.
Aren't you worried at all?
No, and I'll tell you why.
For me, next night will be the best ever.
Namely, I get to know what my grandfather has bequeathed to me.
Just don't say you won't see the whole will.
Grandfather bequeathed me a seed,
which can only be sown during the red full moon.
What is that miracle seed?
No, it's a lucky tree seed.
Or a lucky tree seed?
Does that tree bring you luck then?
Oh, how wonderful.
Of course, even if I get large amounts of gold.
Also, the chicken's brain, the lucky tree is not yours, but Hemul's heirloom tree.
I have no idea what fraction luck manifests in.
But it will be seen when I have planted the seed.
It's so exciting, oh, that...
Father, do you believe Hemul?
I'm not sure.
Here it is, the seed that brings happiness.
Good seed.
I plant the seed of happiness here, and I talk to it every day.
The pit is ready.
The seed is gone, I put it on this stump.
The lucky tree seed is gone.
I need to calm down, the seed was here.
What the hell.
Vanna Hemuli doesn't need any more lucky seeds.
It would be fun to know what it tastes like.
Or should it be roasted on fire first?
Oh my God, oh my God.
I'm like that.
Mamma.
What my darling?
I feel strange.
Like I got stung by the moon.
Hi, have you seen any bandits here?
Bandits? I don't remember seeing it.
Hemuli, what happened?
The lucky seed has disappeared, someone has stolen it.
Can you imagine?
If you see a suspicious looking guy, let me know!
Ari was busy!
Hemuli wasted the seed that makes rich.
Too much tension is clearly not good for Hemul.
Like everyone got a shot of the moon.
I want my happiness back!
Hemuli has been behaving strangely since last night.
Well, maybe.
The seed of the lucky tree has disappeared, come and find it!
A lucky seed?
Maybe the seed is somehow related to the red moon.
Hemuli runs to the police station.
Hemuli, could you describe the wheel of the seed and its size?
When you knock on it, there is a hollow sound, is there any special characteristic?
Or even a special identifier?
It's pointless because the seed is the only quality.
Oh, I'm sorry.
What makes a particular seed so important?
Policeman, it's not just any seed,
but at the same time special and unique.
You are the Moominvalley policeman,
and your job is to track down your stolen Christmas.
Well, that's fine, that's fine. Don't speed up.
But tell me, what is so remarkable about the seed?
When you are so serious, there must be some special aspect related to the seed.
Yeah, yeah. That's right, yeah. Absolutely.
Terrible things happen, find it yesterday.
What? What kind of horrors?
So, when the thing is that...
Night...
All right. I'm only telling you this secret.
This is then strictly confidential.
I'm just an ear.
Before find the seed before evening.
Kuupu brings Moominvalley from the sky to the neck, and everything goes to pieces.
What? Terrible!
I don't believe it.
The magic power of the seed prevents the moon from falling.
I'm a man of science and I know. It's okay for you to believe me.
For which we find the seed before night falls, Moomin Valley is no more.
Oh good miracle.
What do we do?
Let's cheer everyone!
Good. And do your best.
And not a word about the falling moon.
It's okay!
Sorry for the slight exaggeration.
I had to come up with something scary.
The police chief would not have believed me otherwise.
Shut up!
I heard when Hemuli told the police chief.
We must escape or be crushed.
I saw a big swarm of wattles.
Did you really hear about falling?
Let's ask Hemul.
Let's find out right away.
I'm sure the police chief will find a seed in no time.
Hemuli!
Did you find the seed?
Now here we are at the opposite side!
How so?
The rumor that the hood from the sky has spread to Moomin Valley like wildfire!
The whole Moomin valley is!
How is that possible?
Lord time!
Now the villagers are coming here!
The sky is starry!
No, no, no! Try to calm down!
Hemuli, is it true that the hood is coming to Moominvalley tonight?
Tell us the truth!
The truth, Hemuli!
That...
Hemuli, let us speak the truth, we are waiting!
Truth or nothing!
That, yeah, yeah!
So it's true, we all crush!
We must hike!
Good gentlemen!
We have to blow coal together and try to save Johan, the oldest multi-villager in the country!
Joo!
Oh, oh, what do I do now? I can no longer admit that I cheated.
I went too far in my carelessness.
This is getting out of hand!
I can't believe this is true!
Such a terrible upheaval threatens!
My teeth can handle us!
Oh!
I hear you're having more soup?
No, thank you.
It's hard for him to believe that another vilakso is about to fall.
I wouldn't want to believe that either.
However, if that is true, how about us then?
There will be devastation 100 times greater than after a hurricane!
Mm, 1000 times bigger.
I can't think of a single place where I could wear a shirt.
Oh, oh, well either again?
Moomin is the owner of destruction and us with it, you and me.
Don't worry!
I cave in the lonely mountains and crawl under the frying pan.
Ah, what a wonderful dinner it was.
I have to go now.
Where are you going?
It's a secret.
Good wonder papa, what are you doing?
Why are the books lying around?
Hi mom, I'm here.
I don't see, where?
Here.
What did you blow?
I was choosing books to take with me.
All books are important to me, like this one.
What book is that?
This book gave me Kimmoke to become a writer.
Only you and Moomin-Pekko are more important in life there than books.
Books are just as important to me.
Really?
For example, grandma's home medicine book is priceless.
We are very similar.
So.
Many books have already happened.
The entire Moomin House is full of beautiful memories gilded by time.
Well, it is.
Hey, waiting!
Where are you going?
Something like that.
Hey, what's up there?
Oh where?
I won't tell.
Help!
Where are you going?
Just poop out.
Oops, balloons.
What are you going to do with those balloons?
This is an air pack so you know if the moon falls from the sky and there is a lack of air,
so this air pack will save me.
Hey, don't tell anyone that no one steals their business idea.
That was it.
Very pinchy.
Oh, Mother Whip.
What's wrong?
Saloo, what's wrong with you?
And all.
How are you so calm when it's all over next night?
Maybe not calm now, rather tense.
I still don't really believe the whole thing.
Don't try to console.
What were you ashamed of?
Nothing.
Swamp lady, what's up?
He said.
What are you crying for?
Muvi mamma, why am I so sad, even though others are just excited?
Hyys, marsh lady.
We go to the cave in the lonely mountains.
We are safe there.
Don't bother crying.
Niiskunöti Honey, give me your hand.
Ladies and gentlemen.
This air pack makes you feel completely safe.
Please come and shop when the weather is good.
That you skit!
You are trying to profit from a terrible natural disaster.
I'm of no use.
Nobody buys.
Hey, there's one more light burning in the bay.
That's right.
What's going on in the Moomin house?
Hey, make way.
It's true, there is a light.
Why is there a buzz in the Moomin house?
I guess they don't play music there.
They're always just crazier.
Hey, what do I bring?
I'm about to go up.
Isn't it beautiful?
I started getting into the party spirit.
See alta!
Wow, great cake.
Oh, oh mom, what a filling cake.
I put all my baking skills into play.
The most amazing cake I've ever seen.
Fortunately, the jerk isn't here.
You'll get more.
Ha, I knew that.
You eat a full cake when I'm not there.
This has drawn you right into the cave.
A real cake, what is it baked for?
Good evening, dear villagers.
We want to celebrate a little under the guise that we have had many fun moments in Moominvalley.
Welcome to the group.
Do you believe that Moominvalley will soon cease to exist?
Honestly, I don't think so.
You skunk, good evening.
What's going on here?
We have a party. Come join the happy company.
Oh, will you let me come too?
Of course. You live in Moominvalley.
Oh, thank you.
Stink, you know a lot of funny stuff. Don't you know?
Neither do I. I don't really know.
You do know.
You know. I'll tell you about those pranks.
What if you get angry?
Don't get angry.
For once, you can be sure that you won't get angry.
Well, I'll tell you then.
Ladies and gentlemen.
Now you have a unique opportunity to hear about the skunk's kolttos.
Let's start with Mrs. Viljonga.
I put that toad here in his bathtub.
And I washed those spiders in the powder box of Niiskunneid.
That's what I wanted to know.
I poured the glue into the mint jelly.
Oh, that was it.
I sprinkled pepper for sale.
That's what I suspected.
I graffitied the entire police station.
What? Did you do it?
Palliative care.
There were a few carousels in it.
Stinky, I really get excited about those pranks.
Pepper is enough.
Right. I could say more.
Tell me about the last villain meeting.
Oh, that's right.
This morning I went to visit the hemuli.
Onne Siemeni, this one.
Good, good miracle.
Stinky, how could you?
The shell of the seed sometimes clicked quite promisingly.
But it's so hard you can't break it.
Not at all.
Hemuli, this means that Moomin Valley has been saved.
Cheers, cheers, cheers.
Stink, I'll give you a Seed in memory.
But it was so important to you.
Dear Mr. Vekijo, I am very sorry to have caused you trouble.
And I made you believe that the hood will bring your neck.
It was actually a lie.
I lied so that the police chief would get serious about looking for Siemian.
And the Seed is not a seed of happiness either.
Honestly, I doubt there are any lucky trees.
I guess grandpa wanted me to plant a tree,
which would remind of him and the happy times together.
So, in this complete red pit.
Whoah!
Honey look.
Yep, uu isn't red anymore.
Just ordinary moonlight.
Oh, then again we saved.
Awesome, awesome!
Hey, it wasn't a problem in the first place!
Get out of the way, get out of the way!
Shut up, there's no reason to jump for joy.
Who are we to blame for this madness?
Hemulia, hemulia!
Well no, the culprit is Haisuli.
It sucks for someone.
ha Isu Li, ha Isu Li, ha Isu Li.
Well, Haisul must be punished.
The skunk lives for fun. What?
Goodbye.
A true seed of happiness when a tooth broke.
It was just a mess.
It was, but...
What, nitwit?
However, the main thing is that we have each other.
So yeah.