So when Eiti runs as if Mörkö is on her hips, I've hardly ever seen her run as fast.
What is the matter now?
Granny Goblin! Grandma help me!
Calm down, tell me what's wrong.
My brother is going to jump off a cliff.
Nice to meet you.
I hurt him.
He says he'll jump anyway.
Granny Goblin, stop it.
So Eiti, how can I help?
So you can't jump from the southern slope of the cliff.
Oh, he's the type.
So when you go on a test flight.
Good vibes.
So, Eiti, do you mean that your brother's flying horse is finally finished?
Oh no, Blueprint probably just.
That's already something.
He has built the model pieces of the wings of his future flying kite.
But to me they look far too flimsy to be worth it.
They will never be able to support him, never.
Ahaa, share, and now that you are going to try in practice how the wings of the flight attractor work.
Prevents his experiment.
Block the father.
Did you say south facing slope?
I said, it is the steepest and the highest.
Then speed up everything.
Not enough time to waste.
Oh, thank you, Grandma, thank you.
Now.
Niisku, at least those my brothers.
Stand Niisku, don't jump.
Why have you dragged everyone here?
You are far too young to end your day so mournfully.
Fortunately, we managed to save you.
No ettepäs.
Get wet!
Seems like a dangerous experiment.
I built the wings myself.
A strong argument, but still.
I have made exact blue copies. The wings are safe.
Why did you stop suddenly when you were running fast down the slope?
I measured how much speed I needed.
Don't jump, Niisku. I don't want to lose you.
Don't whine, Niisku-neiti.
Can the wings be trusted?
Of course, birds don't fall from the sky either.
Why not try flying closer to the ground?
That way you won't hurt yourself if you fall.
I already tried. I successfully jumped from the roof of the house.
Can you see?
That's how it happened.
I don't think I'm going to jump in front of the rabbit pants.
So what did that mean?
It's just that I don't want you to push one.
It's just that I don't want you to push one measure of your big scum into my affairs.
My business is just as big.
I don't want to lose you.
Then don't continue.
Let's start being people.
Varukaa.
Whoops. I don't think your brother's intentions can be prevented.
Niisku, you are brave.
Now to do it.
This time I'll take a proper start.
Oh, isn't there Nuuska Muikkunen over there?
Where is Nuuska Muikkunen?
You won't see him for that. Get up here.
Where is it?
Down there.
I mumble!
Hi! Did you hear here?
I guess not.
Now let's go.
Good luck on your journey.
It works.
Oh.
It's damp.
impressive
and
it's like
Oh, wonderful!
Do you see, Niskunneiti? Brother on display, this fills the cage!
Oh, he indulged...
I thought he would make it.
Truth be told, so do I.
Ai...
Yeah, yeah, Nisku!
Low!
Misko!
Hey!
Good, good!
The trial will be a resounding success.
Hey!
As I thought, he can't fly and splash at the same time.
You are low.
He will fall if you wave with either hand.
Stink, you are not needed here. Get out of here right away.
That trick could be useful.
I'll go if you stay.
It would be suitable for robberies, because you could get over high fences.
The wind blows the breeze into the sea.
Why didn't you turn around and come back?
It can be difficult to change direction.
Maybe you can turn around.
Of course, you can't.
Hello! What is this? I can't turn around.
Hey!
He hit a tree. Quick help.
Did he die?
No, got a concussion.
Looks dead. And where are the wings?
They stayed up.
Niisku is tired of Takuu's wings.
I'll get them.
The test flight went well, huh?
Yeah, I guess. Except at the end.
I'm pretty sure all you need is more practice.
Well, share, if only iodine and plasters are enough.
I hear you, Niisku.
So?
Oh, are you still using it?
In.
I want to float in the sky too.
It looks like the funniest thing I've ever seen in my life.
Yes, but the flight characteristics of the wings should be tested.
Of course, that's clear. I'll try for you.
Could you maybe give it a try?
Joo.
That's clear. I'll try for you.
Could you possibly help somehow, Moomin?
You didn't answer yet, can I have wings?
You can. On one condition.
Agree to anything?
Now that I have the blue copies ready and the wings are more or less in order,
I need a place to build my mess.
That's what you really need.
It doesn't have to be spectacular, as long as it's on top of the roof,
that no one can spy and steal my wonderful invention.
You get wings for help.
Agreed.
I would have helped anyway, but now that I'm getting my wings, I work with double the enthusiasm.
It's a great thing, that's for sure.
Maybe you will get other eager helpers.
I'm snotty.
Necessarily.
Nipsu, Will you help?
Yeah, but I want something too.
Well, you can borrow wings.
I don't want to break them, I'm too heavy.
Don't worry, I'll try to figure something out.
Something nice, oh I'll be happy to help.
Nipsu, you ooze goodness.
You will definitely need the help of an expert when building a shed.
We're already deep enough.
No, we Moomins build thoroughly and I like the cement ready.
Clear.
Talk.
I've been thinking about it.
You will get one of my worthless machine building books.
A book?
And you don't want to?
If you happen to have anything else.
Would you like my worthless fountain pen?
I don't write much.
What about worthless?
Would there be something that is not worthless?
Aha, a gold coin.
Wow, that sounds like something.
Oh, boys, a real gold coin.
You are digging a really deep hole.
Stop and come eat bread and butter.
In the middle of everything.
So?
Maybe the depth of montu is enough.
Your brother and Nipsu are in the forest.
I know.
Hello, Miss Nisku.
Aah.
Hi, I have a question.
Then ask.
Is it true that your brother gave you a Moomin?
And, and, and.
In.
Sivet Moomin is nice.
Then ask.
Is it true that your brother gave the Moomins the boobies?
There is. Moominpiikko helps build the shed as a guest.
Didn't the straws break in the rush?
My brother is fixing them right now.
You know, I'll take him lunch.
Can your brother fix civets?
He can fix just about anything.
You need an awful lot of wood.
The shed has to be much bigger than the flywheel.
Moomin and Papa Moomin are digging a deep hole.
Everyone is so kind and helpful.
I don't think it's time to go get some nails.
Excellent!
Write him a note about other supplies.
Yes dear brother, you are so planful.
Famous inventors must be.
The aircraft shelter was completed in record time.
Whether it was due to Niisku's design skills or the fact that
that almost everyone in Moomin Valley lent a helping hand to Niisku.
Thanks.
Ugh, building the shed was fun.
I have slightly changed the model of the wings.
Now it's easier to take off and land.
It is more convenient to turn the wings.
Thanks. I can hardly sleep next night because of the excitement.
When will you try the wings?
Tomorrow.
Be careful.
Practice close to the ground before going higher.
I would feel terrible if something happened.
All right.
Where are you going to practice tomorrow?
I don't know yet.
Right on that little hillock, near the cliff.
Good, it's not dangerous. See you there.
Good.
Hello. I don't see wings.
If you came through Kust's door, you couldn't help but see them.
They are on the table.
On the table? There was nothing.
There was nothing.
On the table.
Hey.
You are right. My wings are gone.
Of course I'm right.
What could have happened to them?
Someone has walked them.
What's wrong with you two?
Someone has walked on Moomin's wings.
Maybe they haven't really been stolen.
It is. And I do know who took them.
Where do we start looking for wings?
AI Suri.
You again. It didn't last long.
Aisuli, wait. The wings are mine.
I knew you walked them.
Abomination in that too.
Don't think so.
Let's wait.
I'll let you borrow the wings later.
No, no. I need wings to accelerate my career.
Varu's Moomin brat.
No.
Iti covers that too.
With the help of wings, I become a vestari criminal.
Aisuli is a vile scoundrel.
You shouldn't have left the wings out.
Who would have thought that Aisuli would steal from us.
We are his friends. Or at least almost.
But my coin was saved.
Don't mourn Moomin.
We still get wings.
I give Aisul a muzzle.
Aisuli drifts into the sea.
What is this?
I'll go out of harm's way.
Aisuli didn't know how to handle wings.
And drifted farther and farther.
AI Suri.
I just had to take a bath.
I guess the wings went sour.
Niisku builds new wings for you.
Aisul's mokoma.
AI Suri.