Hemuli is walking again in Moomin Valley looking for rare plants for his collection.
Lord time.
ha I Su Li!
Huh? I'm searching.
Stink, why are you always up to mischief?
Eh, I just know.
What if someone kicked you?
Yes, but when you see someone bending over like that, at least I can't avoid the temptation to kick the little one. Can you do it yourself?
It's like a little devil lives inside you.
Oh what? Well, that's how it is! It's that nasty little devil who tells me to do all the defiance that I would otherwise do in the world.
Then tell it to come out.
Oh, just about that? How can that really work out?
Let's think.
Does the snob know how to do it?
Do you want to evict it?
Of course.
Then it's pretty easy.
Tell me in wonder.
There is nothing evil about you.
Right?
It's just your imagination. You have to make up your mind very firmly not to do any naughty things.
Must decide not to do naughty things.
Haisuli won't change for any reason.
Do you think so?
What do you think?
No.
There's no point in even trying.
There isn't.
Yes.
Good text.
Now I would like a cup of coffee made by my mother.
In.
Does a cup of coffee taste good?
Joo.
Perfect timing.
Yes.
I just thought to myself that I would like a cup of coffee now.
And then you came.
The writing seems to flow well.
Here is a new version of an old story about a devil living inside a tree.
You know.
Shall I have another cup?
What?
Oh, oh.
Oh.
I won't give up.
Hi Muli, what hatana?
I need to get that plant in my collection but I can't get up enough.
I can climb up and get it for you.
You are kind. With pleasure.
Thanks.
Youth is wonderful. You should become a botanist too.
Uh...
Digging plant from the ground with roots and leaves.
Be careful, Moomin-Pekko.
I'm almost there.
Uh...
ha I Su Li!
Uh!
Hehehe...
Are you OK?
It's a pretty flower, it's a shame I don't have a buttonhole.
It is Hemul's flower and you know it. Give it back right away.
I was here first. Will I become a botanist too?
That's enough now.
Uh...
Hehehe...
Plant park.
I'll help you find a similar one. Don't worry.
It seems that the devil really lives in Haisuli.
I think better that Haisuli is just being himself.
That's all.
Hehehe...
Have you ever seen a yellow flower this size...
...with a red middle part.
I guess you can't tell.
Because you don't talk.
Strange beings.
Capp. Hemuli, I found it nobody.
Did the Hattivats leave?
They left. Here is the rare plant you are looking for.
Let me see.
Oh, that's it.
Did you find it?
Yes.
Great.
How can I ever thank you enough, you are a good friend.
What about that?
Thanks to you too, Moomin goblin.
He was impossibly evil, even devilish.
But when he was caught, he began his shrill complaint, promising to be impossibly kind from now on, to help everyone and do favors.
But the captives didn't believe a word because they knew how to read the devil's thoughts.
It was locked in a small cave where it could do no more harm.
And even though it tried everything it could, it couldn't escape.
The name of the cave is still today Pirun Kolo, but no one knows where it got its name from.
It was a strange thing.
And what?
You just said that no one knows where that name comes from.
I meant that in my story no one knows where the name comes from.
Where is Pirun Kolo?
Well, there, in the distant forest where the story takes place.
How far is that forest?
I don't know.
You wrote that story.
It's just a story.
Is the whole story still a fairy tale?
This is a story that has been told from generation to generation and no one knows if it is true or not.
I still find it strange. If you know why it's Pirun Kolo, then others should know about it too.
All right. I'll rewrite it.
Niisku-neiti, would you like to hide?
Let's just be.
Why on earth are you cooking in here even though the sun is shining?
Muunipappa has written a new story and he read it to us.
Really?
It had a few weak points, but luckily we happened to be there to tell what was going on.
Did it really go that way?
Unfortunately, that's how it went.
I wouldn't have guessed that you are literary critics.
I can't help pointing out that we are excellent at that.
Well, just excuse me.
What if today we play a different game of hide and seek, if two of us hide together and everyone else searches?
As long as I don't end up hiding with Nipsu, he's as good at hiding as Ostrich.
We will share the pairs only when we get there.
How are the pairs distributed?
We can do a lottery. That would be fair.
I want to be your partner.
So do I.
Wrong lottery, did you hear? I want one of you to be my partner. In the game of hide and seek, you should be small. We wouldn't be found on Takuu.
I guess you told your mother that you went to play with us?
Did you tell mom?
I don't. Did you tell?
I didn't tell. I thought you told me because you're older.
Then no one told Vili who.
It won't be long enough for him to worry.
But you can't jump in the game of hide and seek either.
A pinch!
Nipsu and Niskunneiti found.
This is how Nipsu is the tail.
I told you to hide it.
I thought it was hidden.
Now we're going to hide with the little one.
Turn away and slowly count to twenty.
One, two, three, four, five, six.
I know a good hiding spot. Come after.
Eight, nine, ten.
Hey, look!
That must be a good hiding place.
We can't be found there.
Can't even be found.
It's harder for me to find a hiding place than you.
You can't fit in there, can you?
I am.
Tasteless Peikko! Tasteless Peikko!
We have been seen.
Long night!
Can they see me too?
But you checked it out.
I think you were making too much noise.
There's no one here.
I'm not sure.
Here I am.
who are you
And where would you hide?
I'm right in front of you.
In front of us is only a dead tree.
Right. And I am inside that Kelo.
Then you must be even smaller than me.
I used to be very big.
But then I was kind of melted here.
Just like that.
Yes, Moomin.
Oh, Moomin.
Did you ask him?
Look.
They don't even try to hide.
Or they got tired of waiting for us and came out of hiding.
Why are they staring at that tree so strangely?
Now I know.
What do you really know now?
An Evil Devil lives inside the tree.
Evil devil?
Confess, you are the Evil Devil.
It was wisely reasoned.
I didn't think you'd recognize me, but it's true.
I'm the devil.
What?
Right again.
Johan is incredible.
Are you talking to that tree?
We are not talking to that tree, but to the devil inside the tree.
To the devil?
Inside the tree? In Moominpapa's story it was in a small cave.
It wouldn't be the first time Moominpappa makes a mistake.
Even familiar stories change over hundreds of years.
You're smart too. You are smarter than you look.
If there's a real devil inside the tree, we should get out of here.
It should.
Wait, I've been inside a tree for 500 years.
I want out.
Sure, but you're an Evil Devil too.
I'm not mean anymore.
I can forgive all my mischief and now I have become a kind devil.
All right, believe me.
Hardly.
It certainly isn't.
If you could only see me, you would understand that you have nothing to worry about.
But you can never see me while I'm a prisoner here.
We don't care.
It's hard to be kind inside a tree.
What do we get out of it if we let you out?
Stop the rant.
You get whatever you want. I have great magical powers when you only wish.
We're not sure if we'll let you out.
He got it out. You can hear from his voice that he is kind.
Could I have a big sack of gold coins?
The second I get out.
Thanks.
We would also like to.
Please tell me.
We don't want mom to get mad at us if we're late for dinner.
It's fine. He won't even notice you're not home.
Wait a minute.
You don't want to let him out either, do you?
He is a kind devil these days.
I would really like a real pearl necklace.
You get it.
I want a new and twice as fast skateboard.
We don't know if the devil has changed.
It better not play tricks on me.
All that's left is the Moomin. What would you like?
All I want is for you to tell us the truth.
It'll be over soon. And you don't want anything else?
I don't. I have no other wishes. Just thank you.
You are stubborn.
Sorry I got nervous.
I am in such an impossible hurry to do good deeds for you.
How can we free you from inside the tree?
You have to push the reed in from the crack that is right in front of you.
That's how I get out.
But there are no reeds here.
Well, go find it then.
Or could it be found somewhere in a meadow?
Oh yeah, of course. Warm up.
A pinch, hey.
Hurry up. I can't wait to give you your gift.
Stink, what are you looking at?
Nus cam Ichinomiya year.
Sorry I took it. I wanted to return it to Hemull.
We already found another one. What exactly are they doing there?
Something strange is happening there. They're talking to that reel.
Hello! I found those reeds.
What the hell is Nipsu doing with the food?
That's it now.
Come on devil, get out of there.
Hm?
Urja-looking clouds.
Oh, oh, oh!
Five hundred years! Five hundred long years in prison!
Now I'm going to have fun!
He lied after all.
Of course. There is no such thing as a good or honest devil.
As long as I get those gold coins, then...
Did you imagine I would keep my promise?
Uh...
What were you thinking of doing? You are guaranteed to rust after 500 years.
First, I'm going to make devils out of you all.
And you don't. I'm running the paddock.
Aaaah!
I can't move.
Did you think you got away?
A real little devil.
It was inside that Kelo.
Ugh... It was really stupid to let it out of there.
Something has to be done about it. I'll go and put an end to this.
Nuskamukkonen wait!
Get ready, Moomin!
What do you mean?
You get to choose because you are the first.
Will you become a devil, a frog or a snake?
Ugh...
Who dares approach me?
Nuskamuikkunen, Moomin's friend.
Do you want to become a devil too?
I want to be like Moomin.
Ugh...
But before that, I would like to make sure of one thing.
What thing?
How do I know you're the real devil?
How dare you! So who do you think I am?
Well, you can be just a magician.
Or just a magician? How did you get such a head?
Well, when you poked around from behind that tree, then...
I came from inside the tree and not from behind it!
Hebe, hebe.
You're not kidding me. Not a large creature would be able to get through such a narrow food.
I'm the devil, and I can do whatever I want.
Just like that, but I did see you sneaking out from behind the tree.
Devils don't sneak around!
Will you believe me if I show you how it happened?
If I could see it with my own eyes, then...
I would like to see it too when I didn't see it properly before.
Well, concentrate properly then!
Jaista?
And it's not impressive...
Do you now believe in power like that?
P eviden moving again.
аемas Chad man.
Hey...
what did you do
,"Cad manRA Orthoङi."
I have
I can move again.
Mouska muikkunen.
Hello. what did you do Don't touch that reed. I can't get out.
Then you must remain there for another five hundred years.
Was I tricked back into Kelo?
I promised you that kickboard.
That ball device, I know what a kickboard is. I don't believe your transparency.
I think we're far enough away.
True.
Don't entangle me in the water. I can't create.
And don't get what you want.
Money, a skateboard and whatever else you ask for. Did you hear?
The coil was thrown far to the ulapa and soon the streamer was gone.
And when Moominpa came home, he wrote the whole story again.