I'll try, I'll try again.
hi what are you doing
Well, how did that happen?
The rain is so hard that I can't get the carrots up.
Yes, I'm frozen.
Experiment with a garden spade.
I'm so tough I can't get carrots up.
Yes, I'm frozen.
Experiment with a garden spade.
No, the ground is frozen solid.
We left this year's carrots in the ground.
Don't be sad Moomin, Goblin.
I cook the same soup, which does not need carrots.
It's just weird.
The earth shouldn't freeze this early.
No.
And so is the biting wind.
This boggles my mind.
The weather report promises beautiful and warm weather.
Weather reports can no longer be trusted at all.
Dad, what do you think?
Would the carrots come off the ground if you pour some kind of water on their roots?
Hardly worth the trouble.
Share, it will be tough in the winter, I say.
Oh, my goodness.
What?
The trees are so beautiful.
Yes, and how many rowan berries.
Not a hard winter for you.
Do you think so?
I can't say I like winter.
Ugh, the air smells like snow already.
We are at home.
Mom, we were chopping firewood.
More is needed.
Lovely scent.
A pinch.
Yeah, yeah.
Moomin, you bring enough trees inside.
We carry as much as we can handle.
Roll the carpet like this.
Wake up.
Ooh, now the claves are done.
Gotta get some water.
The first snow.
Hey, it started snowing.
Oh, how beautiful.
It will snow thickly.
A hundred more, more, more, more!
Yes, it rains because it's powder snow.
Bye! A hundred more, more, more!
A hundred more, a hundred more, hey!
Hey, hey, hey, hey!
It's snowing, it's snowing!
I think!
More, more, more, more!
Let's go, like what I did.
It's raining more, more, more, more!
You don't get snow! You won't get more snow!
It's time to take a winter break.
It is.
Honey, would you like some more hot juice?
No, thank you. I'm going to sleep now.
Oh, have a good winter, mom.
Have a good winter, honey.
Mamma, did you hear the knock?
I heard. As if there was someone at the door.
Who in which? Go take a look.
Joo.
Yeah, yeah. I'll open it.
Oops, the door is stuck. Peculiar.
Just a moment.
Oh, my heavens. The Moomin house is already buried in snow.
Mother, there's someone here.
Who is that?
Oh, gotta run upstairs to see.
There's a postman here.
Or a postman?
Special delivery.
Oh, so much snow.
Never seen before!
Thanks. Who can the package be from?
Oh, no sender name. Are you sure it's for us?
But you're Moomins, aren't you?
Sure, but still...
So I did my job well.
Goodbye.
Where did the children go?
I didn't notice.
Lots of snow.
Stay warm inside, you won't catch a cold.
Joo.
It has indeed been pointed out to us.
But why did it have to be brought here in the middle of the night?
What do you think? Could it be an early Christmas present?
Ha, maybe a delicious cake.
And it's not! The package has speed skates for me!
Maybe there is a message written inside.
So yes. Are we opening already?
Open, open!
What's there?
Oh, there was something moving.
I saw something flash too.
Something alive.
What is it?
Let's return the package.
The postman came such a long way for us that it is not possible to return it.
Unwrapped and opened the package.
What if it bites?
Aren't you a coward?
It's the Duck. I like Oranges and Fekings.
Where is the Duck?
Hi, who are you?
Soot cup.
Oh, how the same little creature.
Is it about you? I don't trust him at all.
First time I've seen something like that.
Is there anywhere to eat here? I'm very hungry.
Oh, I'm sorry.
It must have been terrible to be confined in a cramped box.
Little rascal. Moomin Mama gives you food.
I guess I came up with something.
Oh, boys, he eats a lot.
Good observation from a real big eater.
Can I have more?
Unfortunately, I don't have any more.
Oh well, not then. Thanks for the deal.
Come on, why were you sent here in the mail?
That was better than my mother.
What do you mean?
Well, when mom complained that I'm going to make her another nervous wreck.
What could he mean?
I don't know. Not yet.
He couldn't take care of you.
You must have been so naughty that he thought of getting rid of you.
Well, why anyway?
Selling was not a nice word.
Well, I guess I'll live here with you from now on.
At least you don't live with me?
You eat so much that we become beggars, that's for sure.
I can even speak.
Mom said she can't do anything for me.
Isn't it a mother's duty to raise her children?
Yes, yes, but she's not a good mother.
Mom said she's not a very good mom.
Mother said that he is not even at Kauppia's mother's house.
Or else I'll make you regret it, that's why the day train was born.
You can be sure that I can do the same.
Don't make threats or I'll bite.
What are we doing?
I wouldn't mind caring for a small child again.
I don't like that little bit at all.
Oh, don't say that. You hurt sales-sensitive feelings.
If he stays, I'll go.
What the hell are we doing?
If he is too difficult a child for a mother, then what about us?
In fact, that's what I'm afraid of too.
Ha, I know an excellent breeder.
Well, I'm leaving now.
Don't get lost in the snow.
In.
Where are they taking me now?
Viljonkanluo.
She is a very nice and busy aunt and has three children of her own.
I'm used to being a punching bag.
Anna, excuse me. Maybe I can pick you up after the snow has closed.
Yeh, yeh. There's always an excuse.
Next time I want a pillow in a postal package.
Good time, let's double the snow.
Good thing I brought an umbrella.
Who here can say where is east and where is west?
Didn't papa say that a hundred degrees...
One hundred and eighty.
Exactly. Then let's go in this direction.
Look, we came straight to Viljonka's door.
Just like papa said.
Who is there at this time?
Sorry to bother you. Me here.
Damn mom. The children are already sleeping and I myself was settling down for the night.
What if the kids get sick and catch a cold on a cold night like this?
Oh, oh, sorry. I would like to ask a small favor.
Door closed. Buy warm. In.
I apologize for the inconvenience.
Wishes for happiness seem to be in place.
You never know.
What? Oh, no, no. Not at all. It's not mine. Under no circumstances.
Good him. Doesn't look like Moominpapa.
Except in the sense that it's thick.
Thick?
Listen, Mummy Moomin. Children should not be stuffed with too much food.
That came later.
Isn't it?
At least not in my opinion.
Well, it's none of my business. What is that request?
Yeah, like...
Crazy pants.
Oh, oh.
Are these aunty?
Yeah. I'll put them back right there.
I guess we must be?
No.
Oh.
Sorry for bothering you.
Just don't come back.
It can be difficult to deliver him to the sender under these conditions.
So what do I do?
What if he was placed?
It may be difficult to deliver him to the sender under these conditions.
So what do I do?
What if he was placed in an orphanage?
Orphanage.
So. One has just been built here.
Where do I go now? Although it doesn't matter to me.
This is crazy. Let's go home. You can live with us.
But when I'm not liked...
Yes, if you try to be proper.
I'll try.
The baby got hurt in the snow.
I had fun inside the backpack.
Nice to hear.
Can't sleep?
I'll sing you a lullaby so you can catch your sleep.
Tukutukulanpaitaani, päkäpäkäpäsiäni, päkäpäkäpuskuripäsiäni...
I can't sleep when you sing. My mother can sing.
I have completely forgotten how to treat small children.
I whined, whined...
You rock the cradle so I can't sleep.
Looks like I won't be able to hibernate at all this year.
Help! Earthquake, no!
I knocked myself out.
What was it?
Good morning, Moomin-Pekko!
I am Finland.
Good morning, Moomin-Pekko! Then you sleep soundly.
What did you do with the saw?
I sawed across the foot of the bed. I wanted to see what was inside.
I can't sleep in a three-legged bed.
What are you doing there?
You finally woke up. You know you snore like a pig?
I don't. I never snore, you will learn that.
You don't know it yourself because you are sleeping.
I don't snore. And there are always letters already.
No use. I can't read.
Regardless, leave my letter alone.
What are you staring at?
You're sturdy, but not chubby.
What? Who said that?
Vili-Onkka said to Moomin-Mamma that Miss Niskunnie is quite chubby.
What does it have to do with Vili-Onka?
Good. After all, you have cookies hidden.
They are lending cookies.
No wonder he's gaining weight.
Get out of the room right away, that little moose too. As you already know.
Well, I'm going.
I'll take it anyway. What now?
Then you won't be lying to anyone about these lending cookies.
I'll give you one.
All right.
Gummy Paw, Aren't you sleeping yet?
Moomin Mommy, do you have any secrets?
Oh, secrets. Just a guess.
What's in this bag?
Soso, it's not appropriate to open other people's handbags.
Nothing is ever fun.
You should go to sleep, baby, it's already very late.
The lovely voice is already ringing nicely.
hey what are you doing
What do you have in it?
Bank, for coins.
What are coins?
What, Don't you know that?
I don't know.
In exchange for coins, you can get the things you want.
If you have a lot of coins, you can buy sweets and everything to your heart's content.
Oh, and you could already get yourself a lot of everything, right?
Yeah, exactly.
But don't tell anyone else.
In.
Hurrah!
Nice to know other people's secrets.
I hated this cold.
There's a nightgown in there.
what are you doing No wonder, it's cold.
Close the window already.
Yeah, but isn't that a nightgown for the squeamish?
Tu...
Ssh, I took a nightgown, because a slob never wears one.
Ha, but you haven't asked for permission.
None of your business.
But don't tell the little girl.
You will regret it if you do.
Now I know.
Those holy bones have opened their shroud.
And my heart...
What is that?
Oh you?
So.
Oh yeah, you were rehearsing some play by yourself.
Joo.
I want too.
I don't know.
And I have no choice.
I want to play a hero.
I thought you were a ghost.
Haa, haa, haa.
It's happening, it's happening.
Listen mummy, a nipsulapa is something that rattles.
Joo.
So, what could it be?
Don't you want to know?
Not really.
That's good.
I thus promised not to reveal it.
Aha, right?
I understand.
It just occurred to me that I might as well tell you.
Come on, no, no, no, no, no.
Says nothing.
Nipsu, what's tinkling you got?
Nothing, nothing.
Hi, I hear you.
Do you have something to share?
It's not, isn't it.
At least nothing that concerns me.
Nipsu, Does he know any of your secrets?
Well, no, of course not.
And nothing about me either.
Well, I guess not then.
What happened to you?
No.
There's Hemuli and the police master.
Good evening mummy.
Is dad at home?
Yes, I picked him up.
Thanks.
It has rained a lot.
We should talk in the basement about your plowing.
Fortunately, Grandma doesn't know anything about this.
Smells strongly of secrets.
Are you sure no one will come into the basement to disturb us?
Absolutely sure, we can play in peace.
Or card fraud?
Apparently, you have already decided how to keep the roads open in winter weather.
Right, now we mom.
I brought you tea for the meeting.
Yeah, it looks like you're on a break right now.
Hey, good evening grandma.
Right, our meeting is just ending.
What's wrong with you, you haven't eaten all day?
I've been so excited.
Whence?
Because I know secrets, I want to tell.
No, no, no, no.
I'm about to crack, I have to tell you.
Please come down from the chandelier.
No need to persuade, I'll beat him with a brush.
Oh, I can't take it anymore, I'll get really sick if I hold back.
Niiskunneids have hidden gems.
In the drawing drawer under the clothes.
Is it?
And sell, sell and use.
Hey, stop it, stop it right now.
Niiskunneidi's nightgown without permission.
what did you say
I just borrowed it a bit.
And the pinch has...
Swell!
There are many coins in the tent.
Yes, they do rattle.
And Moomin is secretly rehearsing some silly play, very funny.
Now that all the secrets have been revealed, you can be yourself again.
Necessarily.
I somehow felt refreshed.
We have been so harassed.
Now I don't have to be scared every time he opens his mouth.
Yes, today I still brush him with a floor brush.
Genuine sales talk.
It's easier when you don't have to be afraid.
I'm leaving.
What for?
I don't want to live in a place where there are no secrets.
But what about high heels, Pakkanen?
Lumi doesn't bother me at all.
I'm going on my way now.
Well bye bye.
Are we just going to let him leave us like that?
Of course, enough food now.
Oh well, you stay here.
But does he have a place to go?
He goes home, to his mother.
Mom has already calmed down her nerves.
Mom is overjoyed when she hears about the secrets here.