Moomin, where are you? Wet lady.
A rhinoceros and two tigers now live in the forest surrounding the Moomin house.
The skunk has set them free from the zoo.
Have you seen Moomin?
I won't be all evening.
I couldn't go.
Meanwhile, Moomin and Miss Niisku desperately swim to escape the snake.
I can't even sleep anymore.
You must.
Hi! Hi!
Hmm.
I can take a little longer.
A couple of hippopotamuses are heading this way. Gotta get them on board.
The zoo did not announce that the hippos were also missing.
The last coating Niisku neiti.
Ehdimäpäs
Agile as hippos.
Thank you very much. A huge beast was chasing us.
Do hornets eat hippos?
Thank you for saving our lives.
We are from the zoo.
From the zoo? Have you caught a crocodile?
And it was a tricky case, that's what I'm saying.
Another crocodile swims in these waters.
I know. I wish crocodiles were as easy to catch as you hippopotamuses.
A power horse?
Which zoo are you from? You must be needed.
I'm a Moomin, not a hippopotamus.
Do I look like a hippopotamus?
Racial purity may not be perfect.
It's not, but they look quite enough like hippos.
Can't tell the difference between a hippopotamus and a Moomin, even if you work in a zoo?
I'm not considered a hippopotamus, it's too thick.
Niskuneiti, let's get under our feet.
Stop, stop, we have a suitable cage ready for you.
Hurry up, little lady!
Don't let them run away, men, catch the hippos!
Moomin, Pekka, me, shall we go?
To the sea!
Rescue, boat, quick!
We don't go to any zoo.
What made you come back so suddenly?
Come on!
Don't worry, I never eat while swimming.
Are you sure?
Oh, there's a boat coming.
They are bad men, they are going to send us to the zoo.
Probably me too.
They have already caught the crocodile.
At least I'm not going back to the zoo.
Jump on my back and we'll disappear.
Paho!
Stay tuned!
Come back, disgusting reptile!
Will Moomin, Pekka, get into trouble?
Not alone, Niskunnetti also had to.
Oh, oh, it can't be true.
I almost never lie.
It's a sad story, but it was still worth telling.
Moomin Laakso didn't have the same tricks.
And not a single tiger, eh?
You brought the blade here.
Still, not that I would believe Haisuli's words.
But let's go find the children anyway, papa.
Well, at least I was told, my conscience is a mess now.
Where did the skunk attack them?
With a marsh that is taken to the sea.
Mom on the way.
I'll come along.
No, you stay here and tell Moomin Peiko that we're looking for him in case he comes back.
And you get to be our guide, Stink.
Aha!
Will come.
Have you poked the Moomin Fairy and the Snow Maiden on your cheek?
Mom, we're home.
Moomin and Snow Maiden.
Our new friend.
He's big. Go in as much as you want.
Haisuli just said that the kärme had eaten his plastic trolls, the hit girl.
Stink, where did you hurry?
To tell you the truth, we were chased by the skunk, but then the men started scaring the skunk too.
We escaped on the back of the spear. And now there is our good friend.
Who were those men?
Zoo men. They try to catch the animals and then take them back to the zoo.
And I don't want to go to the zoo anymore.
Father is protected our friends.
To the last scale.
I'm sure the rhinos don't want the tigers back either.
Of course not, now that they get to live in our nice jungle.
Go take a look around. You will definitely feel at home in our jungle.
Come back if you see the men from the zoo.
Thanks, good suggestion.
I'm going to show you the jungle.
Oh, I'm glad you came back safe and sound.
Yes, but I didn't have time to tell everything yet.
So? Can you imagine, we were mistaken for hippos.
What? Who would dare to think so?
Well, those zoo men. They thought we had escaped from the cage and tried to capture us.
The height of rudeness. We Moomins are completely different from hippos.
So the zoo men are trying to cage not only all our wild animal guests, but also us.
So?
Hippos don't wear aprons or write memoirs.
Those men haven't faced Moominpapa's wrath yet.
I'd like to see how you disciplined me.
Maybe one of the tigers.
Not willingly. We became friends at the zoo.
Choke the skunk. That would be fortunate for everyone.
Possibly, but he set us free from the zoo.
I'm really disappointed. I thought you would have been chasing pooches, but you went to the hay to visit.
Nothing is possible. We've always lived in a zoo, and we haven't hunted in the jungle on a moon day.
So what kind of food do you eat?
Share, cat food.
Oh, now. Unheard of before.
Cat food makes our fur shiny.
Our biggest treat is the jars with the black myrrh picture, isn't it?
Yes it is. Do you happen to have cat food?
Yes.
Dad, now those men from the zoo are here!
Dad, what are we doing?
Now let's take the animals in first. Hurry up, Moomin Goblin.
Clear.
The zoo men have come to capture you.
Run inside quickly.
The main road to the Moomin house.
Puck, puck!
Yes, I will.
Thanks.
Well, is the oven a good hiding place?
Nothing seems to come of your hiding.
How so? He doesn't notice me at all.
I lie here and present a porcelain ornament.
No one is going to beat me to it.
Can you guess that there is a rhinoceros under the table?
Thank you, Moomin-Mamma.
Remarkable. The beasts have disappeared like ashes in the wind.
Hey, come here.
Look at the barrel.
Animals are in the house.
Father!
The men from the zoo are coming this way.
Calm down and have fun.
We will defend you until the last Suomu and Viksikarva.
Mom, coffee.
Keep what you get.
Good day!
Hello everyone!
Are you perhaps on a pleasure trip?
Dear sir, we are from the zoo.
Aha, in some course or not?
Are you the owner of this house?
I am, I am Moomin-Daddy.
Is there anything I can do for you?
You can.
Release the animals you have hidden in your house.
I firmly believe that animals should be outside.
Good sir, you can't see it from your chair, but the smoke from your pipe makes you glisten.
Or am I asking?
Yes, please.
It's not a catch.
Right?
No, my daughter plays smoke in the pipe.
He enjoys it there.
We take the zoo's property to where it belongs.
You enter the hall.
Let the animals out so we don't have to barge in.
There are no animals in my house.
Wait a minute, sir seems to be alone among those hippos.
No, I'm Moomin-Pappa and the owner of this house.
You are a hippopotamus.
Fuck you.
A hippo who owns a house and runs an illegal zoo.
Scraper.
You are breaking my peace.
We don't even ask for a drawing. We have a suitably sized cage for you too.
If you break down the door, you will regret it.
Really?
Come on, we're going in now.
Oh!
What does this mean?
Oh look, the little one sells the police.
What do you think you're doing?
The precious animals of our zoo are hidden in this house.
We have come to get them away.
But a good man, you mustn't break other people's property.
We have to break down the door to get in.
How do you know zoo animals are in the house?
There is no doubt about it.
Look at the chimney.
You see, there's a catch peeking out from there.
Remarkable.
Not about me.
A python's head was just bobbing up there.
I support.
Now listen, men.
Either you stop harassing your friend or I will arrest you.
But what about the animals in our zoo?
You heard what the police said, leave.
Do you see?
What?
Bring on the hippopotamus.
A hippopotamus?
It holds our animals.
I'm going to shut him down too.
Or is that what you are planning?
They also want to capture the Moomin troll, the little girl and the Moomin mom.
Criminal undercover project.
Nope.
Or abduction rather.
You can't kidnap a hippopotamus.
He is a Moomin.
I'm sure I can find reasons to stop you from paddling.
Sorry for you.
However, I won't arrest you if you disappear within ten minutes.
Let's throw the youths into the darkest pipe of the police chamber.
There, which rattles angry rats and spiders.
Good idea.
They like animals.
I'll start counting now.
One.
Two.
Three.
Hey guys, come on.
Five.
Six.
What are we doing?
Tell me what you think?
Poop, time is running out, you won't be able to lay eggs.
Now say something.
Minute.
A minute and a half.
Two minutes were up.
Close the bread door and disappear.
All right. Six minutes.
Did you hear?
You're kidding.
The police don't play around. Nine and a half minutes.
What's up now?
Nine minutes and forty seconds.
Let's go, let's go.
We are still thinking about it.
And you won't think, let's go now.
Oops, the zoo people are running away.
Great, the Moomin Valley police chased them away.
Don't ever come from Moomin Valley again, you'll end up behind bars.
Bumpy, bumpy in front of it. Speed, speed.
Thank you, little myy, for being smart enough to bring the police.
I wouldn't have had time to bite them all, there were too many of them.
Come out.
So the animals were saved and could still enjoy the jungle with Moomin.
But one day the weather changed and cold winds blew over Moomin Valley.
The first day of autumn.
The jungle dies in this cold weather, and Mummy doesn't.
I'm afraid the worst.
The jungle grew so fast, maybe it will wither just as fast.
And so it withered.
The jungle withered in a single night.
The cold makes you feel down.
And the Moomin House can't be heated any more.
I miss the warmth of the zoo.
Yes, it is very cold here.
We get warm if we burn the jungle!
Sweet!
Lovely warm.
That was the end of the jungle.
At least it was warm in Aki.
But here you are free.
Free to suffer the cold.
I can't watch my man parka crawl here in the winter.
So all the animals decided to return to the zoo.
Maybe you can come again next summer.
It would be fun when there is a warm head.
Oops, the animals come back.
How?
Nice to see you again, Rhino. Welcome.
No, hurry to the cages now.
We've kept them warm for you.
You look terrible, starving.
Let's cook something good for you tonight.
The hippos also came.
For the last time we are Moomins.
You must be very cold.
Let's warm up a nice cage for you too.
No, we just came to accompany our friends.
Hey, let the hippos in their cage.
Oh, it sounds corny, but we're Moomins.
Yes, you will have fun here. You can eat as much hay as you can.
Do we look like hippos?
We know you're not clean-cut, but the public can't tell the difference.
Father, do we have to stay here forever?
Of course not, I made something up.
Do you have some thoughts?
No, but they will. I'm a writer.
Hui.
Niskunemi, don't cry.
Yes, we get more food than hay.
To show nothing as long as we were.
That would be horrible. Once upon a time, it's unbearable.
Maybe the Moomin Valley police will come looking for us,
when she notices that Moomin and Moomin's handbag are gone.
People are coming this way.
Nuuska Muikkunen.
And Hemul.
And Little Myo.
Nuuska Muikkunen.
Muuska Muikkunen.
Hello Moomin, we came to let you out of the cage.
Please.
Good gentlemen, you were freed.
I was the manager of this zoo.
You will see that this was a quite understandable confusion.
We apologize on behalf of our board.
I went to the Science Academy with Pikku Myy and Vanhan Hemul.
We received a letter from the President of the Academy of Sciences proving that you are not hippos.
Please keep the valuable letter safe.
You can see it there again. You shouldn't judge based on the outer shell alone.
Listen mom.
That's what it sounds like.
Would I look less hippopotamus with a beard?
Hardly.
Autumn weather has arrived in Moomin Valley.
A new year began with new joys.