Individual
Autumn has arrived in Moominvalley. The days are getting shorter and the summer blue sky has turned gray and cloudy.
Iskureiti!
where are you going
I'm taking lunch to my talented brother.
I guess the flight deck is getting ready.
Not even when you work so hard.
Have you seen a raccoon?
I don't. He won't even let me in the shed. Can you imagine?
Can't anyone see his mess?
Of course not. Great inventors must always exercise extreme caution. You understand he.
Kuvi, Teikko wants to see a flying kite?
I know.
Hey, open up. I only have two hands and both are occupied.
You see. A real gramophone.
Daddy, can you fix it?
With pleasure.
Where did it come from?
Daddy, can you fix it?
With pleasure.
Why is it that I'm always given junk items that don't work?
Papa can fix the gramophone.
My aunt said that the record is completely playable and contains beautiful dance music.
Oh right. It's been a while since I last spun around on the dance floor. Did you hear that, papa?
Or didn't spin?
Oops, it's been a week here.
Can you fix it?
Hear the music.
Maybe some real dance music.
Drink.
Did you figure out how to dance?
I think I got to the point.
So do I.
Then dance.
Joo.
You are amazing, Lady.
Nukro!
Moomin, look at papa, he was hard to dance.
Nipsuo, can you dance?
I have not experimented.
Well, let's try then.
Oh, that was fun.
The record must be playing at overspeed.
You don't have the slightest sense of rhythm.
It's possible, let's dance.
Another song.
Sorry, I have to rant.
Shawl.
No thanks, I dance alone.
So.
Nipsuo, come dance with me.
It's fine.
Who?
Yes, it can rain there.
You must be like a bathed dog.
I am.
You guys are having fun.
Yes, Nipsu brought the gramophone and we've been dancing for a long time with all our heart's desire.
I can already smell the scent of winter in the air.
Yes?
I guess you're right.
I'm snuffling.
Sniff me, come dance.
No thanks, I can't.
Sorry.
Sorry again.
Yes.
About.
There was an error again.
Just when we were having so much fun.
Could you fix it again?
My skills are not enough.
Dad try, you are so clever.
Come on, sniveling little one.
Do you know anything about gramophones?
I don't, unfortunately.
We have nothing.
Do you know anything about gramophones?
I don't, unfortunately.
I thought.
But...
So?
I play the harmonica while you tinker with the gramophone.
The dance can continue.
It's a great snuff, little one.
Thanks.
Would this be a suitable dance song?
I give up.
I am.
You're thinking about going away again, aren't you?
I know winter is coming and you go south every year.
down south every year, but I'll still miss you.
Tasteless Peikko.
What's over there?
Hats, I guess.
Where are they going?
To some island where there are no others.
When are you going to leave?
Sniff, when?
I haven't decided yet.
So will you stay for a while?
Do you know where you are going?
In.
I guess hiking is fun.
Share mostly.
It's the best way to enjoy solitude.
We hibernate, but we are not sleepy even when we sleep.
If I had to stay here all winter, I would surely hibernate.
Muuska Muikkunen
Couldn't we go with Muikkunen to the south?
In our family, we hibernate.
It is the old way of our ancestors and we follow it.
I don't want to, I'm not going to sleep without snuff with Muikkunen to the south.
Moomin, would you come back on the first day of spring?
Mom, does this mean I get to go?
Will you give me permission to leave?
If you have such a severe cold, we will prevent it. Or what?
My relatives didn't stop me when I wanted to travel around the world.
Oh thanks dad. Thanks mom.
What does snuff Muikkunen think?
No doubt it would be fun if a Moomin came along.
Yep, I'll come with you then.
No.
Why not?
I'm going alone.
I'm going south to be alone.
My soul demands it after my time here.
Just as my soul demands to be here after loneliness.
And going back is always just as fun.
Yeah, but what about me?
I'll see you again next spring as always.
I promise you I'll be back on the first day of spring.
I'm sitting on the railing of the bridge and through the window you can hear me playing my lip harp.
I came up with a new tune for spring.
Speak up.
I'm sorry for you.
A little about that.
Oh, oh. You'd have to make that bundle a little tighter.
We need a lot of cracks in the coming cold winter.
I'm sure you'll stay warm.
When I grow up, I too will go south alone.
That's fine.
Is Moomin at home?
On, on.
How is he? Is he still slobbering?
Yet. Although I tried her grandmother's best recipe.
And all just because it hurts when he leaves.
So.
But not bigger.
I have a surprise for Moomin that will surely cheer him up.
Haa.
Moomin, are you there?
Hi dear Moomin, don't cry.
Men don't cry.
Cry, you little Hubsu.
At least I'm not crying.
All right. You should get up though.
I don't care.
I have a surprise for you.
I don't mind surprises.
When driving, you can look at Niisku. Come along. Come on.
You know very well that Niisku won't let us there.
Let's go. Today he lets go.
You don't mean he's going to show us his flywheel?
I mean.
Is it finally ready?
No, there's still an awful lot to do.
How in the world is Niisku showing us his bullshit?
He has always turned me back before.
In order to bend Niisku, you need feminine charm and cunning.
How did you manage?
Well, first. Niisku flatly said no.
But when I told you how sick you are and that maybe we shouldn't keep you around much longer, Niisku said.
I don't. I'm so sick.
Nice to hear.
Oh, you know that depressed people sometimes do desperate things.
Niisku miss, thanks for cheering me up.
And remember, no one will know about this. Don't ever tell a soul.
Clear.
Let's go.
Retail.
Now we are in the broth.
And bad.
Gotta pull him by the lip.
But how?
Now I know how we handle the sale.
How?
You just accept everything I say.
Good.
I thought you were bedridden.
No, we're going to Niiskunluo.
Halveli is ready, right?
I'm ready.
No, we're going to Niiskunluo.
Halveli is ready, right?
No, but Niisku needs Silä airport.
We're going to help him.
Have you gotten up from your sick bed to help Niiskua?
To get stumps and tear up roots from the ground.
Maybe you've noticed that I'm not a complete fool.
I spoke the truth.
Take it as a personal insult that you couldn't come up with a better emergency lie.
And you're still pushing the scumbag as the truth.
I'm telling the truth. Isn't it just Niiskunneiti?
Not a word more.
You are trying to hide something from me.
But I can't bear to be interested in any of the slytherins and sly-like woods you move about.
But sell.
No problem.
I happen to be too busy to care to listen to that bullshit right now.
It was on point.
It was.
Oh, they think they can keep a secret from me.
There are no others with you.
Well, of course not, I promised.
Please come in.
Ooo.
It's almost done.
No, no, no, no, no, no, no. The machinery is just in its infancy.
And as you can see, the ship itself is quite interesting.
I couldn't imagine that the ship looks so wonderful.
Well, presumably the design has not gone completely wild.
I'm sure it will fly beautifully.
Do you, do you really think so, Muun Pekko?
I see with the eyes of my soul your ship soars already made on high.
I'm sure it will fly beautifully.
Do you, do you really think so, Muun Pekko?
I see with the eyes of my soul your ship already flying high in the sky.
Thank you, Moomin Pekko.
I think you are right.
It's funny to see that you are so unusually far-sighted.
But hurry up now, Moomin Pekko.
Or is this what you wanted to keep from me?
Sell, how did you get in?
Out the door, Tollo.
But it's always...
I forgot to lock the door.
And now it's too late, but don't be sad.
If I want to come in, I'll come too.
You lied to us.
That's true, but you lied to me too.
And now everything is fine.
Listen, little guy, don't tell anyone what you see or hear here.
Agreed.
Well, the remarkable invention before you has so many excellent new features,
that it is difficult to choose where to start listing them.
But let's first take...
Rate.
Tomorrow Pekko, I want to stay on the shore of that lake.
Why do you want to leave?
Wouldn't it be much more fun to fly?
I want to be one.
Snuff, do you want to come guide?
I don't care.
Bye!
Snuff!
Uuuh!
Goodbye, Moomin.
We will meet again next year.
On the first day of spring.
Goodbye, Snuff!
Heading south again?
I'm leaving. See you Hemuli.
I care about you.
So do you.
I haven't noticed that winter is so close already.
Moomin troll