The morning in Moomin Valley seemed quite ordinary.
However, two days are never exactly alike, as we will soon see.
It is certainly nothing new that Nipsu dreams.
Moomin, I can't carry that much.
Please.
Thanks mom.
In.
Good morning.
Good morning Miss Nipsu.
The Moomin is still in the room.
Oh, then I'll go upstairs.
Miss Nipsu is happy.
It seems so. It's very funny.
In.
Good morning Moomin.
Good morning. You are early.
What are you doing?
I look at fate on the cards.
Then I came appropriately. Tell me about my fate.
Well, that's fine. Pick up the deck twice.
Clear. Another time.
Give me half the pack.
Pick up the final pack two more times.
Another time.
Now. Touch the nose with the cards and immerse yourself in your thoughts.
Touch the tip of the nose.
Enough.
Next, give me the top three cards.
Do you see my destiny?
Of course.
You have experienced something beautiful.
Ai.
Maybe a beautiful dream.
Exactly.
Do you know what happened to the dream?
That...
You got something you like.
That's what I got.
Oh, you're really good at seeing.
Did I get it right?
You hit it. I was dreaming and woke up just as you promised to give me a present.
What did you give me?
I don't know what I do in your dreams.
I look at the cards.
I fucked you. I can't see clearly.
Don't be modest. You just proved yourself to be.
Pure coincidence.
Well, you would even try.
Oh rot.
Moomin! Moomin! Moomin!
What is it. You should be busy.
Moomin troll. Now come now.
Yeah, but...
Right. If my gift is not more important to you than that.
I'm leaving.
Not waiting.
Let the lady go.
Well miss, don't go.
Moomin, let him go.
So, when the lady got hurt, tui.
I dreamed that you and I made a lot of money.
Everyone dreams.
Well, you come with me.
To do what?
This rejuvenator.
Has passed in the mouth for decades.
Let's start selling it.
To sell it?
We sell it by the ton.
Then you can buy something for the wet ones.
And he will be happy.
Ha, Hemuli is a suitable destination.
Hemuli, you work hard.
Kars, are you out and about today?
In the business world, there is talk.
That, we haven't met in a while.
Oh, as I recall, the last time we met was yesterday.
I guess bending over is bad for the old back.
Well, not really, when you can have fun.
But of course you would like to be younger.
A younger one?
Of course.
Moistelepas, or what it was like in your youth.
We have a rejuvenator.
We sell to you at a special price.
To be young.
Experience all the thrills again.
Girlfriends and late nights.
No thanks.
I am happy with my current situation.
My family has had a ton of bad luck.
I have to find another client.
Another one?
I can't find anyone.
No one?
Well, I don't, except maybe dad.
But I don't want to try the medicine on him.
No one believes in your medicine.
Why not join the faith.
Don't screw up.
Do the drugs really work?
Should we try its effect first?
For example, to you.
I don't want to be a rabbit.
Besides, nobody wants to be younger.
At least I want to get older.
Hip bone, is anyone home?
Is there anyone at home?
Looks like an oath.
Hi huh, anyone there?
Can't hear anything.
Did someone yell at me?
Hello, this is Moomin.
what did you say
Moomin troll.
Moomin!
Well, I wish you a merry Christmas.
We have elixirs of rejuvenation.
Want to try?
Harder, I don't understand why everyone likes mummies these days.
I have elixir of rejuvenation.
Do you want to try it?
Do you provide free sample?
In that case, I won't say, no.
Yeah, great stuff.
At least it is strong, I must say.
Comfortably warms the heart underneath.
Did he get younger?
Now you can get over the medicine.
I shouldn't have added sprite.
I guess I can go home.
No, the business world knows no rest.
What tent is there?
Excuse me, may I ask what are you waiting for?
Well, to the clairvoyant.
Oh yeah.
Renowned.
This is our chance.
What do we mean?
Let's get in line and ask how we become rich.
But I don't believe in clairvoyance.
Me neither, but let's try.
Come and be seen, young men, voice calls of fate.
Sit down.
I think you guys are in trouble.
On.
Are you looking for something?
Yep, we're looking for a way to get rich.
Not at all original.
Pallo pallo show how to become rich, the owner of a thick bag, the bearer of gold illinkis.
Now I see.
I don't see anything.
You're not supposed to see it.
What do you see?
I won't tell until you pay.
I don't have any money.
We will pay as soon as we can afford double the price.
Triple.
The curse of danger will fall upon you if you slip.
Honor in the word, we will not slip.
Well then, I saw the shadow of a young woman.
Really?
Really.
The woman knows good luck, but watch out for the balloon.
A balloon predicts doom for you.
How do we get rich from women and balloons?
Maybe we got to hear the truncated version because we didn't pay.
Rubbish, the Clairvoyant guesses that everyone has worries and is looking for a solution to them.
And then he says whatever comes to mind.
Haa!
What happened to you?
Excuse me, how much is the tax for Selvnäkäki?
Three gold coins.
Three?
Are you OK?
Muvi veikko, a real lucky shot.
What?
Let's become Clairvoyants.
Again?
Last time we asked for such a small fee that the audience became suspicious.
100 souls per day makes 300 gold coins.
During the week 2100, 1800 if we rest on Sunday.
More than 7000 per month!
Nipsu honey, control yourself.
Ai ai, kultavuori!
Do you hold your nerve?
I don't want to be Clairvoyant, that's overkill.
That's what the people want, just like when they had breakfast in the morning.
I didn't get high, I was joking.
Yuu-yuu, try to be like the real Clairvoyant and keep that joke down.
But...
When the customer comes, remember to say what is written on the paper.
I'll take care of the rest.
Well, go get some customers.
Hello, Nipsu!
What now? Is there a fire somewhere?
Please come in.
A-a, payment in advance, I would refer.
No, Tipu, this was not my idea.
I want to hear my fate first.
It's fine, but the payments are made when I don't these days.
This is not my idea, I want to hear my fate first.
That's fine, but the payments will be made when our prediction has come true.
That's fine.
Go further.
And then to the most important thing.
Kasni, listen carefully to my words.
Bad luck befalls you.
Or so, and how?
Well, that part is really unclear.
Are you a clairvoyant at all?
Oh, it's me. What can I say for a long time?
Oh yes, a hint, I can give you a hint how you can avoid the danger.
Ha, well, what clue could that be?
Bring it like that, don't look up, because danger lurks below.
A rather obscure clue.
Yes, it says here though.
Where does it say?
Nowhere. I mean the cards say so.
Cards, cards, cards, cards.
Significant cards.
Yeah, yeah.
Don't think I'm paying for that nonsense.
Haa.
Hello, what did you find out?
A lot of bullshit, and I'm not going to pay you a dime for it, okay?
Be careful, the forecast is valid until the evening.
Isn't it a beautiful day?
Good.
Did it happen, bad luck to fall into a pit.
It's okay.
Prediction.
Is this what was predicted for you? In that case, unfortunately, you will have to pay.
Moomin, Moomin.
Behold, Great success.
Was the customer and others staying?
Moomin, Moomin.
Behold, Great success.
Did the customer not seem to believe.
I made him believe, see.
I'll get more customers, we'll be rich.
Don't look up, keep your eyes on the ground.
Happiness I know you will get then.
It's just a bay.
He spoke the truth.
That's what he always says. The fee is four gold coins, please.
The cards say that the sky will open above you.
He knew.
This should work.
You may encounter a ghost, but don't say anything to it.
Especially don't get too close, or it will bite your nose off.
Oh no, I'm so afraid of ghosts.
There's no reason to worry as long as you don't get too close.
I shouldn't have come, it would be clear the seer is, surely wrong.
Ghost ball!
Stupid freak out paint balloon.
Tremble that mortal.
Cry?
I'm right behind you.
That you dare, only members of the ghost association have the right to haunt.
Sorry, not me ever again.
Well, I guess not.
Hemp Haunters ruin the reputation of ghosts.
As punishment, I'll haunt you every night for a week.
No, no, no, no, no, don't, don't, don't, don't.
Here's honey, hold, hold the whole bag.
Wait, wait.
Aaaaaa!
It's strange what the customers were looking for.
And where Nipsun Mokoma would hide.
Experience!
That's the tent.
Good day.
Are you a card fortune teller?
It's me.
Good.
I've heard how fairy-tale predictions come true every day.
Can we start?
SAMATO.
What do you want to know?
Well, now that the masquerade competition is organized,
and I don't know if I would participate in it.
Or a costume contest?
So.
I don't really want to participate in the competition,
if I stay in last place.
You won't be the last.
I should come up with a very special costume.
Too bad I don't know what it would be like.
I have to come up with a costume that won't blow anyone else's head.
What if you were a mermaid?
Mermaid?
Yeah, I saw shoes as jewelry.
Mom can make a suit.
Huh?
Yes, mother agrees.
You will win, mister.
How do you know my name?
Well, here I am.
Remember the rest.
Moomin, how are you here?
It's quite a long story.
Let's go home and prepare the suit.
Will you help me, Moomin?
Of course.
Everyone helps.
A few lobster shells and maybe an old fishing net.
Sounds wonderful.
Well, let's go.
You got a beautiful necklace.
Yeah, a reasonable reward.
My victory is thanks to Moomin.
Well, there were others of us.
I collected some nice shells.
But the mermaid costume was Moomin's idea.
I told you that you are a good clairvoyant.
Elevators.
How exactly did you end up in the soothsayer's tent?
What is it?
I just remembered Nipsu.
Nipsun?
Nipsu, are you at home?
Moomin!
What now?
You left me stranded.
That ghost scared me to death.
And I haven't dared to go out.
Ghost?
Just right.
It got mad when I haunted.
I had to give it all my, all our gold coins.
The head is fine, Nipsu.
Now let's go celebrate Niiskuneidi's first prize in the masquerade costume competition.
Funny costume.
Nuthead! Niiskuneiti is a mermaid!
I received this necklace as a reward.
Or as a reward?
Wedding! Onni kicked Niiskuneit.
You can say that.
The clear seer was right when he spoke about the young woman.
But good luck didn't meet us.
How about a balloon?
I forgot the prediction and painted the Ghost on the balloon.
Just a coincidence, I guess.
I never believe in clairvoyance.
Me neither. Even to that one.
A pinch! I'm you rushing now?
I go back to the clairvoyant and ask how one can preserve one's wealth.
I think Nipsu can be changed into something else.
Gold is Nipsu's only fixed point.
Clear seer! Where are you?
Clear seer!