Hemuli had told Moomin about the goldfish. The fish immediately took over Moomin's thoughts.
My grandfather's mother listen, I saw a goldfish.
You haven't seen it.
Well, I'm a botanist. Goldfish only appear under certain conditions and rarely.
I don't understand.
Well, you can only see goldfish at the end of summer.
At this hour?
Mmm.
It should be a sunny afternoon after the rain.
It narrows the possibilities.
And you have to be calm.
The lake is shallow, even on rough terrain.
Not you.
There are some other conditions that grandpa didn't know about. So that luck is needed that the goldfish would see.
Ice, it's a cloudy sky for the lake. It is located behind the lonely mountains.
If you have to cross mountains, the round trip will take more than two days.
Not necessarily, if you take a short cut, you can get back in a day.
Really?
Joo.
Have you been to the lake?
Just once.
Will you take me there?
Are you serious?
I am. I want to see a goldfish and catch it if I can at all.
Catching up is not easy.
Why not?
The goldfish is at the door. Few have even seen it.
That's why I want to see a goldfish.
Just you?
I didn't eat in them either, women have those whims.
Who else?
Well, small shop.
What about Snipsu?
Yes, he also wants to join.
Four.
Better to take a longer route.
Why can't we take a shortcut?
Well, when the path is overgrown and it takes you through the forest.
There are no witches!
No longer.
Then there's no problem.
Witches or not, but the forest is dark even during the day.
At least we are not afraid.
Towels!
Good morning.
Sorry, I overslept.
The girls haven't come yet either.
Snipsu, you're early.
I dreamed that I caught a goldfish, and I didn't sleep properly after that.
Let's go.
Aren't we waiting for the niskunit and selling?
We agreed that latecomers will not be expected.
Besides, today's trip is too heavy for the girls, so it's better this way.
Which is better this way?
Sell. You came.
But what I said is true.
The trip is tough.
Not for me!
Moomintroll.
Snipsu, speed up!
I'm still sleepy.
Speed up!
Why did we have to leave so early?
We won't make it back the same day.
We're taking a shortcut.
Still, it's already night when we get home.
The journey home is not as hectic, because then I have water and a goldfish in my bucket.
Snipsu, I don't think you'll catch a goldfish.
Then the whole thing is pointless.
I thought you understood that we can be happy forever if we even catch a glimpse of a goldfish.
Yes, but we're on time and we don't make a fuss.
Well, it's true.
I'll catch the goldfish.
Where are they going in the morning, Ani Varhain?
How long is the journey to the forest?
The sky of a couple of hours.
So tell me, how long does it take to go from one end of the forest to the other?
Likewise for a couple of hours.
Ooo, so long!
Surely there are no witches there?
There isn't.
Armi, I'm not afraid of witches.
Gee, I guess not.
I won't drop a drop.
Before there were witches.
Oh, don't.
How else would the name of the forest be that forest?
Say that shit.
Are you sure there are no witches in the forest now?
They're hardly back.
It doesn't scare me any more.
Good morning, where is Moomin?
He went out while you were still sleeping.
Oh yeah, goldfish.
It's going to be hot here.
I would have liked to go with the children.
Don't dawdle, you've got work to do.
I try to concentrate on writing, but the goldfish invades my subconscious.
I could write a whole chapter about it in my memoirs.
Jaa.
Oh, I wish I were free to go.
You are like a little child.
It occurred to me that children might get lost in the woods.
Don't worry, Snuff is on its way.
Haunted forest.
The witches have been able to come back.
Yeah, stop it.
Now listen up muggle heads.
Stay on my kinders so you don't get lost.
HEY!
GRANDFATHER!
It's pretty dark here.
Sunlight cannot filter through the branches.
The sky has clouded over.
And the wind picks up.
The wind is bad.
Shouldn't it be raining now?
Well, if it doesn't rain for long.
Must not.
Me kastumme.
So it seems.
Uh, let's run.
Ota.
Oh, thank you.
With help, the weather did not predict rain.
This rain won't last long.
How do you know?
From experience.
Five of the rain.
So do I.
Let's hurry to the lake before the afternoon.
Let's continue the journey.
In the Sankasä forest, we don't step badly.
Are you that excited?
Stickman, what are you doing?
Ota.
Oh, thank you.
Excited.
Stickman, what are we going to do?
Well, let's see now.
Patti!
We get wet like rats.
Let's press somewhere sheltered from the rain again.
And where could such protection be found?
Kunalatakai.
Yes?
What's wrong now?
A cottage looms over there.
The cabin is just a mess.
It does keep the rain out though.
Whoa! Hi! Is there anyone there?
Deserted.
The cottage has been empty for a long time.
It has been empty for a long time.
Who has lived here before others?
I do know. And yes you know too.
Do you mean that...
A witch has lived here.
Look around you.
Those tricks, by any measure.
Rautpata.
Poison.
What about a broom?
The witch has flown her way with it.
There's someone here.
Cry?
Let's go away.
The sound is heard.
Sounds like that.
Don't you dare, little one.
Let's go away.
Miss Nisku, don't whore me.
ha Isu Li.
Well, you finally got scared.
At least I wasn't scared.
Nipsu behaved badly when he passed out.
Hearing my voice.
Tell me where you're going.
Don't play and get angry.
Starts fair.
There.
Clear.
hey what's up
This is the lake.
It is.
Where is the goldfish?
I can't say because I haven't seen it before.
All requirements have been met.
The goldfish will appear soon.
No goldfish!
Help me.
I'll catch a fish even if I die.
A goldfish swims deep.
I don't see any fish.
Maybe Hemuli was fooling us.
That's not Hemul's case.
What?
Me.
Goldfish.
Not like Hemul.
Sit down and wait.
A goldfish will definitely jump out.
Hyper.
Did you go through all the trouble of the trip just to watch the fish?
There was talk of asking.
And it seems that there will be more to talk about.
Hey, don't make waves.
Oh.
Did they go on such an arduous journey?
I academic their youth.
I would have gone along and put the work on hold.
Are you implying that you are still young?
Well, I don't feel old.
It would be exciting to see Kultakala with your own eyes.
Nipsu bragged that he would catch a fish.
How?
Online probably.
And he brings the fish home in a bucket.
Out.
How so?
Jaa.
I think I forgot to tell the kids one very important point.
Hey, muli said that Goldfish do not show up at the lake all the time.
And who has eaten the Goldfish?
Stinky mouth shut.
Where did you see the Goldfish?
I saw a fish jumping, but I couldn't tell if it was a goldfish.
It was too far.
Only the outline of the fish is visible in this light.
Nothing can be said about its color.
Look, there's a ferry over there!
Hey, let's take a ferry to the middle of the lake.
The ferry is not for all of us.
Don't worry, it won't sink.
I'll stay.
Ipsu, how will you catch a fish if you're afraid of water?
Hey, Stinkbug, Can you help me?
The goldfish is gold in these, it can be sold for a good price.
Niisku, miss, did you see a fish on these roads?
I think so, but I can't be sure.
Did you see the Goldfish?
That's what I saw.
I don't see anything.
Let's wait here.
Yes, you can't think of anything better than that.
I won't leave until I've seen the Goldfish.
No fish in the sky!
The fish thrive in the reeds.
Oops, the ferry is far away.
Others want to see the Goldfish, but I'm going to catch it.
Well, how do you know that, even if you still catch a fish in the bucket.
Did you see the fish?
I also saw melting gold.
What did I say, now I'll shut up.
Goldfish.
It's been forever.
Let's go back to the beach to make it to Moomin Valley in time.
Perhaps we had too high expectations.
I'm terribly disappointed.
I'm sure I'll see a flickering Goldfish.
Another time.
Let's stop.
Did you see the Goldfish?
Goldfish.
It's big.
Goldfish yes.
Great!
I saw the Goldfish.
I caught the Goldfish.
We caught a fish.
Moomin troll.
I caught the fish.
Ai.
Yeah, I caught a Goldfish.
Have you got sunstroke?
I have a Goldfish here.
Nipsu, do you think it's a Goldfish?
Yes?
That's a different fish.
As a golden boy, I asked for it.
Maybe the sun made it sparkle gold?
You said it's a Goldfish.
Nipsu, release the fish back into the lake.
It's not Goldfish.
Oh.
Look how happily the fish swims.
Goldfish.
It looked like a goldfish at first.
We believe you, Nipsu.
Let's go home.
It was hard for Nipsu and Smelly to admit that they had caught an ordinary fish.
But the Moomin hit the daring Moomin and the mouse had become part of a rare piece of luck.