There may be life in outer space, although we don't know what kind.
Space creatures can even resemble jellyfish in appearance.
But at least this isn't an alien, because this is Nipsu, a friend of the Moomins.
Cool, cool, cool, cool!
Help, help, help, help, help!
Hey, hey, hey!
So that rumor is true.
What rumor? I haven't even heard.
That the creatures of outer space have invaded Moominvalley.
You mean I just saw a real flying saucer?
I mean.
They were going to kidnap me.
Hardly.
You mean I just saw a real flying saucer?
I mean.
They were going to kidnap me.
They hardly thought you were that important.
Although you never know.
In this book, the Martians are said to be very civilized and peace-loving.
They wouldn't bother to attack us.
However, the book is not very scientific.
Some creature was going to attack me in Takuu.
Maybe it wasn't from Mars or some other planet.
The monster was hungry.
The police claim that aliens have invaded Moomin Valley from outer space.
A few flying saucers, perhaps.
What kind of people are they?
Moomin, come help me garden. Maybe we will see some space object.
Mom, I'm coming.
Oops, what's that?
At least not a vegetable, that's for sure.
It must be a flying saucer.
Is it full of strangers?
Which are like Tuusa's snuff.
Let's go see.
There appears to be a door opening.
It's a remarkable vector. What is it?
Radio maybe.
Alien radio.
Is there anyone there?
There isn't.
Hi, is anyone there?
Not a living soul.
No, but what's that sound?
This saucer will probably never fly again.
Maybe it can be fixed.
Who would fix it?
Well, at least not papa.
Do you hear flying saucers make that strange noise?
I don't think so.
The space aliens are apparently afraid that we will copy their flying saucer.
For that they have programmed it to explode.
In the middle of the asparagus bed.
Let's hurry out from under it before it crashes.
And it will probably be a blast. That's why there is no one inside the plate.
Let's take Vekot with us.
Mom, it will happen soon.
I guess so.
Lautainen disappeared.
Guard me.
The book knew that space aliens are advanced.
There weren't many pieces of evidence left of the flying saucer crash.
This tip just sucks.
Dad, what is it?
I don't know. At least there are a lot of pieces.
Let's try a little.
Let's start with red.
Tel!
Dad, where are you?
Stupid question. And you don't have eyes in your head.
Dad, to be honest, I can't see you either.
That what?
Yes.
When you press the red button it becomes invisible.
Time Vekotin.
I think it's more fun to see you.
Of course.
Come on, let's press the yellow button.
Can you see me now?
I can't see you.
Remarkable.
Shall I push the button for you?
Press.
I'm already pressing.
I see you.
I guess Vekotin is dangerous.
I don't want to become invisible.
All sorts of things are invented.
Mamma, let's put it somewhere safe.
Let's do that.
Moomi, Peikka!
What is it? What has happened?
We found Auda's creature.
The creature?
It must be an alien.
Share, does it look like a jellyfish?
Not a bit.
The little one is keeping an eye on it.
Oh, come quickly, come quickly.
Way to go, Moomi papa.
Not anywhere, anyway.
Moomin, you could help me with the research.
Oh right?
It is said that the hovercraft is a vegetable that has landed in the garden.
But it's not just a big man here.
What have you done to the flying saucer?
We do nothing.
So where is the hoverboard?
It took and disappeared immediately.
Disappeared?
So he did.
That the hoverboard flew his way.
So it was lost, in one fell swoop.
Moomi Peikko also saw.
Very remarkable.
The song?
Were there aliens on the plate?
Not a single one.
Is that the whole point?
Why would I lie?
I can't think of a reason.
Sorry now, but it's unnerving like aliens have invaded Moomin Valley.
So, can we go already?
Just go.
Where are you going anyway?
For Anna, to collect these shoes.
Have a nice rest of the day.
To collect these shoes while I get aliens from the forest.
Hey, this way!
Is it an alien?
It looks completely different from the book.
Have you tried talking to it?
I am but it doesn't respond.
Come on, have you come from space?
He seems like a child to me.
Reminds me of a lamp.
He must be hungry.
Let's take him to us.
But he hates that the police can't see.
Let's talk.
Unfortunately, we don't understand you, but you certainly drink milk.
Even if you don't speak our language.
Oh poor thing, he misses his home planet.
He couldn't have come alone from that far.
Where are his father and mother?
I can't know, but he's clearly homesick.
Would the police arrest this innocent child?
Who knows, he is officially another man.
I have never seen a more harmless lamp in my life.
Probably not.
He is.
Oh, the police are coming.
We have to hide the alien.
Haisuli is in police custody.
The skunk knows boredom. Hide the creature in the kitchen.
We have to do something.
The thing doesn't fade away.
I know what to do.
So what mom?
Let's use that trigger.
Puller?
I stay invisible for a while.
It was this natto.
They are here.
Hello Moominpappa. They say there's an alien here.
What the hell.
Oh my goodness, how you shine.
So I shine. Yes, it's a remarkable case.
You're like a worm.
Knight in shining armor you mean?
That's exactly what you look like.
You don't even need a lamp anymore.
Yes, criminals can be afraid of me now.
I'm going to quickly show myself.
You will be admired.
Duty calls. Goodbye.
What are you doing now?
I don't know now that the clues still work.
You can talk.
Of course I can talk. I would have liked to talk to you right away.
If you hadn't hidden my translation machine.
That's how easy it is to translate.
Where are you going?
To look at that shining man. The police will arrest you.
He came here looking for you.
But forgot about it when you started to glow.
Don't go.
Come back.
I like the electric glow. It reminds me of my home region.
Hello police.
So what now?
I'll accommodate me.
What?
That's what you gloss over and deny so beautifully.
Do you think so?
In our house, everything sparkles.
It must look funny.
I want to comply.
It would be fun to pack with you.
Moomin are these aliens and I have to find them.
Oh yeah.
I had to ask if aliens had been seen in the Moomin house.
The police will come back.
What about aliens?
Running after the police.
Is the hand in the bag?
Not as far as I saw.
In the name of the law, open the door immediately.
By all means, come in.
We have nothing to hide.
Based on the information I received from a reliable source, you've gone nuts here.
A stranger?
Either again.
In other words, you've been hiding aliens.
It's a hill.
We haven't hidden anything.
Were you hiding something?
Why would I hide?
The skunk played tricks on me again.
Fortunately, he won't find you now.
Here is the reliable of that nice policeman.
He will throw you in the pipe.
You don't want to go there.
Like that police.
Don't go!
I turn the yellow button, and the police are glaring.
All right, honey.
And suddenly, too.
This is the yellow button.
Come on.
He doesn't want to run the police.
He has not thrown the police.
He doesn't want to run after the police when he doesn't shine anymore.
In.
Let's go home then.
Ha ha Moomin, come look, we saved the alien.
The police don't shine anymore, come and have a look, momma.
Mamma!
Mom, where are you?
I'm here.
Hey, where, honey?
I can't see you.
Here I am.
Oh no, what happened now?
I don't know, this is the reason for the trick.
Not only does it make invisible, it also shrinks.
Oh jeez, what do I do now?
I'm getting me a handbag for a handkerchief.
You're a little bitty, but still very funny looking.
Would you like to be like that for a while?
Don't talk nonsense, please, press the button, quickly, before someone sees me.
Well, wait a minute.
What now?
Home has disappeared.
Is there?
Hey, listen, give it back.
A thief too.
Kill.
Don't worry about the trigger back.
Wake up, come back.
In the database.
Omipeikko, grab Stink.
All right, dad.
Hi, Nipsu, I'll catch the thief.
Nipsu, you don't know I'm giving you a gold coin.
Right?
Palme, not five.
Five? Hey, I'll put the vector here.
Don't try anything.
Did you get away with it?
Where is the vector?
The skunk threw it to the bottom of the river.
Oh, oh, oh, mother fucks me.
What's wrong with mom?
He can't get back to his former self without a trigger.
Back to normality.
Now I have the opportunity to do really nice sewing jobs.
Mom, don't worry, we'll take care of you.
Thanks, I'll be fine.
Although I guess I have to get new pots and pans for myself.
I'm leaving now
Te20.
...
Aitika!
ðŸ¥º
ï¿½Have
ðŸ¤‘
ï¿½ amenities
ðŸ™ƒ
ðŸº
What can you bring?
Did they come to pick you up?
Yeah, I took a flying saucer without permission.
Could you ask your parents to return the other mimamma to its former size?
Of course!
I'll show you.
I have to look at you.
Where is the collection mamimu?
Wake up!
Well, it's starting to look familiar.
Oh, six!
Now it was too much.
Sorry, could you try again?
Help!
I can't bear such a heavy spirit.
So the aliens didn't take over Moominvalley, but the people of the valley found out what the aliens look like.
Although they may look different.