One night Moomin had a strange dream.
What have I gotten myself into?
Go ahead, go ahead!
Still forward, forward!
Behind the waterfall you will find what you are looking for.
I'm not looking for anything.
Behind the waterfall!
What will I find there?
Well, that was an impressive dream.
I've often dreamed that I'm falling or flying, but it's never happened to me in a dream that I'm looking for something.
So are you sure to search?
I've thought about it a lot, but I'm not looking for anything.
Aha, have you seen that waterfall?
Well, I'm not. Hey, wait, I've heard of one waterfall you can go behind.
Who told about it?
You.
Me?
It does exist.
You said it's in the lonely mountains.
So I have told about the waterfall.
Oh, take me there. Sleep bothers me so much that I can't think of it.
It was a dream.
The dream feels somehow ominous. Come with me.
Ah, cooking milk.
Good.
I'm watering.
Then go to sleep.
I think I'll go.
Mother, I'm going on a trip to the lonely mountains with the new muikku in the morning.
What, before breakfast?
Yeah, will you pack us some lunch?
Of course.
Thank you, good night.
Mamma, where did Moomin Pekka say he was going?
To the lonely mountains.
Quite far.
Not too much.
So early and in such a strange direction.
Just for fun.
He's hiding something.
How so?
I don't think he was so tired that he needed to go to sleep.
Oh, not about you?
He has something on his mind.
I feel the signs that you crave excitement.
He could get into trouble. I better follow him.
Yes.
Thanks, mom.
Good morning, snort.
Good morning.
I have snacks for both of us.
Mother is a joy.
Oh wonder.
Moomin is soon after.
Oh, you flowers anyway.
I didn't expect that this year at all.
Excellent.
Nice to see you flourishing.
Ha!
I didn't know it was this far.
Is it tiring?
Little.
Let's rest.
Yes, I can. What about you?
I'm a wanderer.
The condition is disappointing.
Exhausting to follow and stay hidden.
Rest already.
After.
Do you think we can find something?
I'm not so sure. It was just a dream.
So yes.
What if I march out and say I have vision.
Maybe I could get something to eat.
No way. Then you could spy on them.
What exactly are they looking for?
Something valuable huh?
This... This is the waterfall I saw in my dream.
But you really don't know what to look for.
No clue.
Dreams are strange.
Let's walk behind the falls and see what you should be looking for.
No clue.
Dreams are strange.
Let's walk behind the falls and see what you should be looking for.
Doesn't look very inviting.
Here's a slippery slope. I'll see where you step.
It's getting wet here!
Now we have come right behind the waterfall.
I don't see anything special.
I can't see ahead yet.
What is that?
What so?
Green thistle!
Probably a smarak.
It's beautiful.
Are you looking for an emerald in your dream?
I wasn't looking.
What else would you have been looking for?
There is nothing else here.
After all, anyone can look for such a fine smarak.
It's awfully big.
I mean, the biggest that exists.
If it were smaller, then Miss Ikon could keep it.
Someone shouts.
Someone is calling us.
There.
Katsoppa.
Help me!
At least I didn't dream of rescuing Haisuli.
He has overshadowed us.
For heaven's sake, stop messing around and try to help.
If you don't help me out on a terrible morning.
It stinks, yes we will help. Stay put.
Stay, stay!
This is a bigger gem.
I would dream as good as a Moomin, Pekko.
Me too.
But I didn't dream of jewels.
Extremely fine.
But of course, we, the hemuli friend, appreciate rare plants more.
Necessarily. I wouldn't trade them for anything.
Not even to this raining rock. As beautiful as it is.
Gems are the best I know.
I agree.
Mom, you get the emerald.
Thank you, Moomin Pekko.
I'd be fine with the emerald, but you have to keep it.
Since your dream came true, you are meant to keep the emerald.
It's great, but what can you do with it?
That would be great letterpress, but I rarely get mail.
It will rain.
Oh, will you?
If the kids are outside, they get soaked.
They get wet anyway because they went swimming.
Now drop by drop.
Let's go to the cave for shelter.
You're already wet.
I'm dry and I'm going to stay dry.
Come on little sell, I'll take you to the cave.
Ha ha, so you don't dare go there alone.
Look, I'm afraid of very few things.
But one of them is Thunder.
In that style.
What rain?
Hey, it's hailing.
This is too much.
It's raining so much that it hurts.
Kasmini.
All my hair.
Script
What's up with that?
How great.
Oh, oh, how long will I roll to this place.
The hailstorm passed.
Unprecedented hailstorms.
There must have been a lot of bad things.
So.
Yes.
Scarecrow! Disaster! The hail would knock out Hemul.
Oh, the horror.
Hemul is being carried here.
Well, I can't carry a meter anymore.
Don't always complain.
Eyes get dark.
Hemuli!
Everything is ruined.
Father, Raekkuuro destroyed Hemul's flower garden and greenhouse.
It's horrible.
All my plants, all my lovely flowers are crushed.
It's all over.
Let's carry Hemuli inside.
Speed up!
Scarf dad, I'm rolling.
A pinch, don't exaggerate.
One step at a time, Nipsu, you can do it.
Cut Hemuli in.
Let's lower him gently onto the couch.
He has developed a high fever.
A nervous breakdown, I'm sure.
Let's go mix the medicine right now.
My beloved plants, all gone.
Don't go in the sky.
The garden will hardly be the same again.
In no way.
Unless we do something, Hemuli will never recover in the world.
I'm sure the garden can be replanted.
It won't work.
Of course we could plant some species, but Hemuli has collected plants from all over the world.
Let's use magic.
Would Noita be able to do something?
I doubt his abilities in this matter.
Let's go ask anyway.
It's pointless for me to complain that Hemuli has been through a lot and that he won't recover.
But you are tough.
But you're a Witch, Can't you really do anything for Hemul's garden?
Not who I said it to, it goes beyond Martini.
But when Hemuli is so depressed that she can't get out of bed.
It doesn't increase my Martian.
Let's go already.
Moomin, too bad we weren't there to help.
If you can't do anything, then you can't.
It doesn't get better by grieving.
Even a witch's power has its limits.
I have had to notice it.
It's sad.
Hello then, Alisa.
Hey hey.
Ah, I made it up.
What did you get in your head?
What do you think, could the Magician restore the garden to its former state?
Magician?
Once we could wish for anything and the Magician made our wishes come true.
True, the Magician can help us, but how do we find him?
Hi Alisa.
What?
Could you ask grandma, Does she know how we can contact Tai Kuri?
And did you know where the Magician can be found?
Apparently, the witch jumped on a broomstick and went looking for him.
Oh, shouldn't those be back already?
The magician doesn't live right next door.
We just have to wait.
I'm worried about Hemul.
Don't worry, grandma is by her side.
Well, Hemuli rukka is better now.
Ooo.
That's where the Magician comes on the Panther's back.
You didn't find those...
We must reward.
We must reward those witches.
I hope the Magician is in a good mood.
It never is, except when you got from tiudi and viudi to the royal order.
You called me.
We desperately need the Magician's help.
I'm not the kind of Magician who gets called in on a whim.
Of course not, we are very sorry to trouble you.
No one else can help.
And last time the Magician made all our wishes come true.
But you also did me a great favor.
Besides, I don't make home visits.
And you have already received a reward for your service.
Even a lot, if you allow me to add.
Can we do another favor?
Forward.
Don't we?
No, no. Hardly.
How so?
You brought me happiness once, it won't happen again.
What favor could we do?
Five of it.
We want to know.
In for a penny in for a pound.
With your help I finally got hold of the king ruby.
So?
But I'm missing.
The finest of emeralds, Queen Smaragdi.
I don't want to wait three hundred years.
Emerald Moomin.
My magic, wait.
Why?
This is it. This is it.
Queen Emerald.
I can't believe this is true.
Good night.
Good night, my Troll.
After this incident, Moomin always fell asleep in the hope of a wonderful dream.
But if he was dreaming, he was dreaming.
This is.