The rain has once again spoiled Moominvalley.
Now it hasn't rained to the point of flooding, but everyone is in a particularly good mood when the rain finally subsides and the sun comes out.
That someone could be that stupid.
How so?
Look at the Moomins and the scumbags and they should be rational beings.
Love, fools.
Joo.
One day you will fall in love too.
Not soon, it's not easy to find a suitable destination.
What? Are you interested in shock or inventions and Hemuli is just too old.
The chief of police would act, but he's in a tizzy.
Nuskamuikko doesn't think too much of it, but he doesn't agree.
There are none other than...
Cry?
A less glamorous type.
What do you mean?
I can't stand being cheated, but I want a lot of presents.
Gifts?
I don't start courting anyone, and I don't give anyone flowers or boxes of chocolates.
I popped the chocolates myself.
Yes, of course.
Mmm, yummy. Well, I'm leaving.
Ai, minne?
How about tell me?
Aha, somewhere where there is gold.
How did you know?
Otherwise, you wouldn't give up the meal break.
Sell, promise you won't cheat on a single soul.
Gold can still be washed upriver to the north.
That's the end of it.
Thank God.
You don't understand how gold goes into the blood.
Where did the snap go?
Away to forget your love for me.
Crazy idea, to get a swing for Luojaparatko.
Oops, looks like it's going to rain.
Best not to rush.
Should have asked for more detailed instructions.
Oh!
Wake up!
Oh, what a thick fog.
No more river.
I have to turn home.
But where is home?
Hi, is anyone there?
Hoi!
I should have taken Myy on the trip.
He has never been lost.
Haa!
I should have taken Myy on the trip.
He has never been lost.
Haa!
This!
Hi, hi, hi...
Well?
Hm?
Hm!
are you sick?
Hm?
Hm!
H?
Treatment!
Anyone here?
Help! Help!
Lovely girl.
Did you find it honey?
Eyelash, I'm talking to you.
Ami.
Can't you hear?
Leave me alone.
Morning.
Good morning, Nipsu.
From that day on, every morning Nipsu went to the mountains to the edge of the stream.
What the hell has happened to Nipsu?
Emuli said that Nipsu always leaves somewhere in the morning and doesn't come back until late.
Every day last week too.
So. What secrets does Nipsu have in the mountains?
What the hell does Nipsu have in the mountains?
Antulee.
It's getting foggy.
What? Did Moomin go after Nipsu?
Yep, he's going to find out why Nipsu disappears somewhere in the mornings.
Muimetta! Minuhan se piti vakoilla Nipsua.
We can trust Moomin's abilities.
He will come!
Moomin, you came and...
Well, tell me! What does Nipsu do all day?
Well, at least it doesn't bring gold.
Moomin!
Myi and Miss Niisku.
Sorry, I can't say anything now.
I want to be alone.
And you said we could trust Moomin's abilities.
That's what I said.
Well, what?
I want to be alone.
And doesn't eat anything.
No, just like Nipsu.
Concern.
No, no, no.
No, just like Nipsu.
Worrying.
What strange thing has happened to them in the mountains?
I'll go find out about it.
You don't. Way too stalky for you.
What do you mean?
It's easy to get lost in the mountains.
And since you don't know what has happened there, you have to be careful.
The task requires experience, courage and skill.
Well, who would have that?
I'll get to it.
Don't be sad. Everything is going well.
Remember to be careful.
Good morning!
Why are you on the move?
I'm not.
Now it is.
I am.
Why are you up so early?
I don't have time to talk now, I'm shadowing them.
Or you work as an undercover cop, why?
Something serious is going on.
Well, what a good habit you brought!
What a trouble!
And the rest we do too.
Moominpapa is also infected.
Even so, he immediately shut himself in the room.
He shouldn't have been in the room.
Moomin, Moomin, Moomin, Moomin.
Moomin, Moomin, Moomin, Moomin!
Moomin, Moomin, Moomin!
He shouldn't have let me in on it.
Oh, wait for the salt?
Give me some salt!
Pardon? What did you say?
Could you pass the salt?
That's enough for me.
How about dessert?
I can't take it anymore either.
I'm going to find out what's behind this!
Me too. Mamma, join us.
Yeah, I don't know. They are such changelings that maybe we shouldn't get involved.
Well, but the rest of the mipekko didn't take dessert seriously.
Hmm, true.
Hi, where are you going?
To the secret place to the north.
There too?
Can I come along?
Oh, you too.
Yeah, I've been working on this. What exactly is the matter?
Seems serious.
Hmm, they come back like a charm. Something inexplicable is happening there.
That along the river facing north, right?
Hmm.
Yeah, right.
Do you know anything about it?
Hardly, but don't be sad Moomin mom.
Yes, that fever will gradually pass.
The fog is rising!
I can't see anything.
Hey, wait for me!
I can walk.
I can't hear the sound of the water.
Oh, we're lost.
Hemuli, where are you going?
Something says this way.
Lightning!
There they are!
Oh, my brother is there too.
What are they staring at?
Good unusual.
What do you see?
Now tell me what you see!
Quietly!
Waters.
Waters?
Oh, how beautiful.
Where did they hide?
Psst, sell, come here.
I don't see anything watery.
What exactly is the matter?
The water went away, because the little ones lived.
Tomorrow then.
He will come back.
Moomin troll.
The news of a lovely mermaid spread to Moomin Valley.
The mermaid has put the women of Moomin Valley in a crisis.
Only men are capable of seeing things that do not exist.
Ladies of Moominvalley, how do we drive this madness away?
Men need to be taught this.
There's only one way.
And what is it?
The mermaid lives in Lammiko and Lammiko must be got rid of.
He likes Lamme, even though he doesn't exist.
Did you come up with something better?
If you still wait.
We women have been trampled on enough.
The suggestion is good.
Let's go fill up the Pond.
Tomorrow we'll set out with hoeing jalapeños.
Lammikko and Lammikko
Good morning
The pond has dried up.
Lammikko and Lammikko
People
Men have more imagination. I've always known that.
Wouldn't it be best to forget the water ones?
It wasn't more beautiful than mymmeli.
Uhu, is this the pond?
Where has the water evaporated?
The rain has washed the pond away.
Myo, Is this what you meant?
Good morning ladies.
Where is the trip? New gold rush huh?
We came to fill this pond.
Really, you ladies?
What do you tolerate laughing at?
Sorry, but when I see in my mind how you fill the pond with shovels and hoes.
Are you healthy yet?
Don't screw up.
Oh, you're Mrs. Yourself again.
I've left you alone for days.
Well, it's okay, I'll have time to clean up.
Mimmel?
I'm hungry, let's go home.
I have too.
The bone-chilling fever passed.
It is said that at this time of the year you can sometimes see mermaids in small mountain ponds.
I wouldn't have believed it.
I didn't see the mermaid!
I think only men see that delusion.
Love is boring, but someone falls in love with an illusion attack!
Come on, I think I'm going to push the envelope.
No one knew where the mermaid disappeared to or if she even existed.
Maybe that's a good thing.