Bye.
Dad, can you fix the roof?
Yeah, yes I can.
Moomin, can you hand me a board over there?
Oh! This one?
Just that, that long. Thank you very much.
Wow!
Oh! Dad, watch out! Don't fall!
Grab something!
Oh! I thought you were going to fall.
My son, I thought so myself.
Be careful, dad.
I don't have a problem anymore.
Moomin! Moomin!
What are we doing here? Hey kids!
Oops, the roof looked broken.
This is quite high. Just don't slide down there.
The roof is ancient. Dad built it when he was young.
Papa Moomin is fixing the roof. I thought he broke it.
Your opinion is not needed.
Moomin Pekku, give me one more board.
Oh, oh, father!
Oh, father!
Stupid to make the same mistake twice.
Hey!
Moomin Pekku, did it go bad?
Hi, hi, hi!
Brother, what a surprise!
I shouldn't have to continue fixing the roof anymore.
I thought I would finish it today.
Could I fix the roof? Would you fix the roof?
Don't let Nipsu fix it? The roof still needs to be watered.
You don't even know that I've studied a carpenter's correspondence course.
Well then, I'll help you.
No thanks. I'll fix it myself. Trust me.
Nipsu is clever, amazing.
Amazing.
We'll see how it goes after the first rain.
What do you do for a living?
It also has a lot of honey.
Nipsu has helped Moominpapa so much that I cut him a really big apple.
Ah, wonderful. Good luck, Pekka.
That roof is still going to collapse, Nipsu.
I think it's right that Nipsu is rewarded. He worked hard.
Well, it did. It's true. Now I'm hawking.
Hey, wait!
Hey, you can get such a big piece of hotcake at once.
Myy is right. Eat the tart with pleasure.
Yeah, I'll lick first then.
Disgusting.
Ompa sweet. And such a big piece that it feels like a salary.
Well, it's a salary.
When you work for someone, you are actually working for yourself.
Oh for his own good. Well, it is. True.
Now what did you come up with?
To shine.
Let's start helping everyone who needs help.
And it's paid for with pies and other goodies.
Let's start helping.
Exactly. Sell, Do you need help with something?
Not in.
Don't be a useless bitch. Tell me what kind of help you need, and I'll get your piece of cake next time.
I don't need your help with anything.
Moovimamma, do you have something for Riuska's helper?
Any work is fine.
Wait and see.
You can bake me a strawberry or cherry cake as a reward.
Nipsu is completely engrossed in his invention.
The pinch was difficult before, but now it's unbearable.
Hi Moovimamma, can I fetch you some water?
No need, thanks. I just got the laundry done.
Well then I'll hang the laundry to dry.
Oh shit.
I see. You have too much work. Leave them to me.
Yes, but a pinch.
Hi dad.
Oh, he's fallen asleep.
Oh, it's time to go water the flowers.
Oh good time.
Freshly washed laundry along the yard.
Strange, the nipsuna skin had to hang the clothes on a line.
I wasted my work too.
Nipsu probably didn't notice using clothespins.
I have to start doing laundry again.
This is for Riuska's helper.
If you hire me right away, you'll get a hefty discount.
What do you say?
I can't offer you any work.
Me neither.
Oh right. I'm not selling this.
Don't tease me!
Asked Nuuskamuikku for a job, if working is what you crave.
Aha, Nuuska from Muikku.
Hello, businessman.
Nuuska Muikkunen.
Hey, little one.
How are you?
I do business as an assistant.
You as a sidekick?
Yeah. Do you have any work to offer?
Everything is fine and you can give your salary...
Wow, that's how tasty your hate soup is, which you tend to cook.
I can't find any work.
Oh, don't say that.
Yes, you will definitely find something.
Not found. I do all the work myself.
Don't be like that. I want nothing but honest work.
Aha, now I figured it out.
Uh! How unclean is the tent?
Clay and grass stains all around.
Of course, my tent is constantly at the mercy of rain and wind.
Hey, I'll wash it for you.
No, no, no way. I have never washed it.
Heavens, then the tent must be washed.
Take the word of a professional, I know.
I'm a dashing helper, helper, helper.
I'll get a strawberry cake from Moomin mamma, and I'll take a sniff of it on the sofa.
My career as a helper is already well underway.
I'm a brisk helper, I'm sure I'll meet the moon.
What? Tent, where is it? Tent!
You must not run away from the tent. Come back, come back.
Here, here and there.
You can't run away from the tent now.
The water is cold! I can't sleep!
Help, help! What?
It's really low here.
Hello, Nipsu. Has the tent been washed?
With Juuk, I'm washed by it. Of course, I'm going crazy, but...
The fabric was bad. I'm not taking any pay this time.
Goodbye. Sorry.
Hi, hi.
Do we have to?
Do we really have to go take care of Vilionka's children?
I fear the worst. I just went to Vilionka's place and he asked us for help.
He himself is going to greet the sick in the community.
To greet the local sick.
And there's no way you'd want to leave your children alone at home to do bad things.
We had other plans.
Well, since we had to go to the beach now.
I don't like Vilionka and I hate his children.
I see. Taking care of children is exactly what I'm good at.
No! He doesn't know where to poke.
Nipsu, as you know madam, Vilionkka is quite demanding.
Good! Then of course he wants me.
Maybe.
But mother Nipsu wants to go.
And Nipsu is a badass.
Well, I guess that suits Mrs. Vilionka.
Yes, I guess.
I will come home late at night.
That's right, ma'am.
I make sure that the children spend their time according to the reading schedule that I have prepared for them.
Yes, yes ma'am.
I have raised my children so that they would always follow certain rules in their lives.
That's my motto.
Right, I know, but I'd like to...
So what?
What do I get paid?
Share, well, what would you like?
I would really like something good to put in my mouth, something delicious, if that's okay.
What? Fits well.
I eat as much as your stomach takes when my kids eat dinner.
Lovely, as much as I want.
Only if you take good care of my children.
Have a nice rest of the day.
Hurrah!
Huh, I'm starving.
That, hey.
Hey.
Listen, isn't it time for dinner already?
Not yet.
Isn't it hard to concentrate when you have a stomach ache?
Dinner is not eaten yet.
The evening snack can only be eaten when it is time.
It's evening and you want a snack.
Let's start eating.
Dinner, kids.
Oh, cookies.
I love cookies.
Our mother will never know where we wasted our time.
Let's attack. Did you hear?
Salty!
Of course.
Mom said sugar is dangerous.
Do you always bring salty cookies?
Joo.
They pay poorly.
Hi, hi, hi.
Moomin-Pekko is currently sitting on the tea table.
That I had to agree to babysit.
Hey!
Hey, I came to see how you're doing.
What are the children doing?
They draw on the first floor according to the reading order.
Do not!
You are the babysitter for a while, I'm just fine.
You get tired easily.
Please.
Ah, I'm sleepy.
Fine, but then you give me a piece of cake.
Oh, a whole piece.
Make up your mind, it takes ages.
Oh no, so be it.
Aha, let's make a drawing, seriously.
What exactly are you drawing?
Oh, what is it?
Flower.
I thought someone had swatted a fly at it.
I'm drawing a boat.
It can't even sail in a teacup.
Ah.
Why do you draw such small pictures?
This is a fish.
Or fish? It is so small that a Worm could eat it.
Think big things.
Draw big pictures.
If the drawing goes wrong, take a new paper.
Or little souls draw little pictures.
Increase size.
So big, huh?
No, no, no, not at all.
Your paper is too small.
Draw here.
What do you get for that?
Yes, yes.
Nobody, or a boat, or a fish.
No matter how big.
What is this?
The challenge is to be happy and let yourself be free.
Maybe you are already too free.
Free and obedient children are the best.
Moomin, Troll.
What are you talking about?
We came to see how things are going here.
Tell me right away what has happened to Nipsu.
Nipsu got tired of protecting the children.
He's snoring over there on the couch in the living room.
And he broke his promise.
So you're in a pinch.
That's right.
Hey, I think we definitely have to get out of here.
Because just believe me.
Tell me why.
So why.
Don't tell.
Well, let's start sinking. Run.
Hrrrrrrrrrrrr
Have a good sleep.
It's quiet.
The seller does his job well.
Hi Myy. Thank you for...
Father!
Oh no.
The floor, walls, pits get a surface.
The adopted ones tore all the places.
This is no joke.
No mother can think these are beautiful.
If Viljonkka sees the storms, then my reputation is gone.
Hi, hi, hi, hi, hi, hi!
What did I do?
What can I do?
Yay!
Luuska Moikkusen's tent.
Ain't screw it up, kid.
I know, let's make it beautiful.
Well, big lines.
Huh, Viljonka's children, are you all helpers?
I'm not, I'm just helping out a bit.
Sell, I can't see Viljonka's children.
Well, that's horrible.
They have moved on since we were talking.
Hello, Luuska the little boy.
Oh, my, this piece fits that.
I hope Viljonkka doesn't notice that the statue is glued.
About, carefully, about.
I have to go see what the kids are doing before Viljonka comes back.
About.
I can't believe my eyes.
Oh rot.
Again, delay.
You are exactly what we were told.
How long have they already reached?
Oh, there they are.
There was nothing to worry about.
Hey, let's see.
Kids are just having fun.
Let's go along.
I'm running.
They really enjoy rowing.
For once they are happy.
Are you in rowing boats for the first time?
Yeah, we are.
First time.
Mom is afraid to let us out to the playground.
Dangerous.
But today you can row as long as you want.
Shall we pick up the pace?
Mummy!
Mene will be crushed if Moomin doesn't stop it.
Precautionary!
No, Moomin, you're about to crash.
Hey, hurry up, Mummy.
I'm a warning.
Issue.
No wait.
I will come.
Terrible, how do we get through this?
Something has to be done, I don't know what, but something has to be done.
Help, come help, help, help.
You here, where are Viljonka's children?
Oh shit, you don't even know.
The children are in trouble for Pinte and so is Mumipeikka.
Hold on.
Keep calm.
Viljonka probably didn't expect this.
Do something, don't procrastinate.
Me?
No, no, I can't swim, you know that.
And you had to be a badass sidekick.
It's not my fault that I hate water.
Help, help, great luck on my beach, come help.
Well, yes, I can shout for help too.
You are of no use.
Shipwreck, children in distress at sea, help.
Nipsu, what happened?
Oh, snuff, little one.
Speed, speed, speed.
Tasteless Peikko.
Can you stay afloat?
Sniff the little one, get the rope.
Catch up.
Well, hey, grab the rope.
Clear.
Don't worry, just hold on to the tire.
Prepare.
Well, let's start pulling now.
Well, now.
No.
Thanks for the help.
This is lovely.
Nuuska Muikkunen's delicious soup is the best.
Hot and tasty.
Delicious.
Do you like my vegetable guide that much?
Are you a vegetable?
Namely.
Surprising carrots.
I hate onions.
You must be paprika.
But you ate them all and praised the soup for its good taste.
Yeah, it tasted good.
For real good.
Oh, and you hate carrots, onions and green peppers.
Our mother never puts carrots, onions or peppers in the soup.
Well, how would you describe this vegetable guide in a few words?
Good, how good.
And then close your eyes.
Huh, are my kids there?
A pinch.
Hey hey.
Mother.
Vili Junkka.
Welcome back.
What owes an explanation?
You wrap my children in raggedy blankets and feed them suspicious-looking broth.
Vili Junkka.
Dear Madam, I can explain everything.
I don't want to hear any more emergency lies.
I will never ask you to babysit again.
We're going home now.
Joo.
There was no praise.
Not so.
Thank you for today.
We had a lot of fun.
Come play again.
what are you doing
Get out of there!
Yes mom.
I wouldn't be surprised at all, even if this was the happiest day of those children.
Nipsu, I guess you're going to play with them again?
Being a babysitter...
I remembered exactly what I had to do.
Oh no.
I guess there's nothing more that can be done about it.
Let it be, Nipsu.
Forget the whole thing and start worrying and only tomorrow when Vili who comes to complain.
No, don't be scared.
And if you need a helper, you don't have to try me.
Thanks for watching!