The weather was so wonderful that Papa Moomin couldn't concentrate on writing his memoirs.
Good morning, Hemuli. Good morning. Have you found a new plant?
Goats. I've already explored Moomin Valley in detail.
So. I, too, already know every inhabitant of Moomin Valley.
Absolutely.
how is it Would you like a cup of tea?
Moomin and sell.
So it seems.
Peeking through a crack in the fence.
It's an abandoned house.
Moomin, what are you doing?
Hi dad.
It hasn't been lived in for years.
Someone just moved in there.
Ai.
Shall I take a peek?
Good manners is how cool.
Would the children come to play with us?
Ice. They look so good together.
I would like to get closer.
So do I. They are sitting there in their seats.
We have to get to the other side of the fence.
How does it work? We can't just march in like that.
Let's go borrow some sugar.
What is your passion?
I'll borrow your magnifying glass.
What's up? Please.
A bit cheeky.
Dad, what are you going to do?
You stay here waiting.
If you come along, the whole plan will go to waste.
Dad, what are you up to?
What is that father examining with a magnifying glass?
I would know.
Mom, there's someone sneaking around.
Goody. What the hell are you guys doing there?
Woe to me for the verse.
I thought nobody lived here.
We live. We just moved.
Oh, I'm so sorry. I don't want to intrude.
So what are you doing here?
I'm investigating a murderous transportation system.
Is there a similar one for them?
Of course it is. It is fascinating research.
Of course it is. It is fascinating to study how they build their way.
This right here is the high street of murderers.
I don't see any regrets.
You're not an expert like me.
Otherwise, welcome to mummy valley.
Even though I live somewhat far away, I'm still your closest helper in these matters.
Oh, you're a Moomin dad.
Actually I am. But how do you know that?
Has our reputation already spread that far?
We've heard that Moomins are a bit unusual.
Oh, how flattering.
And you are Mrs...
Vili, Jonkka, mother and housewife.
How do you do.
Dad seems to have made some new friends for us.
Oh, welcome to the party.
For a long time, we haven't had any good guys.
That's a really good idea, my dear.
How else could we show that they are welcome in mummy valley?
For my part, I took care of the children's entertainment.
Good. Otherwise Hemuli...
I guess. I have to organize fireworks.
Let's collect a lot of flowers.
What flowers would you collect?
I know the flowers in the neighborhood.
The kids will probably like this.
If they survive.
They are weird. Remember to behave especially well.
Yes mom.
Luumi-Peikko, take the cookies to the table.
Clear.
The slide works great.
Good. I'm going to try it.
Name, name, name.
Hey, fingers off, jerk.
I only took one.
Alert, alert.
Vili whose katraine is approaching.
Oh, oh, oh. The rush came. Please help me decorate.
Let's light up.
Shall the rockets be lit immediately or later?
Later, later. In the end, to shine.
Welcome, Moomin house.
Thank you for the kind invitation.
Come in and make yourself at home.
A very pleasant surprise.
Welcome, Moomin house.
Garbage.
Mom, you look very upset.
Rosebuds should have been sprinkled on the floor, but there were none.
Flowers will stain.
No problem. May I introduce our child?
They look very different.
Moomin is the only child of his own.
Others are. The kids will probably have fun.
My children don't play. They read and study. Rather.
Really. Are you sure about that?
Of course.
Let's go to the salon. Vili-some people can study other people's play.
Wipe the chair before you sit down.
Yes, mother.
The children have built.
Special furnishings.
You really don't want to play anything?
In.
The slide would do wonders for you.
No thanks.
No. Absolutely not.
Are you absolutely sure?
Me too.
All the better for us.
Sounds like Moomin.
Beautiful. Beautiful.
A small sale and a pinch.
Yes, your children seem quiet.
So. Kind children are seen, but not heard.
That was my child.
And that was the second one.
We seem to be having fun.
Take a shortbread cereal.
They have a slightly peculiar taste.
Don't worry.
Everyone in turn.
Save my child.
Stop it. It's dangerous.
I told you to behave properly.
You can hurt yourself.
Don't be nervous. I have medicine for my face in my handbag.
Unnatural, Eiti.
Go!
Kids, stop it.
Stop it.
We're going home.
Time for the end of the glitterati, I guess.
Yes, I was warned.
Would I expose my child to all of this?
Muomilaakso is not a suitable place for children.
What exactly is this?
Ilo gunfire in your honor.
What?
I have arranged it for you.
Hello. Come again soon.
Tomorrow.
It won't even be heard.
I don't think Viljonka enjoys the party.
But her kids enjoyed.
I think Viljonka should have lowered himself from the slide.
Adults don't go down slides. They are afraid of looking funny.
Father.
I'm so sorry, Granny. I will fix what I have broken.
Dad, what happened?
It seems like it's been a long time since I last went down slides.
Now let's make the slide so sturdy that it can withstand Moomin mom.
Me too. Let's do it for mom.
Thanks for the fix. I don't.
But remember that we also want to count.
Of course. I'm just trying.
You stay there until I come back.
Did I get out?
You can study in the yard.
So what is someone?
You can never play with those noisy buckets again.
Mom, where are you going?
To find another house. There is a move to Moomin Valley, it was a mistake.
Roa-Vilinjonkka, have a good day.
Stay away from children's activities.
What a pity. We were just thinking of going to pick them up.
Curio.
Is anyone there?
I can.
What?
Stinker.
Please wait.
Good, good.
Good.
Help.
Can't help you anymore.
I have a deep chasm and a hungry crocodile.
We should have taken Vilionka's children with us.
What about Vilionkka?
We wouldn't have told him.
Nipsu, did the spirit leave you?
No, I knocked the crocodile out when I fell on it and now I'm swimming to shore.
I thought I was going to swim.
Bad catch.
Vilionka's children.
Why don't they come here?
Of course, their mother has forbidden them to be.
What now?
Hey, why aren't you playing with Moomin and the others?
They don't want to play with us.
We can always be one.
What is Haisuli doing there?
I guess you guys don't usually have fun.
No, we want to play too.
Listen, I can show you an even better playground.
Really?
Necessarily.
What would I start lying to you about?
It's an exciting place.
It's terribly sad here.
Terribly!
Do you think Moomin won't play with us anymore?
Not sure.
Your brother is right, it is.
Let's go now.
What the heck does Haisuli have in mind?
This is the place I told you about.
Grab the rope and swing yourself to the other side and back.
I've never been so into pullovers.
This is the place I was talking about.
Grab the rope and swing yourself to the other side and back.
I've never been so into pullovers.
Scare.
What's fun exists without shivering.
Isn't the opposite slope a bit higher?
There is. You must raise your thighs.
Who wants to be first?
Let's all go at once.
All of them?
Then you won't be so scared.
I don't want to like that.
Oh, you wanna go alone huh?
Go, it's fun.
Do you dare?
Well, why wouldn't you.
I've done the trick hundreds and hundreds of times.
Show me then, Stinker.
Noni, Toivoteikka.
I didn't even know that Stink was made.
I didn't even know that Haisuli is hard to hang on ropes.
Listen, is this your regular place?
Kind of.
Honestly, I don't think I could do the trick myself,
if I didn't know you got through it.
Stink, you have to show us.
Jump first, I'll be next.
No, no, you just jump.
I have to see with my own eyes how the trick is done.
What, you haven't jumped before yourself?
I am, it's just not fun now.
Ha ha, don't bother spoiling other people's joy.
We're here ready to clap.
Look, Ullias and Urhea Haisuli Tartsan.
Joo.
Are you ready, Stingray? Flip it properly.
My hero, Stink, jumps.
Stink, we're waiting.
Power.
Stink, show me.
Uh...
Or you've done this many times, huh?
I am, like everyone else.
The trick is impossible.
And you knew it, Stink.
I don't know now.
Follow us, let's go play for real.
Stinky, you play Tartsa and stay as rich as you like.
Wait you can leave me here rogue.
This is unfair.
A Moomin.
Oh!
The brother whose kids had a blast,
and they did not return home until late at night.
Bye until tomorrow.
Hello. Hello.
Hello. Hello. Hello. Hello. Hello.
Oh, oh, my child.
Where have you been? I told you to stay home.
We were with Moomin.
Oh, he winged you.
It wasn't quite like that. We...
Forget that horrible family.
We will move from here right away.
Oh, we're moving?
Yeah, get out of here.
It is not suitable for those who love order and spotless homes.
What happened to you now?
We don't want to change.
We do want to stay.
We want to play with Moomin.
Moomin here is fun and dusty.
We want to live in Moomin Valley forever.
Exemplary upbringing, own example.
In my experience, children pull the longest rope.
It's together here.
Monta.
That's how Vili, who with his three children, became the lively inhabitants of Moomin Valley.