Moomipeikko had a dream.
I think it's nice to float in the sky.
Oh Moomipeikko look! Oh, we have a lake too!
I have never experienced anything so wonderful in my entire life.
Me neither. Only now do you understand the life of birds.
They always get to enjoy open landscapes.
We fly wildly high.
It scares me. Let's land already.
Oh my, why did I go along?
I'm not scared!
Niisku, your aircraft is like a fairy tale.
I could build dozens of these.
Niisku, may I direct?
Plastic!
Stink, Can you pilot an aircraft?
Stop now!
You cause a dangerous situation!
I dream of this persecution. I won't die yet.
Father! Mother!
Oh!
All in all, a remarkable sleep.
Why did my Niisku brother let Haisuli pilot the aircraft.
I'm confused. I was chatting with Niisku, but suddenly there was Stink in his place.
And that's when the air fire started to heat up, right?
Yes, but it was just a dream.
It was not a good dream at all.
Niisku's aircraft is starting to need finishing touches.
Why did you have such a dream?
That dream balloon was completely different from Niisku's aircraft.
But what happened to the balloon? Did it keep flying?
I don't know. I canoed it out of sight because I fell.
You could have turned around to see how it went.
I didn't get it.
Just don't tell Niisku about your dream. His nerves are starting to fray.
I won't tell. And you shouldn't remember a dream either.
Well, now it's finally ready.
Yes, but it hasn't gone live yet.
Do you think there will still be some twists and turns?
No, of course, but...
Oh, so there are puzzles?
I can't deny it.
What is it about?
From the fuel.
You said you developed a new efficient fuel.
That's what I said, but the power doesn't seem to be enough.
Is your plane not flying?
It is possible. Then it's not an aircraft, but an ordinary ship.
I hope it's good. At least then it won't fall down.
If I get to fly it, I'll be laughed at.
Or what?
I'm not laughing at you.
What about the others? They laugh.
Well, some maybe, but you don't care about that.
I went to tell some friends that I'm going to do a public test flight soon.
Your ship is so great that everyone would be happy just to see it.
But that's not enough for me.
Moomin, I would like to ask you a favor because you are my Sister's best friend.
Well what can I do for you?
I want you and only you to be the pilot in the flight of experience.
No, are you serious?
Hello! Hello! Hello! Hello! Hello! Hello! Hello! Hello! Hello! Hello! Hello! Hello! Hello! Hello! Hello! Hello! Hello! Hello!
Hello! Hello! Hello! Hello! Hello! Hello! Hello! Hello! Hello!
Moomin!
Listen, I get to control Niisku's aircraft as a searcher, so that the steers can smell it.
What exactly were you talking about?
Isn't it difficult to control?
No, quite easy.
But I have to practice in Niskuk's workshop beforehand.
Does Niisku not come on board at all?
He will, of course, but he will examine the engine during the flight.
I hope everything goes well.
Combustion always does today.
That's a serious flaw.
Isn't it?
That's it.
You hear me, mummy.
Assume that a gusty aircraft takes off.
Of course it will rise.
Yeah, but if it crashes due to air bubbles or fuel problems, so what?
Father!
Mumblebees naturally fly through the air.
One can hurt another, right?
Joo.
How would it be for Niskunk and you then?
Of course we have parachutes.
Parachutes?
Dad, do you know what a parachute is?
Of course, this is how the lily flutters from the upper air.
Yeah, but we don't need parachutes because the test flight will definitely be successful.
And I will be the first pilot in all of Moomin Valley.
Yes?
Good day, son.
Good day.
Hello everyone.
Does the gentleman happen to know where Niisku's workshop is located?
With pleasure.
Great, Niisku misses time with his aircraft.
Yes, how do you know?
I thought that Niisku would have kept his invention a secret.
Share, share, all the cookies worth mentioning in the world have arrived from his work.
Are you inventing too?
Yes, let's be fine.
You must have heard my name before.
I'm Moominpapa.
Nuuska Muikkunen.
And I'm Moomin.
Pleasant.
I, for one, am famous for inventing the muffle.
Then the muffle.
Hungry.
Oh, oh, do none of you really know me?
Sorry.
Maybe I have read about you after all.
What have you come up with so far?
Oh, oh, I've come up with many things in my life.
For example, a button needle that doesn't sting because it has a button at each end.
A newspaper that reads itself.
A wallet that crumbles when you take money out of it.
May I introduce you to perhaps my best invention?
What is that?
Human operated fan brand and wind head.
Absolutely great.
Well, what do you say about my invention?
Well why not?
In addition, I have invented a triangular handkerchief,
an angular balloon, a seven-hole button, and more.
Otherwise, why do you want to meet, Niisku?
I think one of my inventions could be useful to him.
From what invention?
Something like that, but when it's seen it's top secret.
Share it, Niiskun Verstas.
I'll show you.
Oh, thank you.
Niiskun will be amazed for sure.
I'll leave here then.
It's a pleasure to help budding inventors.
Have you seen a triangular handkerchief?
No, and I have no desire to see.
What does that inventor have to show Niisku?
Sanopas se.
So.
The drug troll tells us yes.
Sniffy, can you wait until then?
In.
Wait, I'll come with you.
I thought we had a guest.
Where has everyone gone?
This.
There's still something.
Father and Snuff.
Father, why did you come here?
That about...
What do you mean by that?
Niisku and Muhvel have secret things and they wanted to stay together.
What are they doing inside?
They're chatting, I don't know why.
Too bad.
I can't see inside because the news is in front.
Is this the new and efficient fuel?
Yes, although the invention is less original.
It's a disappointingly practical power fuel.
My ship can only use liquid fuel.
It is not a problem when Kimpaleen dissolves ten liters of water,
the engine runs for ten hours.
Oh so long.
If you live by the word of faith, try it out, even now.
Right away?
I guarantee that if you use fuel in solid form,
your ship's engine will run for up to a hundred hours.
A hundred hours?
If that's true, you're a really big deal.
So the last puzzle of my aircraft is solved.
Yes.
The workshop door doesn't even seem to be locked.
Not so.
If I want to see Niisku, I can march in.
Do you want to see him then?
I want to.
Why?
I don't want Niiskun to fall into that cookie thread.
We'll see how it goes soon.
Dad, not the last time.
Don't last.
We'll see how it goes soon.
Dad, don't be so childish.
I know what they're doing inside.
Don't talk nonsense.
It invented putting fuel in the aircraft's tank.
Did you watch?
I saw it, even though the visibility was poor.
Where were you watching?
In a crevice where only I can fit.
I won't tell you before.
What did they discuss?
There is no rehentel.
I'm disappearing, like you already are.
Don't now, Niisku. There is some misconception here.
Shut up.
I'm disappearing.
Outrageous bullying.
Solid fuel for one hundred hours.
Poor cheater.
Niisku, fine, let me explain.
No need to explain.
I know why you came here to feed me willow rope.
Shit!
Not true.
I didn't come here to talk soft.
I already believe.
Fishing rods of happiness.
Foul language.
Niisku, spoil yourself.
Maybe the fuel is not suitable for your vessel.
It goes with anything?
The fuel was the snow of the eye.
The guy just wanted to see my aircraft.
Yes.
Muhveli is a spy.
What do you mean?
By the way, did you have any business?
No longer.
What a betrayal.
A muffle is a hummus cookie.
What?
I don't know pariah.
What would be the point of inventing hummocks?
I can assure you that all my inventions work.
I have to be teased.
I have to clean the tank because that so called fuel ruined it.
Goodbye.
Oh.
Niisku Ressuka had a bitter disappointment.
Joo.
AI Suri.
I'm doing this for Niisku.
Remember that.
That side of the matter doesn't interest me one bit.
I want to tinker with the aircraft.
The aircraft needs very efficient fuel.
Maybe fuel.
I am efficient fuel, and Niisku has not managed to get it.
No.
But I have invented one.
Guess I'll show you my triangle handkerchief one day.
The important thing now is that we don't dissolve the fuel in the water.
Can't get the door open already?
It's open.
Good.
I'll put it as a trap.
I want to direct.
to an altitude of 2000 meters.
ha Isu Li, still suli.
Altitude 2500 meters.
ha Isu Li.
Now what again?
Try to stay in your skin.
Start the engine as soon as I give the order.
Clear.
Welcome.
It's this button.
Not yet.
A drop of water just spoils it.
Made it clear.
Do I start?
No.
Clear.
So, now start.
At the behest of.
Are you sure you want to start the engine?
Starter.
The engine doesn't even suck! Did you miss the piece I showed you?
Well, I twisted it! Exactly that piece!
Was it wrong?
Long live the fools there! My invention career is at stake!
Still won't start? Well, not now!
Nothing happens!
It was a blast to let you in there! I'll come myself!
Dear Mr. Guess, there's only one more piece left here!
What?
Today, the guidance was down to the last piece!
Now it hums! Now it hums!
Aha! Let's go save the day!
Amazing! I'm not surprised, but certainly happy!
I wish you could see that this is my big moment!
Come on, get up so I can steer!
The ship rises like a phoenix bird towards the stars!
My historical invention! Hooray, hooray, hooray!
Well, I'll lie down then!
Don't get up now, let's fly!
Shocking power! The engine explodes!
My bolt is blowing up the engine!
It stinks, the engine explodes!
The ship takes off!
Go ahead before it crashes!
It's a bit of a shame, but my boyfriend is a boy after all!
Oh!
Hmm...
Selle has seen your small size, but sieve.
I had no intention of destroying the ship in the first place.
Of course not. I would like to ask a small favor from a big cookie.
Could you come up with something non-explosive against the rosy-sucking booths?
It's not an art or a piece of cake.
I would so like to fly!
You can do it bravely, Nisku.
Make a new one.
Nisku, you don't guess, but I had such a dream that I was flying.
No, you just flew. Well, that's interesting.
Yes, it flew. And it wasn't like that, hey?
Yes, but that flight vector was quite different from Nisku's aircraft.
What was it like?
Well, if you would describe it briefly.
It was round and at the bottom there was something like a currant.
For I flew over the mountains.
Oh round. And there was a basket at the bottom.
It was so. Round and basket.
Oh round.
Nisku, what happened to you?
Thanks for the coffee. Something interesting seems to be brewing in my brain.
So thank you and see you soon.
Oh, he's busy.
I feel that look in his eyes.
You won't get a reasonable answer from my brother for at least a month.
That's what I think too.
But in vain he so hard for the horses.
It is what it is.
Niskula is Nisku kujeet.
The explosion did not depress Nisku for long.
Let's see what the next aircraft will be like.
Round.