Terribly boring.
It is.
What bores you?
Would like to play with someone else.
Just like me, for a change.
So yes.
With Alisa, although...
He hasn't been here in ages.
Studying to become a witch requires a lot of effort.
Maybe he will fly here one day.
And teaches us tricks too.
Hey, what are you doing there?
Nothing.
Except you throw stones.
Always the same old faces.
What do you mean?
It would be fun to play with a new friend.
Well, I just came.
And me?
No variation whatsoever.
You'll miss it here.
I'm bored.
I rest sometimes.
Alisa!
Sorry, I just stopped standing like a stone.
You stopped at the wrong time, my lady.
But when I missed so much.
It is an important exercise.
A witch must learn to be patient.
I already am.
You would teach those tricks.
Well, recite your spell for me.
Who is it?
Don't say you've reached out.
How to enchant someone into a troupe.
Or to do other magic if you have cast your own spell.
No way.
That?
Ah, I'll just come.
Enough, enough already.
Now I will teach you a new thing.
Hurrah!
What trick will you teach me?
I want to learn to fly.
First I teach you how to walk everywhere.
But I can walk.
No, no, me neither.
It's very different from your first flywheel.
Oh, and the final air at the beginning is ten times bigger.
How many people can it fit?
Yay, probably just two.
But the good thing about it is that it is as easy to fly as it is to walk.
Like a witch with a broom?
Broom flies my sorcery ship with the power of science.
But both fly?
In a way, but the broom is flying for all the wrong reasons.
On my plane, however, anyone can learn to fly.
So is it wrong to admire a witch's bone?
Necessarily.
Does Niisku show his platform?
Too early.
I want to see it.
Maybe Niisku won't get angry if I tell you just a little.
It carries two people.
Then it's not an airship.
But it can make sudden turns.
Just like walking.
That's how Niisku described it.
Niisku's airship is surprisingly small.
Why doesn't he show it to us?
Yes, the time will come.
Let's be patient.
I want to see right away.
What would you come up with here?
Let's go see those.
I'm Alice.
You are interested in gas, Alisa.
Yeah, I'm interested.
I have to feed the niisku.
I remembered that I am booked.
Are you still afraid of the witch?
No, but witchcraft is suspect.
Sell, is tomorrow ok?
It's the same, will you be a swamp lady too?
Of course I will.
Nipsu, are you busy tomorrow too?
I don't know yet, but you're missing something.
Hmm, a very multifaceted question.
Niisku thinks that science is more valuable than witchcraft.
That's the opinion of Niisku.
I think witchcraft is much nicer.
So do I.
The witch has only a bone.
At least Niisku's aircraft will be more comfortable.
A broom handle is a hard place to sit.
Grandma, can't you get a little broom ready for this?
Birch's toes would fly, but I'm too tired.
So do I.
Studying to be a witch is hard work.
Teaching to be a witch is hard work.
If the apprentice takes all day to learn witch walk,
what will become of you?
Witches, of course.
Could I fail when you're teaching me?
Well, yeah.
Moomin troll.
Hey.
Are you going out to sea to fish?
I don't know.
Hemuli told me that he has seen a mamluk fish.
Mamluks?
Hemuli says it is a rare fish and very tasty.
We were thinking of going together to see Alisa.
I haven't seen him down either.
I haven't seen him down.
We were thinking of going together to see Alisa.
I haven't seen him in ages either.
Now it would be our turn to go to Alisa.
Snuff!
Hi sell.
Are you coming to the witch too?
I don't. I won't come.
He goes fishing.
See you again.
Where's the knuckles?
Oh, coming soon.
There will also be a pinch.
Of course not.
The forest is terribly scary.
Then why did you reverse your decision?
Better to be safe than sorry I thought, but now I'm not sure.
Hey!
Keeh!
Fun!
Heilitse, you were a bird yourself!
Pretty stupid if you think about it.
Let's go play with that scion.
No one is stopping you from coming back.
Don't be silly!
I wouldn't even be able to get home from here!
Oida Ninja Greatest ever!
Opedan salaat s lobbiä tubin Ian jaügen Studios-symonas sp abundance
Que occupation영 morgen esim
P och like el
Ompas, someone is coming.
And it won't, you're just trying to freak out.
What sound?
Run!
Jukranpujut, there's still something glamorous about running around.
That sound stopped already.
Shall we hide if we hear it again?
I hear a voice. The sound is approaching. It comes here.
Oh, hide me!
Oh, let's see!
It's here!
Hi Nipsu!
Sorry, I almost ran over you.
Alisa!
Hi, nice to see you.
Where are you going?
We were coming to see you, Alisa.
Häras came along, or because he was so bored?
I was coming for you.
I would like to show you one particularly difficult witch trick.
Great! We have something to show too.
Aha!
Listen to what I'm telling you.
I have finally become a witch.
A witch, right?
I'm a full witch, almost.
Do you like pancakes?
That's right!
Frogs, porcini mushrooms and crazy cabbage taste great, but variety is refreshing.
Are witches not allowed to eat pancakes?
Yes, they will.
But grandma doesn't know how to fry them.
Come on, let the pan fry!
I can't do that trick.
Then he can never eat pancakes and jelly, except in the Moomin house.
Terrible.
Pölle, the Moomin mom teaches Alisa how to fry.
I could come and learn one day.
For all I care.
I feel like witchcraft isn't all that wonderful.
Alisa, when are you going to show what you've learned?
Well, anytime, as soon as you want.
Then show immediately.
Good, let's go to the pond after I eat.
To the lake?
Joo.
Well Alisa, show me what you can do.
Look, I'm showing the walk.
A walk?
Those walks on the pond.
Oh, so you walk on water?
I'm walking.
Are you sure?
I'll save him if something happens.
Keep an eye on everything.
Wait!
What now?
Can you hoot?
I can't.
That would be enough for a teenager.
You know the pond is deep.
I know, I walk on the surface and not on the bottom.
If you wait a bit, I'll bring the boat and...
No trouble, believe me.
Hey, shut up now.
I cast a spell.
A spell?
A spell that only I can use.
I'll have to make a note of that.
Papa.
Oh, sorry.
In the sizzling sarago kannelorum lom.
Barbarossa of the whistle stable.
Tilulilulaa
Oh, usko matonda.
Impressive!
Welcome, let's see you.
What a wonder!
Great, Alisa!
Good, Alice!
Good!
Listen, if I remembered the Spell, would I be able to walk on water too?
You wouldn't be able to.
Ha, first you have to learn to eat rat liver and lizard tongues.
What about me? I eat everything.
Huh? Nothing would come of it now.
How so?
You wouldn't dare try.
None of us are witches.
Just speak for yourself, I could do whatever I wanted.
You wouldn't use witchcraft for anything sensible.
As?
To turn stones into gold.
Jaha, I'd turn you into a slimy toad.
What did I say?
Hey, sell trinkets! Hurry up!
You know you don't like toads.
What do you think? Can those tricks also be done scientifically?
Those tricks are precisely unscientific.
I guess so.
I might be able to figure out a way to walk on the surface of the water.
Could you?
I wouldn't be surprised.
I'm here!
Niiskoneiit's turn to be impressed.
All right! Now I did!
A sniff of muikkune and hemuli!
Alisa, you missed me.
In the middle of nowhere...
No spells, Alisa! You have to catch others!
Bye!
Alisa, walk snuff to the muikku's boat!
Selvon!
You're not kidding!
Oh hemuli!
Alisa has learned these tricks from her grandmother.
Nice to see you again!
You walk on water.
You thought I couldn't?
Well indeed.
What now?
A fish of enormous size lurked below!
Mamelukkikala!
Very big!
It's a mamluk fish.
We try to catch it!
I'm a little scared. Can I come on your boat?
As long as you keep quiet, of course.
Thanks.
Good day, hemuli!
Good day, ladies!
Oh hemuli!
Mameluke hooked!
Don't run away!
Oh wow!
Hemuli!
Be warned!
You caught a mamluk fish!
Who asked who?
Big fish!
Alisa, stop the boat!
What?
Bring the boat to a stop!
Sorry, but all I can do is walk!
Mamelukkikala!
Uskavuikku, that makes him!
This is equivalent to fishing.
I don't understand what we do with such a big fish!
The line broke.
Oh wet! That's what you got!
It's getting late.
Does your grandma get angry?
He hasn't been away himself.
But now it's time to go home.
Come and play tomorrow too.
Can you make it?
No.
Let's go.
Come and play tomorrow too.
Can you make it?
It just depends on what mood grandma is in.
That's how the step-by-step day of my grandma and partnerships ended.
Where did he stay?
If you're not in a hurry, I'll go already!
What strange thing have you got into your head?
What do you mean?
Those goddamn tricks.
You will think differently when you see what these can be used for.
Father, Niisku-neiti and Niisku are coming.
Can you walk on water with them?
I invented them.
Do they stay afloat on their own?
Remember to be careful.
There is nothing to worry about.
Well, now I'll try.
Hurrah!
I'm ready.
What have I said?
Science works for these.
Anyone can walk...
Uhh...
Help!
Sell, you are my only hope.
Trust me, Niisku!
Get wet!
I'll do anything...
Well, as you can see, science trumps witchcraft.
Niisku, good water skates only work on my feet.
Others are horribly clumsy.
This is fun!
Ugh!
You would think that riding the waves is difficult.
Science knows what witches do.
I'm not sure.
Science is supreme.
Are water skis a science?
Oh sell, will be back!
And it won't!
I'm having fun!
Come back when I feel like it.
Hey!
Oho, luhkia silver!
Is Hanseen a coward?
Sell, watch out!
Ugh!
I have to admit, you just got better.
I wonder myself why bother.
Once you're in it, you wouldn't be able to come up with your own spell for me.
That's how I would help you with witchcraft.
In!
You have already saved me twice.
I could surprise you sometimes.
I miss your surprises in the meantime.